<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SSL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SSL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ssl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Port Names and Terminating HTTPS Traffic on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/21/kubernetes-port-names-and-terminating-https-traffic-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/21/kubernetes-port-names-and-terminating-https-traffic-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t immediately intuitive with regard to terminating HTTPS traffic on an AWS Elastic Load Balancer (ELB) when using &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; on AWS. At least, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive to &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that it may not be intuitive to some other readers as well. Kudos to my teammates &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hhoover&#34;&gt;Hart Hoover&lt;/a&gt; and Brent Yarger for identifying the resolution, which I&amp;rsquo;m going to call out in this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 116</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #116! This one is a bit shorter than usual, due to holidays in the US and my life being busy. Nevertheless, I hope that I managed to capture something you find useful or helpful. As always, your feedback is welcome, so if you have suggestions, corrections, or comments, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe&#34;&gt;contact me via Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting TLS Certificates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/20/troubleshooting-tls-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/20/troubleshooting-tls-certificates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently working on a blog post involving the use of TLS certificates for encryption and authentication, and was running into errors. I&amp;rsquo;d checked all the &amp;ldquo;usual suspects&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;AWS security groups, host-level firewall rules (via &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt;), and the application configuration itself&amp;mdash;but still couldn&amp;rsquo;t get it to work. When I did finally find the error, I figured it was probably worth sharing the commands I used in the event others might find it helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #77</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #77. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new collection of links and articles from around the Web on various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  Mark Brookfield takes a moment to remind everyone that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use the (deprecated) C# vSphere Client to manage NSX environments. Good advice. Michael Kashin has a great article on how Open Virtual Network (OVN, part of the Open vSwitch project) implements virtual networks in OpenStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #45</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #45. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a collection of links to various articles pertaining to data center-related technologies for your enjoyment. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Cormac Hogan has a list of a few useful NSX troubleshooting tips.
  If you&amp;rsquo;re not really a networking pro and need a &amp;ldquo;gentle&amp;rdquo; introduction to VXLAN, this post might be a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #41, the latest in my series of random thoughts, articles, and links from around the Internet. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) is a networking topic that is starting to get more and more attention (some may equate &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;hype&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to draw your own conclusion there). In any case, I liked how this article really hit upon what I personally feel is something many people are overlooking in NFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #40. The content is a bit light this time around; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give you, my readers, a little break. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s still some useful and interesting stuff here. Enjoy!
Networking   Bob McCouch has a nice write-up on options for VPNs to AWS. If you&amp;rsquo;re needing to build out such a solution, you might want to read his post for some additional perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #21</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/12/technology-short-take-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/12/technology-short-take-21/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I published my last Technology Short Take (found here), and in browsing my list of saved links I find that I don&amp;rsquo;t really have that many to share. Which then leads to me to ask the question, &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; I think it&amp;rsquo;s because I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing lots of stuff via my Twitter account.
In any event, here are some older links that I&amp;rsquo;ve been saving up to share with you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next-Gen Stuff: Verifying the SHA-1 Fingerprint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/25/next-gen-stuff-verifying-the-sha-1-fingerprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 11:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/25/next-gen-stuff-verifying-the-sha-1-fingerprint/</guid>
      <description>This post is not necessarily specific to next-generation ESX/ESXi and vCenter Server, but it was prompted by behaviors in these products. (Besides, the truth is that I&amp;rsquo;m really just trying to be sensationalist and capitalize on interest in the next-generation products.)
When you add an ESX/ESXi host to vCenter Server in the next generation of products, you will receive a security warning that displays the SHA1 thumbprint (or fingerprint) of the ESX/ESXi host&amp;rsquo;s default SSL certificate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s lots of good information flowing around the Internet, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming increasingly difficult to sort through all the useless stuff to find the valuable gems. Hopefully, some of the links that I have collected here will prove to be more useful than useless!
  I came across this VMware KB article titled &amp;ldquo;Dedicating specific NICs to portgroups while maintaining NIC teaming and failover for the vSwitch&amp;rdquo;. I was hoping it would shed new light on some NIC teaming functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache as an OWA Front-End</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 11:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I discussed the use of Apache to protect OWA from web-based attacks. This configuration placed an Apache HTTP server in front of a server running Microsoft Exchange Server 2003 to protect it against web-based attacks, offload SSL encryption, and enable name-based virtual hosts (for the conservation of public DNS hostnames, especially important for smaller organizations). While this is a useful configuration, it is not without its drawbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting SSL Certificates with OpenSSL</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/converting-ssl-certificates-with-openssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 10:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/converting-ssl-certificates-with-openssl/</guid>
      <description>The OpenSSL toolkit is a veritable Swiss Army knife of SSL functionality. Among the many, many things that can be done using OpenSSL is converting SSL certificates between formats. This is particularly helpful in a heterogeneous environment where different platforms may require SSL certificates to be in different formats.
A mixed Windows-Linux shop is one excellent example. Windows typically requires certificates in PFX format; Linux, on the other hand, typically needs PEM format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Details on Transparent RDP Tunneling</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/19/details-on-transparent-rdp-tunneling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2006 17:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/19/details-on-transparent-rdp-tunneling/</guid>
      <description>Quite a long time ago, I posted two short articles on transparent RDP tunneling (read more here and here). To be honest, I had forgotten that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t posted more complete details on how exactly I went about making it work. So, to rectify that problem, here are the full details.
First, some background. I have a number of customers whose servers I manage remotely via Remote Desktop. Remote Desktop (or Terminal Services, if running in Application Server mode), as you may be aware, uses Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s RDP as the protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Blackberry Workaround?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/13/open-source-blackberry-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2006 16:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/13/open-source-blackberry-workaround/</guid>
      <description>Funambol, formerly Sync4j, is claiming that its latest product, Funambol 3, could function as an open-source Blackberry workaround, allowing push e-mail to be delivered to a variety of mobile devices, including Blackberries. This is particularly important in light of the threat of a Blackberry shutdown due to the RIM-NTP patent dispute.
Currently in beta, the v3 server software runs on Linux or Windows, and clients are available for Outlook, Windows Mobile, Blackberry, Palm, and (believe it or not) iPod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application-Specific VPNs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2005 11:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</guid>
      <description>I coined the term &amp;ldquo;application specific VPNs&amp;rdquo; as I began exploring the many uses of tools such as SSH (the OpenSSH implementation, in particular) and Stunnel (the open source SSL wrapper). An &amp;ldquo;application specific VPN&amp;rdquo; is a technique for employing encrypted communication with a particular remote application that does not affect the operation of other applications (local or remote) on the system.
In general, most VPNs employ technology such as PPTP or IPSec.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
