<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMwareSRM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwaresrm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMwareSRM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:00:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwaresrm/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look at VPLEX and VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>The announcement of VPLEX last week at EMC World 2010 in Boston has introduced lots of new possibilities in how virtualized data centers should be designed and deployed. Of particular interest to a number of people is how VPLEX interacts with VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM).
Jason Nash of Varrow mulls over VPLEX and VMware SRM in this post, where he asks if VMware SRM is even necessary:
 If money was no object, or if you needed VPLEX anyway, where does that leave VMwares Site Recovery Manager?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #31</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/18/virtualization-short-take-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/18/virtualization-short-take-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to yet another Virtualization Short Take! Here is a collection of virtualization-related items&amp;mdash;some recent, some not, but hopefully all interesting and/or useful.
  Matt Hensley posted a link to this VIOPS document on how to setup VMware SRM 4.0 with an EMC Celerra storage array. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to read through it yet.
  Jason Boche informs us that both Lab Manager 3 and Lab Manager 4 have problems with the VMXNET3 virtual NIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s lots of good information flowing around the Internet, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming increasingly difficult to sort through all the useless stuff to find the valuable gems. Hopefully, some of the links that I have collected here will prove to be more useful than useless!
  I came across this VMware KB article titled &amp;ldquo;Dedicating specific NICs to portgroups while maintaining NIC teaming and failover for the vSwitch&amp;rdquo;. I was hoping it would shed new light on some NIC teaming functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3183: VMware SRM on NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 09:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>This session described VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) on NetApp storage. The session started out with a review of VMware SRM, its features and functionality, and some of the requirements. I was not aware, for example, that SRM cannot use SQL Server Express like VirtualCenter can; you must use a full-blown instance of SQL Server. Given VMware&amp;rsquo;s development history, I should not have been surprised to find that Perl 5.8 is required (it&amp;rsquo;s included in the distribution and installed automatically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware SRM 1.0 Update 1 Released</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/05/vmware-srm-10-update-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2008 09:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/05/vmware-srm-10-update-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Many thanks to Dave Lawrence, aka VMguy, for the heads-up: Update 1 for VMware Site Recovery Manager 1.0 has been released. Missing in this update: NFS support. I mention that only because I heard numerous references to NFS Support in SRM 1.0U1 at NetApp Insight a few weeks ago. Of course, they also mentioned a March 2009 timeframe, so I was a bit surprised when I saw that Update 1 had been released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Keynote - Automating DR with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>There is no general session this morning at VMworld 2008; instead, a &amp;ldquo;keynote&amp;rdquo; will be delivered about automating disaster recovery (DR) using VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM). This is similar to the way in which other vendors have delivered various &amp;ldquo;keynotes&amp;rdquo; throughout the conference instead of all the announcements being crammed into the morning general sessions.
The speaker this morning is Jay Judkowitz, the product manager for VMware SRM. I&amp;rsquo;ve met Jay before; he&amp;rsquo;s a good guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC1693: Architecting DR Solutions with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc1693-architecting-dr-solutions-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc1693-architecting-dr-solutions-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>Late again! Man, I need to get on the ball! Fortunately, I only missed the first part of the agenda. Once again, no Wi-Fi access in the session breakout, so I&amp;rsquo;ll publish this at the first available opportunity.
This is BC1693, Architecting DR Solutions with VMware SRM. The presenters are John Arrasjid and Will Crittenden; these are two solid guys that know DR and know SRM very well.
John starts the session with an overview of the influencing factors that affect a DR solution using SRM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few SRM Discussion Points</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/06/a-few-srm-discussion-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 23:16:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/06/a-few-srm-discussion-points/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never really discussed VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) here; there always seemed to be plenty of coverage elsewhere. Just recently, though, I had the opportunity to spend some time with a very knowledgeable SRM resource within VMware, and gathered some notes about VMware SRM that I thought might be helpful. Some of this stuff may be obvious, so bear with me.
  Storage array replication is a necessity. Without it, SRM can&amp;rsquo;t be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #13</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/17/virtualization-short-take-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 11:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/17/virtualization-short-take-13/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the latest installation of Virtualization Short Takes, my occasionally-weekly view on various virtualization news, reviews, and other happenings. Hopefully I can share something interesting with you!
  Via VMblog.com, I saw that Transitive Corporation is supporting the use of QuickTransit within Hyper-V virtual machines. This is interesting because it extends the ability of Hyper-V to help customers consolidate applications. QuickTransit, in case you aren&amp;rsquo;t aware, allows applications written for Solaris/SPARC environments to run in Linux/x86 environments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
