<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musing on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/musing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musing on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 15:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/musing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thinking and Learning About API Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/24/thinking-and-learning-about-api-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/24/thinking-and-learning-about-api-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In July of 2018 I talked about &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scottslowe/polyglot&#34;&gt;Polyglot&lt;/a&gt;, a very simple project I&amp;rsquo;d launched whose &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; purpose was simply to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/23/bolstering-my-software-development-skills/&#34;&gt;bolster my software development skills&lt;/a&gt;. Work on Polyglot has been sporadic at best, coming in fits and spurts, and thus far focused on building a model for the APIs that would be found in the project. Since I am not a software engineer by training (I have no formal training in software development), all of this is new to me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself encountering lots of questions about API design along the way. In the interest of helping others who may be in a similar situation, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a bit here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Thinking About Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/on-thinking-about-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/on-thinking-about-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished reading Cindy Sridharan&amp;rsquo;s excellent post titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@copyconstruct/effective-mental-models-for-code-and-systems-7c55918f1b3e&#34;&gt;Effective Mental Models for Code and Systems&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; and some of the points Sridharan makes immediately jumped out to me&amp;mdash;not for &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; code development, but for the development of infrastructure as code. Take a few minutes to go read the post&amp;mdash;seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; good. Done reading it? Good, now we can proceed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts on the Docker-Kubernetes Announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/some-thoughts-on-docker-kubernetes-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/some-thoughts-on-docker-kubernetes-announcement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today at DockerCon EU, Docker announced that the next version of Docker (and its upstream open source project, the Moby Project) will feature integration with Kubernetes (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/dockercon-eu-day-1-keynote/&#34;&gt;my liveblog of the day 1 general session&lt;/a&gt;). Customers will be able to choose whether they leverage Swarm or Kubernetes for container orchestration. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a few thoughts on this move by Docker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on AWS re:Invent Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/thoughts-aws-reinvent-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/thoughts-aws-reinvent-day-1/</guid>
      <description>As I wrap up Day 1 of AWS re:Invent 2016 in Las Vegas (can I consider today to be day 1?), I wanted to capture a quick summary of thoughts about the sessions, the content, the attendees, and the event (not necessarily in that order).
First, here are some links to the liveblogs I posted from today&amp;rsquo;s sessions:
Liveblog: Scaling to Your First 10 Million Users
Liveblog: Hybrid Architectures, Bridging the Gap to the Cloud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/09/thinking-out-loud-future-of-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/09/thinking-out-loud-future-of-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just wrapped up KubeCon/CloudNativeCon 2016 in Seattle, WA. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt the Kubernetes community is active and engaged, and the project itself is charging forward. As both the community and the project grow, though, what does that mean for the future of Kubernetes?
Here are my thoughts, hopefully presented in a somewhat logical fashion.
It seems to me that Kubernetes has been successful thus far because of a strong focus on the problem it&amp;rsquo;s trying to solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Luminus Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/23/thoughts-on-luminus-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/23/thoughts-on-luminus-networks/</guid>
      <description>Late last week, Cyrus Durgin from Luminus Networks published an article on SDx Central titled &amp;ldquo;The (R)evolution of Network Operations.&amp;rdquo; You may notice that my name is mentioned at the bottom of the article as someone who provided feedback. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some thoughts&amp;mdash;high-level and conceptual in nature&amp;mdash;on network operations and Luminus Networks.
I was first introduced to Luminus Networks when I met its CEO, Kelly Wanser, at the Open Networking User Group (ONUG) meeting in New York City last November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Does Docker on Windows Matter?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/30/thinking-out-loud-does-docker-on-windows-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/30/thinking-out-loud-does-docker-on-windows-matter/</guid>
      <description>Nigel Poulton recently posted an article titled &amp;ldquo;ESXi vs. Hyper-V - Could Docker Support Be Significant,&amp;rdquo; in which he contemplates whether Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s announcement of Docker support on Windows will be a factor in the hypervisor battle between ESXi and Hyper-V. His post got me thinking&amp;mdash;which is a good thing, I&amp;rsquo;d say&amp;mdash;and I wanted to share my thoughts on the topic here.
Naturally, it&amp;rsquo;s worth pointing out that I work for VMware, although I do work in a business unit that makes a multi-hypervisor product (NSX).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Documenting Systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/23/self-documenting-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/23/self-documenting-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Singapore this past week, wrapping up the week by speaking at the inaugural Singapore VMUG User Conference. While at the User Conference, I had the opportunity to attend a session by John Arrasjid (you probably know him as @vcdx001 on Twitter) on the art of IT infrastructure design. Although John&amp;rsquo;s session was on helping IT architects understand one possible methodology of approaching infrastructure design, his session got me thinking about documenting IT systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Intel Rack-Scale Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard of Intel Rack-Scale Architecture (RSA), a new approach to designing data center hardware. This is an idea that was discussed extensively a couple of weeks ago at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014 in San Francisco, which I had the opportunity to attend. (Disclaimer: Intel paid my travel and hotel expenses to attend IDF.)
Of course, IDF 2014 wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I&amp;rsquo;d heard of Intel RSA; it was also discussed last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Handling Career Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</guid>
      <description>As IT pros at the &amp;ldquo;cutting edge&amp;rdquo; of technology and industry change, I think sometimes we forget that not everyone has the same mindset toward learning, growth, and career evolution. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true, I think, for those of us who are bloggers, because it&amp;rsquo;s our passion for the technology that not only drives us to write about it but also drives us to constantly explore new trends, new areas, and new concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the Threshold</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/16/crossing-the-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/16/crossing-the-threshold/</guid>
      <description>Last week while attending the CloudStack Collaboration Conference in my home city of Denver, I had a bit of a realization. I wanted to share it here in the hopes that it might serve as an encouragement for others out there.
Long-time readers know that one of my projects over the last couple of years has been to become more fluent in Linux (refer back to my 2012 project list and my 2013 project list).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: DIY Network Virtualization?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 11:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Following on the heels of this week&amp;rsquo;s VMware NSX announcement at VMworld 2013, I had someone contact me about a statement this person had heard. The statement claimed NSX was nothing more than a collection of tools, and that it was possible to get the equivalent of NSX using completely free (as in speech and as in beer) open source tools&amp;mdash;specifically, IPTables, StrongSwan, OpenVPN, and Open vSwitch (OVS). Basically, the statement was that it was possible to create do-it-yourself network virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of VLANs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me how much the idea of a VLAN has invaded the consciousness of data center IT professionals. Data center folks primarily tasked with managing compute workloads are nearly as familiar with VLANs as their colleagues primarily tasked with managing network connectivity. However, as networking undergoes a transformation at the hands of SDN, NFV, and network virtualization, what will happen to the VLAN?
The ubiquity of the VLAN is due, I think, to the fact that it serves as a reasonable &amp;ldquo;common ground&amp;rdquo; for both compute-focused and networking-focused professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Symbiosis Between Automation and Engineering</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/10/the-symbiosis-between-automation-and-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/10/the-symbiosis-between-automation-and-engineering/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago Steve Beaver wrote a post titled &amp;ldquo;Is Automation Killing The Engineering?&amp;rdquo; In the post, Steve ponders whether the increased use of automation in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers is killing engineering knowledge. The argument, as I understand it, says that because tasks are becoming increasingly automated, data center professionals are increasingly less knowledgeable about how things actually work. But is this a valid argument? Is automation killing engineering?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very Early Thoughts about EMC ViPR</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/06/very-early-thoughts-about-emc-vipr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 18:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/06/very-early-thoughts-about-emc-vipr/</guid>
      <description>EMC announced ViPR today, the culmination of the not-so-secret Project Bourne and its lesser-known predecessor, Project Orion. Although I used to work at EMC before I joined VMware earlier this year, I never really had deep access to what was going on with this project, so my thoughts here are strictly based on what&amp;rsquo;s been publicly disclosed. Naturally, given that the product was only announced today, these are very early thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
