<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nicira on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nicira/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nicira on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nicira/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 7: Handling the NVP to NSX Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/01/learning-nvp-part-7-handling-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/01/learning-nvp-part-7-handling-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 7 of the Learning NVP blog series, in which I will discuss transitioning from a focus on NVP to looking at NSX.
If you&amp;rsquo;re just now joining me for this series, here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s transpired thus far:
  In part 1, I provided a high-level overview of NVP and its core components.
  In part 2, I showed you how to build NVP controllers and configure them into a controller cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 6: Adding an NVP Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/28/learning-nvp-part-6-adding-an-nvp-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/28/learning-nvp-part-6-adding-an-nvp-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 6 of the Learning NVP blog series. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to add an NVP gateway appliance to your NVP environment. In future posts, you&amp;rsquo;ll use this NVP gateway to host either L2 or L3 gateway services (more on those in a moment). First, though, let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick recap of what&amp;rsquo;s transpired so far:
  In part 1, I provided a high-level overview of NVP and its core components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 5: Creating a Logical Network</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/06/learning-nvp-part-5-creating-a-logical-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/06/learning-nvp-part-5-creating-a-logical-network/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with more NVP goodness; this time, I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking you through the process of creating a logical network and attaching VMs to that logical network. This work builds on the stuff that has come before it in this series:
  In part 1, I introduced you to the high-level architecture of NVP.
  In part 2, I walked you through setting up a cluster of NVP controllers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 4: Adding Hypervisors to NVP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/22/learning-nvp-part-4-adding-hypervisors-to-nvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/22/learning-nvp-part-4-adding-hypervisors-to-nvp/</guid>
      <description>This is part 4 of the Learning NVP blog series. Just to quickly recap what&amp;rsquo;s happened so far, in part 1 I provided the high-level architecture of NVP and discussed the role of the components in broad terms. In part 2, I focused on the NVP controllers, showing you how to build/configure the NVP controllers and establish a controller cluster. Part 3 focused on NVP Manager, which allowed us to perform a few additional NVP configuration tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 3: NVP Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/19/learning-nvp-part-3-nvp-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 09:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/19/learning-nvp-part-3-nvp-manager/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 3 of the Learning NVP blog series. In part 1, I provide an overview of the high-level architecture of NVP and discussed the role of the components in broad terms. In part 2, I focused on the NVP controllers, showing you how to build/configure the NVP controllers and establish a controller cluster. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to turn my attention to NVP Manager, which will allow us to further configure NVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 2: NVP Controllers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 2 of the Learning NVP blog series. In part 1 of the series, I provided a high-level overview of the NVP architecture and components. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into a bit more detail on one key component of the architecture: the NVP controllers and controller cluster.
(Just a quick reminder: although I&amp;rsquo;m talking about NVP 3.1&amp;ndash;our publicly available, GA product already running in production with customers&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that the NVP architecture serves as the basis for the upcoming VMware NSX product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 1: High-Level Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</guid>
      <description>This blog post kicks off a new series of posts describing my journey to become more knowledgeable about the Nicira Network Virtualization Platform (NVP). NVP is, in my opinion, an awesome platform, but there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a great deal of information shared about the product, how it works, how you configure it, etc. That&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to address in this series of posts. In this first post, I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a high-level description of the NVP architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life at VMware, Two Weeks In</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/25/life-at-vmware-two-weeks-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/25/life-at-vmware-two-weeks-in/</guid>
      <description>Today marks my &amp;ldquo;two week anniversary&amp;rdquo; in my new role at VMware. So far, it&amp;rsquo;s been everything that I thought it would be&amp;mdash;exciting, but also challenging.
My entire first week was taken up by new hire onboarding and some training on Nicira&amp;rsquo;s Network Virtualization Platform (NVP). I was pleased to find that the time and effort I&amp;rsquo;d spent familiarizing myself with OpenFlow and Open vSwitch (OVS) proved quite useful in hitting the ground running with NVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Challenges, New Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/25/new-year-new-challenges-new-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 17:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/25/new-year-new-challenges-new-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>I suppose there&amp;rsquo;s no sense in beating around the bush. As the blog post title indicates, I&amp;rsquo;m taking on a new set of challenges (and a new set of opportunities) in 2013&amp;ndash;and the way to do that is in a new role with a new company. So, effective 2/8/2013, I am leaving EMC Corporation to join the former Nicira group at VMware, working directly for Martin Casado. I&amp;rsquo;ll be working with folks like Brad Hedlund (see his announcement here), Bruce Davie, and Teemu Koponen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
