<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2016/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EMEA 2016 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/19/vmworld-emea-2016-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/19/vmworld-emea-2016-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 general session at VMworld EMEA 2016 in Barcelona, Spain. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to write a liveblog of the day 1 session due to some scheduling/logistical conflicts, but managed to get things arranged for day 2 (well, most of it&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to cut this short so I can get to a customer meeting).
At 9am, Sanjay Poonen takes the stage to kick off the general session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2016 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/30/vmworld2016-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/30/vmworld2016-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 general session here at VMworld 2016 at Mandalay Bay in Las Vegas, NV. Today, VMware is expected to talk more about containers, end-user computing, and other topics not covered in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s general session (which focused heavily on Cross-Cloud Services, VMware&amp;rsquo;s new set of SaaS-based offerings for multi-cloud management).
The general session kicks off with Sanjay Poonen taking the stage. Poonen is an energetic speaker who&amp;rsquo;s generally very entertaining and lively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2016 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/29/vmworld2016-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/29/vmworld2016-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 1 keynote at VMworld 2016 in Las Vegas, NV. I managed to snag a somewhat decent seat in the massive bloggers/press/analysts area, though it filled up really quickly. Based on the announcements made this morning, it should be a great general session, and I&amp;rsquo;m really interested to see how its received by the community.
The keynote starts with a high-energy percussion/DJ session, followed by a talk about tomorrow&amp;mdash;from where tomorrow will emerge, what tomorrow will look like, and what tomorrow will care about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Me at VMworld 2016?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/25/meet-me-at-vmworld-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/25/meet-me-at-vmworld-2016/</guid>
      <description>VMworld is upon us, and if you&amp;rsquo;ve been to the conference before you know it can sometimes be challenging to catch up with folks. (If this is your first time, now you know it can sometimes be challenging to catch up with folks.) This post is an effort to help make it a bit easier if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in meeting up with me at VMworld.
In years past, I published my schedule so that others could see what sessions I was attending, find times we could meet, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2016 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/vmworld-2016-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/vmworld-2016-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve helped organize a gathering of Christians for a brief time of prayer while at VMworld. This year, I’d like to again offer fellow believers attending VMworld 2016 the same opportunity to gather together for a time of prayer before starting the day. If you’re interested in attending, here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer
Where: Mandalay Bay Convention Center, level 1 (same level as the food court), at the bottom of the escalators heading upstairs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at VMworld 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/29/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/29/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2016/</guid>
      <description>Many of you have asked, and here&amp;rsquo;s the answer: Yes, there will be Spousetivities at VMworld 2016 in Las Vegas, NV! For those of you who may be new to the VMworld scene, Spousetivities started in 2008 when my wife got together with a small group of spouses and partners traveling with the conference attendees. From there, it&amp;rsquo;s become a staple of the VMworld community events. Read on for more details on what&amp;rsquo;s planned this year at VMworld 2016!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
