<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/apache/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apache on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 12:36:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/apache/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu and Mac OS X Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/02/ubuntu-and-mac-os-x-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 12:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/02/ubuntu-and-mac-os-x-integration/</guid>
      <description>One of my projects over the Christmas holiday has been to rebuild the home network. You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d want to avoid that sort of thing since I&amp;rsquo;ve been on vacation from work for the past two weeks, but working on a home network is a different sort of beast than working on a network for a company. There are different challenges to be addressed.
My primary goals for this &amp;ldquo;home network rebuild&amp;rdquo; were the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on Kerberos Authentication Against Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/21/more-on-kerberos-authentication-against-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2006 15:25:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/21/more-on-kerberos-authentication-against-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll break the information down according by the article to which the information pertains. If the information pertains to all the articles equally, it is included in the &amp;ldquo;All Articles&amp;rdquo; portion. Links back to the original articles are included.
All Articles User Accounts vs. Computer Accounts One thing in common across all these articles is the need to create special accounts in Active Directory. I originally recommended the use of computer accounts, but over the course of time additional integration tasks with Kerberos have led me to believe that the user of user accounts, not computer accounts, is the best way to handle this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kerberos-Based SSO with Apache</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/10/kerberos-based-sso-with-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 09:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/10/kerberos-based-sso-with-apache/</guid>
      <description>The key to the magic here is the mod_auth_kerb module, which adds Kerberos authentication to Apache. This module not only allows Apache to use Kerberos on the &amp;ldquo;back-end,&amp;rdquo; so to speak, but also supports the SPNEGO and GSS-API stuff on the &amp;ldquo;front-end&amp;rdquo; that allow it to transparently authenticate users connecting with supported browsers, without ever prompting for a password.
Preparing Active Directory (Each Apache Server) These steps need to be repeated for each Apache server that will authenticating via Kerberos to Active Directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache as an OWA Front-End</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 11:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I discussed the use of Apache to protect OWA from web-based attacks. This configuration placed an Apache HTTP server in front of a server running Microsoft Exchange Server 2003 to protect it against web-based attacks, offload SSL encryption, and enable name-based virtual hosts (for the conservation of public DNS hostnames, especially important for smaller organizations). While this is a useful configuration, it is not without its drawbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Open Source</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/04/thinking-about-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 19:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/04/thinking-about-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Reading about the &amp;ldquo;Vulnerability Discovery and Remediation Open Source Hardening Project&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;a security audit funded by the Department of Homeland Security to regularly review popular open source software (this article has more information)&amp;mdash;got me thinking.
The article that sparked my thinking discussed how a critical flaw had been discovered in the X Window System. This flaw was described as one of the most serious flaws uncovered to date. The flaw was corrected quickly, as is typical of most open source projects, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really the flaw itself or the quick response to the flaw that really got to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting OWA with Apache</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/03/protecting-owa-with-apache/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2005 09:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/03/protecting-owa-with-apache/</guid>
      <description>Outlook Web Access (OWA) is the web-based interface for accessing e-mail and other resources handled by Microsoft Exchange. Unfortunately, OWA&amp;rsquo;s popularity also makes it the target of numerous worms and security exploits. As a result, many organizations seek to deploy OWA behind a reverse proxy that can help shield OWA from web-based attacks and exploits. In this posting, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share information to help build a reverse proxy using Apache 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Integration Task(s)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/24/next-integration-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2005 23:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/24/next-integration-tasks/</guid>
      <description>With the majority of my Linux servers now authenticating against Active Directory, I&amp;rsquo;m now able to broaden my integration focus and work on some related tasks:
  SASL2/PAM: I still have one server, running SASL2, that has not been switched over to the standard Kerberos/LDAP configuration. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to research the interplay between SASL2 and PAM before I tackle this one.
  OpenBSD Authentication: I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched any of the OpenBSD servers yet for Kerberos/LDAP authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Use a Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>A fair number of people have asked me why I use an Apple Mac when my business centers primarily around Microsoft products such as Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, and Exchange? That&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable question.
My computer is simply a tool to get my job done. About two years ago, I started to evaluate the tasks that I tackle on a regular basis as part of supporting my customers&amp;rsquo; networks. In reviewing those tasks, it become evident to me that using Windows myself was not a prerequisite for designing, installing, and supporting Windows-based networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New del.icio.us Links</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 10:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve added a couple new links to my del.icio.us bookmarks. Most notably, I&amp;rsquo;ve added an entry for a recent article on ONLamp.com, a site hosted by the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Network, on mod_security.
The article, Securing Web Services with mod_security, is a great introduction to an Apache module that I&amp;rsquo;ve known about and used for a while now. Similar to URLScan for IIS 5.0, mod_security serves to block malicious URLs and invalid requests, even within encrypted HTTPS sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
