<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tagging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/tagging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tagging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 18:48:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/tagging/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Listing All Unique MailTags Keywords</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/24/listing-all-unique-mailtags-keywords/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2007 18:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/24/listing-all-unique-mailtags-keywords/</guid>
      <description>After figuring out yesterday how to list all the unique MailTags projects in use, today I worked out how to list all the unique MailTags keywords in use. As it turns out, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as hard as I had suspected that it would be.
(Note to experienced UNIX hackers: I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I probably could have worked out a more elegant solution involving more pipes and redirection, but this works for a UNIX apprentice such as me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listing Unique Projects Used by MailTags</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/23/listing-unique-projects-used-by-mailtags/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2007 18:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/23/listing-unique-projects-used-by-mailtags/</guid>
      <description>Spurred to see if I could become more efficient than I am currently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with some GTD-style applications. As a result of my experiments, I found that I needed a list of all the MailTags projects I&amp;rsquo;ve ever used in any of my mailboxes. (To make a long story short, I want to use the same project names across all applications&amp;mdash;Mail, GTD application, Spotlight comments for files, etc.) While you can see a list of projects in the Preferences, that list does not include all projects that might ever have been used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Bookmark Managers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/25/mac-bookmark-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2007 22:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/25/mac-bookmark-managers/</guid>
      <description>The idea behind del.icio.us is great, but for me it becomes truly useful using a &amp;ldquo;rich client&amp;rdquo; instead of a web browser. For a long time, Cocoalicious has been that &amp;ldquo;rich client,&amp;rdquo; offering a combination of native Mac OS X technologies with the web services offered by del.icio.us. Unfortunately, it appears as though Cocoalicious is no longer under active development, and so I&amp;rsquo;ve gone seeking other solutions.
There are quite a few bookmark managers out there for the Mac, but not so many that offer integration with del.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crude Document Management System</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/26/a-crude-document-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 17:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/26/a-crude-document-management-system/</guid>
      <description>My rudimentary &amp;ldquo;document management system&amp;rdquo; is comprised of a variety of technologies, some built into Mac OS X and some added on via separate third-party applications. At the core of the system is Spotlight, the search engine that is the object of a love-hate relationship with many Mac users. Despite Spotlight&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings, it is still a very useful tool to have. (I will have to admit that I am sure I am still not taking full advantage of Spotlight&amp;rsquo;s abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tags, RSS, and Other Site Changes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/15/tags-rss-and-other-site-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2006 12:31:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/15/tags-rss-and-other-site-changes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wrestling with Technorati not indexing my weblog for quite a while now. It appears that ever since I added Ultimate Tag Warrior to my weblog and moved the tags into the keywords portion of the weblog (instead of the posting body), Technorati stopped indexing the site. It appears that the tags aren&amp;rsquo;t being added to the RSS and Atom feeds in the content, and therefore Technorati won&amp;rsquo;t properly index the site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tagging Tactics</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/18/tagging-tactics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 23:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/18/tagging-tactics/</guid>
      <description>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t dare to describe myself an expert on the use of such sites or services as del.icio.us, Technorati, or other sites that promote the use of &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; as a means of organizing links or other content. I do use these sites (you&amp;rsquo;ll note the &amp;ldquo;Technorati Tags&amp;rdquo; added to each post), and I do find them very useful. However, I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to shift tactics in my use of tags, and hoping that this change will make these services even more useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
