<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/security/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 155</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #155, just in time for the 2022 Memorial Day holiday weekend! (Here in the US, at least.) I mean, don&amp;rsquo;t you want to spend this weekend catching up on some technology-related articles instead of cooking on the grill and gathering with friends and family? I certainly hope not! Still, for those who need a little technology fix over the weekend, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve included something useful in the list of articles below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Control Plane Access with Cluster API</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/12/fine-tuning-control-plane-access-with-cluster-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/12/fine-tuning-control-plane-access-with-cluster-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api.sigs.k8s.io&#34;&gt;Cluster API&lt;/a&gt; creates a workload cluster, it also creates a load balancing solution to handle traffic to the workload cluster&amp;rsquo;s control plane. This is necessary so that the control plane endpoint is decoupled from the underlying control plane nodes (which facilitates scaling the control plane, among other things). On AWS, this mean creating an ELB and a set of security groups. For flexibility, Cluster API provides a limited ability to customize this control plane load balancer. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use this functionality to fine-tune access to a workload cluster&amp;rsquo;s control plane when using Cluster API with AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 154</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #154! My link of links and articles from around the Internet is a bit light on networking and virtualization this time around, but heftier in the security, cloud, and OS/application sections. I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something that you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful. Enjoy the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 153</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #153! My personal and professional life has kept me busy over the last couple of months, so things have been quiet here on the blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve still been collecting links to share with you, though, and here&amp;rsquo;s the latest collection. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 152</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #152! Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish a Technology Short Take in the morning on a Friday, but I really wanted to get this one out so I&amp;rsquo;m making it live late in the day on a Monday. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve included some content below that you find useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 151</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #151, the first Technology Short Take of 2022. I hope everyone had a great holiday season and that 2022 is off to a wonderful start! I have a few more links than normal this time around, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t find articles in a couple categories. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my eyes peeled and my RSS reader ready to pull in new articles in those categories for next time. And now for the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Certificate Details from HashiCorp Vault</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/12/getting-certificate-details-from-hashicorp-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/12/getting-certificate-details-from-hashicorp-vault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems there are lots of tutorials on setting up a PKI (public key infrastructure) using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vaultproject.io/&#34;&gt;HashiCorp Vault&lt;/a&gt;. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found missing from most of these tutorials, however, is how to get details on certificates issued by a Vault-driven PKI &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the initial creation. For example, someone other than you issued a certificate, but now you need to get the details for said certificate. How is that done? In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you a couple ways to get details on certificates issued and stored in HashiCorp Vault.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 149</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #149! I&amp;rsquo;ll have one more Technology Short Take in 2021, scheduled for three weeks from now (on the last day of the year!). For now, though, I have a small collection of articles and links for your reading pleasure&amp;mdash;not as many as I usually include in a Technology Short Take, but better than nothing at all (I hope!). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 147</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #147! The list of articles is a bit shorter than usual this time around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a good collection of articles and posts covering topics in networking, hardware (mostly focused on Apple&amp;rsquo;s processors), cloud computing, and virtualization. There&amp;rsquo;s bound to be something in here for most everyone! (At least, I hope so.) Enjoy your weekend reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 146</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #146! Over the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a few technology-related links for you all. There&amp;rsquo;s some networking stuff, a few security links, and even a hardware-related article. But enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get into the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 144</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #144! I have a fairly diverse set of links for readers this time around, covering topics from microchips to improving your writing, with stops along the way in topics like Kubernetes, virtualization, Linux, and the popular JSON-parsing tool &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
