<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GRE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/gre/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GRE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/gre/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Bare Metal Workloads Using GRE Tunnels and OVS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/connecting-bare-metal-workloads-using-gre-tunnels-and-ovs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/connecting-bare-metal-workloads-using-gre-tunnels-and-ovs/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how you could use Open vSwitch (OVS) and GRE tunnels to connect bare metal workloads. While OVS is typically used in conjunction with a hypervisor such as KVM or Xen, you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not restricted to only using it on hypervisors. Similarly, while GRE tunnels are commonly used to connect VMs or containers, you&amp;rsquo;re definitely not restricted from using them with bare metal workloads as well. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore how you would go about connecting bare metal workloads over GRE tunnels managed by OVS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC, Open vSwitch, and GRE Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/26/lxc-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/26/lxc-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>This post will show you how to use Open vSwitch (OVS) to connect LXC containers on different hosts together using GRE tunnels. This process is quite similar to using OVS and GRE tunnels to connect VMs, and even has some similarity to connecting network namespaces over a GRE tunnel.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with LXC, my introductory post on LXC might be useful. I also found this post on networking with LXC to be extremely helpful, as was this overview of LXC on Ubuntu 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on Using GRE Tunnels with Open vSwitch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/22/an-update-on-using-gre-tunnels-with-open-vswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/22/an-update-on-using-gre-tunnels-with-open-vswitch/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide an update on using GRE tunnels with Open vSwitch (OVS) to include more than 2 hosts. I previously showed you how to use GRE tunnels with OVS to connect VMs on different hypervisor hosts, but in my testing I didn&amp;rsquo;t use this technique with more than two hypervisors. A few readers posted comments to that article asking how to extend the solution to more than 2 hypervisors, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t had the time to test anything more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces, VLANs, Open vSwitch, and GRE Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/09/namespaces-vlans-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/09/namespaces-vlans-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how I combined Linux network namespaces, VLANs, Open vSwitch (OVS), and GRE tunnels to do something interesting. Well, I found it interesting, even if no one else does. However, I will provide this disclaimer up front: while I think this is technically interesting, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it has any real, practical value in a production environment. (I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be proven wrong, BTW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GRE Tunnels with Open vSwitch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/07/using-gre-tunnels-with-open-vswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 17:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/07/using-gre-tunnels-with-open-vswitch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with another &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; article on Open vSwitch (OVS), this time taking a look at using GRE (Generic Routing Encapsulation) tunnels with OVS. OVS can use GRE tunnels between hosts as a way of encapsulating traffic and creating an overlay network. OpenStack Quantum can (and does) leverage this functionality, in fact, to help separate different &amp;ldquo;tenant networks&amp;rdquo; from one another. In this write-up, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the process of configuring OVS to build a GRE tunnel to build an overlay network between two hypervisors running KVM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
