<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/podcast/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #3: Jonathan Frappier</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #3 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I have the pleasure of speaking with none other than Jonathan Frappier. Jonathan blogs at VirtXpert, and is probably quite well-known for his role in wrangling speakers for the vBrownBag podcasts. Jonathan is @jfrappier on Twitter, and uses the same username on GitHub as well. Jonathan&amp;rsquo;s been in the IT industry for, as he puts it, &amp;ldquo;somewhere between 16 and 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #2: Matt Oswalt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #2 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, my guest is none other than Matt Oswalt. You may know Matt as the primary author at Keeping It Classless, or as @mierdin on Twitter or GitHub (he also has a YouTube channel and a podcast of his own). Matt is primarily focused on network infrastructure, but is really interested in the intersection of network infrastructure and software development. Matt, along with Jason Edelman and yours truly, is one of the co-authors of a new book on network automation and programmability, and as such is a perfect guest for the Full Stack Journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #1: Bart Smith</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</guid>
      <description>In this first-ever episode of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I talk with Bart Smith (old GitHub account migrating to new GitHub account, YouTube channel). Bart shares some details about his journey from being a Microsoft-centric infrastructure engineer to what he calls a cloud-native full-stack engineer. Here are some notes from our conversation, along with some additional resources Bart wanted to share with readers/listeners. Enjoy!
The podcast audio recording is available on Soundcloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a New Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</guid>
      <description>After quite a bit of deliberation and planning, I&amp;rsquo;m excited (and nervous!) to announce the launch of a new podcast, titled &amp;ldquo;The Full Stack Journey Podcast&amp;rdquo;. Here are the details, structured in a Q&amp;amp;A format.
What topics does this new podcast cover?
The focus of The Full Stack Journey Podcast is to talk about the journey to becoming a full-stack engineer. That term is a bit of a loaded term&amp;mdash;some people like it, some people don&amp;rsquo;t, and there&amp;rsquo;s some disagreement over exactly what it means.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
