<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novell on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/novell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Novell on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 20:30:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/novell/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Old NetWare Integration Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/17/old-netware-integration-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 20:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/17/old-netware-integration-notes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m posting this stuff here on the off chance that it someday might be useful to someone out there somewhere. About four years ago, I had a wild hunch to start learning Novell NetWare 6.5, and to perform some integration testing with some other technologies with which I was already familiar. Along the way, I gathered these notes. I make no warranties about the accuracy, validity, or relevance of this information; I&amp;rsquo;m just publishing it here in case it may prove useful later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Quality vs. Just Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2006 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article discussing Novell&amp;rsquo;s leadership change, one analyst was quoted regarding the change as being positive for Novell in that they (Novell) could stop building very high quality products and instead build products that are just good enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but this spirit of mediocrity is exactly the wrong kind of thinking for IT vendors.
Specifically, the quote stated this:
 &amp;ldquo;Ron Hovsepian appears to be an astute business person, one who will be able to quickly take stock of the environment and Novell&amp;rsquo;s position within that environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xen Momentum Growing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/03/xen-momentum-growing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2006 11:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/03/xen-momentum-growing/</guid>
      <description>There is an incredible amount of momentum growing around the open source Xen hypervisor, and it is increasingly looking like market leaders VMware and Microsoft should be less worried about each other and more worried about Xen.
Check out some of the recent news articles regarding Xen:
&amp;ldquo;Novell to integrate Xen 3.0 in the next Open Enterprise Server&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;http://searchopensource.techtarget.com/columnItem/0,294698,sid39_gci1176440,00.html&amp;gt;
&amp;ldquo;Virtual Iron annonces 3.0 commercial and free editions based on Xen&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novell Open Sources AppArmor</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/14/novell-open-sources-apparmor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 23:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/14/novell-open-sources-apparmor/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Novell open sourced the AppArmor software under the GPL, hoping to promote adoption and development of the security framework for Linux. I was alerted to the move by a number of articles on the subject, such as this article from ComputerWorld and this article from eWeek.
AppArmor competes with Security Enhanced Linux, or SELinux, which&amp;mdash;due to its complexity&amp;mdash;is often turned off completely. Clearly, Novell hopes to gain some traction by opening up the source code to AppArmor and providing it to anyone to download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novell to Broaden SuSE&#39;s Reach</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/08/03/novell-to-broaden-suses-reach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2005 18:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/08/03/novell-to-broaden-suses-reach/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard good things about SuSE, but have never had the opportunity to work with it in greater depth. Now, Novell has detailed its plans to open SuSE to community development in a manner similar to the approach used by Red Hat with its Fedora Project.
I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing. Anything that Novell can do to broaden the reach and influence of SuSE will certainly help both Novell and the SuSE Linux distribution itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Good Article for Those New to LDAP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/22/a-good-article-for-those-new-to-ldap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2005 12:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/22/a-good-article-for-those-new-to-ldap/</guid>
      <description>Novell recently posted the article An Introduction to LDAP: Part 1&amp;ndash;LDAP Primer on their Cool Solutions web site. It&amp;rsquo;s a good article for those that are new to LDAP. I&amp;rsquo;m neither new to LDAP nor an expert, but this article was helpful in solidifying some basics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
