<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IDF2013 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IDF2013 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 11:40:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2013/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013 Summary and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/13/idf-2013-summary-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 11:40:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/13/idf-2013-summary-and-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back home in Denver after spending a few days in San Francisco at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2013, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a few minutes to sit down and share a summary of the event and my thoughts.
First, here are links to all the liveblogging I did while at the conference:
IDF 2013 Keynote, Day 1
Enhancing OpenStack with Intel Technologies for Public, Private, and Hybrid Cloud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Enabling NFV/SDN with Intel ONP Server Reference Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-enabling-nfvsdn-with-intel-onp-server-reference-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-enabling-nfvsdn-with-intel-onp-server-reference-design/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS003, titled &amp;ldquo;Enabling Network Function Virtualization and Software Defined Networking with the Intel Open Network Platform Server Reference Architecture Design.&amp;rdquo; (How&amp;rsquo;s that for a mouthful!) The speakers are Frank Schapfel, Senior Product Line Manager with Intel, and Brian Skerry, Open Networks System Architect with Intel. This session is slightly related to IDF 2013 session COMS0002, which focused more on the Intel ONP Switch reference design.
Frank kicks the session off with a quick review of the agenda, then dives right into the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Future of SDN with the Intel ONP Switch Reference Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS002, titled &amp;ldquo;The Future of Software-Defined Networking with the Intel Open Network Platform Switch Reference Design.&amp;rdquo; The speakers are Recep Ozdag, a PME with Intel, and Gershon Schatzberg, a PLM with Wind River Systems. The Intel Open Network Platform (ONP) Switch is the official name for Seacliff Trail, which I talked about last year at IDF 2012.
Recep starts the session with some brief background; he came to Intel through the Fulcrum acquisition a couple of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Virtualizing the Network to Enable SDI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 17:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</guid>
      <description>This is session EDCS008, &amp;ldquo;Virtualizing the Network to Enable a Software-Defined Infrastructure (SDI).&amp;rdquo; The speakers are Brian Johnson (@thehevy on Twitter) from Intel and Jim Pinkerton from Microsoft. Brian is a Solution Architect; Jim is a Windows Server Architect. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in one of Brian&amp;rsquo;s presentations, you know he does a great job of really diving deep in some of this stuff. (Can you tell I&amp;rsquo;m a fan?)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Rack Scale Architecture for Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-rack-scale-architecture-for-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 15:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-rack-scale-architecture-for-cloud/</guid>
      <description>This is IDF 2013 session CLDS001, titled &amp;ldquo;Rack Scale Architecture for Cloud.&amp;rdquo; The speaker is Mohan Kumar, a Sr Principal Engineer with Intel. Kumar works in the Server Platforms Group.
Kumar mentions that Krzanich mentions rack-scale architecture (RSA, not to be confused with a security company of the same name) as one of three pillars of accelerating the data center, and this session will be diving a bit deeper on rack-scale architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Keynote, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-keynote-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 12:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-keynote-day-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 keynote at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2013 in San Francisco. (Here is the link for the liveblog from the day 1 keynote.)
The keynote starts a few minutes after 9am, following a moment of silence to observe 9/11. Following that, Ulmonth Smith (VP of Sales and Marketing) takes the stage to kick off the keynote. Smith takes a few moments to recount yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote, particularly calling out the Quark announcement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Enhancing OpenStack with Intel Technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/idf-2013-enhancing-openstack-with-intel-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 17:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/idf-2013-enhancing-openstack-with-intel-technologies/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2013 session EDCS003, titled &amp;ldquo;Enhancing OpenStack with Intel Technologies for Public, Private, and Hybrid Cloud.&amp;rdquo; The presenters are Girish Gopal and Malini Bhandaru, both with Intel.
Gopal starts off by showing the agenda, which will provide an overview of Intel and OpenStack, and then dive into some specific integrations in the various OpenStack projects. The session will wrap up with a discussion of Intel&amp;rsquo;s Open IT Cloud, which is based on OpenStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013 Keynote, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/idf-2013-keynote-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/idf-2013-keynote-day-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Intel Developer Forum (IDF) Day 1 keynote. I was lucky enough to be invited to attend, as I did last year, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be liveblogging as many sessions and events as possible.
The keynote starts promptly at 9AM with Ulmont Smith (I didn&amp;rsquo;t catch his title at Intel). He mentions that this is the 16th year of hosting IDF, and previews some of the things that will be available this year at IDF: 170 technical sessions, poster chats, longer hours in the Technology Showcase, and more engineers on-site than any previous IDF.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
