<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerCLI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/powercli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerCLI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/powercli/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 96</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/16/technology-short-take-96/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/16/technology-short-take-96/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 96! Ahead, lying in wait, is a unique collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies. Browse if you dare&amp;hellip;OK, so I&amp;rsquo;m being a bit melodramatic. It&amp;rsquo;s still some good stuff here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 81</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #81! I have another collection of links, articles, and thoughts about key data center technologies, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something here that will prove useful or thought-provoking. Enjoy!
Networking  Matt Oswalt has a great post on the need for networking professionals to learn basic scripting skills&amp;mdash;something he (rightfully) distinguishes from programming as a full-time occupation. This is a post well worth spending a few minutes to read, and I wholeheartedly agree with Matt&amp;rsquo;s position here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #79</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #79! There&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting links for you this time around.
Networking  I was sure I had mentioned Skydive before, but apparently not (a grep of all my blog posts found nothing), so let me rectify that first. Skydive is (in the project&amp;rsquo;s own words) an &amp;ldquo;open source real-time network topology and protocols analyzer.&amp;rdquo; The project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository is here, and documentation for Skydive is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #3: Jonathan Frappier</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #3 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I have the pleasure of speaking with none other than Jonathan Frappier. Jonathan blogs at VirtXpert, and is probably quite well-known for his role in wrangling speakers for the vBrownBag podcasts. Jonathan is @jfrappier on Twitter, and uses the same username on GitHub as well. Jonathan&amp;rsquo;s been in the IT industry for, as he puts it, &amp;ldquo;somewhere between 16 and 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
