<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EMC on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/emc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EMC on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/emc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #66</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/13/technology-short-take-66/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/13/technology-short-take-66/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #66! In this post you&amp;rsquo;ll find a collection of links to articles about the major data center technologies. Hopefully something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be useful to you. Enjoy!
Networking  I recently spoke at Interop 2016 in Las Vegas, and while I was there I scribbled down some notes pertaining to how decomposing applications into microservices-based architectures was similar in some respects to decomposing networks into an overlay network and an underlay (physical) network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #55</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/22/technology-short-take-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/22/technology-short-take-55/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #55! Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to find something of value and interest to you in this latest collection of links and articles from around the web on networking, storage, virtualization, security, and other data center-related technologies. Enjoy!
Networking  I recently came across Kuryr, an OpenStack project aimed at connecting Docker&amp;rsquo;s libnetwork efforts to OpenStack Neutron. The end result, as I understand it, would be to allow any Neutron plugin to be able to provide container networking functionality to Docker via libnetwork.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #38</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 09:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #38, another installment in my irregularly-published series that collects links and thoughts on data center-related technologies from around the web. But enough with the introduction, let&amp;rsquo;s get on to the content already!
Networking   Jason Edelman does some experimenting with the Python APIs on a Cisco Nexus 3000. In the process, he muses about the value of configuration management tool chains such as Chef and Puppet in a world of &amp;ldquo;open switch&amp;rdquo; platforms such as Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very Early Thoughts about EMC ViPR</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/06/very-early-thoughts-about-emc-vipr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 18:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/06/very-early-thoughts-about-emc-vipr/</guid>
      <description>EMC announced ViPR today, the culmination of the not-so-secret Project Bourne and its lesser-known predecessor, Project Orion. Although I used to work at EMC before I joined VMware earlier this year, I never really had deep access to what was going on with this project, so my thoughts here are strictly based on what&amp;rsquo;s been publicly disclosed. Naturally, given that the product was only announced today, these are very early thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Long, Status Quo (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/07/so-long-status-quo-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 09:24:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/07/so-long-status-quo-again/</guid>
      <description>A little over two years ago, I wrote a blog post titled &amp;ldquo;So Long Status Quo.&amp;rdquo; (The title is taken from the Nichole Nordeman song &amp;ldquo;Brave&amp;rdquo;, in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t catch the reference.) At the time, I was making a pretty big move in my life, moving from a career in the VAR/reseller space&amp;mdash;where I&amp;rsquo;d been for over a decade&amp;mdash;into a job working for EMC Corporation on the vSpecialist (aka the VMware Affinity) team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at a New Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/28/spousetivities-at-a-new-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 19:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/28/spousetivities-at-a-new-conference/</guid>
      <description>In case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard, Spousetivities&amp;ndash;the spouse activities that had their genesis at VMworld 2008 in Las Vegas&amp;mdash;has expanded once again! Last year, Spousetivities expanded to include EMC World, and just last week Crystal concluded her second year of activities at EMC World 2012 in Las Vegas. This year, Spousetivities expands to not only include VMworld and EMC World, but also Dell Storage Forum 2012, located this year in Boston, MA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not Too Late</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/18/its-not-too-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 09:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/18/its-not-too-late/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to sign up for Spousetivities at EMC World 2012! The conference is upon us next week, and if you have a spouse/partner/friend/family member traveling with you then you owe it to them to check out Spousetivities. More information on the activities, costs, and the ability to actually register for activities can be found on the registration page. Go sign up now!
Here&amp;rsquo;s a preview of what will be available next week:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at EMC World 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/27/spousetivities-at-emc-world-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/27/spousetivities-at-emc-world-2012/</guid>
      <description>This year at EMC World 2012 (being held once again in Las Vegas, NV), Spousetivities returns for their second year at EMC&amp;rsquo;s user conference. As usual, my wife Crystal&amp;mdash;who founded and runs Spousetivities&amp;mdash;has a great set of activities planned for any spouses, partners, family members, or friends that will be traveling with EMC World conference attendees. (EMC&amp;rsquo;ers: those of you attending the TC Conference can have your traveling companions attend Spousetivities too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SRM and Stretched Clusters Webinar</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/23/srm-and-stretched-clusters-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 16:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/23/srm-and-stretched-clusters-webinar/</guid>
      <description>This coming Thursday, April 26, I&amp;rsquo;ll be participating in an EMC webinar titled &amp;ldquo;Best Practices: When and How to Use Stretched Clusters.&amp;rdquo; (I wanted to title it as &amp;ldquo;Current Recommended Practices,&amp;rdquo; but the marketing group shot me down.) The webinar starts at 8 AM PT/9 AM MT/11 AM ET.
This webinar will discuss whether stretched clusters or a solution like VMware Site Recovery Manager is a better fit for your needs, as well as provide some guidelines around the use of stretched clusters as of vSphere 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 09:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #20, the latest collection of various data center-related links, articles, and thoughts. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking   For all the writing and thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve done on VXLAN (here, here, and here), someone (thanks Ed!) mentioned something to me recently that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even considered. (It&amp;rsquo;s so simple I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed that I overlooked it.) VXLAN uses UDP for its encapsulation. What about dropped packets, lack of sequencing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSI 5.1 Issue and Fixes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/13/vsi-5-1-issue-and-fixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 12:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/13/vsi-5-1-issue-and-fixes/</guid>
      <description>As you might have already seen (Chad broke the news here, Itzik has more details here), EMC has released version 5.1 of the Virtual Storage Integrator (VSI), the vCenter plugin available to customers at no additional charge. I won&amp;rsquo;t revisit all the new features; rather, I wanted to bring to your attention a late-discovered issue with the VSI 5.1 release. If this information hasn&amp;rsquo;t already made it into the Release Notes, it should be there soon (there&amp;rsquo;s also an EMC Primus case being created).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #19, the first Technology Short Take for 2012. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s first collection of links, articles, and thoughts regarding virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center technology-related topics. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   While configuration limits aren&amp;rsquo;t the most exciting reading, they are important from time to time. Here&amp;rsquo;s some configuration limits for the UCS 6100 and 6200 series.
  Understanding the differences&amp;mdash;both positive and negative&amp;mdash;between the various approaches to solving a particular challenge is a key skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #17</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #17, another of my irregularly-scheduled collections of various data center technology-related links, thoughts, and comments. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   I think it was J Metz of Cisco that posted this to Twitter, but this is a good reference to the various 10 Gigabit Ethernet modules.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken quite a bit about stretched clusters and their potential benefits. For an opposing view&amp;mdash;especially regarding the use of stretched clusters as a disaster avoidance solution&amp;mdash;check out this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some vSphere 5 Video Content</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/14/some-vsphere-5-video-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/14/some-vsphere-5-video-content/</guid>
      <description>While I was in Copenhagen for VMworld EMEA 2011, I ran into a few EMC colleagues from the Solutions Center in Cork, Ireland. I&amp;rsquo;d visited Cork a couple of times last year (haven&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity this year, sadly), so it was great to catch up with them. During our conversation, one of them mentioned that the EMC Proven Solutions Group has a YouTube channel and had posted some new vSphere 5-related content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fate, Free Will, Virtualization, and Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/01/fate-free-will-virtualization-and-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2011 09:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/01/fate-free-will-virtualization-and-storage/</guid>
      <description>You might wonder what fate and free will have to do with virtualization and storage. The title of this post is a reference to the debate of Fate vs. Free Will, which in turn is a reference to Stephen Foskett&amp;rsquo;s recent post VMware as Oedipus: How Server Virtualization will Change Storage Forever. I won&amp;rsquo;t provide all the details here (go read the post), but the basic idea behind the post is that VMware&amp;rsquo;s drive to add storage features to the virtualization stack puts it on a collision course with EMC, a leading storage vendor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
