<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fusion on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fusion on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fusion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 115</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/06/21/technology-short-take-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/06/21/technology-short-take-115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #115! I&amp;rsquo;m back from my much-needed vacation in Bali, and getting settled back into work and my daily routine (which, for the last few weeks, was mostly swimming in the pool and sitting on the beach). Here&amp;rsquo;s a fresh new collection of links and articles from the around the web to propel myself back into blogging. I hope you find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 108</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/21/technology-short-take-108/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/21/technology-short-take-108/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #108! This will be the last Technology Short Take of 2018, so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I can provide something useful for you. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quadruple-Provider Vagrant Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/&#34;&gt;I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; a triple-provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment I&amp;rsquo;d created that worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;, and the VMware provider (tested with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&#34;&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt;). Since that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve incorporated Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, specifically) into my computing landscape, and I started using the Libvirt provider for Vagrant (see my write-up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/06/using-vagrant-with-libvirt-on-fedora/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). With that in mind, I updated the triple-provider environment to add support for Libvirt and make it a quadruple-provider environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on Using Docker Machine with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/24/update-on-using-docker-machine-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/24/update-on-using-docker-machine-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of a project on which I&amp;rsquo;m working, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/machine/overview/&#34;&gt;Docker Machine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; over the last few days. You may recall that I first wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/08/04/using-vagrant-docker-machine-together/&#34;&gt;using these two tools together&lt;/a&gt; back in August 2015. As a result of spending some additional time with these tools&amp;mdash;which I chose because I felt like they streamlined some work around this project&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ve uncovered some additional information that I wanted to share with readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with VMware-Formatted Cumulus VX Vagrant Box</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/11/issue-with-vmware-cumulus-vx-vagrant-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/11/issue-with-vmware-cumulus-vx-vagrant-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a need to revisit the use of Cumulus VX (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cumulusnetworks.com&#34;&gt;Cumulus Networks&lt;/a&gt; virtual appliance running Cumulus Linux) in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment, and I wanted to be sure to test what I was doing on multiple virtualization platforms. Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.vagrantup.com/boxes/search&#34;&gt;Vagrant Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, Cumulus distributes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;Libvirt&lt;/a&gt; versions of Cumulus VX, and there is a slightly older version that also provides a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/personal-desktop-virtualization.html&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;-formatted box. Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s a simple error in the VMware-formatted box that prevents it from working. Here&amp;rsquo;s the fix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 85</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #85! This is my irregularly-published collection of links and articles from around the Internet related to the major data center technologies: networking, hardware, security, cloud computing, applications/OSes, storage, and virtualization. Plus, just for fun, I usually try to include a couple career-related links as well. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 82</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #82! This issue is a bit behind schedule; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty heads-down on some projects. That work will come to fruition in a couple weeks, so I should be able to come up for some air soon. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links and articles for your reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 81</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #81! I have another collection of links, articles, and thoughts about key data center technologies, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something here that will prove useful or thought-provoking. Enjoy!
Networking  Matt Oswalt has a great post on the need for networking professionals to learn basic scripting skills&amp;mdash;something he (rightfully) distinguishes from programming as a full-time occupation. This is a post well worth spending a few minutes to read, and I wholeheartedly agree with Matt&amp;rsquo;s position here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Triple-Provider Vagrant Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you some techniques I used to build a triple-provider Vagrant environment&amp;mdash;that is, a Vagrant environment that will work unmodified with multiple backend providers. In this case, it will work (mostly) unmodified with AWS, VirtualBox, and the VMware provider (tested with Fusion, but should work with Workstation as well). I know this may not seem like a big deal, but it marks something of a milestone for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Now Using VirtualBox with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I often tell people is, &amp;ldquo;Use the right tool for the job.&amp;rdquo; As technologists, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get so locked onto any one technology or product that we can&amp;rsquo;t see when other technologies or products might solve a particular problem more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s for this reason that I recently made VirtualBox&amp;mdash;not VMware Fusion&amp;mdash;my primary virtualization provider for Vagrant environments.
I know it seems odd for a VMware employee to use/prefer a non-VMware product over a competing VMware product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a VMware-Formatted Cumulus VX Vagrant Box</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/04/building-vmw-cumulus-vx-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/04/building-vmw-cumulus-vx-box/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through the process I used to build a Vagrant box for Cumulus VX that will work with VMware desktop hypervisors (like VMware Fusion or VMware Workstation). Although Cumulus Networks offers several different versions of Cumulus VX to download, they do not (strangely enough) offer a Vagrant box that will work with VMware&amp;rsquo;s desktop hypervisors.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Cumulus VX, it&amp;rsquo;s a virtual appliance version of Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #64</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #64. Normally, I try to publish Short Takes on Friday, but this past Friday was April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day. Given the propensity for &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; information to get lost among all the pranks, I decided to push this article back to today. Unlike most of what is published around April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day, hopefully everything here is helpful, informative, and useful!
Networking  Phil Gervasi has an article on fate sharing in the network core, where he discusses some of the advantages&amp;mdash;and disadvantages&amp;mdash;of centralizing the control plane in network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #60</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #60. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered what I hope to be a useful but varied collection of articles and links on key data center technologies. I hope something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be helpful&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking  The rise of Linux in importance in the networking industry continues, with Arista announcing enhancements to Arista EOS to support&amp;mdash;among other things&amp;mdash;Docker containers. (See this SDx Central article or this Network World article for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Photon on Fusion via Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/21/running-photon-fusion-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/21/running-photon-fusion-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Most of you have probably picked up on the news of VMware&amp;rsquo;s new container-optimized Linux distribution, code-named &amp;ldquo;Photon&amp;rdquo;. (More details here.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a very quick walkthrough on running Photon on VMware Fusion via Vagrant. This walkthrough will leverage a Vagrant box for Photon that has already been created.
To make things easier, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a photon directory to my GitHub &amp;ldquo;learning-tools&amp;rdquo; repository. Feel free to pull those files down to make it easier to follow along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an etcd-Backed Docker Swarm Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/19/running-etcd-backed-docker-swarm-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 07:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/19/running-etcd-backed-docker-swarm-cluster/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll build on a couple of previous posts and show you how to build your own Docker Swarm cluster that leverages etcd for cluster node discovery. This post builds on the information presented on how to run an etcd 2.0 cluster on Ubuntu as well as the information found in this post on running a Consul-backed Docker Swarm cluster.
To help you follow along, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a Vagrant environment that you can use to turn up the configuration described in this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
