<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Postfix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/postfix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Postfix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 12:09:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/postfix/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating Users for a Postfix-Based Mail Relay</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/01/creating-users-for-a-postfix-based-mail-relay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2006 12:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/01/creating-users-for-a-postfix-based-mail-relay/</guid>
      <description>This is a really, really, really simple task, but to save me the time of looking it up on those rare occasions when I need to do it I&amp;rsquo;m capturing the information here. This is how to create, delete, or modify users for a Postfix-based mail relay using SASL.
All of these examples assume that SASL is configured to use &amp;ldquo;sasldb&amp;rdquo; as the authentication mechanism.
To create a new user, use the following syntax:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Tech Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 14:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then, I like to post out here a list of my current &amp;ldquo;tech projects.&amp;rdquo; These are the things that I&amp;rsquo;m working on for my own network, things that I may or may not start recommending to or supporting for customers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my current list:
  InterNetNews (INN): I had an installation of INN up and running a short while back, but had to resort to an ugly hack with stunnel in order to make SSL work from a newsreader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Use a Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>A fair number of people have asked me why I use an Apple Mac when my business centers primarily around Microsoft products such as Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, and Exchange? That&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable question.
My computer is simply a tool to get my job done. About two years ago, I started to evaluate the tasks that I tackle on a regular basis as part of supporting my customers&amp;rsquo; networks. In reviewing those tasks, it become evident to me that using Windows myself was not a prerequisite for designing, installing, and supporting Windows-based networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split E-Mail Routing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/19/split-e-mail-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2005 23:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/19/split-e-mail-routing/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have Perdition up and running (although not in the way I really wanted; see my post titled &amp;ldquo;Perdition Working Now&amp;rdquo;), I&amp;rsquo;m moving on to setting up an internal news server.
Before I can get the internal news server up and running, though, I must first address the issue of e-mail submissions to these newsgroups. See, right now I can send an e-mail to newsgroupname@domain.com (this is obviously an invalid address) and that message will be posted to the newsgroup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
