<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cisco on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cisco/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cisco on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cisco/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 146</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #146! Over the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a few technology-related links for you all. There&amp;rsquo;s some networking stuff, a few security links, and even a hardware-related article. But enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get into the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 109</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #109! This is the first Technology Short Take of 2019. It may be confirmation bias, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed of number of sites adding &amp;ldquo;Short Take&amp;rdquo;-type posts to their content lineup. I&amp;rsquo;ll take that as flattery, even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily intended that way. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 103</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/17/technology-short-take-103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/17/technology-short-take-103/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 103, where I&amp;rsquo;m back yet again with a collection of links and articles from around the World Wide Web (Ha! Bet you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that term used in a while!) on various technology areas. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something useful to you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 95</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 95! This Short Take was a bit more challenging than normal to compile, given that I spent the week leading up to its publication visiting customers in Europe. (My travel schedule in Europe is also why it didn&amp;rsquo;t get published until Saturday instead of the typical Friday.) Nevertheless, I have persevered in order to deliver you this list of links and articles. I hope it proves useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 90</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/10/technology-short-take-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/10/technology-short-take-90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 90! This post is a bit shorter than most, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the road quite a bit recently. Nevertheless, there&amp;rsquo;s hopefully something here you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 88</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/14/technology-short-take-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/14/technology-short-take-88/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #88! Travel is keeping me pretty busy this fall (so much for things slowing down after VMworld EMEA), and this has made it a bit more difficult to stick to my self-imposed biweekly schedule for the Technology Short Takes (heck, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get this one published on Friday!). Sorry about that! Hopefully the irregular schedule is outweighed by the value found in the content I&amp;rsquo;ve collected for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 82</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #82! This issue is a bit behind schedule; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty heads-down on some projects. That work will come to fruition in a couple weeks, so I should be able to come up for some air soon. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links and articles for your reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 80</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/24/technology-short-take-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/24/technology-short-take-80/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #80! This post is a week late (I try to publish these every other Friday), so my apologies for the delay. However, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to gather together some articles with useful information for you. Enjoy!
Networking  Biruk Mekonnen has an introductory article on using Netmiko for network automation. It&amp;rsquo;s short and light on details, but it does provide an example snippet of Python code to illustrate what can be done with Netmiko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #76</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #76, the first Technology Short Take of 2017. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but due to extenuating circumstances (my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow) I&amp;rsquo;m posting it today. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking  As of Vagrant 1.9.1, the Cumulus plugin for Vagrant is no longer needed. See this post for more details. Ivan Pepelnjak (one of my absolutely favorite folks in the IT industry) has a great post on using regex filters in Ansible to parse text printouts from network devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #68</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/technology-short-take-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/technology-short-take-68/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #68, my erratically-published collection of links, articles, and posts from around the web&amp;mdash;all focused on today&amp;rsquo;s major data center technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stick to a schedule that has these posts published on a Friday, but given the pending holiday weekend I wanted to get this out a bit early. As always, I hope that something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here proves useful to you.
Networking  Brent Salisbury retweeted a ton of MACVLAN- and IPVLAN-related posts right after I published the last Technology Short Take, so they had to get bumped to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #67</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #67. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping something I&amp;rsquo;ve collected for you here proves useful!
Networking  Anthony Burke has written a script that uses VMware NSX to protect VMware Log Insight instances. More information on the script is in his blog post. Russ White tackles the issue of networking engineers needing to learn to code. Is it necessary? Russ thinks so&amp;mdash;but probably not for the reasons you might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #62</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #62. Sorry for the long delay since the last TST; some global travel has really thrown my schedule off. In any case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until Friday (the day I normally publish these) so I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there sooner. Enjoy!
Networking  PowerNSX is pretty cool&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a set of PowerShell cmdlets for administrators of VMware NSX running in vSphere environments. Check out Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s introductory post on PowerNSX for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #61</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #61. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to find a nice range of articles and links, so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I was successful and that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking  Along with the release of rkt 1.0 (see below in the &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems/Applications&amp;rdquo; section), Metaswitch has announced a Container Networking Interface (CNI) plugin for Project Calico. (This appears to be primarily through the Calico plugin for Kubernetes and Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; support for CNI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #49</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #49 (also known as Distraction-as-a-Service)! I have here for your reading pleasure an eclectic collection of links and articles from around the web, focusing on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful. Bring on the content!
Networking  I love this post from Matt Oswalt on five next-gen skills for networking pros. I highly recommend you read the entire post, but in short the five skills Matt recommends are software skills (which includes configuration management and software development tools like Git), Linux, deep protocol knowledge, hypervisor and container networking, and IPv6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
