<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DockerCon2015 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dockercon2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DockerCon2015 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 09:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dockercon2015/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon Vendor Briefings</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/24/dockercon-vendor-briefings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/24/dockercon-vendor-briefings/</guid>
      <description>At DockerCon 2015 in San Francisco, I had the opportunity to meet with a few vendors in the Docker ecosystem. Here are some notes from my vendor briefings.
StackEngine StackEngine describes themselves as enterprise-grade container application management. They tout features like being able to compose Docker applications using a drag-and-drop interface, deploy containers across multiple hosts, and provide automation&amp;mdash;all with the sort of controls that enterprise IT groups are seeking. That&amp;rsquo;s all well and good, but the key problem in my mind is that these are features Docker is seeking for themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Scaling New Services</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/scaling-new-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/scaling-new-services/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the DockerCon 2015 session titled &amp;ldquo;Scaling New Services: From Container Creation to Automated Deployments&amp;rdquo;. This session is being led by the Disney Systems Engineering team and will feature a discussion/demo involving Docker, Mesos, Chef, Consul, and HAProxy.
The session starts with an introduction by Alex Williams, founder of The New Stack, who quickly turns it over to the Disney staff&amp;mdash;Brian Scott and Patrick O&amp;rsquo;Connor. Brian starts with an overview of all the various companies within Disney, and the challenges that breadth creates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: DockerCon 2015 Day 2 General Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/dockercon-day2-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 10:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/dockercon-day2-general-session/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog from the day 2 general session at DockerCon 2015. I was running late from some early morning meetings (sorry folks), so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to catch the first part of the general session (about the first 15 minutes or so). Here&amp;rsquo;s what I was able to capture.
Chris Buckley, Director of DevOps at Business Insider, took the stage to provide an overview of how Business Insider (BI) started using Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Docker Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/docker-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/docker-networking/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Docker Networking breakout session. This session is led by Madhu Venugopal and Jana Radhakrishnan, both formerly of Socketplane (and now with Docker following the acquisition). They are introduced by John Willis, also formerly of Socketplane and well-known within the DevOps community.
Some display issues plague the session at the beginning, so it appears that Murphy&amp;rsquo;s Law is back with a vengeance.
Madhu starts out the session with an overview of why networking (in particular Docker networking) is so important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Resilient Routing and Discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/resilient-routing-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/resilient-routing-discovery/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the DockerCon 2015 session on resilient routing and discovery, part of the &amp;ldquo;Advanced Tech&amp;rdquo; track. Simon Eskilden (@Sirupsen on Twitter) from Shopify is the speaker for this session.
Not surprisingly (you&amp;rsquo;d understand this if you walked Eskilden&amp;rsquo;s presentation from DockerCon EU 2015), he starts out with a mention of the walrus (his favorite animal). Eskilden starts with a brief overview of Shopify (his employer) and Shopify&amp;rsquo;s production deployment of Docker (they&amp;rsquo;ve had Docker in production for over a year).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Secret Session (Docker Plugins)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/top-secret-session-docker-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/top-secret-session-docker-plugins/</guid>
      <description>This is the &amp;ldquo;Top Secret Docker Session led by Gordon the Turtle,&amp;rdquo; which is really a session on Docker Plugins. However, since Docker Plugins were only announced this morning during the general session, the title for this session had to be obscured. On stage are ClusterHQ (Luke Marsden), Glider Labs (Jeff Lindsay), and Weaveworks (Alexis Richardson).
Marsden starts the session with a brief history of the Docker Plugins project, and how it grew out of Powerstrip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: DockerCon 2015 Day 1 General Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/docker-con-day1-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/22/docker-con-day1-general-session/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the day 1 general session at DockerCon 2015, taking place this week (today and tomorrow, anyway) at the Marriott Marquis in San Francisco, CA. This is my first DockerCon, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to picking up lots of new knowledge.
The general session starts with a video (cartoon) about something working in development but not in production, and how Solomon Hykes came up with the idea for containers and Docker.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
