<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 13:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/review/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review: OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/23/review-owc-thunderbolt-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/23/review-owc-thunderbolt-dock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About six months ago I purchased an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owcdigital.com/products/thunderbolt-3-dock-14-port&#34;&gt;OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock&lt;/a&gt; to replace my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anker.com/a8396launch&#34;&gt;Anker PowerElite Thunderbolt 3 Dock&lt;/a&gt; (see my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/24/review-anker-powerexpand-elite-thunderbolt-3-dock/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). While there was nothing necessarily wrong with the Anker PowerElite, it lacked a digital audio port that I could use to send audio to a soundbar positioned under my monitor. (I&amp;rsquo;d grown accustomed to using a soundbar when my 2012 Mac Pro was my primary workstation.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief review of the OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Logitech Ergo K860 Ergonomic Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/17/review-logitech-ergo-k860-ergonomic-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/17/review-logitech-ergo-k860-ergonomic-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of an ongoing effort to refine my work environment, several months ago I switched to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.logitech.com/en-us/products/keyboards/k860-split-ergonomic.920-009166.html&#34;&gt;Logitech Ergo K860 ergonomic keyboard&lt;/a&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;m not a &amp;ldquo;keyboard snob,&amp;rdquo; I am somewhat particular about the feel of my keyboard, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how I would like the K860. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide my feedback, and provide some information on how well the keyboard works with both Linux and macOS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: 2020 M1-Based MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/02/review-2020-m1-based-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/02/review-2020-m1-based-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done a personal hardware refresh in a while; my laptop was a 2017-era MacBook Pro (with the much-disliked butterfly keyboard) and my tablet was a 2014-era iPad Air 2. Both were serviceable but starting to show their age, especially with regard to battery life. So, a little under a month ago, I placed an order for some new Apple equipment. Included in that order was a new 2020 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro with the Apple-designed M1 CPU. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide a brief review of the 2020 M1-based MacBook Pro based on the past month of usage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: CPLAY2air Wireless CarPlay Adapter</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/10/review-cplay2air-wireless-carplay-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/10/review-cplay2air-wireless-carplay-adapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late September, I was given a CPLAY2air wireless CarPlay adapter as a gift. Neither of my vehicles support wireless CarPlay, and so I was looking forward to using the CPLAY2air device to enable the use of CarPlay without having to have my phone plugged into a cable. Here&amp;rsquo;s my feedback on the CPLAY2air device after about six weeks of use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Anker PowerExpand Elite Thunderbolt 3 Dock</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/24/review-anker-powerexpand-elite-thunderbolt-3-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 11:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/24/review-anker-powerexpand-elite-thunderbolt-3-dock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of weeks or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my 2017 MacBook Pro (running macOS &amp;ldquo;Mojave&amp;rdquo; 10.14.6) more frequently as my daily driver/primary workstation. Along with it, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anker.com/products/variant/powerexpand-elite-13in1-thunderbolt-3-dock/A8396141&#34;&gt;the Anker PowerExpand Elite 13-in-1 Thunderbolt 3 Dock&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience with this dock and provide a quick review of the Anker PowerExpand Elite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Magic Mouse 2 and Magic Trackpad 2 on Fedora</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/08/review-magic-mouse-2-and-magic-trackpad-2-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/08/review-magic-mouse-2-and-magic-trackpad-2-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a new Apple Magic Mouse 2 and an Apple Magic Trackpad 2&amp;mdash;not to use with my MacBook Pro, but to use with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;-powered laptop (a Lenovo 5th generation ThinkPad X1 Carbon; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/13/review-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;). I know it seems odd to buy Apple accessories for a non-Apple laptop, and in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about why I bought these items as well as provide some (relatively early) feedback on how well they work with Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: REST API Design Rulebook</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/04/book-review-rest-api-design-rulebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/04/book-review-rest-api-design-rulebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;REST API Design Rulebook&lt;/em&gt; (written by Mark Masse and published by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media; more details &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920021575.do&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) is an older book, published in late 2011. However, having never attempted to design a REST API before, I found lots of useful information inside that really helped shape my understanding of REST APIs and REST API design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/31/book-review-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/31/book-review-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2018 projects&lt;/a&gt;, I committed to reading and reviewing more technical books this year. As part of that effort, I recently finished reading &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Kief Morris and published in September 2015 by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly (more details &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920039297.do&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Infrastructure as code is very relevant to my current job function and is an area of great personal interest, and I&amp;rsquo;d been half-heartedly working my way through the book for some time. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve completed it, here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/13/review-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/13/review-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the transition into my new role at &lt;a href=&#34;https://heptio.com/&#34;&gt;Heptio&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/02/the-future-is-containerized/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more information), I had to select a new corporate laptop. Given that my last attempt at running Linux full-time was thwarted due primarily to work-specific collaboration issues that would no longer apply (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/25/linux-migration-wrap-up/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), and given that other members of my team (the Field Engineering team) are also running Linux full-time, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it another go. Accordingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve started working on a Lenovo ThinkPad X1 Carbon (5th generation). Here are my thoughts on this laptop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Dell Latitude E7370</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/30/review-dell-latitude-e7370/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/30/review-dell-latitude-e7370/</guid>
      <description>As part of my Linux migration (see my initial progress report), late this past week I started setting up my first non-Apple laptop since 2003. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts on my new laptop, a Dell Latitude E7370.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s get the specs&amp;mdash;the &amp;ldquo;speeds and feeds&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;out of the way:
 Intel Core m7 CPU 16 GB of RAM 512 GB NVMe SSD 3200x1800 touchscreen Intel HD graphics and Intel 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations in Markdown Using Deckset</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/18/presentations-markdown-deckset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/18/presentations-markdown-deckset/</guid>
      <description>Over the past couple of years, Markdown has become an important part of my computing landscape. I&amp;rsquo;ve transitioned almost all of my text-based content creation, including this blog, over to Markdown. I&amp;rsquo;d also been looking for ways that I might be able to extend my use of Markdown into creating presentations as well, but hadn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;mdash;until recently&amp;mdash;found a tool that fit into my workflow. Then I started using Deckset.
The idea behind Deckset is not unique; there are other projects out there that do the same sort of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on a Couple of Books</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/02/thoughts-on-a-couple-of-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 12:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/02/thoughts-on-a-couple-of-books/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been remiss in posting some thoughts on books that I&amp;rsquo;ve recently read, so here is an attempt to catch up a little bit on a couple of titles. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I would classify these as true reviews, but here are my thoughts and key take-aways from these titles.
Automating vSphere with VMware vCenter Orchestrator This title, by Cody Bunch (of ProfessionalVMware.com and vBrownbag fame), is one of the first VMware Press titles to be published (Mike Laverick&amp;rsquo;s SRM book is another).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware View Client for Mac with PCoIP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/16/vmware-view-client-for-mac-with-pcoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 13:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/16/vmware-view-client-for-mac-with-pcoip/</guid>
      <description>VMware just released the PCoIP-enabled version of the VMware View client for Mac OS X (download here; login required). After having used it this morning to connect to my corporate View desktop, I must say that I am quite impressed.
The responsiveness of my View desktop is significantly improved over RDP. Under RDP, browsing any sort of Web site&amp;mdash;and accessing various internal-only sites is a key use for my corporate View desktop&amp;mdash;was just downright painful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experiences with Lion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/25/my-experiences-with-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 23:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/25/my-experiences-with-lion/</guid>
      <description>About two weeks ago, I purchased a new 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro for use as my primary laptop. As you probably know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Mac user for a while; this 13&amp;quot; MBP replaces a 15&amp;quot; MBP that I purchased about two years ago. Predictably, the new laptop was preloaded with Mac OS X 10.7 &amp;ldquo;Lion&amp;rdquo;, the latest and greatest OS from Apple. Since the release of Lion, I&amp;rsquo;d made no secret of the fact that I had no intention of upgrading my existing laptop from 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying iTerm2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/17/trying-iterm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/17/trying-iterm2/</guid>
      <description>In 2007 I posted an article about iTerm, an open source terminal application for Mac OS X. At that time, I gave up on iTerm and switched back to the Apple-supplied Terminal.app. For a while, it seemed as if iTerm was stagnating and development had stalled.
However, I recently learned that some developers forked the original iTerm to create iTerm2. Like the original iTerm, iTerm2 supports AppleScript and tabbed terminals. The tabbed terminals I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about (I don&amp;rsquo;t use tabs, generally speaking), but I do like AppleScript support (in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t picked that up already).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
