<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VirtualBox on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/virtualbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VirtualBox on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/virtualbox/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 138</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #138. I have what I hope is an interesting and useful set of links to share with everyone this time around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do so well on storage links; apologies to my storage-focused friends! However, there should be something for most everyone else. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 128</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #128! It looks like I&amp;rsquo;m settling into a roughly monthly cadence with the Technology Short Takes. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a (hopefully) interesting collection of links. The collection seems a tad heavier than normal in the hardware and security sections, probably due to new exploits discovered in Intel&amp;rsquo;s speculative execution functionality. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered for you. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 106</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #106! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while (over a month) since the last Tech Short Take, as this one kept getting pushed back. Sorry about that, folks! Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to find useful and helpful links to include below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quadruple-Provider Vagrant Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/&#34;&gt;I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; a triple-provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment I&amp;rsquo;d created that worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;, and the VMware provider (tested with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&#34;&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt;). Since that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve incorporated Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, specifically) into my computing landscape, and I started using the Libvirt provider for Vagrant (see my write-up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/06/using-vagrant-with-libvirt-on-fedora/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). With that in mind, I updated the triple-provider environment to add support for Libvirt and make it a quadruple-provider environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 97</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/30/technology-short-take-97/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/30/technology-short-take-97/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 97! This Tech Short Take marks the end of an era (sort of); it&amp;rsquo;s the last Tech Short Take published while I&amp;rsquo;m a VMware employee (today is my last day; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more details). But enough about me&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s talk some tech! This Short Take may be a bit longer than some, so buckle up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 96</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/16/technology-short-take-96/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/16/technology-short-take-96/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 96! Ahead, lying in wait, is a unique collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies. Browse if you dare&amp;hellip;OK, so I&amp;rsquo;m being a bit melodramatic. It&amp;rsquo;s still some good stuff here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 95</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 95! This Short Take was a bit more challenging than normal to compile, given that I spent the week leading up to its publication visiting customers in Europe. (My travel schedule in Europe is also why it didn&amp;rsquo;t get published until Saturday instead of the typical Friday.) Nevertheless, I have persevered in order to deliver you this list of links and articles. I hope it proves useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on Using Docker Machine with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/24/update-on-using-docker-machine-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/24/update-on-using-docker-machine-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of a project on which I&amp;rsquo;m working, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/machine/overview/&#34;&gt;Docker Machine&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; over the last few days. You may recall that I first wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/08/04/using-vagrant-docker-machine-together/&#34;&gt;using these two tools together&lt;/a&gt; back in August 2015. As a result of spending some additional time with these tools&amp;mdash;which I chose because I felt like they streamlined some work around this project&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ve uncovered some additional information that I wanted to share with readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 85</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #85! This is my irregularly-published collection of links and articles from around the Internet related to the major data center technologies: networking, hardware, security, cloud computing, applications/OSes, storage, and virtualization. Plus, just for fun, I usually try to include a couple career-related links as well. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 84</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #84! This episode is a bit late (sorry about that!), but I figured better late than never, right? OK, bring on the links!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #79</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #79! There&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting links for you this time around.
Networking  I was sure I had mentioned Skydive before, but apparently not (a grep of all my blog posts found nothing), so let me rectify that first. Skydive is (in the project&amp;rsquo;s own words) an &amp;ldquo;open source real-time network topology and protocols analyzer.&amp;rdquo; The project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository is here, and documentation for Skydive is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #77</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #77. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new collection of links and articles from around the Web on various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  Mark Brookfield takes a moment to remind everyone that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use the (deprecated) C# vSphere Client to manage NSX environments. Good advice. Michael Kashin has a great article on how Open Virtual Network (OVN, part of the Open vSwitch project) implements virtual networks in OpenStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to the VirtualBox CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/10/intro-to-vbox-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/10/intro-to-vbox-cli/</guid>
      <description>This post provides a basic introduction to the VirtualBox CLI (command-line interface) tool, vboxmanage. This post does not attempt to replace the comprehensive documentation; rather, its purpose is to help users who are new to vboxmanage (such as myself, having recently adopted VirtualBox for my Vagrant environments) get somewhat up to speed as quickly and as painlessly as possible.
Basic Commands Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some basic operations. Here are a few to get you started:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Triple-Provider Vagrant Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you some techniques I used to build a triple-provider Vagrant environment&amp;mdash;that is, a Vagrant environment that will work unmodified with multiple backend providers. In this case, it will work (mostly) unmodified with AWS, VirtualBox, and the VMware provider (tested with Fusion, but should work with Workstation as well). I know this may not seem like a big deal, but it marks something of a milestone for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Now Using VirtualBox with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I often tell people is, &amp;ldquo;Use the right tool for the job.&amp;rdquo; As technologists, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get so locked onto any one technology or product that we can&amp;rsquo;t see when other technologies or products might solve a particular problem more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s for this reason that I recently made VirtualBox&amp;mdash;not VMware Fusion&amp;mdash;my primary virtualization provider for Vagrant environments.
I know it seems odd for a VMware employee to use/prefer a non-VMware product over a competing VMware product.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
