<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libvirt on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/libvirt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libvirt on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 01:10:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/libvirt/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fixes for Some Vagrant Issues on Fedora</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/23/fixes-for-some-vagrant-issues-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 01:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/23/fixes-for-some-vagrant-issues-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I needed to perform some testing of an updated version of some software that I use. (I was conducting the testing because this upgrade contained some breaking changes, and needed to understand how to mitigate the breaking changes.) So, I broke out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vagrant-libvirt/vagrant-libvirt&#34;&gt;the Libvirt provider&lt;/a&gt;) on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; laptop&amp;mdash;and promptly ran into a couple issues. Fortunately, these issues were relatively easy to work around, but since the workarounds were non-intuitive I wanted to share them here for the benefit of others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quadruple-Provider Vagrant Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/quadruple-provider-vagrant-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/05/triple-provider-vagrant-environment/&#34;&gt;I wrote about&lt;/a&gt; a triple-provider &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment I&amp;rsquo;d created that worked with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;, and the VMware provider (tested with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&#34;&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt;). Since that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve incorporated Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, specifically) into my computing landscape, and I started using the Libvirt provider for Vagrant (see my write-up &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/06/using-vagrant-with-libvirt-on-fedora/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). With that in mind, I updated the triple-provider environment to add support for Libvirt and make it a quadruple-provider environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Vagrant with Libvirt on Fedora 27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/06/using-vagrant-with-libvirt-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/06/using-vagrant-with-libvirt-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;Libvirt&lt;/a&gt; via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vagrant-libvirt/vagrant-libvirt&#34;&gt;vagrant-libvirt provider&lt;/a&gt; when running on &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27. Both Vagrant and Libvirt are topics I&amp;rsquo;ve covered more than a few times here on this site, but this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed combining the two projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker Machine with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/24/using-docker-machine-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/24/using-docker-machine-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker Machine is, in my opinion, a useful and underrated tool. I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about using Docker Machine with various services/providers; for example, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/22/using-docker-machine-with-aws/&#34;&gt;this article on using Docker Machine with AWS&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/09/24/using-docker-machine-with-openstack/&#34;&gt;this article on using Docker Machine with OpenStack&lt;/a&gt;. Docker Machine also supports local hypervisors, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&#34;&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use Docker Machine with KVM and Libvirt on a Linux host (I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27 as an example).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Virtualization Provider</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/08/linux-migration-virtualization-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/08/linux-migration-virtualization-provider/</guid>
      <description>As part of my migration to Linux as my primary laptop OS, I needed to revisit my choice of virtualization provider. Long-time readers probably know that I was an early adopter of VMware Fusion, starting way back in 2006 with the very first &amp;ldquo;friends and family&amp;rdquo; release (before it was even publicly available). Obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t use Fusion on Linux, but do I use VMware Workstation for Linux? VirtualBox? Or something else?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OVN with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how to use OVN (Open Virtual Network; part of the Open vSwitch project) with KVM and Libvirt to provide virtual networking for KVM-based virtual machines. This post will build on some concepts around OVS and Libvirt that I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed previously; be sure to review the OVS posts and Libvirt posts on this site for more details and prerequisite knowledge.
I&amp;rsquo;ll structure this discussion around 2 key steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using KVM with Libvirt and macvtap Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/09/using-kvm-libvirt-macvtap-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/09/using-kvm-libvirt-macvtap-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use KVM with Libvirt and macvtap interfaces for networking (as opposed to a Linux bridge or Open vSwitch). Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide some context around why this sort of approach might be interesting/useful to you.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you are already somewhat familiar with KVM and Libvirt; if you need an introduction to either of those, you might find this post, this post, and this post (all from my site) helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Arista vEOS on KVM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/11/running-arista-veos-on-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/11/running-arista-veos-on-kvm/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how I got Arista&amp;rsquo;s vEOS software running under KVM to create a virtualized Arista switch. There are a number of other articles that help provide instructions on how to do this, but none of those that I found included the use of libvirt and/or Open vSwitch (OVS).
In order to run vEOS, you must first obtain a copy of vEOS. I can&amp;rsquo;t provide you with a copy; you&amp;rsquo;ll have to register on the Arista Networks site (see here) in order to gain access to the download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sessions at the Fall OpenStack Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/05/sessions-at-the-fall-openstack-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/05/sessions-at-the-fall-openstack-summit/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time again&amp;mdash;time for community voting on sessions for the fall OpenStack Summit, being held in Paris this year in early November. I wanted to take a moment and share some of the sessions in which I&amp;rsquo;m involved and/or that I think might be useful. It would be great if you could take a moment to add your votes for the sessions.
My Sessions I have a total of four session proposals submitted this year:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Open vSwitch with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to manage Open vSwitch (OVS) using the popular open source configuration management tool Puppet. This is not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this topic; in the past I showed you how to automate OVS configuration with Puppet via a hack utilizing some RHEL-OVS integrations. This post, however, focuses on the use of an actual Puppet module that will manage the configuration of OVS, a much cleaner solution&amp;mdash;in my view, at least&amp;mdash;than leveraging the file-based integrations I discussed earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting LXC to Open vSwitch Using Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/03/connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch-using-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/03/connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch-using-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to expand a little bit on using libvirt to connect Linux containers (created using LXC) to Open vSwitch (OVS). I made brief mention of this in my post on using LXC with libvirt, but did not provide any details. This post aims to provide those details.
I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with LXC, OVS, and libvirt. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with these projects, I suggest you have a look back at other articles I&amp;rsquo;ve written about them in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Containers via LXC and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/27/linux-containers-via-lxc-and-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/27/linux-containers-via-lxc-and-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about libvirt is the ability to work with multiple hypervisors and virtualization technologies, including Linux containers using LXC. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use libvirt with LXC, including leveraging libvirt to help automate attaching containers to Open vSwitch (OVS).
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Linux containers and LXC, I invite you to have a look at my introductory post on Linux containers and LXC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjusting VNC Console Access via Libvirt XML</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/adjusting-vnc-console-access-via-libvirt-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/10/adjusting-vnc-console-access-via-libvirt-xml/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while since I talked about libvirt directly, but in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to go back to libvirt to talk about how you can edit a guest domain&amp;rsquo;s libvirt XML definition to adjust access to the VNC console for that guest domain.
This is something of a follow-up to my post on using SSH to access the VNC consoles of KVM guests, in which I showed how to use SSH tunneling (including multi-hop tunnels) to access the VNC console of a KVM guest domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Mock to Build Libvirt 1.0.1 RPMs for CentOS 6.3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/22/using-mock-to-build-libvirt-1-0-1-rpms-for-centos-6-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 13:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/22/using-mock-to-build-libvirt-1-0-1-rpms-for-centos-6-3/</guid>
      <description>In this third post on using Mock to build RPMs for CentOS 6.3, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use Mock to build RPMs for Libvirt 1.0.1 that you can install on CentOS. As you&amp;rsquo;ll see later, this post builds on the previous two posts (one on using Mock to build RPMs for sanlock 2.4 and one on using Mock to build RPMs for libssh2 1.4.1).
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of the process:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
