<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/podcast/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2017 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has become my custom for the past several years, I wanted to take a look  at how well I fared on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2017 project list&lt;/a&gt;. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this before the end of 2017, but during this past holiday season I decided to more fully &amp;ldquo;unplug&amp;rdquo; and focus on the truly important things in life (like my family). So, here&amp;rsquo;s a look back at my 2017 projects and a report card on my progress (or lack thereof, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big News About the Full Stack Journey Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/26/big-news-full-stack-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/26/big-news-full-stack-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following the Full Stack Journey podcast, you know that the podcast has been silent for a few months. Some of that was due to some adverse situations in life (it happens to all of us from time to time), but some of it was due to the coordination of a major transition in the podcast. And that&amp;rsquo;s the big news I&amp;rsquo;m here to share&amp;mdash;read on for the full details!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2017 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing my list of projects for each year (here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2012, the list for 2013, 2015&amp;rsquo;s list, and last year&amp;rsquo;s list&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a list for 2014). Toward the end of each year, I also publish a &amp;ldquo;report card&amp;rdquo; assessing my performance against that year&amp;rsquo;s list (here&amp;rsquo;s the 2016 assessment). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share my list of planned projects for 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/28/podcast-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/28/podcast-update/</guid>
      <description>As many of you probably know, I launched a new podcast, called the Full Stack Journey Podcast, back in January. (Here&amp;rsquo;s the blog post announcing the new podcast.) In this post, I wanted to provide a quick update on the podcast.
Dedicated Website Now Up First, the podcast now has its own website! Like this site, the Full Stack Journey site is a Jekyll-powered site hosted on GitHub (here&amp;rsquo;s the site&amp;rsquo;s repository).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #3: Jonathan Frappier</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #3 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I have the pleasure of speaking with none other than Jonathan Frappier. Jonathan blogs at VirtXpert, and is probably quite well-known for his role in wrangling speakers for the vBrownBag podcasts. Jonathan is @jfrappier on Twitter, and uses the same username on GitHub as well. Jonathan&amp;rsquo;s been in the IT industry for, as he puts it, &amp;ldquo;somewhere between 16 and 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Containers, Virtualization, and Interop</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/17/technology-advice-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/17/technology-advice-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I had the pleasure of attending and speaking at Interop for the very first time. (I did some liveblogging while I was there; here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the liveblogs published from last year&amp;rsquo;s Interop.) Fortunately, I was invited back again this year (very excited about that!), and as a returning speaker I recently had the opportunity to do a podcast with Technology Advice about SDN, virtualization, containers, and Interop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #2: Matt Oswalt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #2 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, my guest is none other than Matt Oswalt. You may know Matt as the primary author at Keeping It Classless, or as @mierdin on Twitter or GitHub (he also has a YouTube channel and a podcast of his own). Matt is primarily focused on network infrastructure, but is really interested in the intersection of network infrastructure and software development. Matt, along with Jason Edelman and yours truly, is one of the co-authors of a new book on network automation and programmability, and as such is a perfect guest for the Full Stack Journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #1: Bart Smith</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</guid>
      <description>In this first-ever episode of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I talk with Bart Smith (old GitHub account migrating to new GitHub account, YouTube channel). Bart shares some details about his journey from being a Microsoft-centric infrastructure engineer to what he calls a cloud-native full-stack engineer. Here are some notes from our conversation, along with some additional resources Bart wanted to share with readers/listeners. Enjoy!
The podcast audio recording is available on Soundcloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a New Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</guid>
      <description>After quite a bit of deliberation and planning, I&amp;rsquo;m excited (and nervous!) to announce the launch of a new podcast, titled &amp;ldquo;The Full Stack Journey Podcast&amp;rdquo;. Here are the details, structured in a Q&amp;amp;A format.
What topics does this new podcast cover?
The focus of The Full Stack Journey Podcast is to talk about the journey to becoming a full-stack engineer. That term is a bit of a loaded term&amp;mdash;some people like it, some people don&amp;rsquo;t, and there&amp;rsquo;s some disagreement over exactly what it means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/14/good-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 22:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/14/good-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>Up until now, I haven&amp;rsquo;t really messed around with listening to podcasts. I know all about them, what they are, how they work, and all that wonderful jazz. But I typically have not listened to podcasts at all.
I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure why, although I suppose it could be due to not having some podcasts that I really find useful or enjoyable.
So I&amp;rsquo;ll toss it back to you, the readers, for your feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
