<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VPLEX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vplex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VPLEX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vplex/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #40. The content is a bit light this time around; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give you, my readers, a little break. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s still some useful and interesting stuff here. Enjoy!
Networking   Bob McCouch has a nice write-up on options for VPNs to AWS. If you&amp;rsquo;re needing to build out such a solution, you might want to read his post for some additional perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #15</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #15, the latest in my irregular series of posts on various articles and links on networking, servers, storage, and virtualization&amp;mdash;everything a growing data center engineer needs!
Networking My thoughts this time around are pretty heavily focused on VXLAN, which continues to get lots of attention. I talked about posting a dissection of VXLAN, but I have failed miserably; fortunately, other people smarter than me have stepped up to the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stretched Clusters, Distance vMotion and L2 Adjacency</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/12/stretched-clusters-distance-vmotion-and-l2-adjacency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/12/stretched-clusters-distance-vmotion-and-l2-adjacency/</guid>
      <description>Beth Pariseau recently published an article discussing the practical value of long-distance vMotion, partially in response to EMC&amp;rsquo;s announcement of VPLEX Geo at EMC World 2011. In that article, Beth quotes some text from a tweet I posted as well as some text from Chad Sakac&amp;rsquo;s recent post on VPLEX Geo. However, there are a couple inaccuracies from Beth&amp;rsquo;s article that I really feel need to be cleared up:
  Long-distance vMotion and stretched clusters are not the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing the IP Address on a VPLEX Management Server</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/18/changing-the-ip-address-on-a-vplex-management-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 11:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/18/changing-the-ip-address-on-a-vplex-management-server/</guid>
      <description>EMC VPLEX leverages a Linux-based management server as an integral part of the overall architecture. The management server, as the name implies, provides the management interfaces&amp;mdash;both HTTPS (web-based) and CLI&amp;mdash;for managing the VPLEX cluster(s). In a VPLEX Local configuration, changing the IP address is a single-step process; in a VPLEX Metro configuration, there is an additional step required. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through both situations.
All in all, it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty simple process, but the one thing that might trip you up is the different CLI environments involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to the VPLEX CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/22/an-introduction-to-the-vplex-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/22/an-introduction-to-the-vplex-cli/</guid>
      <description>The VPLEX command line interface (CLI) is a bit different than a lot of other CLIs with which I&amp;rsquo;ve worked. In some respects, it&amp;rsquo;s similar to the scope-based CLI that Cisco uses with Unified Computing System (UCS). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore the VPLEX CLI a bit and provide a brief introduction to the VPLEX CLI. Keep in mind that this is just an introduction&amp;mdash;for a complete reference to the VPLEX CLI, I&amp;rsquo;ll refer you to the VPLEX product area on EMC PowerLink where a complete VPLEX CLI User&amp;rsquo;s Guide is available in PDF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VPLEX and Data Replication Together</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/20/using-vplex-and-data-replication-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/20/using-vplex-and-data-replication-together/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post on EMC VPLEX, I provided a review of the VPLEX storage objects. In that post, I discussed the difference between a storage volume, an extent, a device, and a virtual volume. If you are unclear on the distinctions between those terms, I suggest you go back and read that post again before proceeding.
The following diagram illustrates these various storage objects again:
As you can see from the diagram, VPLEX offers a number of different ways to combine these objects together:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Review of VPLEX Storage Objects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/13/a-quick-review-of-vplex-storage-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/13/a-quick-review-of-vplex-storage-objects/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get my VPLEX clusters up and running, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start providing some posts on VPLEX and how it&amp;rsquo;s configured and used. To get things started, I want to first provide an overview of VPLEX storage objects and how they relate to each other.
Storage volumes: Storage volumes are the LUNs that are presented to the VPLEX back-end ports from the storage array. The screenshot below, taken from the VPLEX management GUI, shows a series of storage volumes taken from two separate back-end arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stretched Cluster Presentation from Denver VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/30/stretched-cluster-presentation-from-denver-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/30/stretched-cluster-presentation-from-denver-vmug/</guid>
      <description>I had the honor of speaking in front of the Denver VMUG on Tuesday of this week. It was a blast, and I got to meet a great group of people. I received some positive feedback on the presentation that I gave at the VMUG, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here as well.
Here is a link to the presentation.
This is my first time using SlideShare, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably go back and update the slide deck here since some of the builds and formatting get lost in the conversion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPLEX Webcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/03/vplex-webcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 10:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/03/vplex-webcast/</guid>
      <description>Next Thursday, August 12, I&amp;rsquo;ll be hosting an EMC Live webcast titled &amp;ldquo;Disaster Avoidance with VMware vSphere and VPLEX&amp;rdquo;. The webcast is part of EMC&amp;rsquo;s weekly VMware-focused webcasts. We&amp;rsquo;ll be starting next Thursday, August 12, at 8AM Pacific/11AM Eastern/4PM BST.
As you can tell by the name, I&amp;rsquo;ll be discussing EMC VPLEX and how you can use VPLEX to potentially build a DR-avoidance scenario for your virtualized environment. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more, register for the webcast here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deeper Look at VPLEX</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/07/a-deeper-look-at-vplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/07/a-deeper-look-at-vplex/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been promising a post on VPLEX for quite some time now, and now it&amp;rsquo;s finally here. Having spent some hands-on time with VPLEX this past week, I think I&amp;rsquo;m finally ready to discuss VPLEX in some detail.
The Basics First, I need to cover the basics of what VPLEX is as well as what it isn&amp;rsquo;t. VPLEX is another step in delivering EMC&amp;rsquo;s vision of Virtual Storage and storage federation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look at VPLEX and VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>The announcement of VPLEX last week at EMC World 2010 in Boston has introduced lots of new possibilities in how virtualized data centers should be designed and deployed. Of particular interest to a number of people is how VPLEX interacts with VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM).
Jason Nash of Varrow mulls over VPLEX and VMware SRM in this post, where he asks if VMware SRM is even necessary:
 If money was no object, or if you needed VPLEX anyway, where does that leave VMwares Site Recovery Manager?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More VPLEX Linkage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/more-vplex-linkage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/more-vplex-linkage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll have my own write-up on VPLEX soon&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m taking the time to prepare a thoughtful response rather than just repeating the same things that have been said elsewhere&amp;mdash;but until then here are some of the things that are being said elsewhere (note that I&amp;rsquo;ve included negative coverage as well, to show that I welcome all viewpoints):
Your Virtual Machine Teleporter is ready Are you?
EMC creates VMware-inspired storage system
VPLEX&amp;rsquo;ing their way to Distributed Data Centers, How EMC stole the show (Part 1-Hardware)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC VPLEX Launches Today</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-vplex-launches-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 10:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-vplex-launches-today/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll have a more comprehensive blog post up later today or tonight, but I did want to bring everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention to the announcement of the VPLEX today at EMC World 2010. Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a more in-depth post up later, but for now here are a few links to some other coverage:
VPLEX: The Birth Of A New Storage Platform
EMC Shouts VPLEX In A Crowded EMCWorld
EMC Launches VPlex for Global Pooling of Stored Data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
