<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FTP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ftp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FTP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 22:54:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ftp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hidden Growl Preference for Interarchy</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/02/hidden-growl-preference-for-interarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2010 22:54:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/02/hidden-growl-preference-for-interarchy/</guid>
      <description>Interarchy is a well-known FTP/SFTP client for Mac OS X that I&amp;rsquo;ve used off and on for a few years. It&amp;rsquo;s been mostly off in recent times as I tended to use Cyberduck, but since Cyberduck&amp;rsquo;s AppleScript support got whacked in a recent update I&amp;rsquo;ve been re-evaluating Interarchy again.
This hidden preference for Interarchy is one that I actually found out about from the Interarchy developer quite some time ago, but apparently never published anything about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Hang of Interarchy</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/28/getting-the-hang-of-interarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 22:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/28/getting-the-hang-of-interarchy/</guid>
      <description>Interarchy is a well-respected FTP/SFTP client for Mac OS X, although the feature set now makes calling it an &amp;ldquo;FTP/SFTP client&amp;rdquo; a bit of a misnomer. After, when you add in HTTP, WebDAV, and Amazon S3 support, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly just an FTP/SFTP client any longer. (For simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake, we&amp;rsquo;ll continue calling it an FTP/SFTP client.) For users of other FTP/SFTP clients, however, Interarchy&amp;rsquo;s interface is different enough to throw users off and prevent them from really being able to take advantage of the application&amp;rsquo;s full functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Follow Up on Mac FTP/SFTP Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/27/quick-follow-up-on-mac-ftpsftp-clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2007 10:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/27/quick-follow-up-on-mac-ftpsftp-clients/</guid>
      <description>Unable to cope with the slow performance of Cyberduck any longer (even though I love everything else about the application), I started looking at other Mac FTP/SFTP clients. Since performance was the key driving factor causing me to seek a new client, I thought it would probably be important to perform some informal performance comparisons between the major candidates&amp;ndash;Interarchy, Transmit, and Fetch (and, for reference, Cyberduck as well).
First, the parameters of the test:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac FTP/SFTP Clients</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/22/mac-ftpsftp-clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2007 21:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/22/mac-ftpsftp-clients/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d gotten turned on to Cyberduck as my primary FTP/SFTP client after really getting into Growl, the global notification system for Mac OS X. The application I was using at the time, Fugu, didn&amp;rsquo;t have Growl support. Cyberduck did, so I switched, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Cyberduck ever since.
I like the Cyberduck interface; it seems to make sense to me and I&amp;rsquo;ve never really run into any major compatibility issues (seems like I ran into one minor problem after an upgrade of OpenSSH on one of my servers, but that problem was quickly resolved as I recall).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
