<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Citrix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/citrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Citrix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:12:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/citrix/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Citrix Acquires Sanbolic</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/12/citrix-acquires-sanbolic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 09:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/12/citrix-acquires-sanbolic/</guid>
      <description>I just saw the news that Citrix has acquired Sanbolic, a storage virtualization company that I&amp;rsquo;ve written about before. (TechCrunch also has a quick write-up as well.) Early this year, Sanbolic announced their storage virtualization product, completing a pivot from offering a Windows-only solution (file system and volume manager) to a multi-platform solution that encompasses multiple storage tiers, multiple operating systems, and multiple hypervisors.
It will be interesting to see how this acquisition affects the virtualization industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #24, another instance of my irregularly-published collection of links, thoughts, and rants on various data center technologies like networking, operating systems, security, hardware, virtualization, and cloud computing. This is a slightly shorter version of my Technology Short Takes; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down since some readers have indicated the previous Short Takes weren&amp;rsquo;t short enough. Anyway, I hope you find something useful.
Networking   This page is a decent reference to the open source software-defined networking (SDN) projects that are out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #17</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #17, another of my irregularly-scheduled collections of various data center technology-related links, thoughts, and comments. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   I think it was J Metz of Cisco that posted this to Twitter, but this is a good reference to the various 10 Gigabit Ethernet modules.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken quite a bit about stretched clusters and their potential benefits. For an opposing view&amp;mdash;especially regarding the use of stretched clusters as a disaster avoidance solution&amp;mdash;check out this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #9</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 12:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #9, the last Technology Short Take for 2010. In this Short Take, I have a collection of links and articles about networking, servers, storage, and virtualization. Of note this time around: some great DCI links, multi-hop FCoE finally arrives (sort of), a few XenServer/XenDesktop/XenApp links, and NTFS defragmentation in the virtualized data center. Here you go&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking   Brad Hedlund has a great post discussing Nexus 7000 connectivity options for Cisco UCS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 11:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>It has been a busy week since I last posted, and the blogging/micro-blogging world has been quite busy. I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered quite the collection of links and posts over the last week or so; here are a few that caught my eye. Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #41!
  About a month ago Rick Vanover posted a quick note about the use of Disk.SchedNumReqOutstanding as a potential performance tweak. As Rick mentions at the end of his article, it&amp;rsquo;s important to &amp;ldquo;test before and after with an intensive workload&amp;rdquo;; otherwise, you could find yourself actually hurting performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bit Harsh, Don&#39;t You Think?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/23/a-bit-harsh-dont-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 22:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/23/a-bit-harsh-dont-you-think/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Alex Barrett of TechTarget posted a tweet about her predictions for 2010:
 No wishy washy 2010 predictions from me: VMware will cut prices, and Citrix will give up on XenServer: http://bit.ly/75vDxc
 The link in the tweet corresponds to this TechTarget article in which Alex predicts that VMware will cut prices and Citrix will dump XenServer and focus instead on its management products like Citrix Essentials. Citrix Essentials, as you probably know, already supports Microsoft Hyper-V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Is VMware Legitimizing the Competition?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 09:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a completely unrelated post on Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s site this morning about how VKernel is reacting to VMware&amp;rsquo;s release of CapacityIQ when a thought occurred to me: is VMware legitimizing the competition?
Here&amp;rsquo;s the excerpt from Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s post that started me thinking:
 And of course VKernel now is also in hurry to clarify that support for Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer is coming.
 Now, let me ask you this question: what is one of the largest complaints about products like Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper9 VMM Released</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/hyper9-vmm-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 09:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/hyper9-vmm-released/</guid>
      <description>In case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t already heard elsewhere, our good friends at Hyper9 have released the final version of Virtualization Mobile Manager (VMM). VMM works with VMware Infrastructure 3, VMware vSphere 4, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer 5. Users can use VMM with just about any mobile device, including the Apple iPhone, Blackberry, Google Android, and Windows Mobile devices.
VMM is available for users to manage up to five virtual machines for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This VMworld Thing is Like Watching a Train Wreck</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/30/this-vmworld-thing-is-like-watching-a-train-wreck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 11:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/30/this-vmworld-thing-is-like-watching-a-train-wreck/</guid>
      <description>Watching VMware destroy their public image over this VMworld exhibitor agreement is like watching a train wreck: you want to take your eyes off of it, but it&amp;rsquo;s just so awful and so terrible that you&amp;rsquo;re mesmerized.
In case you don&amp;rsquo;t have any idea what&amp;rsquo;s going on, jump over and give this post a quick read. Done? OK, let&amp;rsquo;s continue.
In the update to that post, I said that VMware had clarified their position and that competition would be allowed at VMworld.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper9 Virtualization Mobile Manager Beta Invitations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/14/hyper9-virtualization-mobile-manager-beta-invitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/14/hyper9-virtualization-mobile-manager-beta-invitations/</guid>
      <description>The fine folks over at Hyper9 recently offered me a very limited number of special beta invitations for Hyper9&amp;rsquo;s new Virtualization Mobile Manager (VMM) product. As you may already know, VMM is the brainchild of Andrew Kutz, who recently joined Hyper9 and has already released a few snippets of code via H9Labs.
Here are some highlights of VMM:
  Supports all major hypervisors: VMware Server 2, VMware Infrastructure 3 (VMware ESX and VMware ESXi 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iForum 218: What the Other Virtualization Guys Don&#39;t Want You to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/06/iforum-218-what-the-other-virtualization-guys-dont-want-you-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 17:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/06/iforum-218-what-the-other-virtualization-guys-dont-want-you-to-know/</guid>
      <description>This is iForum 218, titled &amp;ldquo;XenServer 5: What the Other Virtualization Guys Don&amp;rsquo;t Want You to Know&amp;rdquo;. The presenters are Roger Klorese and Jill Skok.
Klorese starts out the presentation with XenCenter, the centralized multi-node management tool that ships with XenServer. As I&amp;rsquo;ve noted here on this site before, XenCenter&amp;rsquo;s real-time replication and multi-node behavior is, I believe, superior to the highly-centralized model that VMware uses with vCenter Server. He then goes through some of the features available in XenServer (which Klorese tells us really means &amp;ldquo;XenServer + Citrix Essentials for XenServer&amp;rdquo;) like XenMotion, High Availability, Dynamic Provisioning Services (which I believe refers to Citrix Provisioning Server aka Ardence), and Lab Management (OEM&amp;rsquo;d from VMlogix).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citrix Synergy Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/06/citrix-synergy-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 13:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/06/citrix-synergy-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>The Citrix Synergy Day 2 keynote starts about 8:40 AM with Pat Gelsinger of Intel, a figure becoming increasingly visible at events such as this conference. He starts his talk with a review of IDC statistics on the pressures and forces that are shaping IT, which is much a review of what John Gantz said yesterday.
At least the keynote is a bit more technology focused than yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote.
Gelsinger shares that Intel&amp;rsquo;s vision is 100% virtualized, and Intel&amp;rsquo;s engineers and technologists are driven toward eliminating all of the overhead involved in virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citrix Synergy Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/citrix-synergy-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 21:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/citrix-synergy-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>In advance of speaking at Virtualization Congress 2009 on Thursday, I&amp;rsquo;m attending Citrix Synergy. The Internet connection here in the main conference call is unavailable, so I&amp;rsquo;ll publish this as soon as I have connectivity back to the site.
The keynote starts with Garr Reynolds, an associate professor at Kansai Gaidai in Japan. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit unsure why he is on-stage getting the keynote started, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good presentation. After leading the audience through a self-introduction in Japanese, Garr Reynolds launches into a discussion of simplicity, the beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind, and nakedness (no, not that kind!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon everRun 2G and everRun VM Lockstep</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/20/marathon-everrun-2g-and-everrun-vm-lockstep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2009 18:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/20/marathon-everrun-2g-and-everrun-vm-lockstep/</guid>
      <description>I first wrote about Marathon Technologies and their everRun VM product last September just prior to the start of VMworld 2008 in Las Vegas, NV. Back at the start of 2009 I also mentioned Marathon&amp;rsquo;s joint development agreement with Microsoft and the intended plan to bring everRun VM to Hyper-V environments.
Today Marathon announced the availability of their everRun VM Lockstep product, which brings full circle the product announcement from last September.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
