<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>杨豪-博客 </title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Howell Yang</author>
    <rights>(C) 2022</rights>
    <updated>2022-05-29 22:53:20 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome</title>
        <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/29/welcome/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 22:53:20 UTC</pubDate>
        <author>Howell Yang</author>
        <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/29/welcome/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;很高兴你来到了我的博客！这是我的博客的第一篇内容。我决定在之后的日子里，在这里记录和更新我的技术日志，技术分享，以及一些我觉得有意思的项目。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先，我先简单介绍一下我自己。我是一名算法工程师，目前就职于腾讯地图，主要负责模型的量化、部署、性能优化相关的工作。在此之前，我在北京航空航天大学获得了本科和硕士学位。毕业后，我进入了依图科技工作。在依图科技工作期间，我负责了机器翻译模型的训练，基于&amp;quot;求索&amp;quot;芯片的模型量化和部署，模型量化工具的开发等工作。进入腾讯后。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also a dad, trying hard with my wife to raise our family. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail on my family here, such as providing names or ages of kids, or anything like that, because (to be perfectly honest) none of you really need to know that kind of information. Suffice it to say that it is a large family and that I am blessed to have them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that leads me to my final (and perhaps most important) piece of information, and that is that I am a Christian. That I am going to openly discuss my beliefs and my religion here will probably offend some people, but my Christianity and my faith are interwoven into all that I am and all that I do. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to speak honestly here and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; involve my faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any event, I hope that something you find here will a) help you solve a technical problem; b) encourage you as a parent; or c) lift you up in your faith.  At the very least, it should help you occupy some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
