<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snapshot on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/snapshot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snapshot on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 14:28:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/snapshot/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Future of NetApp</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 14:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</guid>
      <description>As I was sitting in London&amp;rsquo;s Heathrow Airport this morning catching up on RSS feeds before boarding my plane back to the United States, an article headline caught my eye: Why NetApp Must Seek Acquisition.
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how glad I am to see this article published, because it gives me the opportunity to share something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a while, even before I joined EMC. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that everything I have to say about NetApp will be colored by the fact that I now work for EMC, and&amp;mdash;whether I like it or not&amp;mdash;all comments about any other storage vendor or technology are immediately suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSS Can Cause Problems with RM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/11/vss-can-cause-problems-with-rm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 11:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/11/vss-can-cause-problems-with-rm/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick post about a potential fix for some timeout issues when using EMC Replication Manager (RM). An e-mail sent to an internal distribution list described a situation in which a user was using RM but was getting an error when trying to take a VMware snapshot. The error reported was a fairly generic error:
 Cannot create a quiesced snapshot because the create snapshot operation exceeded the time limit for holding off I/O in the frozen virtual machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner Exchange 2010 Session TECHBC0320</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/09/partner-exchange-2010-session-techbc0320/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 14:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/09/partner-exchange-2010-session-techbc0320/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for VMware Partner Exchange session TECHBC0320, &amp;ldquo;How VMware Leverages Microsoft Volume Shadow Services for Virtual Machine Snapshots&amp;rdquo;. The presenter is Paul Vasquez with VMware; he works within the Technical Alliances Organization at VMware with a focus on backups.
The session starts out with an overview of VMware snapshots followed by a quick overview of Microsoft Volume Shadow Copy Services.
Vasquez is careful to distinguish VMware snapshots from array-based snapshots, which is good since that seems to confuse a number of people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Issue with VMware Data Recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/29/snapshot-issue-with-vmware-data-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 10:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/29/snapshot-issue-with-vmware-data-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Reader Kyle Ross shared with me a potential issue with VMware&amp;rsquo;s new backup product, VMware Data Recovery. Others within the VMware blogging scene have also covered this, but I wanted to mention it as well so that others didn&amp;rsquo;t run into the problem. Here&amp;rsquo;s Kyle&amp;rsquo;s write-up:
 I was made aware of a serious (in my opinion) bug with VDR during a call with VMware support that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen discussed anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing LUN Space Requirements with NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 23:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Network Appliance storage before, you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with the idea of snap reserve (storage space set aside to accommodate for Snapshots) and fractional reserve (used with LUNs). I&amp;rsquo;m going to hold the in-depth discussion of why you need snap reserve and fractional reserve for a different day, but I did want to pass on these commands that were shared with me by a colleague of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM File-Level Recovery with NetApp Snapshots</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/vm-file-level-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 16:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/vm-file-level-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I wrote an article about using NetApp Snapshots and LUN clones to enable the recovery on individual files within a VM. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;d like to have a quick at that same process, but this time using NFS instead of block-level storage.
As I mentioned a couple of weeks ago, NFS is getting more and more attention as a key storage enabler for Virtual Infrastructure implementations. I do still plan to conduct some tests of my own between iSCSI and NFS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Data Inside VMs Using NetApp Snapshots</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/30/recovering-data-inside-vms-using-netapp-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2006 11:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/30/recovering-data-inside-vms-using-netapp-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Network Appliance Snapshots&amp;mdash;point-in-time copies of a file system that can be created almost instantaneously and which generally require much smaller amounts of storage to keep&amp;mdash;are an integral part of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s value over other storage systems. These snapshots make it far easier and quicker to recover from data loss or corruption than a tape backup system.
But how do we go about recovering individual files from a snapshot when those files are stored in a virtual disk (VMDK) file used by a VM?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
