<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Standards on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/standards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Standards on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 13:29:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/standards/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Thought Regarding Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/09/a-quick-thought-regarding-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2009 13:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/09/a-quick-thought-regarding-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>So, a number of sites have been tossing around this conversation regarding cloud computing, what it is (and isn&amp;rsquo;t), and where it&amp;rsquo;s headed. As I was responding to a private e-mail from another conspirator in this conversation, I came up with something that I thought would be best shared with everyone else.
First, a question: if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever architected a large enterprise solution, what was the one thing that gave you the most flexibility in designing that solution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuing the FCoE Discussion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/09/continuing-the-fcoe-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 10:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/09/continuing-the-fcoe-discussion/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I examined FCoE in the context of it&amp;rsquo;s description as an &amp;ldquo;I/O virtualization&amp;rdquo; technology in my discussion of FCoE versus MR-IOV. (Despite protestations otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to maintain that FCoE is not an I/O virtualization technology.)
Since that time, I read a few more posts about FCoE in various spots on the Internet:
Is FCoE a viable option for SMB/Commercial?
Is the FCoE Starting Pistol Aimed at iSCSI?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCoE versus MR-IOV...huh?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/17/fcoe-versus-mr-iovhuh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 16:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/17/fcoe-versus-mr-iovhuh/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this link sitting in my &amp;ldquo;Articles To Read&amp;rdquo; list for quite some time, but&amp;mdash;to be perfectly honest&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ve been just too busy to really do anything about it. Now that a hectic few weeks has wrapped up and I have a small breather before the next hectic few weeks, I wanted to comment briefly on Doug Gourlay&amp;rsquo;s discussion of FCoE versus MR-IOV.
First, some background: For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, FCoE is Fibre Channel over Ethernet, a T11 standard for running Fibre Channel Protocol over Ethernet, specifically 10 Gigabit Ethernet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Tidbits</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/12/miscellaneous-tidbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2006 19:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/12/miscellaneous-tidbits/</guid>
      <description>I have a variety of miscellaneous tidbits to mention, in case you haven&amp;rsquo;t already heard about them.
  ODF for Microsoft Office: Now that OpenDocument format (ODF) has been approved as an ISO standard, the OpenDocument Foundation has announced a plug-in for ODF that allows Microsoft Office (as far back as Office 97) to open, render, and save files as ODF. This, in my opinion, is a great thing, as it allows those organizations that can&amp;rsquo;t use an alternate office suite to still take advantage of open file formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenDocument Gets ISO Approval</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/03/opendocument-gets-iso-approval/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 23:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/03/opendocument-gets-iso-approval/</guid>
      <description>Mark one up for cross-platform standards: the OpenDocument format, an XML-based file format originally derived from work on OpenOffice.org (and Sun&amp;rsquo;s StarOffice) has been officially approved as an ISO standard.
There are numerous announcements of the approval&amp;mdash;this eWeek article, which initially alerted me; this press release at the OpenOffice.org web site; and this blog entry by Andy Updegrove, a participant in the standardization committees.
Of course, Microsoft continues to push its Open XML format as an alternative to ODF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems with 802.1Q</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/14/problems-with-8021q/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2006 09:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/14/problems-with-8021q/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled across a forum on Apple&amp;rsquo;s web site this morning (referred to me in turn by Derrick Story&amp;rsquo;s request for MacBook Pro feedback) that makes me glad I&amp;rsquo;m not yet able to afford a MacBook Pro.
According to the forum, there is a bug in the Ethernet driver in the Intel version of Mac OS X 10.4 that causes excessive packet loss on networks that employ 802.1Q. 802.1Q, in case you aren&amp;rsquo;t already familiar with it, is an Ethernet networking standard used in networks that employ multiple VLANs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Enough for Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</guid>
      <description>Not suprisingly, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s moves to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for current and future versions of Microsoft Office have swayed the State of Massachusetts back to its side again. Get the details here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Promises Not to Sue</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft recently made a move to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for Microsoft Office 2003 and the forthcoming Office 12. These file formats were offered to ECMA International for consideration as a formal open standard. However, the &amp;ldquo;license&amp;rdquo; for these file formats was merely a promise not to sue people violating its patents on the use of the file formats. Read more here.
Also see these comments from a legal analyst regarding Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Patent Protection Covenant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft&#39;s Counter-Move</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 23:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</guid>
      <description>The rallying cry around OpenDocument prompted Microsoft to make its counter-move. As fully expected, Microsoft is trying to create a standard based on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own (until now) proprietary XML formats. Please tell me you saw this coming, right?
With companies from Novell to Corel standing in support of the OpenDocument format, a new coalition forming in support of the format, and governments agencies such as the State of Massachusetts requiring the use of file formats such as PDF and OpenDocument, clearly Microsoft was worried.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSB Recognized by ISO</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/01/lsb-recognized-by-iso/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 19:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/01/lsb-recognized-by-iso/</guid>
      <description>News surfaced today that the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) has approved the Linux Standards Base (LSB) as an international standard. The LSB 2.0.1 core specification has been accepted by the ISO and will be published as International Standard 23360.
In my eyes, this is a big indicator of Linux&amp;rsquo;s maturity. Does Linux still need growth in some areas to be more competitive with Microsoft Windows, Novell NetWare, Solaris, or Mac OS X?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonstandard Implementations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2005 22:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</guid>
      <description>In my experiments with Perdition, I learned a couple of very interesting facts. First, the IMAP4 implementation on Exchange Server 2003 does not support the STARTTLS command, as described in RFC 2595 and re-affirmed in RFC 3501. Instead, Exchange expects an SSL session to be established immediately, and then IMAP is spoken. This is similar to the smtpd_tls_wrappermode directive that Postfix supports.
Second, it appears that the Mac OS X Mail application (commonly referred to as Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
