<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sun on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/sun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sun on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/sun/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Return of Virtualization Short Takes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</guid>
      <description>My irregular &amp;ldquo;Virtualization Short Takes&amp;rdquo; series was put on hold some time ago after I started work on Mastering VMware vSphere 4. Now that work on the book is starting to wind down just a bit, I thought it would be a good time to try to resurrect the series. So, without further delay, welcome to the return of Virtualization Short Takes!
  Trigged by a series of blog posts by Arnim van Lieshout on VMware ESX memory management (Part 1, Part 2, and Part 3), Scott Herold decided to join the fray with this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Viewpoints on Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/03/a-collection-of-viewpoints-on-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/03/a-collection-of-viewpoints-on-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks have passed since the announcement of Cisco&amp;rsquo;s Unified Computing System (UCS), and in that timeframe I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a number of links to articles and blog posts about UCS. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d collect them here and try to get a feel from all of the various viewpoints where the industry stands on UCS.
I&amp;rsquo;ll start with Robin Harris aka StorageMojo and his initial take on UCS. The one thing that jumped out at me about his article was this statement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Sun Preparing to Take on Cisco?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/09/is-sun-preparing-to-take-on-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 16:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/09/is-sun-preparing-to-take-on-cisco/</guid>
      <description>A while back in Virtualization Short Take #25 I briefly mentioned Sun&amp;rsquo;s Crossbow network virtualization software, which brings new possibilities to the Solaris networking world. Not being a Solaris expert, it was hard for me at the time to really understand why Solaris fans were so excited about it; since then, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to understand that Crossbow brings to Solaris the same kind of full-blown virtual network interfaces and such that I use daily with VMware ESX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week I provided a list of virtualization-related items that had made their way into my Inbox in some form or another; today I&amp;rsquo;ll share storage-related items with you in Storage Short Take #4! This post will also be cross-published to the Storage Monkeys Blogs.
  Stephen Foskett has a nice round-up of some of the storage-related changes available to users in VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. Of particular note to many users is the VMDK Recovery Tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Suing Sun over ZFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 21:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</guid>
      <description>I was on the road most of the day today, so I must have missed this news earlier. Apparently, Sun Microsystems and Network Appliance have had a little spat over ZFS and WAFL, and now NetApp is suing Sun for patent infringement.
Dave Hitz explained the situation in a blog entry:
 This morning, NetApp filed an IP (intellectual property) lawsuit against Sun. It has two parts. The first is a &amp;ldquo;declaratory judgment&amp;rdquo;, asking the court to decide whether we infringe a set of patents that Sun claims we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Solaris</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/07/31/learning-solaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2007 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/07/31/learning-solaris/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve targeted Solaris (specifically, Solaris 10 on x86) as the next major technology that I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to learn. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been fascinated with UNIX and UNIX-like operating systems such as Linux, and Linux&amp;rsquo;s popularity on the x86 platform made it much easier to learn because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to acquire any exotic hardware. With Sun&amp;rsquo;s (apparent) renewed interest in x86/x64, Solaris is much more accessible now than it was in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistically Secure</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/27/statistically-secure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/27/statistically-secure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll start out by saying that I am neither a security expert nor a statistician. With that disclaimer in hand, I wanted to briefly share my thoughts on the &amp;ldquo;days of risk&amp;rdquo; assessment that has recently been used to compare the security of Windows, Linux (Red Hat and SuSE), Mac OS X, and Sun Solaris. Before continuing, I encourage you to have a look at the actual report itself, along with a few related articles:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solaris 10 and Active Directory Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/15/solaris-10-and-active-directory-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 17:47:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/15/solaris-10-and-active-directory-integration/</guid>
      <description>As with the procedure for authenticating Linux against Active Directory and providing Kerberos-based SSO with Apache, there are a few steps to be performed. Some of these steps are performed on the Active Directory side, some of them are performed on the Solaris 10 system.
This procedure assumes that you are using Windows Server 2003 R2; if you are using a previous version, the LDAP attribute mapping will need to be modified to match the schema extensions found in Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Services for Unix (SfU) add-on product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Quality vs. Just Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2006 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article discussing Novell&amp;rsquo;s leadership change, one analyst was quoted regarding the change as being positive for Novell in that they (Novell) could stop building very high quality products and instead build products that are just good enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but this spirit of mediocrity is exactly the wrong kind of thinking for IT vendors.
Specifically, the quote stated this:
 &amp;ldquo;Ron Hovsepian appears to be an astute business person, one who will be able to quickly take stock of the environment and Novell&amp;rsquo;s position within that environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/15/open-source-hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2006 21:47:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/15/open-source-hardware/</guid>
      <description>Sun joins IBM in trying to use the open source software model to help with hardware as well. (Thanks to Linux-Watch for the news.) Creating a new project called OpenSPARC, Sun is open sourcing the specifications for its latest SPARC processor, the UltraSPARC T1, code-named &amp;ldquo;Niagara&amp;rdquo;.
According to the Linux-Watch article, the effort is intended to help drive the development of ports of Linux and BSD that can take full advantage of the CoolThreads technology in the UltraSPARC T1, which provides 32 threads of execution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
