<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VLAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vlan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VLAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 09:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vlan/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Trunking with Mikrotik RouterOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/07/02/vlan-trunking-mikrotik-routeros/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/07/02/vlan-trunking-mikrotik-routeros/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to configure VLAN trunking with Mikrotik RouterOS, and along the way provide a brief introduction to this software and some of the functionality it offers. While it is Linux-based, RouterOS operates quite a bit differently than a lot of the other network operating systems with which I&amp;rsquo;ve worked, and so I hope that this post will help ease the learning curve a bit for others who decide to take the same path.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Trunking with Cumulus Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/25/vlan-trunking-cumulus-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/25/vlan-trunking-cumulus-linux/</guid>
      <description>Following up on my earlier post on Cumulus Linux networking concepts, I wanted to build on that information with a guide on configuring VLAN trunking. This would be useful in a number of different scenarios: supporting multiple (VLAN-backed) port groups on vSphere hosts, or connecting an Open vSwitch (OVS) bridge on a KVM or Xen hypervisor to multiple VLANs. You might also need to use a VLAN trunking configuration to connect a Cumulus Linux-powered switch to another switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 16: Routing to Multiple External VLANs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/13/learning-nsx-part-16-routing-to-multiple-external-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/13/learning-nsx-part-16-routing-to-multiple-external-vlans/</guid>
      <description>This is part 16 of the Learning NSX series, in which I will show you how to configure VMware NSX to route to multiple external VLANs. This configuration will allow you to have logical routers that could be uplinked to any of the external VLANs, providing additional flexibility for consumers of NSX logical networks.
Naturally, this post builds on all the previous entries in this series, so I encourage you to visit the Learning NVP/NSX page for links to previous posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Networking: Part 2, A Few More Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/07/introduction-to-networking-part-2-a-few-more-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/07/introduction-to-networking-part-2-a-few-more-basics/</guid>
      <description>In part 1 of this series, I covered some networking basics (OSI and DoD models; layer 2 vs. layer 3; bridging, switching, and routing; Spanning Tree Protocol; and ARP and flooding). In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to build on those basic concepts to introduce a few more fundamental building blocks. As the series progresses, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to build on concepts and technologies introduced in earlier sections.
In this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of VLANs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me how much the idea of a VLAN has invaded the consciousness of data center IT professionals. Data center folks primarily tasked with managing compute workloads are nearly as familiar with VLANs as their colleagues primarily tasked with managing network connectivity. However, as networking undergoes a transformation at the hands of SDN, NFV, and network virtualization, what will happen to the VLAN?
The ubiquity of the VLAN is due, I think, to the fact that it serves as a reasonable &amp;ldquo;common ground&amp;rdquo; for both compute-focused and networking-focused professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Trunking to Guest Domains with Open vSwitch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/28/vlan-trunking-to-guest-domains-with-open-vswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/28/vlan-trunking-to-guest-domains-with-open-vswitch/</guid>
      <description>In other articles, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about how to use Open vSwitch (OVS) with VLANs to place guest domains (VMs) into a particular VLAN. In this article, I want to show you how to pass VLAN tags all the way into the guest domain&amp;mdash;in other words, how to do VLAN trunking to guest domains using OVS. To do this, we&amp;rsquo;re going to leverage the OVS-libvirt integration I referenced in this post on using VLANs with OVS and libvirt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VLANs with OVS and libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/07/using-vlans-with-ovs-and-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/07/using-vlans-with-ovs-and-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In previous posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve shown you how to use Open vSwitch (OVS) with VLANs through fake bridges, as well as how to wrap libvirt virtual networks around OVS fake bridges. Both of these techniques are acceptable for configuring VLANs with OVS, but in this post I want to talk about using VLANs with OVS via a greater level of libvirt integration. This has been talked about elsewhere, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to make it work until libvirt 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link Aggregation and VLAN Trunking with Brocade FastIron Switches</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/26/link-aggregation-and-vlan-trunking-with-brocade-fastiron-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/26/link-aggregation-and-vlan-trunking-with-brocade-fastiron-switches/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing with you information on how to do link aggregation (with LACP) and VLAN trunking on a Brocade FastIron switch with both VMware vSphere as well as Open vSwitch (OVS).
Throughout the majority of my career, my networking experience has been centered around Cisco&amp;rsquo;s products. You can easily tell that from looking at the articles I&amp;rsquo;ve published here. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently had the opportunity to spend some time working with a Brocade FastIron switch (a 48-port FastIron Edge X, specifically, running software version 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLANs with Open vSwitch Fake Bridges</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/19/vlans-with-open-vswitch-fake-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 15:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/19/vlans-with-open-vswitch-fake-bridges/</guid>
      <description>In other posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve (briefly) talked about how to configure Open vSwitch (OVS) for use with VLANs. If you know the port to which a guest is connected, you can configure that particular port as a VLAN trunk like this:
ovs-vsctl set port &amp;lt;port name&amp;gt; trunks=10,11,12  This configuration would pass the VLAN tags for VLANs 10, 11, and 12 all the way up to the guest, where&amp;mdash;assuming the OS installed in the guest has VLAN support&amp;mdash;you could configure network connectivity appropriately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from South Florida VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Back in early March I was invited to speak at the South Florida VMUG, and I gave this presentation on vSphere networking challenges and solutions. The idea behind the presentation was to give attendees some visibility into IEEE and IETF efforts at creating new network technologies and protocols. I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here just in case someone might find it useful or helpful.
Here is a link to the presentation.
As always, your questions, corrections, or clarifications are welcome in the comments below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #18</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 23:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #18! I hope you find something useful in this collection of networking, OS, storage, and virtualization links. Enjoy!
Networking The number of articles in my &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo; bucket continues to overflow; I have so many articles on so many topics (soft switching, OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, MPLS) that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get my head wrapped around all of it. Here are a few posts that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #14</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #14, another collection of links and tidbits of information I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last few weeks. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Networking Much of my focus in the networking space recently has been around virtualization-centric initiatives, so the items on this list might seem a bit skewed in that direction. Sorry!
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some reading on 802.1Qbg (Edge Virtual Bridging). I still have a long way to go, but I think that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to better understand this draft and the problem(s) it&amp;rsquo;s attempting to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Trunking Between Nexus 5010 and Dell PowerConnect Switches</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/02/vlan-trunking-between-nexus-5010-and-dell-powerconnect-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/02/vlan-trunking-between-nexus-5010-and-dell-powerconnect-switches/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t work in the networking space on a regular basis, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to overlook interoperability issues between equipment from different vendors. After all, a VLAN trunk is a VLAN trunk is a VLAN trunk, right? Alas, the answer is not always quite so simple.
While standards such as 802.1Q promise easy interoperability, the devil is usually in the details. I ran into just this sort of problem today in the lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vMotion Practicality</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/vmotion-practicality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/vmotion-practicality/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago I posted an article titled The vMotion Reality. In that article, I challenged the assertion that vMotion was a myth, not widely implemented in data centers today due to networking complexity and networking limitations.
In a recent comment to that article, a reader again mentions networking limitations&amp;mdash;in this instance, the realistic limits of a large Layer 2 broadcast domain&amp;mdash;as a gating factor for vMotion and limiting its &amp;ldquo;practical use&amp;rdquo; in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vMotion Reality</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/13/the-vmotion-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 19:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/13/the-vmotion-reality/</guid>
      <description>The quite popular GigaOm site recently published an article titled &amp;ldquo;The VMotion Myth&amp;rdquo;, in which the author, Alex Benik, debunks the myth of vMotion and the live migration of virtual machines (VMs).
In his article, Benik states that the ability to dynamically move workloads around inside a single data center or between two data centers is, in his words, &amp;ldquo;far from an operational reality today&amp;rdquo;. While I&amp;rsquo;ll grant you that inter-data center vMotion isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm, vMotion within a data center is very much an operational reality of today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
