<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NVP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nvp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NVP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nvp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 15: NSX Gateways, Gateway Services, and Logical Routers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/16/learning-nsx-part-15-nsx-gateways-gateway-services-and-logical-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/16/learning-nsx-part-15-nsx-gateways-gateway-services-and-logical-routers/</guid>
      <description>This is part 15 of my Learning NSX blog series, in which I will spend some time diving a bit deeper into some of the components involved in the logical routing process I described in part 14. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking a deeper look at gateway appliances, gateway services, and logical routers, and the relationships among these various components.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read any of the prior posts in this series, it would be ideal to read all of them before continuing; you can find links on my Learning NVP/NSX page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 14: Using Logical Routing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/20/learning-nsx-part-14-using-logical-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/20/learning-nsx-part-14-using-logical-routing/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 14 of the Learning NSX blog series, in which I discuss the ability for VMware NSX to do Layer 3 routing in logical networks. This post will also include a look at a very cool feature within VMware NSX known as distributed logical routing. This post will take a closer look at distributed logical routing within the context of an OpenStack environment that&amp;rsquo;s been integrated with VMware NSX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 13: Revisiting Logical Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/28/learning-nsx-part-13-revisiting-logical-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/28/learning-nsx-part-13-revisiting-logical-networking/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 13 of the Learning NSX blog series, in which I revisit the idea of logical networking with VMware NSX. This is a topic I first discussed in part 5 of this series, but I want to go back and look at it again, this time from a more practical perspective of what it looks like to use VMware NSX for logical networking in an OpenStack environment.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been keeping up with the Learning NVP/NSX series, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably want to go back and catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 12: Integrating VMware NSX with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/25/learning-nsx-part-12-integrating-vmware-nsx-with-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/25/learning-nsx-part-12-integrating-vmware-nsx-with-openstack/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 12 of the Learning NSX blog series, in which I continue the discussion around integration between OpenStack and VMware NSX, and in which I&amp;rsquo;ll provide more details about how exactly to integrate them.
If you are just now joining the series, I encourage you to visit the Learning NVP/NSX page, where you can find links to all the posts in the series. While you&amp;rsquo;ll want to be caught up on all the posts (they do build on one another in various ways), in particular you&amp;rsquo;ll want to make sure you&amp;rsquo;ve read part 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 11: Reviewing OpenStack Integration Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/12/learning-nsx-part-11-reviewing-openstack-integration-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/12/learning-nsx-part-11-reviewing-openstack-integration-basics/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 11 of the Learning NSX blog series, in which I provide a high-level overview of the basics on integrating VMware NSX into an OpenStack deployment using OpenStack Neutron. In case you&amp;rsquo;re just now catching up on this blog series, I encourage you to visit my Learning NVP/NSX page, which has a brief summary of all the posts in the series.
Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve shown you how to build all the different components of NSX (NSX controllers, NSX Manager, gateway appliances, and service nodes), it&amp;rsquo;s time to add integration into a cloud management platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 10: Adding a Service Node</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/27/learning-nsx-part-10-adding-a-service-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/27/learning-nsx-part-10-adding-a-service-node/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 10 of the Learning NSX blog series, in which I will walk through adding an NSX service node to your NSX configuration.
In the event you&amp;rsquo;ve joined this series mid-way, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve covered thus far:
  In part 1, I provided a high-level overview of NVP/NSX and its core components.
  In part 2, I showed you how to build NVP/NSX controllers and configure them into a controller cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NSX, Part 9: Adding a Gateway Service</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/26/learning-nsx-part-9-adding-a-gateway-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 13:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/26/learning-nsx-part-9-adding-a-gateway-service/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 9 in the Learning NVP/NSX blog series, in which I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss adding a gateway service to a logical network.
If you are just now joining me for this series, let me bring you up to speed real quick:
  Part 1 provided a high-level overview of NVP/NSX and its core components. (Reminder: NVP&amp;rsquo;s core components are much the same as NSX&amp;rsquo;s core components in multi-hypervisor environments.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 8: An Update on the NVP to NSX Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/05/learning-nvp-part-8-an-update-on-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/05/learning-nvp-part-8-an-update-on-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</guid>
      <description>In part 7 of the Learning NVP series, I mentioned that I was planning to transition this series from NVP to NSX through an upgrade. I had an existing NVP installation running (all virtually) inside an OpenStack cloud, and I would just upgrade that to NSX 4.0.0. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick update on that plan and the NVP-to-NSX transition.
As I mentioned, I have an installation of NVP 3.1.1 running successfully in a nested (virtualized) environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 7: Handling the NVP to NSX Transition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/01/learning-nvp-part-7-handling-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/01/learning-nvp-part-7-handling-the-nvp-to-nsx-transition/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 7 of the Learning NVP blog series, in which I will discuss transitioning from a focus on NVP to looking at NSX.
If you&amp;rsquo;re just now joining me for this series, here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s transpired thus far:
  In part 1, I provided a high-level overview of NVP and its core components.
  In part 2, I showed you how to build NVP controllers and configure them into a controller cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 6: Adding an NVP Gateway</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/28/learning-nvp-part-6-adding-an-nvp-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/28/learning-nvp-part-6-adding-an-nvp-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 6 of the Learning NVP blog series. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to add an NVP gateway appliance to your NVP environment. In future posts, you&amp;rsquo;ll use this NVP gateway to host either L2 or L3 gateway services (more on those in a moment). First, though, let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick recap of what&amp;rsquo;s transpired so far:
  In part 1, I provided a high-level overview of NVP and its core components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 5: Creating a Logical Network</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/06/learning-nvp-part-5-creating-a-logical-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/06/learning-nvp-part-5-creating-a-logical-network/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with more NVP goodness; this time, I&amp;rsquo;ll be walking you through the process of creating a logical network and attaching VMs to that logical network. This work builds on the stuff that has come before it in this series:
  In part 1, I introduced you to the high-level architecture of NVP.
  In part 2, I walked you through setting up a cluster of NVP controllers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 4: Adding Hypervisors to NVP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/22/learning-nvp-part-4-adding-hypervisors-to-nvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/22/learning-nvp-part-4-adding-hypervisors-to-nvp/</guid>
      <description>This is part 4 of the Learning NVP blog series. Just to quickly recap what&amp;rsquo;s happened so far, in part 1 I provided the high-level architecture of NVP and discussed the role of the components in broad terms. In part 2, I focused on the NVP controllers, showing you how to build/configure the NVP controllers and establish a controller cluster. Part 3 focused on NVP Manager, which allowed us to perform a few additional NVP configuration tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 3: NVP Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/19/learning-nvp-part-3-nvp-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 09:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/19/learning-nvp-part-3-nvp-manager/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 3 of the Learning NVP blog series. In part 1, I provide an overview of the high-level architecture of NVP and discussed the role of the components in broad terms. In part 2, I focused on the NVP controllers, showing you how to build/configure the NVP controllers and establish a controller cluster. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;m going to turn my attention to NVP Manager, which will allow us to further configure NVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 2: NVP Controllers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 2 of the Learning NVP blog series. In part 1 of the series, I provided a high-level overview of the NVP architecture and components. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into a bit more detail on one key component of the architecture: the NVP controllers and controller cluster.
(Just a quick reminder: although I&amp;rsquo;m talking about NVP 3.1&amp;ndash;our publicly available, GA product already running in production with customers&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that the NVP architecture serves as the basis for the upcoming VMware NSX product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 1: High-Level Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</guid>
      <description>This blog post kicks off a new series of posts describing my journey to become more knowledgeable about the Nicira Network Virtualization Platform (NVP). NVP is, in my opinion, an awesome platform, but there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a great deal of information shared about the product, how it works, how you configure it, etc. That&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to address in this series of posts. In this first post, I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a high-level description of the NVP architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
