<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/debian/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recent Changes in my &#34;Learning Tools&#34; Repository</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/06/recent-changes-learning-tools-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/06/recent-changes-learning-tools-repository/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, I created &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scottslowe/learning-tools&#34;&gt;a &amp;ldquo;learning-tools&amp;rdquo; repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of creating environments/tools that would help others learn new technologies. At first, the contents of the repository were almost exclusively leveraging &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;, but over time I&amp;rsquo;ve extended the environments to also leverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ansible.com/&#34;&gt;Ansible&lt;/a&gt; and to use tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.terraform.io/&#34;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt;. Over the past month or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few additional (albeit relatively minor) updates that I also wanted to share.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Other Users&#39; Stories, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts sharing other users&amp;rsquo; stories about their migration to Linux as their primary desktop OS. As I mentioned in part 1 of the series, there seemed to be quite a bit of pent-up interest in using Linux as your primary desktop OS. I thought it might be helpful to readers to hear not just about my migration, but also about others&amp;rsquo; migrations. You may also find it interesting/helpful to read part 2 and part 3 of this series for more migration stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OVS Integration with Debian Network Scripts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/ovs-integration-debian-network-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/ovs-integration-debian-network-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me recently with some questions regarding the use of Open vSwitch (OVS) on Debian &amp;ldquo;Jessie&amp;rdquo; 8.5 and using the OVS integration with the Debian network scripts. For those of you that might be unfamiliar with this functionality, it&amp;rsquo;s the ability to configure OVS via instructions and directives found in the /etc/network/interfaces file. As I was helping this reader, I came across a couple potential &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; that I wanted to point out here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #27! This is my usual collection of links, thoughts, rants, and ideas about data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about OpenFlow and software-defined networking but need to do this on a shoestring budget in your home lab, a number of guides have been written to help out. I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally used any of these guides yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m working my way in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nexenta Alpha 6 on ESX Server</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/10/24/nexenta-alpha-6-on-esx-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2006 22:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/10/24/nexenta-alpha-6-on-esx-server/</guid>
      <description>Nexenta (also called GNU/OpenSolaris) is a blend of OpenSolaris, GNU, and Debian (Ubuntu, specifically). It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool, actually&amp;mdash;blending the OpenSolaris kernel with Ubuntu userland binaries to create something that&amp;rsquo;s not quite Solaris and not quite Linux, but has some of the values of both. For those of you interested in running it on VMware ESX Server, I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that it does work just fine.
To install Nexenta as a VM in ESX, I used the following settings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bypassing Root&#39;s Password</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/bypassing-roots-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 10:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/bypassing-roots-password/</guid>
      <description>I had a situation today where a customer forgot the root password to a Debian GNU/Linux 3.1 system in their office. That left it up to me to try to find a way to get into the system. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I managed to gain access.
(Note: As far as I am aware, NONE of the information I&amp;rsquo;m going to list in this article will work across the network; you MUST have physical access to the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Impressions of Debian GNU/Linux 3.1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/27/initial-impressions-of-debian-gnulinux-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2005 17:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/27/initial-impressions-of-debian-gnulinux-31/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in a couple of previous posts, I have several servers running Red Hat Linux 9.0 that I am looking to upgrade to a newer distribution. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a couple of recent versions of CentOS (a clone version of Red Hat Enterprise Linux), but ran into problems with ntpd (I may have finally resolved those). I&amp;rsquo;d heard good things about Debian GNU/Linux, so I decided to give that a try as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
