<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Envoy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/envoy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Envoy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/envoy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 153</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #153! My personal and professional life has kept me busy over the last couple of months, so things have been quiet here on the blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve still been collecting links to share with you, though, and here&amp;rsquo;s the latest collection. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 152</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #152! Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish a Technology Short Take in the morning on a Friday, but I really wanted to get this one out so I&amp;rsquo;m making it live late in the day on a Monday. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve included some content below that you find useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 147</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #147! The list of articles is a bit shorter than usual this time around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a good collection of articles and posts covering topics in networking, hardware (mostly focused on Apple&amp;rsquo;s processors), cloud computing, and virtualization. There&amp;rsquo;s bound to be something in here for most everyone! (At least, I hope so.) Enjoy your weekend reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 142</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #142! This time around, the Networking section is a bit light, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of cloud computing links and articles for you to enjoy, along with some stuff on OSes and applications, programming, and soft skills. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s something useful here for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping Envoy Metrics Using the Prometheus Operator</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/01/scraping-envoy-with-prometheus-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/01/scraping-envoy-with-prometheus-operator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a recent customer project, I recommended the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/heptio/contour&#34;&gt;Heptio Contour&lt;/a&gt; for ingress on their Kubernetes cluster. For this particular customer, Contour&amp;rsquo;s support of the IngressRoute CRD and the ability to delegate paths via IngressRoutes made a lot of sense. Of course, the customer wanted to be able to scrape metrics using &lt;a href=&#34;https://prometheus.io/&#34;&gt;Prometheus&lt;/a&gt;, which meant I not only needed to scrape metrics from Contour but &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.envoyproxy.io/&#34;&gt;Envoy&lt;/a&gt; (which provides the data plane for Contour). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to scrape metrics from Envoy using the Prometheus Operator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
