<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iSCSI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/iscsi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iSCSI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/iscsi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #40. The content is a bit light this time around; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give you, my readers, a little break. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s still some useful and interesting stuff here. Enjoy!
Networking   Bob McCouch has a nice write-up on options for VPNs to AWS. If you&amp;rsquo;re needing to build out such a solution, you might want to read his post for some additional perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #39</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/07/technology-short-take-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 09:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/07/technology-short-take-39/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #39, in which I share a random assortment of links, articles, and thoughts from around the world of data center-related technologies. I hope you find something useful&amp;mdash;or at least something interesting!
Networking   Jason Edelman has been talking about the idea of a Common Programmable Abstraction Layer (CPAL). He introduces the idea, then goes on to explore&amp;mdash;as he puts it&amp;mdash;the power of a CPAL. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if this is the right level at which to put the abstraction layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #38</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 09:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #38, another installment in my irregularly-published series that collects links and thoughts on data center-related technologies from around the web. But enough with the introduction, let&amp;rsquo;s get on to the content already!
Networking   Jason Edelman does some experimenting with the Python APIs on a Cisco Nexus 3000. In the process, he muses about the value of configuration management tool chains such as Chef and Puppet in a world of &amp;ldquo;open switch&amp;rdquo; platforms such as Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #32</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #32, the latest installment in my irregularly-published series of link collections, thoughts, rants, raves, and miscellaneous information. I try to keep the information linked to data center technologies like networking, storage, virtualization, and the like, but occasionally other items slip through. I hope you find something useful.
Networking   Ranga Maddipudi (@vCloudNetSec on Twitter) has put together two blog posts on vCloud Networking and Security&amp;rsquo;s App Firewall (part 1 and part 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #31</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #31, my irregularly published series that takes a look at links, posts, articles, and thoughts from around the web related to core data center technologies. I hope that you find something useful!
Networking   Umair Hoodbhoy speculates in this post that the inclusion of Cisco&amp;rsquo;s ONE Controller in the recently-announced &amp;ldquo;Daylight&amp;rdquo; effort could mean the end for Big Switch&amp;rsquo;s Floodlight. (Umair&amp;rsquo;s play on words&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;in Daylight there is no need for Floodlights&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;is cute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of FCoE Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/04/a-collection-of-fcoe-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 11:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/04/a-collection-of-fcoe-posts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had these FCoE-related articles sitting around in my Yojimbo database for a while, but I&amp;rsquo;m only now getting around to doing something with them. There&amp;rsquo;s some great information in these posts, but be sure to check the comments to the posts as well&amp;mdash;there&amp;rsquo;s some equally good information to be found there as well.
FCoE Multi-hop: Why wait?
Re-examining FCoE and iSCSI Pros and Cons
FCoE vs. iSCSI: The Cagefight!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESX, EMC CLARiiON Arrays, and Multiple Protocols</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/05/vmware-esx-emc-clariion-arrays-and-multiple-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 10:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/05/vmware-esx-emc-clariion-arrays-and-multiple-protocols/</guid>
      <description>I was browsing through an EMC technical document titled &amp;ldquo;EMC CLARiiON Integration with VMware ESX Server&amp;rdquo; (download it here) a little while ago and I came across a phrase in the document that caught my attention:
 &amp;ldquo;VMware ESX/ESXi support both Fibre Channel and iSCSI storage. However, VMware and EMC do not support connecting VMware ESX/ESXi servers to CLARiiON Fibre Channel and iSCSI devices on the same array simultaneously.&amp;rdquo;
 What?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using IP-Based Storage with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 09:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me with a couple of questions, one of which I felt warranted a blog post. Paraphrased, the question was this: How do I make IP-based storage work with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS?
At first glance, you might look at this question and scoff. Remember though, that Cisco UCS does&amp;mdash;at this time&amp;mdash;have a few limitations that make this a bit more complicated than at first glance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 12:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #30, my irregularly posted collection of links and thoughts on virtualization. I hope you find something useful here!
  I believe Jason Boche already mentioned this on his own blog (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link) and also started this VMware Communities thread discussing the fact that the 8/6 patch breaks FT compatibility between ESX and ESXi hosts in the same cluster. This VMware KB article is now available with more information on the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #29</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/virtualization-short-take-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 19:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/virtualization-short-take-29/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to go ahead and get another issue of Virtualization Short Takes out the door before VMworld, as I suspect that I&amp;rsquo;ll be covered up both during and for some time after VMworld. So, here&amp;rsquo;s my latest collection of links and articles about virtualization, storage, and anything else I find interesting.
  Chad Sakac brings up an important issue for EMC CLARiiON users also using vSphere and iSCSI; be sure to read the full post for all the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere vDS, VMkernel Ports, and Jumbo Frames</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 13:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</guid>
      <description>In April 2008, I wrote an article on how to use jumbo frames with VMware ESX and IP-based storage (NFS or iSCSI). It&amp;rsquo;s been a pretty popular post, ranking right up there with the ever-popular article on VMware ESX, NIC teaming, and VLAN trunks.
Since I started working with VMware vSphere (now officially available as of 5/21/2009), I have been evaluating how to replicate the same sort of setup using ESX/ESXi 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Unified Fabric an Inevitability?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/20/is-unified-fabric-an-inevitability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 18:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/20/is-unified-fabric-an-inevitability/</guid>
      <description>So here&amp;rsquo;s another &amp;ldquo;thinking out loud&amp;rdquo; post. This time, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about Fibre Channel over Ethernet (FCoE) and unified fabric.
I was going back through a list of blog posts and articles that I wanted to read and think on, and I came across a link to Dave Graham&amp;rsquo;s article titled Moving a Fabric forward: FCoE Adoption and other Questions. His blog entry was partially in response to my FCoE discussion post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESX and ESXi SAN I/O Issue</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/12/vmware-esx-and-esxi-san-io-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 22:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/12/vmware-esx-and-esxi-san-io-issue/</guid>
      <description>Via this Twitter post, I learned that VMware has posted a new KB article about a SAN I/O failure that can occur with VMware ESX and ESXi 3.5 Update 3. If you are using VMware ESX or ESXi 3.5 Update 3, please be sure to read the KB article and stay tuned here for additional updates. I will update this post when I get more information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
