<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/hp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/hp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #41, the latest in my series of random thoughts, articles, and links from around the Internet. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) is a networking topic that is starting to get more and more attention (some may equate &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;hype&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to draw your own conclusion there). In any case, I liked how this article really hit upon what I personally feel is something many people are overlooking in NFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #33</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #33, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles discussing various data center technology-related links, articles, rants, thoughts, and questions. I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking   Tom Nolle asks the question, &amp;ldquo;Is virtualization reality even more elusive than virtual reality?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a good read; the key thing that I took away from it was that SDN, NFV, and related efforts are great, but what we really need is something that can pull all these together in a way that customers (and providers) reap the benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Summit 2013: OpenStack Back to the Enterprise, Keep Calm and Boldly Go On</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/17/openstack-summit-2013-openstack-back-to-the-enterprise-keep-calm-and-boldly-go-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 13:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/17/openstack-summit-2013-openstack-back-to-the-enterprise-keep-calm-and-boldly-go-on/</guid>
      <description>This is a session titled &amp;ldquo;OpenStack Back to the Enterprise: Keep Calm and Boldly Go.&amp;rdquo; The session is led by Florian Otel (@florianotel on Twitter), with HP Cloud Services in EMEA. The purpose of this talk is to share some of the &amp;ldquo;lessons learned&amp;rdquo; in how to position OpenStack to enterprise customers and overcome their objections.
Florian starts out the presentation with a slide that says, &amp;ldquo;This is a business, not a science project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusion or Not?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago I read Stephen Foskett&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Alas, VMware, Whither HDS?&amp;rdquo;, and I felt like I really needed to respond to this growing belief&amp;mdash;stated in Stephen&amp;rsquo;s article and in the sources to his article&amp;mdash;that VMware is, for whatever reason, somehow excluding certain storage vendors from future virtualization-storage integration development. From my perspective, this is just bogus.
As far as I can tell, Stephen&amp;rsquo;s post&amp;mdash;which is just one of several I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on this subject&amp;mdash;is based on two sources: my session blog of VSP3205 and an article by The Register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right vSphere Design Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 11:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</guid>
      <description>I was on a conference call the other day where the topic of the call was VMware View 5.0. If you attended VMworld&amp;mdash;or even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s been kind of hard to miss&amp;mdash;you know already that VMware made significant improvements to PCoIP in View 5. For one reason or another, the topic of the Teradici PCoIP offload card came up on the call, and other participants in the call were immediately asking about the availability of the card in mezzanine card format for blade server implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #39</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/03/virtualization-short-take-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 16:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/03/virtualization-short-take-39/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #39! This is my latest (as of May 3, 2010) collection of virtualization-related articles, links, and thoughts. I hope you find something useful buried in this random collection of bits of information I&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled across over the past few weeks.
  Dave Lawrence aka &amp;ldquo;the VMguy&amp;rdquo; had a recent post on Changed Block Tracking and why you (should) care. The difference that CBT makes in backups, replication, and other storage-related tasks can be notable, but remember that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to upgrade your VMs to VM hardware version 7 first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #34</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/24/virtualization-short-take-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2010 19:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/24/virtualization-short-take-34/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #34, my occasionally-weekly collection of virtualization-related links, posts, and comments. As usual, this information is a hodge-podge of information I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered from across the Internet over the last few weeks. I hope that you find something useful or helpful here, and thanks for reading!
  First up is Arne Fokkema&amp;rsquo;s PowerCLI script to check Windows VM partition alignment. As one commenter pointed out, the fact that the starting offset isn&amp;rsquo;t 65536&amp;mdash;which is what Arne&amp;rsquo;s script checks&amp;mdash;doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that it isn&amp;rsquo;t aligned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding NPIV and NPV</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/27/understanding-npiv-and-npv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 10:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/27/understanding-npiv-and-npv/</guid>
      <description>Two technologies that seem to have come to the fore recently are NPIV (N_Port ID Virtualization) and NPV (N_Port Virtualization). Judging just by the names, you might think that these two technologies are the same thing. While they are related in some aspects and can be used in a complementary way, they are quite different. What I&amp;rsquo;d like to do in this post is help explain these two technologies, how they are different, and how they can be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #5</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/17/storage-short-take-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 12:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/17/storage-short-take-5/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to resurrect my Storage Short Take series, after almost a year since the last one was published. I find myself spending more and more time in the storage realm&amp;mdash;which is completely fine with me&amp;mdash;and so more and more information coming to me in various forms is related to storage. While I&amp;rsquo;m far from the likes of storage rockstars such as Robin Harris, Stephen Foskett, Storagebod, and others, hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll find something interesting and useful here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: HP Flex-10 Design Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/28/thinking-out-loud-hp-flex-10-design-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2009 10:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/28/thinking-out-loud-hp-flex-10-design-considerations/</guid>
      <description>Along with a number of other projects recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been spending time working with HP Virtual Connect Flex-10. You may have seen these (relatively) recent Flex-10 articles:
Using VMware ESX Virtual Switch Tagging with HP Virtual Connect
Using Multiple VLANs with HP Virtual Connect Flex-10
Follow-Up About Multiple VLANs, Virtual Connect, and Flex-10
As I began to work up some documentation for internal use at my employer, I asked myself this question: what are the design considerations for how an architect should configure Flex-10?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Nexus 5000 to Older Gigabit Ethernet Switches</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/connecting-nexus-5000-to-older-gigabit-ethernet-switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 15:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/connecting-nexus-5000-to-older-gigabit-ethernet-switches/</guid>
      <description>One of the things that confused me when I first started working with the Nexus 5000 line was how I would connect this 10Gb Ethernet switch to older 1Gb Ethernet switches, like the older Cisco Catalyst or HP ProCurve switches that I also have in the lab. It turns out&amp;mdash;many of you probably already know this&amp;mdash;that the first 8 ports on a Nexus 5010 and the first 16 ports on Nexus 5020 can be configured to operate as Gigabit Ethernet ports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mudslinging Between Cisco and HP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/16/mudslinging-between-cisco-and-hp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2009 09:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/16/mudslinging-between-cisco-and-hp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll preface this article by saying that I am not (yet) an expert with Cisco&amp;rsquo;s Unified Computing System (UCS), so if I have incorrect information I&amp;rsquo;m certainly open to clarification. Some would also accuse me of being a UCS-hater, since I had the audacity to call UCS a blade server (the horror!). Truth is, I&amp;rsquo;m on the side of the customer, and as we all know there is no such thing as a &amp;ldquo;one size fits all&amp;rdquo; solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-Up About Multiple VLANs, Virtual Connect, and Flex-10</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/09/follow-up-about-multiple-vlans-virtual-connect-and-flex-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 11:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/09/follow-up-about-multiple-vlans-virtual-connect-and-flex-10/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to post a quick follow-up on the previous two articles that I published regarding using VLANs, Virtual Switch Tagging, HP Virtual Connect, and Flex-10:
Using VMware ESX Virtual Switch Tagging with HP Virtual Connect
Using Multiple VLANs with HP Virtual Connect Flex-10
One thing that I wanted to really clarify was that you can present multiple VLANs to FlexNICs on the same LOM, but you can&amp;rsquo;t present the same set of VLANs to FlexNICs on the same LOM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Multiple VLANs with HP Virtual Connect Flex-10</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/09/using-multiple-vlans-with-hp-virtual-connect-flex-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 10:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/09/using-multiple-vlans-with-hp-virtual-connect-flex-10/</guid>
      <description>In this article on using VMware ESX Virtual Switch Tagging (VST) with HP Virtual Connect, I showed you how to use the Multiple VLANs setting to map multiple VLANs onto a network connection so that the VLAN tags would pass all the way up to the VMware ESX/ESXi host&amp;mdash;a necessary prerequisite for making VST work.
However, there is a key caveat to this approach that applies when using HP Virtual Connect Flex-10 and HP blades that have Flex-10 LOM (LAN on Motherboard) interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VMware ESX Virtual Switch Tagging with HP Virtual Connect</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/06/using-vmware-esx-virtual-switch-tagging-with-hp-virtual-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 17:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/06/using-vmware-esx-virtual-switch-tagging-with-hp-virtual-connect/</guid>
      <description>In January 2008, SearchVMware.com published an article of mine titled VMware ESX Server Networking with HP Virtual Connect. In that article, I stated that one drawback of HP Virtual Connect was that it forced you to use External Switch Tagging (EST):
 When used in conjunction with ESX Server, shared uplink sets force the use of EST because VLAN tags are stripped away by the Virtual Connect switch. Therefore, the ESX Server can&amp;rsquo;t use the VLAN tags, and must resort to a different vSwitch&amp;mdash;each with one or more pNICs as uplinks&amp;mdash;for each VLAN/associated network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
