<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UCS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ucs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UCS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ucs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #61</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #61. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to find a nice range of articles and links, so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I was successful and that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking  Along with the release of rkt 1.0 (see below in the &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems/Applications&amp;rdquo; section), Metaswitch has announced a Container Networking Interface (CNI) plugin for Project Calico. (This appears to be primarily through the Calico plugin for Kubernetes and Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; support for CNI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #42</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #42, another installation in my ongoing series of irregularly published collections of news, items, thoughts, rants, raves, and tidbits from around the Internet, with a focus on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s series on VMware NSX continues with part 5.
  Aaron Rosen, a Neutron contributor, recently published a post about a Neutron extension called Allowed-Address-Pairs and how you can use it to create high availability instances using VRRP (via keepalived).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Network Health Check and Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/30/vsphere-network-health-check-and-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/30/vsphere-network-health-check-and-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>Reader Brian Markussen&amp;mdash;with whom I had the pleasure to speak at the Danish VMUG in Copenhagen earlier this month&amp;mdash;brought to my attention an issue between VMware vSphere&amp;rsquo;s health check feature and Cisco UCS when using Cisco&amp;rsquo;s VIC cards. His findings, confirmed by VMware support and documented in this KB article, show that the health check feature doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly with Cisco UCS and the VIC cards.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote from the KB article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #29</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/04/technology-short-take-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/04/technology-short-take-29/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #29! This is another installation in my irregularly-published series of links, thoughts, rants, and raves across various data center-related fields of technology. As always, I hope you find something useful here.
Networking   Who out there has played around with Mininet yet? Looks like this is another tool I need to add to my toolbox as I continue to explore networking technologies like OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #22</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 13:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #22! Once again, I find myself without too many articles to share with you this time around. I guess that will make things a bit easier for you, the reader, but it does make me question whether or not I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;listening&amp;rdquo; to the right communities. If any readers have suggestions on sources of information to which I should be subscribing or I should be following, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #19, the first Technology Short Take for 2012. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s first collection of links, articles, and thoughts regarding virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center technology-related topics. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   While configuration limits aren&amp;rsquo;t the most exciting reading, they are important from time to time. Here&amp;rsquo;s some configuration limits for the UCS 6100 and 6200 series.
  Understanding the differences&amp;mdash;both positive and negative&amp;mdash;between the various approaches to solving a particular challenge is a key skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #18</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 23:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #18! I hope you find something useful in this collection of networking, OS, storage, and virtualization links. Enjoy!
Networking The number of articles in my &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo; bucket continues to overflow; I have so many articles on so many topics (soft switching, OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, MPLS) that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get my head wrapped around all of it. Here are a few posts that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right vSphere Design Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 11:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</guid>
      <description>I was on a conference call the other day where the topic of the call was VMware View 5.0. If you attended VMworld&amp;mdash;or even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s been kind of hard to miss&amp;mdash;you know already that VMware made significant improvements to PCoIP in View 5. For one reason or another, the topic of the Teradici PCoIP offload card came up on the call, and other participants in the call were immediately asking about the availability of the card in mezzanine card format for blade server implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #13</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 10:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #13. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last Technology Short Take, and much has happened (vSphere 5 was announced, HP discontinued the TouchPad and webOS, and I announced my move to Denver). Here are a few data center technology-related links that stood out to me over the last few weeks. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   Here&amp;rsquo;s a good post by Jeremy Waldrop on Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 FEX (fabric extender) topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKCOM-3002: Network Redundancy and Load Balancing Designs for UCS Blade Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkcom-3002-network-redundancy-and-load-balancing-designs-for-ucs-blade-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkcom-3002-network-redundancy-and-load-balancing-designs-for-ucs-blade-servers/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKCOM-3002, Network Redundancy and Load Balancing Designs for UCS Blade Servers, presented by none other than M. Sean McGee (available as @mseanmcgee on Twitter; I highly recommend you follow him on Twitter if you are interested in UCS). I was really looking forward to this presentation, as I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken with Sean before and I know that he is a super-sharp UCS guru. Sean also blogs here.
Sean starts out the presentation by asking, &amp;ldquo;Do you know how UCS networking thinks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #12: Networking Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve published the Storage Edition of Technology Short Take #12, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Networking Edition. Enjoy, and I hope you find something useful!
  Ron Fuller&amp;rsquo;s ongoing deep dive series on OTV (Overlay Transport Virtualization) has been great for me. I knew about the basics of OTV, but Ron&amp;rsquo;s articles really gave me a better understanding of the technology. Check out the first three articles here: part 1, part 2, and part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi Local Disks Showing as Remote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/27/vmware-esxi-local-disks-showing-as-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 09:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/27/vmware-esxi-local-disks-showing-as-remote/</guid>
      <description>A little over a month ago, I was installing VMware ESXi on a Cisco UCS blade and noticed something odd during the installation. I posted a tweet about the incident. Here&amp;rsquo;s the text of the tweet in case the link above stops working:
 Interesting&amp;hellip;this #UCS blade has local disks but all disks are showing as remote during #ESXi install. Odd&amp;hellip;
 Several people responded, indicating they&amp;rsquo;d run into similar situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing ESXi though UCSM KVM via RDC on OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/25/installing-esxi-though-ucsm-kvm-via-rdc-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 20:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/25/installing-esxi-though-ucsm-kvm-via-rdc-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>How&amp;rsquo;s that for acronyms?
In all seriousness, though, as I was installing VMware ESXi this evening onto some remote Cisco UCS blades, I ran into some interesting keymapping issues and I thought it might be handy to document what worked for me in the event others run into this issue as well.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the scenario: I&amp;rsquo;m running Mac OS X 10.6.7 on my MacBook Pro, and using VMware View 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #11</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 18:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right folks, it&amp;rsquo;s time for another installation of Technology Short Takes. This is Technology Short Take #11, and I hope that you find the collection of items I have for you this time around both useful and informative. But enough of the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get to the good stuff!
Networking   David Davis (of Train Signal) has a good write-up on the Petri IT Knowledgebase on using a network packet analyzer with VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #9</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 12:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #9, the last Technology Short Take for 2010. In this Short Take, I have a collection of links and articles about networking, servers, storage, and virtualization. Of note this time around: some great DCI links, multi-hop FCoE finally arrives (sort of), a few XenServer/XenDesktop/XenApp links, and NTFS defragmentation in the virtualized data center. Here you go&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking   Brad Hedlund has a great post discussing Nexus 7000 connectivity options for Cisco UCS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
