<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GitHub on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GitHub on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/github/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bolstering my Software Development Skills</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/23/bolstering-my-software-development-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/23/bolstering-my-software-development-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe/status/1019743197105229824&#34;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; that I was about to undertake a new pet project where I was, in my words, &amp;ldquo;probably going to fall flat on my face&amp;rdquo;. Later, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe/status/1020776898870181888&#34;&gt;I asked on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if I should share some of the learning that will occur (is ocurring) as a result of this new project, and a number of folks indicated that I should. So, with that in mind, I&amp;rsquo;m announcing this project I&amp;rsquo;ve undertaken is a software development project aimed at helping me bolster my software development skills, and that I&amp;rsquo;ll be blogging about it along the way so that others can benefit from my mistakes&amp;hellip;er, learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloning All Repositories in a GitHub Organization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/19/cloning-all-repositories-in-a-github-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/19/cloning-all-repositories-in-a-github-organization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;https://ballerina.io/&#34;&gt;Ballerina&lt;/a&gt;, and upon the suggestion of some folks on Twitter wanted to clone down some of the &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; Ballerina GitHub repositories to provide code examples and guides that would assist in my learning. Upon attempting to do so, however, I found myself needing to clone down 39 different repositories (all under a single organization), and so I asked on Twitter if there was an easy way to do this. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checking Out GitHub Pull Requests Locally</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/09/04/checking-out-github-pull-requests-locally/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/09/04/checking-out-github-pull-requests-locally/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use the Git command-line to check out GitHub pull requests locally. I take absolutely no credit for this trick! I picked this up from this GitHub Gist, and merely wanted to share it here so that others would benefit.
The GitHub gist shows you how to modify the Git configuration for a particular repository so that when you run git fetch it will fetch all the pull requests for that repository as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git with GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/26/using-git-with-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/26/using-git-with-github/</guid>
      <description>Building on my earlier non-programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to Git, I wanted to talk a little bit about using Git with GitHub, a very popular service for hosting Git repositories. This post, in conjunction with the earlier introductory post on Git, will serve as the basis for a future post that talks about how to use Git and GitHub to collaborate with others on an open source project hosted on GitHub.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Git and haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the earlier introductory post, I strongly recommend reading that post first.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
