<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentation on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentation on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 16:05:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/presentation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from Midwest Regional VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/presentation-from-midwest-regional-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/presentation-from-midwest-regional-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Today I had the opportunity to speak at the Midwest Regional/Kansas City VMUG User Conference in Overland Park, KS. Below is the presentation I delivered, as hosted by SpeakerDeck.
If you&amp;rsquo;d like a PDF version of the deck for direct download, it is available here.
As always, courteous comments are both welcomed and encouraged! Feel free to speak up below.
UPDATE: During the blog migration in late 2014, all embedded presentations like the one originally found in this post were converted to hyperlinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from Portland VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/29/presentation-from-portland-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 13:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/29/presentation-from-portland-vmug/</guid>
      <description>At the request of a few individuals, I&amp;rsquo;m posting my presentation from the Portland VMUG here. It&amp;rsquo;s my first presentation on OpenStack, and hopefully I didn&amp;rsquo;t mangle things too badly. Feel free to provide any corrections, clarifications, or other feedback in the comments below (courteously, of course).
Here&amp;rsquo;s the presentation as hosted on SpeakerDeck.
For those that would like a direct download, it&amp;rsquo;s available here as a PDF.
Also, several readers indicated they&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to have direct downloads for some of the other presentations, so here are links to those presentations (as PDFs) as well:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from UK VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/25/presentation-from-uk-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 23:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/25/presentation-from-uk-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this month (November 2012), I had the honor of presenting the closing keynote at the 2nd annual UK National VMUG user conference. I was thrilled to be able to support the worldwide VMUG community, and a number of attendees asked if I would make my presentation available. So, in addition to providing a copy of the deck to the VMUG leaders, I&amp;rsquo;m also publishing it here via SpeakerDeck.
This is, by and large, the same presentation that I&amp;rsquo;ve given in Indianapolis in late July and in Chicago in late September.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere on NFS Design Considerations Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This presentation is one that I gave at the New Mexico, New York City, and Seattle VMUG conferences (this specific deck came from the Seattle conference, as you can tell by the Twitter handle on the first slide). The topic is design considerations for running vSphere on NFS. This isn&amp;rsquo;t an attempt to bash NFS, but rather to educate users on the things to avoid if you&amp;rsquo;re going to build a rock-solid NFS infrastructure for your VMware vSphere environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from South Florida VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Back in early March I was invited to speak at the South Florida VMUG, and I gave this presentation on vSphere networking challenges and solutions. The idea behind the presentation was to give attendees some visibility into IEEE and IETF efforts at creating new network technologies and protocols. I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here just in case someone might find it useful or helpful.
Here is a link to the presentation.
As always, your questions, corrections, or clarifications are welcome in the comments below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from VMware Partner Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/05/presentation-from-vmware-partner-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/05/presentation-from-vmware-partner-exchange/</guid>
      <description>On February 13, just before the official start of VMware Partner Exchange in Las Vegas, NV, I had the opportunity to present at the EMC Boot Camp. It&amp;rsquo;s beginning to seem that all my presentations focus on stretched clusters, but I assure you that&amp;rsquo;s not the case (give me a day or two and I&amp;rsquo;ll prove it to you). In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s the deck that I used during my presentation at the EMC Boot Camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from Australia VMUG Conferences</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/05/presentation-from-australia-vmug-conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 21:46:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/05/presentation-from-australia-vmug-conferences/</guid>
      <description>In early December of last year, I had the great opportunity to travel to Australia to participate in the inaugural full-day VMUG conferences in both Brisbane and Melbourne. I have been remiss in publishing the presentation that I gave at those meetings, so I&amp;rsquo;m fixing that now!
Here is a link to the presentation.
As always, if you have any questions, clarifications, or thoughts, please feel free to speak up in the comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Stretched Cluster Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/updated-stretched-cluster-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 22:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/updated-stretched-cluster-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Last week I had the opportunity to speak to the Toronto VMUG and present an updated version of my talk on considerations for building stretched vSphere clusters. Stretched clusters are a topic I&amp;rsquo;ve touched on several times, first in Denver in June 2010, again this past May in Charlotte, and finally in Toronto last week. Last week&amp;rsquo;s presentation, found here, includes new and updated content for vSphere 5.
As usual, feel free to speak up with any comments, suggestions, clarifications, or corrections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Networking Design Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/21/vsphere-networking-design-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/21/vsphere-networking-design-presentation/</guid>
      <description>It seems this is the week for catching up on stuff that I should have done a long time ago! Earlier in the week it was posting a video of the stretched cluster presentation I gave back in May at the Carolina VMware User Summit; this time it&amp;rsquo;s finally getting around to posting the presentation I gave at the Denver VMUG back at the end of June.
The presentation is on vSphere network design considerations and discusses some of the more commonly-encountered questions/issues regarding vSphere network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stretched Clustering Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/10/stretched-clustering-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 17:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/10/stretched-clustering-presentation/</guid>
      <description>On May 5, I had the privilege of speaking in Charlotte, NC, at the Carolina VMware User&amp;rsquo;s Summit. I had been asked to deliver a presentation on the pros and cons of stretched clusters in VMware vSphere. Since I know that not everyone could make it to Charlotte, here&amp;rsquo;s a copy of the presentation I gave. It&amp;rsquo;s hosted via Sliderocket. Enjoy, and feel free to post any questions or suggestions in the comments to this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation on VMware vSphere 4.1 Storage Features</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/29/presentation-on-vmware-vsphere-4-1-storage-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 12:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/29/presentation-on-vmware-vsphere-4-1-storage-features/</guid>
      <description>I had the privilege this past week of speaking at the Triad VMUG meeting in Greensboro, NC, along with fellow blogger, podcaster (is that a real word?), and speaker Rich Brambley. In the event you were unable to attend (there was quite a crowd attending), here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the presentation I gave at the meeting.
Feel free to share any additional thoughts, questions, or comments below. Thank you!
UPDATE: Embedded presentations were converted to links during the migration of the blog in late 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations from Midwest Regional VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/09/presentations-from-midwest-regional-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2010 10:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/09/presentations-from-midwest-regional-vmug/</guid>
      <description>This past Monday, December 6, I had the pleasure of speaking at the Midwest Regional VMUG held in Kansas City, Kansas. I delivered two presentations on Monday:
  Next-Generation Best Practices for Storage and VMware (keynote)
  Top 6 VMware vSphere Design Questions
  A number of people asked me after my presentations about getting copies of the presentations, so I&amp;rsquo;m making them available here via Slideshare. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Integration Presentation from East TN VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/01/storage-integration-presentation-from-east-tn-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/01/storage-integration-presentation-from-east-tn-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Last week I was invited to speak at a joint session of the East Tennessee VMware and EMC user groups in Knoxville. Despite some bad weather that kept some people from attending, the meeting was a great success. I&amp;rsquo;m posting a copy here, via SlideShare, of the presentation that I used for that meeting. Note that the actual presentation had some embedded videos in it that SlideShare won&amp;rsquo;t translate; these appear as blank slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stretched Cluster Presentation from Denver VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/30/stretched-cluster-presentation-from-denver-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 10:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/30/stretched-cluster-presentation-from-denver-vmug/</guid>
      <description>I had the honor of speaking in front of the Denver VMUG on Tuesday of this week. It was a blast, and I got to meet a great group of people. I received some positive feedback on the presentation that I gave at the VMUG, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share it here as well.
Here is a link to the presentation.
This is my first time using SlideShare, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably go back and update the slide deck here since some of the builds and formatting get lost in the conversion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
