<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CLARiiON on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/clariion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLARiiON on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 23:34:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/clariion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #12: Storage Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/08/technology-short-take-12-storage-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/08/technology-short-take-12-storage-edition/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind in my technology reading that I have this massive list of blog posts and links that I would normally put into an issue of Technology Short Takes. However, people are already &amp;ldquo;complaining&amp;rdquo; that my Short Takes aren&amp;rsquo;t all that short. To keep from overwhelming people, I&amp;rsquo;m breaking Technology Short Take #12 into three editions: Virtualization, Storage, and Networking.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Storage Edition&amp;rdquo; of Technology Short Take #12!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #11</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 18:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right folks, it&amp;rsquo;s time for another installation of Technology Short Takes. This is Technology Short Take #11, and I hope that you find the collection of items I have for you this time around both useful and informative. But enough of the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get to the good stuff!
Networking   David Davis (of Train Signal) has a good write-up on the Petri IT Knowledgebase on using a network packet analyzer with VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Inactive New Paths on an EMC CLARiiON</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/20/fixing-inactive-new-paths-on-an-emc-clariion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/20/fixing-inactive-new-paths-on-an-emc-clariion/</guid>
      <description>I ran into an issue in the lab today with some VMware ESX 4.0 hosts and some older CLARiiON CX3 arrays. I&amp;rsquo;d been working to fix up the lab so that it more properly reflects a &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; configuration with dual SAN fabrics, dual-homed HBAs and CNAs, network connections spread across multiple physical switches, etc.&amp;mdash;you know, all the wonderful things that we recommend to our customers.
As a result of cross-connecting both the HBAs and the CLARiiON&amp;rsquo;s storage processors to both SAN fabrics, I ended up with more paths to the LUNs than I had previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing IP Addresses on an EMC Celerra NS-960</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/changing-ip-addresses-on-an-emc-celerra-ns-960/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 09:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/changing-ip-addresses-on-an-emc-celerra-ns-960/</guid>
      <description>Changing the IP addresses on an EMC Celerra unified storage array is generally a pretty straightforward process. EMC supplies a script called clariion_mgmt that you can use to change the IP addresses on the back-end CLARiiON storage processors (SPs). In the large majority of cases, the process for changing the IP addresses on an EMC Celerra using this script looks something like this:
  Change the IP address of the Control Station using Celerra Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
