<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certification on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/certification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certification on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/certification/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 116</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #116! This one is a bit shorter than usual, due to holidays in the US and my life being busy. Nevertheless, I hope that I managed to capture something you find useful or helpful. As always, your feedback is welcome, so if you have suggestions, corrections, or comments, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe&#34;&gt;contact me via Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #45</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #45. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a collection of links to various articles pertaining to data center-related technologies for your enjoyment. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Cormac Hogan has a list of a few useful NSX troubleshooting tips.
  If you&amp;rsquo;re not really a networking pro and need a &amp;ldquo;gentle&amp;rdquo; introduction to VXLAN, this post might be a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2012 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/07/looking-back-2012-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 19:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/07/looking-back-2012-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I posted a look at my planned projects for 2012. Now, a year later, it&amp;rsquo;s time to review my progress (or lack thereof) and measure myself on how well I did (or didn&amp;rsquo;t) do on those projects.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s review the original project list:
  Learn to script in Perl.
  Learn to speak German.
  Become more familiar with Xen (and Open vSwitch and OpenStack).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Year Project Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/25/mid-year-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/25/mid-year-project-update/</guid>
      <description>In early January, I posted a 2012 project list. To summarize, here are the four broad goals that I set for myself for 2012:
 Learn to script in Perl. Learn to speak German. Become very familiar with the Xen hypervisor. Pursue CCNP certification.  Now that we are halfway through the year, where do things stand? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick update.
  My Perl skills are still really elementary. The biggest challenge I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that without some sort of task or process to try to automate, trying to write code in Perl is kind of &amp;ldquo;disconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Projects for 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/02/some-projects-for-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 10:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/02/some-projects-for-2012/</guid>
      <description>Rather than posting some sort of &amp;ldquo;2011 in review&amp;rdquo; article where I talk about how many visitors the site had or how many RSS subscribers there are, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d instead focus on the upcoming year and some of the projects in which I&amp;rsquo;ll be involved. By describing some of the projects that I&amp;rsquo;m undertaking this year in 2012, that gives you&amp;mdash;the readers&amp;mdash;a rough idea of some of the types of content that will likely appear in the coming year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few References for CCNA Certification</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/04/a-few-references-for-ccna-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/04/a-few-references-for-ccna-certification/</guid>
      <description>It seems as if there&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of an increase in interest in attaining CCNA, especially among colleagues within the virtualization and storage areas. (One could allege that this is further evidence of a growing trend away from highly specialized IT folk, but that&amp;rsquo;s another topic for another day.) With that in mind, I thought I might post a few networking-related references to help others in their quest. So, with that in mind, here you go.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
