<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WAFL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wafl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WAFL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 14:28:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wafl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Future of NetApp</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 14:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</guid>
      <description>As I was sitting in London&amp;rsquo;s Heathrow Airport this morning catching up on RSS feeds before boarding my plane back to the United States, an article headline caught my eye: Why NetApp Must Seek Acquisition.
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how glad I am to see this article published, because it gives me the opportunity to share something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a while, even before I joined EMC. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that everything I have to say about NetApp will be colored by the fact that I now work for EMC, and&amp;mdash;whether I like it or not&amp;mdash;all comments about any other storage vendor or technology are immediately suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031: Enhancements to NetApp Cloning Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on enhancements to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s cloning functionality. These enhancements are due to be released along with Data ONTAP 7.3.1, which is expected out in December. Of course, that date may shift, but that&amp;rsquo;s the expected release timeframe.
The key focus of the session was new functionality that allows for Data ONTAP to clone individual files without a backing Snapshot. This new functionality is an extension of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s deduplication functionality, and is enabled by changes within Data ONTAP that enable block sharing, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Short Take is a collection of links and articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last few weeks (or longer ago, in some cases!) that I thought others might find interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  Alessandro broke the news to the general public about some anticipated new virtualization features that are expected to make their debut in Windows Server 2008 R2, expected sometime in 2010. Microsoft announced live migration for Hyper-V back at the beginning of September, so that part was already known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Suing Sun over ZFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 21:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</guid>
      <description>I was on the road most of the day today, so I must have missed this news earlier. Apparently, Sun Microsystems and Network Appliance have had a little spat over ZFS and WAFL, and now NetApp is suing Sun for patent infringement.
Dave Hitz explained the situation in a blog entry:
 This morning, NetApp filed an IP (intellectual property) lawsuit against Sun. It has two parts. The first is a &amp;ldquo;declaratory judgment&amp;rdquo;, asking the court to decide whether we infringe a set of patents that Sun claims we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of WAFL and ZFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/12/comparison-of-wafl-and-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 17:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/12/comparison-of-wafl-and-zfs/</guid>
      <description>This comparison of ZFS (Zettabyte File System) and WAFL (Write Anywhere File Layout) by Network Appliance (no direct link for WAFL) is an interesting comparison of these two advanced filesystems and their feature set. Be sure to read the comments for some additional insight on the comparison of the two filesystems and some clarification about supported features.
One distinction raised in the comments that&amp;rsquo;s worthy to be noted here is that any comparison of this sort also, by its very nature, takes into account the operating system that runs the filesystem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
