<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/san/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/san/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #74</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #74! The end of 2016 is nearly upon us, and it looks as if there will be only one more Technology Short Take before the end of the year. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with the content&amp;mdash;time is short!
Networking  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apstra, David Varnum has a great introduction to Apstra available on his site. Will Robinson talks about how to structure your Ansible playbooks in the context of using Ansible to control your network gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #58</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/18/technology-short-take-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/18/technology-short-take-58/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #58. This will be the last Technology Short Take of 2015, as next week is Christmas and the following week is the New Year&amp;rsquo;s holiday. Before I present this episode&amp;rsquo;s collection of links, articles, and thoughts on various data center technologies, allow me to first wish all of my readers a very merry and very festive holiday season. Now, on to the content!
Networking  Looking for a step-by-step install guide for VMware NSX?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKSAN-3707: Advanced SAN Services</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKSAN-3707, Advanced SAN Services, presented by Mike Dunn.
According to TIP&amp;rsquo;s Storage Research, the top five storage initiatives are deduplication, technology refresh, tiered storage build-out, archiving, and consolidation.
The three main sections of the presentation are SAN consolidation with virtualization, tiered storage and backup design, and Fibre Channel over Ethernet (FCoE).
The presentation starts with SAN consolidation using virtualization. This is really a discussion of virtual SANs (VSANs), which allow you to consolidate SANs onto the same hardware but still providing logical separation of fabrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using VAAI to Maintain Control?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/16/using-vaai-to-maintain-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/16/using-vaai-to-maintain-control/</guid>
      <description>Chris M Evans (@chrismevans) aka The Storage Architect recently posted an article on his site titled &amp;ldquo;VAAI - Offloading or Maintaining Control?&amp;rdquo; The article was a follow-up to a discussion with Nigel Poulton (@nigelpoulton) at HP Discover 2011.
The basic premise of the article as I understand it was a discussion of whether the introduction of VAAI (vStorage APIs for Array Integration), while it does bring benefits to the storage layer, also gives VMware more control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #12: Storage Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/08/technology-short-take-12-storage-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2011 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/08/technology-short-take-12-storage-edition/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m so far behind in my technology reading that I have this massive list of blog posts and links that I would normally put into an issue of Technology Short Takes. However, people are already &amp;ldquo;complaining&amp;rdquo; that my Short Takes aren&amp;rsquo;t all that short. To keep from overwhelming people, I&amp;rsquo;m breaking Technology Short Take #12 into three editions: Virtualization, Storage, and Networking.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;Storage Edition&amp;rdquo; of Technology Short Take #12!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCoE through a Nexus to a MDS-Attached Storage Array</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/15/fcoe-through-a-nexus-to-a-mds-attached-storage-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/15/fcoe-through-a-nexus-to-a-mds-attached-storage-array/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I want to pull together all the steps necessary to take a Converged Network Adapter (CNA)-equipped server and connect it, using FCoE, to a Fibre Channel-attached storage array. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of &amp;ldquo;net new&amp;rdquo; information in this post, but rather I&amp;rsquo;m summarizing previous posts, organizing the information, and showing how these steps relate to each other. I hope that this helps someone understand the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; of how FCoE and Fibre Channel relate to each other and how they interoperate (which, quite frankly, is one of the key factors for the adoption of FCoE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Review of VPLEX Storage Objects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/13/a-quick-review-of-vplex-storage-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/13/a-quick-review-of-vplex-storage-objects/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get my VPLEX clusters up and running, I&amp;rsquo;m ready to start providing some posts on VPLEX and how it&amp;rsquo;s configured and used. To get things started, I want to first provide an overview of VPLEX storage objects and how they relate to each other.
Storage volumes: Storage volumes are the LUNs that are presented to the VPLEX back-end ports from the storage array. The screenshot below, taken from the VPLEX management GUI, shows a series of storage volumes taken from two separate back-end arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Device Aliases on a Cisco MDS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/08/using-device-aliases-on-a-cisco-mds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 20:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/08/using-device-aliases-on-a-cisco-mds/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I posted a couple of articles on configuring and managing Cisco MDS Fibre Channel zones via the CLI:
New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Configuring Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Managing Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
In those posts, I discussed the use of the fcalias command to create aliases for World Wide Port Names (WWPNs) on the fabric. A couple of people suggested via Twitter and blog comments that I should use device aliases instead of the the fcalias command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAN Port Channels from Nexus 5010 to MDS 9134</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 09:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</guid>
      <description>As part of an ongoing effort to expand the functionality of the vSpecialist lab in the EMC RTP facility, we recently added a pair of Cisco MDS 9134 Fibre Channel switches. These Fibre Channel switches are connected to a pair of Cisco Nexus 5010 switches, which handle Unified Fabric connections from a collection of CNA-equipped servers. To connect the Nexus switches to the MDS switches, we used SAN port channels to bond multiple Fibre Channel interfaces together for both redundancy and increased aggregate throughput.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #5</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/17/storage-short-take-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 12:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/17/storage-short-take-5/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to resurrect my Storage Short Take series, after almost a year since the last one was published. I find myself spending more and more time in the storage realm&amp;mdash;which is completely fine with me&amp;mdash;and so more and more information coming to me in various forms is related to storage. While I&amp;rsquo;m far from the likes of storage rockstars such as Robin Harris, Stephen Foskett, Storagebod, and others, hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll find something interesting and useful here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for FCoE in Your Data Center Today</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 15:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of attending a Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 class. I have learned a tremendous amount about FCoE this week and after some conversations with Scott about the topic, I wanted to tackle it one more time from a different point of view. I have included a list of some of Scott&amp;rsquo;s FCoE articles at the bottom for those interested in a more in-depth analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/25/virtualization-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 10:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/25/virtualization-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s Virtualization Short Take #27, a collection of news, tidbits, thoughts, articles, and useless trivia I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last week or so. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ll find a diamond in the rough among these items!
  Interested in more information on how it is, exactly, that Cisco is going to provide so much memory in their UCS blades and rack mount servers to make them ideal virtualization hosts? This article from CommsDesign and this &amp;ldquo;Catalina&amp;rdquo; article by Rodos Haywood both provide some great information on how Cisco is working around the Intel reference architecture limitations introduced with the Xeon 5500 and Quick Path Interconnect (QPI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Generates Insane Amounts of I/O</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/vmware-vsphere-generates-insane-amounts-of-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 17:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/vmware-vsphere-generates-insane-amounts-of-io/</guid>
      <description>The news has hit the Internet in various places, but I wanted to point it out here because it does help to debunk the myth that virtualization can&amp;rsquo;t handle all workload. What&amp;rsquo;s the news? EMC and VMware have jointly demonstrated that a single VMware vSphere host running just three virtual machines can drive just above 350,000 I/O operations per second (IOPS).
I&amp;rsquo;ll let that sink in for just a moment. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t understand just how significant that number is, consider that a typical Fibre Channel drive can sustain somewhere just below 200 IOPS (and that&amp;rsquo;s being a bit generous).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanbolic Brings Snapshots to Melio FS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/sanbolic-brings-snapshots-to-melio-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 22:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/sanbolic-brings-snapshots-to-melio-fs/</guid>
      <description>Sanbolic is continuing to differentiate its clustered file system, Melio FS, in advance of the rudimentary clustered file system Microsoft plans on introducing in Windows Server 2008 R2. In an announcement last week, Sanbolic announced support for fully journaled snapshots. This functionality allows any server accessing the clustered file system to invoke a snapshot. The new snapshot functionality provides support for VSS and &amp;ldquo;full industry standard APIs,&amp;rdquo; although I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what those &amp;ldquo;full industry standard APIs&amp;rdquo; are exactly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
