<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firefox on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/firefox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Firefox on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 16:15:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/firefox/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making Firefox on Linux use Private Browsing by Default</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/13/making-firefox-on-linux-use-private-browsing-by-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 16:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/13/making-firefox-on-linux-use-private-browsing-by-default/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While there are a couple different methods to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/products/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; use private browsing by default (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://ccm.net/faq/15012-how-to-start-firefox-in-private-mode-by-default&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; for a couple methods), these methods essentially &lt;em&gt;force&lt;/em&gt; private browsing and disable the ability to use &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; (non-private) browsing. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe what I consider to be a better way of achieving this, at least on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making File URLs Work Again in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/04/04/making-file-urls-work-again-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 19:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/04/04/making-file-urls-work-again-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At some point in the last year or so&amp;mdash;I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly when it happened&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, along with most of the other major browsers, stopped working with &lt;code&gt;file://&lt;/code&gt; URLs. This is a shame, because I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/07/linux-migration-creating-presentations/&#34;&gt;using Markdown for presentations&lt;/a&gt; (at least, when it&amp;rsquo;s a presentation where I don&amp;rsquo;t need to collaborate with others). However, using this sort of approach generally requires support for &lt;code&gt;file://&lt;/code&gt; URLs (or requires running a local web server). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to make &lt;code&gt;file://&lt;/code&gt; URLs work again in Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 101</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/technology-short-take-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/technology-short-take-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #101! I have (hopefully) crafted an interesting and varied collection of links for you today, spanning all the major areas of modern data center technology. Now you have some reading material for this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manually Installing Firefox 60 on Fedora 27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/15/manually-installing-firefox-60-on-fedora-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/15/manually-installing-firefox-60-on-fedora-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla recently released version 60 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;, which contains a number of pretty important enhancements (as outlined &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/60.0/releasenotes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). However, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; repositories don&amp;rsquo;t (yet) contain Firefox 60 (at least not for Fedora 27), so you can&amp;rsquo;t just do a &lt;code&gt;dnf update&lt;/code&gt; to get the latest release. With that in mind, here are some instructions for manually installing Firefox 60 on Fedora 27.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending Group Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/09/extending-group-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 17:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/09/extending-group-policy/</guid>
      <description>Two articles recently surfaced amid the wave of information that deluges me daily, and both were regarding the extension of Group Policy&amp;mdash;a key feature of Active Directory&amp;mdash;into areas that were previously untapped.
First, there came the announcement of the FrontMotion Firefox Community Edition, a version of Firefox that is deployable and configurable via Group Policy in Active Directory. With this build of Firefox, organizations can deploy Firefox and centrally manage Firefox settings via Group Policy, much in the same way that organizations can centrally deploy and manage Internet Exploder, er, Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Updates and Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 15:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla released Firefox 1.0.5, which patches a number of security vulnerabilities. You can get more information on the release here or by visiting the Mozilla.org web site.
In addition, more information has been revealed about Firefox 1.1, the next version of the open source web browser. An alpha version of Firefox 1.1 could be ready within just a few days.
If Mozilla can continue to innovate with Firefox and address my two primary concerns&amp;mdash;ease of deployment and distributing security updates&amp;mdash;then they will continue to steal market share away from Internet Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out, IE Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</guid>
      <description>A couple of articles are highlighting a recently uncovered security flaw in Microsoft Internet Explorer&amp;mdash;this article from eWeek and this article from ComputerWorld, both of which reference this security advisory from Microsoft.
The fix is to set the Security Level for the Internet Zone to High, which disables the functionality required for the exploit to work. Unfortunately, it also disables a lot of other things that non-malicious sites use, so this workaround will affect your ordinary browsing experience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
