<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2013 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2013/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2013 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2013/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vendor Meetings at VMworld 2013</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/05/vendor-meetings-at-vmworld-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/05/vendor-meetings-at-vmworld-2013/</guid>
      <description>This year at VMworld, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in any of the breakout sessions because employees aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed to register for breakout sessions in advance; we have to wait in the standby line to see if we can get in at the last minute. So, I decided to meet with some vendors that seemed interesting and get some additional information on their products. Here&amp;rsquo;s the write-up on some of the vendor meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve attended while in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2013 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/27/vmworld-2013-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2013 12:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/27/vmworld-2013-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 keynote at VMworld 2013 in San Francisco. For a look at what happened in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote, see here. Depending on network connectivity, I may or may not be able to update this post in real-time.
The keynote kicks off with Carl Eschenbach. Supposedly there are more than 22,000 people in attendance at VMworld 2013, making it&amp;mdash;according to Carl&amp;mdash;the largest IT infrastructure event. (I think some other vendors might take issue with that claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2013 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/26/vmworld-2013-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 12:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/26/vmworld-2013-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 1 keynote for VMworld 2013. Depending on network connectivity, this might not get published until after the keynote is finished. The keynote starts, as usual, with a snazzy marketing video.
After the video wraps up, Robin Matlock takes the stage. Robin invites some 10-year veterans of VMworld to share memorable moments from the previous 10 VMworlds.
From there, she launches into a discussion of the &amp;ldquo;customer virtualization journey&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s the same 3-step journey of IT production, business production, and IT-as-a-Service that we&amp;rsquo;ve heard about for several years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
