<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VSAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vsan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VSAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vsan/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 124</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #124! It seems like the natural progression of the Tech Short Takes is moving toward monthly articles, since it&amp;rsquo;s been about a month since my last one. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that I&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful for you. Enjoy! (And yes, normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but I messed up and forgot. So, I decided to publish on Monday instead of waiting for Friday.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 94</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/09/technology-short-take-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/09/technology-short-take-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 94! Ready for another round of links, articles, and thoughts on data center technologies? (Who knows, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll throw a rant or two in there.) OK, enough rambling&amp;hellip;here&amp;rsquo;s the good stuff!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EMEA 2016 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/19/vmworld-emea-2016-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/19/vmworld-emea-2016-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 general session at VMworld EMEA 2016 in Barcelona, Spain. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to write a liveblog of the day 1 session due to some scheduling/logistical conflicts, but managed to get things arranged for day 2 (well, most of it&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to cut this short so I can get to a customer meeting).
At 9am, Sanjay Poonen takes the stage to kick off the general session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2016 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/30/vmworld2016-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/30/vmworld2016-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 2 general session here at VMworld 2016 at Mandalay Bay in Las Vegas, NV. Today, VMware is expected to talk more about containers, end-user computing, and other topics not covered in yesterday&amp;rsquo;s general session (which focused heavily on Cross-Cloud Services, VMware&amp;rsquo;s new set of SaaS-based offerings for multi-cloud management).
The general session kicks off with Sanjay Poonen taking the stage. Poonen is an energetic speaker who&amp;rsquo;s generally very entertaining and lively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #67</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #67. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping something I&amp;rsquo;ve collected for you here proves useful!
Networking  Anthony Burke has written a script that uses VMware NSX to protect VMware Log Insight instances. More information on the script is in his blog post. Russ White tackles the issue of networking engineers needing to learn to code. Is it necessary? Russ thinks so&amp;mdash;but probably not for the reasons you might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #56</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #56! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a few links on various data center technologies, news, events, and trends. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking  Open Virtual Network (OVN) is really ramping up and getting lots of attention, which I personally think is absolutely well-deserved. Russell Bryant has a couple great articles on OVN&amp;mdash;how to test OVN&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;EZ Bake&amp;rdquo; release with DevStack as well as an article on implementing OpenStack security groups using OVN ACLs (which in turn leverage the integration between Open vSwitch and the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s conntrack module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #39</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/07/technology-short-take-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 09:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/07/technology-short-take-39/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #39, in which I share a random assortment of links, articles, and thoughts from around the world of data center-related technologies. I hope you find something useful&amp;mdash;or at least something interesting!
Networking   Jason Edelman has been talking about the idea of a Common Programmable Abstraction Layer (CPAL). He introduces the idea, then goes on to explore&amp;mdash;as he puts it&amp;mdash;the power of a CPAL. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if this is the right level at which to put the abstraction layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #38</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 09:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #38, another installment in my irregularly-published series that collects links and thoughts on data center-related technologies from around the web. But enough with the introduction, let&amp;rsquo;s get on to the content already!
Networking   Jason Edelman does some experimenting with the Python APIs on a Cisco Nexus 3000. In the process, he muses about the value of configuration management tool chains such as Chef and Puppet in a world of &amp;ldquo;open switch&amp;rdquo; platforms such as Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating UCS Service Profiles Part 2: Storage Elements</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/07/creating-ucs-service-profiles-part-2-storage-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2010 10:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/07/creating-ucs-service-profiles-part-2-storage-elements/</guid>
      <description>This article is part 2 of a series of posts that provide some additional inormation on creating UCS service profiles. In part 1 of the series, I discussed some of the networking-related elements that you should create before you create your service profile (or service profile template). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the storage-related items that you should create in advance of creating the service profile (or service profile template).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
