<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NetApp on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/netapp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NetApp on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/netapp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years of writing here, I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a pretty fair amount of content. To help folks discover older content, I thought it might be fun to revisit what I&amp;rsquo;ve published in October in years past. Here are some &amp;ldquo;posts from the past,&amp;rdquo; all from October of previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #29</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/04/technology-short-take-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/04/technology-short-take-29/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #29! This is another installation in my irregularly-published series of links, thoughts, rants, and raves across various data center-related fields of technology. As always, I hope you find something useful here.
Networking   Who out there has played around with Mininet yet? Looks like this is another tool I need to add to my toolbox as I continue to explore networking technologies like OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusion or Not?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago I read Stephen Foskett&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Alas, VMware, Whither HDS?&amp;rdquo;, and I felt like I really needed to respond to this growing belief&amp;mdash;stated in Stephen&amp;rsquo;s article and in the sources to his article&amp;mdash;that VMware is, for whatever reason, somehow excluding certain storage vendors from future virtualization-storage integration development. From my perspective, this is just bogus.
As far as I can tell, Stephen&amp;rsquo;s post&amp;mdash;which is just one of several I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on this subject&amp;mdash;is based on two sources: my session blog of VSP3205 and an article by The Register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #10</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/27/technology-short-take-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 10:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/01/27/technology-short-take-10/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #10, my latest collection of data center-oriented links, articles, thoughts, and tidbits from around the Internet. I hope you find something useful or informative!
Networking   Link aggregation with VMware vSwitches is something I&amp;rsquo;ve touched upon a great many posts here on my site, but one thing that I don&amp;rsquo;t know I&amp;rsquo;ve ever specifically called out is that VMware vSwitches don&amp;rsquo;t support LACP. But that&amp;rsquo;s OK&amp;mdash;Ivan Pepelnjak takes care of that for me with his recent post on LACP and the VMware vSwitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of NetApp</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 14:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/18/the-future-of-netapp/</guid>
      <description>As I was sitting in London&amp;rsquo;s Heathrow Airport this morning catching up on RSS feeds before boarding my plane back to the United States, an article headline caught my eye: Why NetApp Must Seek Acquisition.
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how glad I am to see this article published, because it gives me the opportunity to share something I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about for a while, even before I joined EMC. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that everything I have to say about NetApp will be colored by the fact that I now work for EMC, and&amp;mdash;whether I like it or not&amp;mdash;all comments about any other storage vendor or technology are immediately suspect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #29</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/virtualization-short-take-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2009 19:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/27/virtualization-short-take-29/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to go ahead and get another issue of Virtualization Short Takes out the door before VMworld, as I suspect that I&amp;rsquo;ll be covered up both during and for some time after VMworld. So, here&amp;rsquo;s my latest collection of links and articles about virtualization, storage, and anything else I find interesting.
  Chad Sakac brings up an important issue for EMC CLARiiON users also using vSphere and iSCSI; be sure to read the full post for all the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp RCU and VSC</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/17/netapp-rcu-and-vsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 13:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/17/netapp-rcu-and-vsc/</guid>
      <description>I spent some time last week at the NetApp RTP office getting a special sneak preview of a couple of software products getting announced at VMworld 2009 in San Francisco. One of these is the Rapid Cloning Utility (RCU); the other is the Virtual Storage Console (VSC). Both of these software products are intended to plug into vCenter Server to provide more centralized access to both storage and virtualization management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republished: FlexClones or Deduplication?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/03/republished-flexclones-or-deduplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 23:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/03/republished-flexclones-or-deduplication/</guid>
      <description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: This content was first published over at Storage Monkeys, but it appears that it has since disappeared and is no longer available. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m republishing it here (with minor edits). Where applicable, I&amp;rsquo;ll also be republishing other old content from that site in the coming weeks. Thanks!
I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed this topic before, but I felt like it was a topic that needed to be revisited again. Storage admins need to know how their choices in storage technologies may or may not impact virtualization efforts, and this particular choice&amp;mdash;leveraging pointer-based snapshots or deduplication&amp;mdash;is particularly important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware, This is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/28/vmware-this-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 09:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/28/vmware-this-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: VMware has clarified their position; they will allow competitors to exhibit at VMworld. The text in the exhibitors agreement was legalese&amp;mdash;supposedly consistent with other major vendor-sponsored conferences&amp;mdash;meant to give them an out in the event an exhibitor behaves inappropriately.
I sincerely hope that Brian Madden is wrong about the recent change to vendor policies for VMworld.
This is exactly the wrong thing to do in this sort of competitive landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp VIF Member Limitations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/02/netapp-vif-member-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 21:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/02/netapp-vif-member-limitations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a couple of times about NetApp virtual interfaces (VIFs), which are Data ONTAP&amp;rsquo;s name for a link aggregate using either EtherChannel or dynamic LACP. The earlier articles I wrote are:
Cisco Link Aggregation and NetApp VIFs
LACP with Cisco Switches and NetApp VIFs
I came across an issue today of which I was not aware. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new NetApp deployment with a fellow engineer that called for a number of different VIFs to be created: one for CIFS traffic, one for NFS traffic, and one for SnapMirror traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #25, the first edition of this series for 2009! Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of articles and posts that I found interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off today&amp;rsquo;s list with some Hyper-V links. First up is this article on how to manually add a VM configuration to Hyper-V. It would be interesting to me to know some of the technical details&amp;mdash;i.e., the design decisions that led Microsoft to architect things in this way&amp;mdash;that might explain why this process is, in my opinion, so complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blasts from the Past</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/01/blasts-from-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 19:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/01/blasts-from-the-past/</guid>
      <description>I was visiting Unclutterer and saw them sharing older content from the site in a similar fashion. So, I thought I might try it here. Enjoy some of these &amp;ldquo;blasts from the past&amp;rdquo;!
One Year Ago LACP with Cisco Switches and NetApp VIFs
Hyper-V Architectural Issue
Latest VDI Article Published
Two Years Ago Bookmark Spam?
Personal Computing as a Collection of VMs?
Application Agnosticism
Three Years Ago Mac OS X and .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3183: VMware SRM on NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 09:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>This session described VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) on NetApp storage. The session started out with a review of VMware SRM, its features and functionality, and some of the requirements. I was not aware, for example, that SRM cannot use SQL Server Express like VirtualCenter can; you must use a full-blown instance of SQL Server. Given VMware&amp;rsquo;s development history, I should not have been surprised to find that Perl 5.8 is required (it&amp;rsquo;s included in the distribution and installed automatically).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
