<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Puppet on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/puppet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Puppet on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/puppet/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years of writing here, I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a pretty fair amount of content. To help folks discover older content, I thought it might be fun to revisit what I&amp;rsquo;ve published in October in years past. Here are some &amp;ldquo;posts from the past,&amp;rdquo; all from October of previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 88</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/14/technology-short-take-88/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/14/technology-short-take-88/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #88! Travel is keeping me pretty busy this fall (so much for things slowing down after VMworld EMEA), and this has made it a bit more difficult to stick to my self-imposed biweekly schedule for the Technology Short Takes (heck, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even get this one published on Friday!). Sorry about that! Hopefully the irregular schedule is outweighed by the value found in the content I&amp;rsquo;ve collected for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #78</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #78! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of links and articles from around the Internet discussing various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  The rise of the disaggregated network operating system (NOS) marches on: this time, it&amp;rsquo;s Big Switch Networks announcing expanded hardware support in Open Network Linux (ONL), upon which its own NOS is based. The Pivotal Engineering blog has an article that shows how to use BOSH with the vSphere CPI to automate adding servers to an NSX load balancing pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #65</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #65! As usual, I gathered an odd collection of links and articles from around the web on key data center technologies and trends. I hope you find something useful!
Networking  Michael Ryom has a nice (but short) article on using Log Insight along with a NetFlow proxy to help provide more detailed visibility into traffic flows between VMs on NSX logical networks. Brent Salisbury has an article on GoBGP, a Go-based BGP implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #49</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #49 (also known as Distraction-as-a-Service)! I have here for your reading pleasure an eclectic collection of links and articles from around the web, focusing on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful. Bring on the content!
Networking  I love this post from Matt Oswalt on five next-gen skills for networking pros. I highly recommend you read the entire post, but in short the five skills Matt recommends are software skills (which includes configuration management and software development tools like Git), Linux, deep protocol knowledge, hypervisor and container networking, and IPv6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Documenting Systems?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/23/self-documenting-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/23/self-documenting-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Singapore this past week, wrapping up the week by speaking at the inaugural Singapore VMUG User Conference. While at the User Conference, I had the opportunity to attend a session by John Arrasjid (you probably know him as @vcdx001 on Twitter) on the art of IT infrastructure design. Although John&amp;rsquo;s session was on helping IT architects understand one possible methodology of approaching infrastructure design, his session got me thinking about documenting IT systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #44</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #44, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles, links, ideas, and thoughts about various data center-related technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   One of the original problems with the VXLAN IETF specification was that it (deliberately) didn&amp;rsquo;t include any control plane information; as a result, the process of mapping MAC addresses to VTEPs (VXLAN Tunnel Endpoints) wasn&amp;rsquo;t defined, and the early implementations relied on multicast to handle this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #43</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/08/technology-short-take-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/08/technology-short-take-43/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #43, another episode in my irregularly-published series of articles, links, and thoughts from around the web, focusing on data center technologies like networking, virtualization, storage, and cloud computing. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful.
Networking   Jason Edelman recently took a look at Docker networking. While Docker is receiving a great deal of attention, I have to say that I feel Docker networking is a key area that hasn&amp;rsquo;t received the amount of attention that it probably needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #42</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #42, another installation in my ongoing series of irregularly published collections of news, items, thoughts, rants, raves, and tidbits from around the Internet, with a focus on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s series on VMware NSX continues with part 5.
  Aaron Rosen, a Neutron contributor, recently published a post about a Neutron extension called Allowed-Address-Pairs and how you can use it to create high availability instances using VRRP (via keepalived).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #41, the latest in my series of random thoughts, articles, and links from around the Internet. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) is a networking topic that is starting to get more and more attention (some may equate &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;hype&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to draw your own conclusion there). In any case, I liked how this article really hit upon what I personally feel is something many people are overlooking in NFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #38</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 09:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #38, another installment in my irregularly-published series that collects links and thoughts on data center-related technologies from around the web. But enough with the introduction, let&amp;rsquo;s get on to the content already!
Networking   Jason Edelman does some experimenting with the Python APIs on a Cisco Nexus 3000. In the process, he muses about the value of configuration management tool chains such as Chef and Puppet in a world of &amp;ldquo;open switch&amp;rdquo; platforms such as Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2013 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/03/looking-back-2013-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/03/looking-back-2013-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing my annual &amp;ldquo;projects list&amp;rdquo; and then grading myself on the progress (or lack thereof) on the projects at the end of the year. For example, I shared my 2012 project list in early January 2012, then gave myself grades on my progress in early January 2013.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to grade myself on my 2013 project list. Here&amp;rsquo;s the project list I posted just under a year ago:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Open vSwitch with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to manage Open vSwitch (OVS) using the popular open source configuration management tool Puppet. This is not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this topic; in the past I showed you how to automate OVS configuration with Puppet via a hack utilizing some RHEL-OVS integrations. This post, however, focuses on the use of an actual Puppet module that will manage the configuration of OVS, a much cleaner solution&amp;mdash;in my view, at least&amp;mdash;than leveraging the file-based integrations I discussed earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Ubuntu Cloud Archive Support with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/17/updating-ubuntu-cloud-archive-support-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/17/updating-ubuntu-cloud-archive-support-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago, I showed you how to use Puppet to add Ubuntu Cloud Archive support to your Ubuntu installation. Since that time, OpenStack has had a new release (the Havana release) and the Ubuntu Cloud Archive repository has been updated with new packages to support the Havana release. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you an updated snippet of code to take advantage of these newer packages in the Ubuntu Cloud Archive repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #36</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/23/technology-short-take-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/23/technology-short-take-36/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #36. In this episode, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a variety of links from around the web, along with some random thoughts and ideas along the way. I try to keep things related to the key technology areas you&amp;rsquo;ll see in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers, though I do stray from time to time. In any case, enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;bring on the content! I hope you find something useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
