<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 16:18:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/privacy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Markdown Files in BoxCryptor on iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago, I published an article showing you how to use EncFS and BoxCryptor to provide client-side encryption of Dropbox data. After working with this configuration for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve run across a problem (at least, a problem for me&amp;mdash;it might not be a problem for you). The problem lies on the iPad end of things.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the earlier post, the basic gist of the idea is to use EncFS&amp;mdash;an open source encrypting file system&amp;mdash;and OSXFUSE to provide file-level encryption of Dropbox data on your OS X system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Matter of Privacy, Not Security</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/05/its-a-matter-of-privacy-not-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2006 14:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/05/its-a-matter-of-privacy-not-security/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Jalkut, in his Red Sweater Blog, recently posted that he had detected (via Little Snitch) some network activity from Dashboard back to Apple&amp;rsquo;s web site. Upon further investigation, he found that the activity was apparently tied to this one-line entry in the release notes for 10.4.7:
 You can now verify whether or not a Dashboard widget you downloaded is the same version as a widget featured on (www.apple.com) before installing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on Microsoft&#39;s Calling Home Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/14/more-on-microsofts-calling-home-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2006 15:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/14/more-on-microsofts-calling-home-problem/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a short while ago about the fact that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows Genuine Advantage tool is phoning home on a regular basis (daily, in fact). This issue has garnered more attention over the last week or so, and very smart people are tackling the issue.
These two articles, Big Brother Microsoft and Big Brother Microsoft is Snooper Than I Thought, were written following my original posting and include more information about the information disclosed to Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Phones Home</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/08/windows-phones-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2006 22:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/08/windows-phones-home/</guid>
      <description>As if Microsoft didn&amp;rsquo;t have a reputation that wasn&amp;rsquo;t already bad enough, now comes the news that their anti-piracy initiative&amp;mdash;Windows Genuine Advantage&amp;mdash;is &amp;ldquo;phoning home&amp;rdquo; to Microsoft every day.
According to this article, Microsoft has acknowledged that the Windows Genuine Advantage tool, installed automatically by Windows Update in order to &amp;ldquo;verify&amp;rdquo; the authenticity of the installed copy of Windows, makes contact with servers at Microsoft daily. Supposedly this is to see if it should continue to run, but it also turns out that Microsoft may be updating the list of &amp;ldquo;invalid&amp;rdquo; Windows product keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s This All About, Anyway?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/20/whats-this-all-about-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 11:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/20/whats-this-all-about-anyway/</guid>
      <description>Is it just me, or is anyone else bothered by the recent stories of MSN and Yahoo turning over customers&amp;rsquo; search terms to the Federal government? Apparently, the same request was made to Google as well, and Google is battling the request.
Supposedly, the data being requested by the government is intended to be used as evidence in a trial that could revive a child privacy law intended to protect children online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Viewpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/10/06/an-interesting-viewpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 12:27:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/10/06/an-interesting-viewpoint/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I necessarily agree with his viewpoint, but in &amp;ldquo;A fake freedom&amp;rdquo;, the question is raised: Do we really own our data?
Are the pictures uploaded to Flickr still yours? What about the bookmarks you&amp;rsquo;ve posted on del.icio.us? Or the weblog entries on a free weblog service such as Blogger? You think so? Says who?
Truly paranoid people could be worried that these services might maintain copies of their information, even after the user has requested that they be deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
