<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2014 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2014 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:36:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2014/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2014 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/26/vmworld-2014-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 11:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/26/vmworld-2014-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a semi-liveblog of the day 2 keynote at VMworld 2014 in San Francisco.
Ben Fathi, CTO of VMware, takes the stage to start the keynote, and goes through a recap of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s announcements: EVO and EVO:RAIL, vCloud Air rebranding and the availability of new services, VMware Integrated OpenStack (VIO), and new product versions (vCloud Suite 5.8, betas of vSphere and VSAN).
Fathi re-emphasizes that VMware&amp;rsquo;s SDDC vision is an architecture, one built on the &amp;ldquo;power of AND.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2014 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/25/vmworld-2014-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 11:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/25/vmworld-2014-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 1 keynote at VMworld 2014 in San Francisco, CA. (Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;semi-liveblog&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll post this immediately after the keynote session wraps up.) As in previous years, the keynote is being held in the massive space in Moscone North, and this year&amp;mdash;like previous years&amp;mdash;it looks like there is quite a crowd gathered here this morning. I have the privilege of sitting with newly-minted VCDX-NVs and other VCDXes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2014 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/15/vmworld-2014-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/15/vmworld-2014-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned this on Twitter a few days ago, but wanted to go ahead and formalize some of the details. A blog reader/Twitter follower contacted me with the idea of getting together briefly at VMworld 2014 for some prayer time. I thought it was a great idea (thanks David!), so here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer
Where: Yerba Buena Gardens, behind Moscone North
When: Monday 8/25 through Wednesday 8/27 at 7:45am (this should give everyone enough time to grab breakfast before the keynotes start at 9am)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at VMworld 2014</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/04/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2014-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/04/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2014-2/</guid>
      <description>Many of you know that my wife, Crystal, has been organizing activities&amp;mdash;aka Spousetivities&amp;mdash;at VMworld since 2008. This year is no different, and registration is already open for activities at VMworld US 2014 in San Francisco. This year Crystal has another great set of activities planned, including:
  The usual &amp;ldquo;Getting to Know You&amp;rdquo; breakfast, held again this year at Jillian&amp;rsquo;s
  Mission Street food tour
  Whale watching tour</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving Back to the Community</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/28/giving-back-to-the-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/28/giving-back-to-the-community/</guid>
      <description>(This is a repost of an announcement from the Spousetivities web site. I wanted to include it here for broader coverage. &amp;ndash;Scott)
For seven years, Spousetivities has been fortunate to be part of the VMware/VMworld community. Since 2008, we&amp;rsquo;ve been the only community-focused and community-driven spouse activities program, and it&amp;rsquo;s been an honor. Spousetivities exists thanks to the support of the community. However, Spousetivities also exists to provide support back to that same community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at VMworld 2014</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/21/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:11:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/21/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2014/</guid>
      <description>Long-time readers know that since VMworld 2008 in Las Vegas, my wife Crystal has been organizing spouse activities&amp;mdash;aka &amp;ldquo;Spousetivities&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;for spouses, partners, family members, and friends traveling with VMworld conference attendees. This is a true labor of love for Crystal; she works tirelessly to gather sponsors, organize activities, and handle the logistics for the events. Although registration is opening a bit later than usual this year (Crystal&amp;rsquo;s been sick and in the hospital recently), registration for Spousetivities at VMworld 2014 in San Francisco is now open.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
