<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LISP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/lisp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LISP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/lisp/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examining Some Networking-Virtualization Chimeras</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</guid>
      <description>I like to spend time examining the areas where different groups of technologies intersect. Personally, I find this activity fascinating, and perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the reason that I find myself pursing knowledge and experience in virtualization, networking, storage, and other areas simultaneously&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s an effort to spend more time &amp;ldquo;on the border&amp;rdquo; between various technologies.
One border, in particular, is very interesting to me: the border between virtualization and networking. Time spent thinking about the border between networking and virtualization is what has generated posts like this one, this one, or this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #15</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #15, the latest in my irregular series of posts on various articles and links on networking, servers, storage, and virtualization&amp;mdash;everything a growing data center engineer needs!
Networking My thoughts this time around are pretty heavily focused on VXLAN, which continues to get lots of attention. I talked about posting a dissection of VXLAN, but I have failed miserably; fortunately, other people smarter than me have stepped up to the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
