<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vista on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vista/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vista on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 14:43:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vista/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Something About This Just Doesn&#39;t Seem Right</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/01/something-about-this-just-doesnt-seem-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2007 14:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/01/something-about-this-just-doesnt-seem-right/</guid>
      <description>First, let&amp;rsquo;s set the stage. I first became aware of this issue&amp;mdash;network slowdowns when playing multimedia files in Microsoft Windows Vista&amp;mdash;when this article by Adrian Kingsley-Hughes at ZDNet popped up in one of my NetNewsWire subscriptions. I read the article and found that I was apparently coming in on the middle of an ongoing story, so I read Mark Russinovich&amp;rsquo;s response to the slowdowns with Vista. As usual, Mark&amp;rsquo;s work was concise, clear, very informative, and well-written.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return of the Old Microsoft</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/27/return-of-the-old-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2007 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/27/return-of-the-old-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft just can&amp;rsquo;t seem to shake off the perception in the industry that it will do whatever it takes to kill the competition, even if that includes unfairly leveraging a monopoly on the desktop OS market&amp;mdash;an act which is criminal in nature and violates US anti-trust laws. It was those laws that landed Microsoft in trouble for bundling Internet Explorer with Windows in an effort to kill Netscape. (I&amp;rsquo;ll leave for another day the discussion of what is right and wrong for a company to do in a competitive marketplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Defections</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/19/windows-defections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2007 20:57:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/19/windows-defections/</guid>
      <description>As expected, there are lots of comparisons between Mac OS X and Windows Vista. This relatively recent article by Network Computing takes the two operating systems head-to-head; in most areas, Mac OS X takes the win. These comparisons are fully to be expected, and I imagine there are as many pundits, experts, and analysts that claim Windows Vista is the best as there are that claim Mac OS X is the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancel or Allow?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/08/cancel-or-allow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2007 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/08/cancel-or-allow/</guid>
      <description>I know that no operating system is perfect, that every operating system and application has its security flaws, and that no vendor should be casting stones at another&amp;mdash;you know, that whole &amp;ldquo;people who live in glass houses shouldn&amp;rsquo;t throw rocks&amp;rdquo; thing.
Now, having said all that&amp;hellip;this is just plain funny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows and OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/25/windows-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 11:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/25/windows-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of industry pundits out there proclaiming that the introduction of Boot Camp&amp;mdash;Apple&amp;rsquo;s new beta application that simplifies and streamlines the installation of Windows XP (and presumably Windows Vista as well) on Intel-based Macs&amp;mdash;is simply the first step in a complex scheme that will eventually culminate in something much bigger. I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure about that.
The predictions range the whole gamut of possibilities. Some are predicting that Apple will begin reselling Windows XP pre-loaded on its Intel-based Macs, much in the way that MacMall is now doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vista Failures</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/21/vista-failures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 13:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/21/vista-failures/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll have to say, this one came as a bit of a surprise to me. Paul Thurrott, maintainer of the WinSuperSite and a longtime reporter of Microsoft and Windows (he&amp;rsquo;s the author of the WinInfo UPDATE newsletter that&amp;rsquo;s been out for years and years) has published an review of Windows Vista that outlines some of Vista&amp;rsquo;s significant failures. He speaks honestly about Vista and how it will not meet the expectations that Microsoft is setting for the product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even Microsoft Knows It</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/04/even-microsoft-knows-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 16:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/04/even-microsoft-knows-it/</guid>
      <description>I hope Microsoft Vista is going to address the malware problem that is plaguing Windows users worldwide right now. Even Microsoft knows it&amp;rsquo;s bad. How bad? Read on.
In this article from eWeek, Mike Danseglio, a program manager in the Security Solutions group at Microsoft, is quoted as saying:
 &amp;ldquo;When you are dealing with rootkits and some advanced spyware programs, the only solution is to rebuild from scratch. In some cases, there really is no way to recover without nuking the systems from orbit&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Innovation Equal Increased Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/21/does-innovation-equal-increased-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 19:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/21/does-innovation-equal-increased-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Paul Thurrott, a longtime reporter on Microsoft and its products, wrote today in &amp;ldquo;Windows IT Pro UPDATE&amp;rdquo; (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link to the article online) that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s innovation in their upcoming products, Windows Vista and Office 2007, will lead to a decrease in productivity, not an increase.
The basis for his argument (a position with which I agree, personally) is that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s innovation in both Windows Vista and Office 2007 will cause confusion and disorientation for experienced users in an effort to actually make things easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vista on Intel-Based Macs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/13/vista-on-intel-based-macs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 10:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/13/vista-on-intel-based-macs/</guid>
      <description>Apparently, there are some rather heated arguments occurring in certain circles about the inability to boot Microsoft Windows Vista on the new Intel-based Macs (as a side note, I seriously do not like the term &amp;ldquo;Mactel,&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;ll instead be referring to them as &amp;ldquo;Intel-based Macs&amp;rdquo;). While I can see both sides of the debate, I personally feel that holding Apple to blame for not being able to run Windows is a bit of a stretch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
