<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2009 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2009/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2009 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 14:38:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2009/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Out Some VMworld Info</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/07/cleaning-out-some-vmworld-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 14:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/07/cleaning-out-some-vmworld-info/</guid>
      <description>VMworld is always a very busy time of year. Press releases, product announcements, new product or technology releases, companies emerging from stealth mode&amp;mdash;it all happens around VMworld. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m back home again from VMworld, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d clear out my Inbox from all the various VMworld-related news items. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ll find something interesting or useful here!
VMware and HP Unveil Solution to Simplify Datacenter Management
World&amp;rsquo;s Leading Service Providers Build New Cloud Services on the VMware Platform</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA2384 - Deploying the Nexus 1000V</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/ta2384-deploying-the-nexus-1000v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 20:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/ta2384-deploying-the-nexus-1000v/</guid>
      <description>There is no Internet connectivity in this session, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to publish this after the session has concluded.
The Cisco Nexus 1000V is, of course, a Layer 2 distributed virtual switch for VMware vSphere built on Cisco NX-OS (the same operating system that drives the physical Nexus switches). It&amp;rsquo;s compatible with all switching platforms, meaning that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require physical Nexus switches upstream in order to work. The Nexus 1000V brings policy-based VM connectivity, network and security property mobility, and a non-disruptive operational model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Additional VMworld Vendor Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/some-additional-vmworld-vendor-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 17:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/some-additional-vmworld-vendor-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Earlier I posted some notes on meetings I&amp;rsquo;d had with Virsto and Xangati. In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss some additional meetings I&amp;rsquo;ve had with Virtual Instruments and Tranxition.
Virtual Instruments Virtual Instruments makes a solution that is intended to help troubleshoot and optimize storage environments. I had the opportunity to grab some coffee with them this morning and hear about what they&amp;rsquo;re doing and how they&amp;rsquo;re doing it. As a company carved out of Finisar and taken private, their goal is to help drive higher levels of virtualization by providing more visibility into the storage fabric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Some VMworld Vendor Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/notes-on-some-vmworld-vendor-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 13:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/notes-on-some-vmworld-vendor-meetings/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to speak with a few different vendors over the last couple of days here in San Francisco at VMworld 2009. Here are some notes on my meetings.
Virsto My first meeting of the week was with Virsto, a early storage startup (they just closed Series A funding in the last few weeks). Virsto is led by some long-time storage professionals from companies such as StorageTek, Veritas, and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/vmworld-2009-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 11:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/02/vmworld-2009-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>The day 2 keynote starts with another entertaining video.
After the video concludes, Steve Herrod, VMware&amp;rsquo;s CTO, takes the stage. He echoes that virtualization is a &amp;ldquo;tectonic shift&amp;rdquo; in the IT industry. Herrod again shows the three pillars&amp;mdash;VMware vSphere, VMware View, and VMware vCenter. Herrod&amp;rsquo;s initial focus is on VMware View, due to the increased emphasis on desktop virtualization and the focus VMware is providing in that arena.
VMware vSphere provides the foundation for desktop virtualization and is the best platform for desktop virtualization due to commonality, security, availability, and efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC3209 and DV2484</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/bc3209-and-dv2484/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 19:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/bc3209-and-dv2484/</guid>
      <description>I had on my schedule for today two sessions, BC3209 and DV2484. BC3209 was titled &amp;ldquo;Creating the Fastest Possible Backups Using VMware Consolidated Backup - A Design Blueprint&amp;rdquo;; DV2484 was titled &amp;ldquo;Server and Storage Sizing for VMware View&amp;rdquo;. You might be wondering why I haven&amp;rsquo;t published summaries of either of these two sessions.
I skipped out on BC3209 to attend the vCloud event with Paul Maritz, which&amp;mdash;unfortunately&amp;mdash;turned out to be a complete non-event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vCloud Event with Paul Maritz</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmware-vcloud-event-with-paul-maritz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 17:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmware-vcloud-event-with-paul-maritz/</guid>
      <description>This special event with Paul Maritz around VMware&amp;rsquo;s vCloud initiative took place back in the same general hall as the morning keynote. The subject of this special meeting is VMware&amp;rsquo;s cloud offerings.
VMware&amp;rsquo;s strategy has three legs: choice, application compatibility, and something else that I didn&amp;rsquo;t stay long enough to find out.
With regard to choice, VMware now has over 1,000 service providers that provide VMware-ready cloud services. Examples include services from AT&amp;amp;T and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC1500 - Site Recovery Manager Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/bc1500-site-recovery-manager-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 13:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/bc1500-site-recovery-manager-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>I arrived at this session a few minutes late because the VMworld 2009 Day 1 keynote was running late. The early part of the session was pretty straightforward with information on the various SRM components: multiple vCenter Server instances, SRM servers, storage replication, SRAs, etc., so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother recreating this here. Most people are already familiar with the basics of SRM.
The technology preview of SRM (the beta of the next version) does support vCenter Server linked mode, which means that your two vCenter Server instances can run in a linked mode group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Day 0 Wrap-Up and Links</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmworld-day-0-wrap-up-and-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 12:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmworld-day-0-wrap-up-and-links/</guid>
      <description>Today was a crazy day. I started the day with the second day of the Partner Technical Advisory Board (PTAB) meeting.
Of course, VMware released a bevy of press releases this morning, and being stuck in the PTAB meeting I haven&amp;rsquo;t really even had the chance to digest the news announcements. The announcements included:
Next-Generation VMware Partner Network Helps Partners Increase Virtualization Expertise to Expand Business Opportunities
VMware Ushers in a New Era of IT Management to Drive Business Agility with VMware vCenter Product Family</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmworld-2009-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 11:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/01/vmworld-2009-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>(Note: You can also follow my Twitter updates here.)
I start out the Day 1 keynote at VMworld 2009 at the bloggers&amp;rsquo; table, sitting with folks like Rodney Haywood, Mike Laverick, Alessandro Perilli, Rich Brambley, Thomas Bryant, Bob Plankers, and&amp;mdash;of course&amp;mdash;the ever-present John Troyer. There should be some good coverage of the event. Later today, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post with links to the coverage from some of the other bloggers here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VMworld 2009 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/23/my-vmworld-2009-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2009 22:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/23/my-vmworld-2009-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Well, VMworld 2009 is nearly upon us. Like thousands of others, I&amp;rsquo;ll be there next week attending sessions, meeting with vendors, networking with other virtualization professionals, and&amp;mdash;of course&amp;mdash;covering all of it right here on my blog. So, if you aren&amp;rsquo;t able to make it next week, stay tuned here for my coverage of the conference. And, to give you a feel of what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing and what sessions I&amp;rsquo;m planning on attending, here&amp;rsquo;s my VMworld 2009 conference schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Spouse Activities FAQs and Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities-faqs-and-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 12:33:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities-faqs-and-updates/</guid>
      <description>Wow! The response to the spouse activities that my wife, Crystal (@crystal_lowe on Twitter) is organizing has been phenomenal. Almost overwhelming, in fact. (You have to keep in mind that she&amp;rsquo;s not getting paid to do this&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s all volunteer work.)
With now only a week or so before the conference starts, here&amp;rsquo;s the latest update on spouse activities. Be sure to refer to this post for more details on the schedule of activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Ask the Experts Session: Call For Questions!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/04/vmworld-2009-ask-the-experts-session-call-for-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 22:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/04/vmworld-2009-ask-the-experts-session-call-for-questions/</guid>
      <description>VMworld 2009 is rapidly approaching, and along with it are coming the deadlines for us to submit our final presentation for TA2259, Ask The Experts on virtualization design. As you probably already know, this is a joint session with Rick Scherer, Chad Sakac, Duncan Epping, Tom Howarth, and me. TA2259 is scheduled for Thursday, September 3, at 1PM in the afternoon. Now that Schedule Builder is live, you can go register for the session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Spouse Activities Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/29/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 12:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/29/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities-update/</guid>
      <description>Last year, after attending VMworld with me for the previous two years, my wife Crystal (@crystal_lowe on Twitter) decided to organize some activities for spouses traveling to VMworld 2008. This year she&amp;rsquo;s volunteered to do it again! If you&amp;rsquo;re planning on bringing your spouse&amp;mdash;or if you are a spouse traveling to San Francisco while your significant other will be attending VMworld 2009&amp;ndash;you definitely want to look into joining Crystal for these activities!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Forget to Submit Your Question!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/27/dont-forget-to-submit-your-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 20:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/27/dont-forget-to-submit-your-question/</guid>
      <description>Time is running out! As most of you already know, I&amp;mdash;along with Chad Sakac, Duncan Epping, Tom Howarth, and Rick Scherer&amp;ndash;will be speaking at VMworld 2009 at TA2259, Ask the Experts.
One of things we wanted to do was to poll the VMware community ahead of time for questions that you wanted to include as part of the discussion, in addition to the questions raised by the audience. If you have a question you&amp;rsquo;d like to submit, time is running out!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
