<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LXC on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/lxc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in LXC on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/lxc/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #76</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #76, the first Technology Short Take of 2017. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but due to extenuating circumstances (my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow) I&amp;rsquo;m posting it today. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking  As of Vagrant 1.9.1, the Cumulus plugin for Vagrant is no longer needed. See this post for more details. Ivan Pepelnjak (one of my absolutely favorite folks in the IT industry) has a great post on using regex filters in Ansible to parse text printouts from network devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #64</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #64. Normally, I try to publish Short Takes on Friday, but this past Friday was April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day. Given the propensity for &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; information to get lost among all the pranks, I decided to push this article back to today. Unlike most of what is published around April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day, hopefully everything here is helpful, informative, and useful!
Networking  Phil Gervasi has an article on fate sharing in the network core, where he discusses some of the advantages&amp;mdash;and disadvantages&amp;mdash;of centralizing the control plane in network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Containers, Virtualization, and Interop</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/17/technology-advice-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/17/technology-advice-podcast/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I had the pleasure of attending and speaking at Interop for the very first time. (I did some liveblogging while I was there; here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the liveblogs published from last year&amp;rsquo;s Interop.) Fortunately, I was invited back again this year (very excited about that!), and as a returning speaker I recently had the opportunity to do a podcast with Technology Advice about SDN, virtualization, containers, and Interop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #60</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #60. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered what I hope to be a useful but varied collection of articles and links on key data center technologies. I hope something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be helpful&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking  The rise of Linux in importance in the networking industry continues, with Arista announcing enhancements to Arista EOS to support&amp;mdash;among other things&amp;mdash;Docker containers. (See this SDx Central article or this Network World article for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Introduction to LXD</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/06/quick-intro-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2015 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/06/quick-intro-lxd/</guid>
      <description>With the recent release of Ubuntu 15.04, aka &amp;ldquo;Vivid Vervet&amp;rdquo;, the Ubuntu community has also unveiled an early release of LXD (pronounced &amp;ldquo;lex-dee&amp;rdquo;), a new project aimed at revitalizing the use of LXC and LXC-based containers in the face of application container efforts such as Docker and rkt. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a quick introduction to LXD.
To make it easier to follow along with some of the examples of using LXD, I&amp;rsquo;ve created an lxd directory in my GitHub &amp;ldquo;learning-tools&amp;rdquo; repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Making Its Move</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/docker-making-its-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/docker-making-its-move/</guid>
      <description>Today marked the start of Dockercon, and Docker, Inc., the commercial entity behind the incredibly popular open source Docker project, is taking this opportunity to make its move. Already the focus of quite a bit of attention (some might say a disproportionate amount of attention), Docker is making several announcements today that indicate an intent to broaden its reach:
  Docker (also referred to as Docker Engine) 1.0 is released today, signaling the project&amp;rsquo;s readiness to be officially used in production environments (although many firms were/are already using pre-1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Introduction to Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/11/a-quick-introduction-to-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/03/11/a-quick-introduction-to-docker/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following trends in the &amp;ldquo;cloud&amp;rdquo; world, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of Docker. In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a quick introduction to Docker, which might be helpful if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what Docker is and why it&amp;rsquo;s garnered so much attention.
The best way to describe Docker is to use the phrase from the Docker web site&amp;mdash;Docker is &amp;ldquo;an open source project to pack, ship and run any application as a lightweight container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically Connecting LXC to Open vSwitch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/23/automatically-connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/23/automatically-connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously discussed using Open vSwitch (OVS) with Linux Containers (LXC) in a couple of previous posts (here and here). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you one way to have your containers automatically connected to OVS on startup without having to use libvirt.
I tested this configuration using Ubuntu 12.04 with the Linux 3.8.0 kernel and an alpha release of LXC 1.0.0 from the precise-backports repository. The version of LXC in the 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Open vSwitch with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/18/managing-open-vswitch-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to manage Open vSwitch (OVS) using the popular open source configuration management tool Puppet. This is not the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve written about this topic; in the past I showed you how to automate OVS configuration with Puppet via a hack utilizing some RHEL-OVS integrations. This post, however, focuses on the use of an actual Puppet module that will manage the configuration of OVS, a much cleaner solution&amp;mdash;in my view, at least&amp;mdash;than leveraging the file-based integrations I discussed earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting LXC to Open vSwitch Using Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/03/connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch-using-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/03/connecting-lxc-to-open-vswitch-using-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to expand a little bit on using libvirt to connect Linux containers (created using LXC) to Open vSwitch (OVS). I made brief mention of this in my post on using LXC with libvirt, but did not provide any details. This post aims to provide those details.
I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with LXC, OVS, and libvirt. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with these projects, I suggest you have a look back at other articles I&amp;rsquo;ve written about them in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Bare Metal Workloads Using GRE Tunnels and OVS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/connecting-bare-metal-workloads-using-gre-tunnels-and-ovs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/connecting-bare-metal-workloads-using-gre-tunnels-and-ovs/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how you could use Open vSwitch (OVS) and GRE tunnels to connect bare metal workloads. While OVS is typically used in conjunction with a hypervisor such as KVM or Xen, you&amp;rsquo;re certainly not restricted to only using it on hypervisors. Similarly, while GRE tunnels are commonly used to connect VMs or containers, you&amp;rsquo;re definitely not restricted from using them with bare metal workloads as well. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore how you would go about connecting bare metal workloads over GRE tunnels managed by OVS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Containers via LXC and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/27/linux-containers-via-lxc-and-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/27/linux-containers-via-lxc-and-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things about libvirt is the ability to work with multiple hypervisors and virtualization technologies, including Linux containers using LXC. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use libvirt with LXC, including leveraging libvirt to help automate attaching containers to Open vSwitch (OVS).
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Linux containers and LXC, I invite you to have a look at my introductory post on Linux containers and LXC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXC, Open vSwitch, and GRE Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/26/lxc-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/26/lxc-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>This post will show you how to use Open vSwitch (OVS) to connect LXC containers on different hosts together using GRE tunnels. This process is quite similar to using OVS and GRE tunnels to connect VMs, and even has some similarity to connecting network namespaces over a GRE tunnel.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with LXC, my introductory post on LXC might be useful. I also found this post on networking with LXC to be extremely helpful, as was this overview of LXC on Ubuntu 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Introduction to Linux Containers with LXC</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/25/a-brief-introduction-to-linux-containers-with-lxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/25/a-brief-introduction-to-linux-containers-with-lxc/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a brief introduction to working with Linux containers via LXC. Linux containers are getting a fair amount of attention these days (perhaps due to Docker, which leverages LXC on the back-end) as a lightweight alternative to full machine virtualization such as that provided by &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; hypervisors like KVM, Xen, or ESXi.
Both full machine virtualization and containers have their advantages and disadvantages. Full machine virtualization offers greater isolation at the cost of greater overhead, as each virtual machine runs its own full kernel and operating system instance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
