<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HyperV on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/hyperv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HyperV on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/hyperv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 144</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #144! I have a fairly diverse set of links for readers this time around, covering topics from microchips to improving your writing, with stops along the way in topics like Kubernetes, virtualization, Linux, and the popular JSON-parsing tool &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 120</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/11/22/technology-short-take-120/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/11/22/technology-short-take-120/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #120! Wow&amp;hellip;hard to believe it&amp;rsquo;s been almost two months since the last Tech Short Take. Sorry about that! Hopefully something I share here in this Tech Short Take is useful or helpful to readers. On to the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 113</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/03/technology-short-take-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/03/technology-short-take-113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #113! I hope the collection of links and articles I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered for you contains something useful for you. I think I have a pretty balanced collection this time around; there&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of something for almost everyone. Who says you can&amp;rsquo;t please everyone all the time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 111</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/01/technology-short-take-111/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/01/technology-short-take-111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #111! I&amp;rsquo;m a couple weeks late on this one; wanted to publish it earlier but work has been keeping me busy (lots and lots of interest in Kubernetes and cloud-native technologies out there!). In any event, here you are&amp;mdash;I hope you find something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 91</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/08/technology-short-take-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/08/technology-short-take-91/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 91! It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit longer than usual since the last Tech Short Take (partly due to the US Thanksgiving holiday, partly due to vacation time, and partly due to business travel), so apologies for that. Still, there&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of links and articles here for you, so dig in and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 89</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 89! I have a collection of newer materials and some older materials this time around, but hopefully all of them are still useful. (I needed to do some housekeeping on my Instapaper account, which is where I bookmark stuff that frequently lands here.) Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 82</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #82! This issue is a bit behind schedule; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty heads-down on some projects. That work will come to fruition in a couple weeks, so I should be able to come up for some air soon. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links and articles for your reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #79</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #79! There&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting links for you this time around.
Networking  I was sure I had mentioned Skydive before, but apparently not (a grep of all my blog posts found nothing), so let me rectify that first. Skydive is (in the project&amp;rsquo;s own words) an &amp;ldquo;open source real-time network topology and protocols analyzer.&amp;rdquo; The project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository is here, and documentation for Skydive is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #78</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #78! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of links and articles from around the Internet discussing various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  The rise of the disaggregated network operating system (NOS) marches on: this time, it&amp;rsquo;s Big Switch Networks announcing expanded hardware support in Open Network Linux (ONL), upon which its own NOS is based. The Pivotal Engineering blog has an article that shows how to use BOSH with the vSphere CPI to automate adding servers to an NSX load balancing pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #76</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #76, the first Technology Short Take of 2017. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but due to extenuating circumstances (my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow) I&amp;rsquo;m posting it today. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking  As of Vagrant 1.9.1, the Cumulus plugin for Vagrant is no longer needed. See this post for more details. Ivan Pepelnjak (one of my absolutely favorite folks in the IT industry) has a great post on using regex filters in Ansible to parse text printouts from network devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #71</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #71! As always, I have a list of links related to various data center technologies found below; hopefully something here proves useful.
Networking  Dmitri Kalintsev is back with another article in a series of articles on using hardware VXLAN tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) with VMware NSX. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s on validating HW VTEP deployment for integration with NSX. In particular, Dmitri points out that you need connectivity both on the management plane as well as on the data plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #67</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/03/technology-short-take-67/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #67. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping something I&amp;rsquo;ve collected for you here proves useful!
Networking  Anthony Burke has written a script that uses VMware NSX to protect VMware Log Insight instances. More information on the script is in his blog post. Russ White tackles the issue of networking engineers needing to learn to code. Is it necessary? Russ thinks so&amp;mdash;but probably not for the reasons you might think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #65</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #65! As usual, I gathered an odd collection of links and articles from around the web on key data center technologies and trends. I hope you find something useful!
Networking  Michael Ryom has a nice (but short) article on using Log Insight along with a NetFlow proxy to help provide more detailed visibility into traffic flows between VMs on NSX logical networks. Brent Salisbury has an article on GoBGP, a Go-based BGP implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #57</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/11/technology-short-take-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/11/technology-short-take-57/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #57. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking  Tor Anderson has an article on using IPv6 for network boot using UEFI and iPXE. Larry Smith Jr. has a great blog series going called &amp;ldquo;Hey, I can DevOps my Network too!&amp;rdquo; He started out with an intro post just to set the stage for the series, then had a post on the prep work required to get ready to proceed with the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #55</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/22/technology-short-take-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/22/technology-short-take-55/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #55! Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to find something of value and interest to you in this latest collection of links and articles from around the web on networking, storage, virtualization, security, and other data center-related technologies. Enjoy!
Networking  I recently came across Kuryr, an OpenStack project aimed at connecting Docker&amp;rsquo;s libnetwork efforts to OpenStack Neutron. The end result, as I understand it, would be to allow any Neutron plugin to be able to provide container networking functionality to Docker via libnetwork.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
