<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nexus on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nexus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nexus on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 11:47:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nexus/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recent Cisco Product Launch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/06/recent-cisco-product-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 11:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/06/recent-cisco-product-launch/</guid>
      <description>Cisco recently launched a number of new products and new versions of products aimed at showing Cisco&amp;rsquo;s dedication and innovation in network switching. You can get Cisco&amp;rsquo;s summary of the products here. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with the hardware-focused announcements.
Hardware-Focused Announcements Cisco&amp;rsquo;s announcements on the hardware side primarily centered around new switching capabilities in the form of 40/100 Gigabit Ethernet (GE) cards for both the Nexus 7000 series platform as well as a 40 GE card for the Catalyst 6500 series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 09:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #20, the latest collection of various data center-related links, articles, and thoughts. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking   For all the writing and thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve done on VXLAN (here, here, and here), someone (thanks Ed!) mentioned something to me recently that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even considered. (It&amp;rsquo;s so simple I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed that I overlooked it.) VXLAN uses UDP for its encapsulation. What about dropped packets, lack of sequencing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-2121: Virtual Device Context Design and Implementation Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/13/brkdct-2121-virtual-device-context-design-and-implementation-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 22:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/13/brkdct-2121-virtual-device-context-design-and-implementation-considerations/</guid>
      <description>I joined this session late (a last minute change from the UCS VM-FEX session). This session is on VDC design considerations with the Nexus 7000, presented by Ron Fuller, CCIE #5851 (@ccie5851 on Twitter).
A VDC (virtual device context) is a &amp;ldquo;superstructure&amp;rdquo; that encapsulates (or encompasses) both VLANs and VRFs. Each VDC maintains its own VLAN table and its own VRF instances. There are some resources that are global (not dedicated to a particular VDC); these would include things like a boot image configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Cisco Catalyst 2960-S to Nexus 5010</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/20/connecting-cisco-catalyst-2960-s-to-nexus-5010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/20/connecting-cisco-catalyst-2960-s-to-nexus-5010/</guid>
      <description>As part of the all-star team that is currently heads down in preparation for some cool stuff that will be at EMC World 2011 in just a couple of weeks, today I needed to connect a Cisco Catalyst 2960-S to a Nexus 5010 over a 10GbE connection. Simple enough, right? You would think so, but as it turns out there was a bit more involved than I suspected.
And it was simple, too&amp;mdash;configure each side as a VLAN trunk, make sure the port on each side is enabled (not administratively down), and plug in a Cisco-branded TwinAx cable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco&#39;s Data Center Launch</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/30/ciscos-data-center-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 23:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/30/ciscos-data-center-launch/</guid>
      <description>Cisco had a pretty major product/technology launch today. I was briefed on the product launch some time ago&amp;mdash;one of the perks of being a &amp;ldquo;leading blogger&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;and so it was great to see this stuff finally come to light. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to read some of the other blog posts on the topic (I know there have been several), so I apologize for any duplication.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick look at the &amp;ldquo;new product&amp;rdquo; news included in the launch:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #11</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 18:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/02/17/technology-short-take-11/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s right folks, it&amp;rsquo;s time for another installation of Technology Short Takes. This is Technology Short Take #11, and I hope that you find the collection of items I have for you this time around both useful and informative. But enough of the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get to the good stuff!
Networking   David Davis (of Train Signal) has a good write-up on the Petri IT Knowledgebase on using a network packet analyzer with VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #9</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 12:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/29/technology-short-take-9/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #9, the last Technology Short Take for 2010. In this Short Take, I have a collection of links and articles about networking, servers, storage, and virtualization. Of note this time around: some great DCI links, multi-hop FCoE finally arrives (sort of), a few XenServer/XenDesktop/XenApp links, and NTFS defragmentation in the virtualized data center. Here you go&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking   Brad Hedlund has a great post discussing Nexus 7000 connectivity options for Cisco UCS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #8</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/17/technology-short-take-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/17/technology-short-take-8/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #8, my latest collection of item from around the Internet pertaining to data center technologies such as virtualization, networking, storage, and servers. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   A couple weeks ago I wrote about how to connect a Nexus 2148T to a Nexus 5010. What I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually done yet is connect the Nexus 2148T to dual Nexus 5010 upstream switches using virtual port-channels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting a Nexus 2148 to a Nexus 5010</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/connecting-a-nexus-2148-to-a-nexus-5010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 23:35:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/connecting-a-nexus-2148-to-a-nexus-5010/</guid>
      <description>The Cisco Nexus 2000 series fabric extender (or &amp;ldquo;fex&amp;rdquo;) is an implementation of network interface virtualization. Because the Nexus 2000 fabric extender acts as a remote line card to the upstream IV-capable bridge (a Nexus 5000 series switch, typically), all the configuration takes place on the upstream bridge. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe how to connect a Nexus 2148T to a Nexus 5010. In reality, the process is incredibly simple and not really worthy of a blog post, but in the interest of completeness I&amp;rsquo;ll document it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAN Port Channels from Nexus 5010 to MDS 9134</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 09:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</guid>
      <description>As part of an ongoing effort to expand the functionality of the vSpecialist lab in the EMC RTP facility, we recently added a pair of Cisco MDS 9134 Fibre Channel switches. These Fibre Channel switches are connected to a pair of Cisco Nexus 5010 switches, which handle Unified Fabric connections from a collection of CNA-equipped servers. To connect the Nexus switches to the MDS switches, we used SAN port channels to bond multiple Fibre Channel interfaces together for both redundancy and increased aggregate throughput.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/28/technology-short-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2010 13:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/28/technology-short-take-2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #2, a collection of links, thoughts, ideas, and items pertaining to data center technologies&amp;mdash;virtualization, networking, storage, and security. I hope you find something useful or interesting!
  The release of FLARE 30 and DART 6 by EMC (formally announced last week) introduces some new concepts and new functionality. Matt Hensley recently did a write-up on some of the new functionality in this post on virtual provisioning, storage pools, and FLARE 30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure NPV on a Nexus 5000</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/28/how-to-configure-npv-on-a-nexus-5000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/28/how-to-configure-npv-on-a-nexus-5000/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I posted a &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; article on how to configure FCoE on a Nexus 5000 switch. At that time, I did not put the Nexus 5000 into NPV mode but rather connected it to a Cisco MDS Fibre Channel switch without using NPV. In this entry, I&amp;rsquo;d like to follow up on that article and show you how to configure NPV on a Nexus 5000.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with NPV (N_Port Virtualization) and how it&amp;rsquo;s different than NPIV (N_Port ID Virtualization), check out this article titled &amp;ldquo;Understanding NPIV and NPV&amp;rdquo;; It should help clear things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/18/virtualization-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/18/virtualization-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 40th post in the Virtualization Short Take series, where I share with you various virtualization-related links, thoughts, and news tidbits. (Occasionally, I throw in some stuff that&amp;rsquo;s not virtualization related just to see if you are paying attention.) Enjoy!
  There have been a couple of posts now discussing Storage IO Control, a new feature that is possibly slated for inclusion in a future release of VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Look at VPLEX and VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 15:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/17/a-quick-look-at-vplex-and-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>The announcement of VPLEX last week at EMC World 2010 in Boston has introduced lots of new possibilities in how virtualized data centers should be designed and deployed. Of particular interest to a number of people is how VPLEX interacts with VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM).
Jason Nash of Varrow mulls over VPLEX and VMware SRM in this post, where he asks if VMware SRM is even necessary:
 If money was no object, or if you needed VPLEX anyway, where does that leave VMwares Site Recovery Manager?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: What is multi-hop FCoE?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/21/thinking-out-loud-what-is-multi-hop-fcoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 09:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/21/thinking-out-loud-what-is-multi-hop-fcoe/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last posted a &amp;ldquo;Thinking Out Loud&amp;rdquo; post, but a Twitter discussion this morning prompted me to post this one. Last night, I posted a question to Brad Hedlund (@bradhedlund on Twitter and a great data center networking resource) regarding the Nexus 2232PP fabric extender. My tweet to Brad was this: does the Nexus 2232PP make &amp;ldquo;multi-hop FCoE&amp;rdquo; possible via NIV?
(If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already read my post on the relationship between FCoE and NIV, go read it now as it provides a good background and context for this discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
