<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/travel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Closing out the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019, I announced that I would be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;temporarily relocating to Tokyo for a six-month assignment&lt;/a&gt; to build out a team focused on cloud-native services and offerings. A few months later, I was still in Colorado, and I explained what was happening in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/&#34;&gt;a status update on the Tokyo assignment&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few folks ask me about it, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and share that the Tokyo assignment did not happen and will not happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 15:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right at the end of 2019 I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that in early 2020 I was temporarily relocating to Tokyo, Japan, for a six month work assignment. It&amp;rsquo;s now March, and I&amp;rsquo;m still in Colorado. So what&amp;rsquo;s up with that Tokyo assignment, anyway? Since I&amp;rsquo;ve had several folks ask, I figured it&amp;rsquo;s probably best to post something here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the build-up and jump straight to the whole point of this post: a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity has come up and I&amp;rsquo;m embarking on a new adventure starting in early 2020. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not changing jobs&amp;hellip;but I am changing time zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on VPNs for Road Warriors</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/28/thoughts-on-vpns-for-road-warriors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/28/thoughts-on-vpns-for-road-warriors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I was talking with a few folks on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and the topic of using VPNs while traveling came up. For those that travel regularly, using a VPN to bypass traffic restrictions is not uncommon. Prompted by my former manager &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/martin_casado/&#34;&gt;Martin Casado&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I might share a few thoughts on VPN options for road warriors. This is by no means a comprehensive list, but hopefully something I share here will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming VMUG Events</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/11/upcoming-vmug-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/11/upcoming-vmug-events/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m extremely honored to have the opportunity to help support VMware User Group (VMUG) meetings all over the world. I will be speaking at a few upcoming events; if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be at one of these events, I&amp;rsquo;d love to meet you, say hi, and chat for a bit. Here are the details.
Tuesday, February 23, 2016
I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to be back in Sydney again for an opportunity to speak at the Sydney VMUG UserCon (see the event page for full details).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timbuk2 Commute Messenger Bag, Two Months Later</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/31/timbuk2-commute-messenger-bag-two-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/31/timbuk2-commute-messenger-bag-two-months-later/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my thoughts on the Timbuk2 Commute messenger bag. It was about two months ago that I tweeted that I bought a new bag:
 @scott_lowe: I picked up a new @timbuk2 messenger bag yesterday. Looking forward to seeing how well it works on my next business trip.
 The bag I ended up purchasing was the Timbuk2 Commute in black. Since I bought it in early September (just after returning from San Francisco for VMworld), I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled with it to various points in the US, to Canada, and most recently to Barcelona for VMworld EMEA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Move to Colorado: Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/07/the-move-to-colorado-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 09:19:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/07/the-move-to-colorado-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 of our road trip to Colorado completes our trip and puts us in Denver. The trip today was pretty straightforward. We left Kansas City this morning and just followed I-70 across Kansas into Colorado. When it was all said and done, it took about 9 hours of driving to go from Kansas City to Denver.
Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve arrived in Denver, we&amp;rsquo;re in a hotel for the next few days until our house in Castle Pines North is ready for us to move in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Move to Colorado: Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/05/the-move-to-colorado-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 22:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/05/the-move-to-colorado-day-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just wrapped up Day 2 of my road trip to Colorado. I started the day in Nashville, TN and ended the day in Kansas City, KS (actually Overland Park). If I had two words to describe today, those words would be windy and corn.
Why those two words? Well, if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever driven across Missouri, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand why I chose &amp;ldquo;corn&amp;rdquo; because you&amp;rsquo;ve already seen the fields upon fields of corn, as far as the eye can see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Move to Colorado: Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/05/the-move-to-colorado-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 09:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/05/the-move-to-colorado-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The move to Colorado has begun. I&amp;rsquo;m typing this from a hotel in Nashville, TN, where we wrapped up our day 1 travel just a short while ago. We&amp;rsquo;ll be here only one night, leaving in the morning to get to Kansas City for our second night.
The last few days have been a whirlwind. Crystal and I got home from VMworld 2011 on Friday night; Saturday we jumped in with both feet on getting our Chevy Suburban (nicknamed &amp;ldquo;Big Red&amp;rdquo; because it&amp;rsquo;s a big red Suburban; I&amp;rsquo;ll post a picture at some point) packed and ready for the trip to Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time for a Fresh Start</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/19/time-for-a-fresh-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/19/time-for-a-fresh-start/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll bet that when you saw the title for this post, your first thought was that I was leaving EMC and starting a new job with a new employer. C&amp;rsquo;mon, admit it! No, I&amp;rsquo;m staying at EMC; this post is about getting a fresh start in a new location. That&amp;rsquo;s right; I&amp;rsquo;m relocating to the Denver, CO area. In fact, I signed lease papers on a house in the Castle Pines North area, just south of Denver, yesterday afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Month with Localscope</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/02/a-month-with-localscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 10:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/02/a-month-with-localscope/</guid>
      <description>For the last month or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an iPhone app called Localscope when I travel. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty handy little app, designed to integrate with various online services such as Google, Twitter, Bing, and Foursquare, that leverages the iPhone&amp;rsquo;s GPS functionality and built-in compass to help you find local places of interest: restaurants, coffee shops, ice cream, etc.
Basically, the app works like this: you select what you&amp;rsquo;re looking to find&amp;mdash;restaurant, cafe, bank, gas station, or even a custom search like &amp;ldquo;Starbucks&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;and then Localscope goes out and gets that information from the selected online source (there&amp;rsquo;s a slider at the bottom where you choose the online source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Training This Week</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/26/ucs-training-this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 21:56:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/26/ucs-training-this-week/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be in San Jose, CA, all week for hands-on Cisco Unified Computing System training at the old Nuova Systems location. UCS has seen a great deal of attention, but the chance this week to actually get my hands on the UCS equipment will afford me the ability to form a more concrete opinion on the product, its strengths, and its weaknesses (yes, every product has weaknesses).
Now that first customer ship (FCS) for UCS has occurred&amp;mdash;it happened last week, if I recall correctly&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that the majority of the material being presented in the training class is material that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to share both here on the blog and via Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2009 Spouse Activities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/19/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 10:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/19/vmworld-2009-spouse-activities/</guid>
      <description>As many of you probably already know, my wife Crystal is in the midst of planning another round of activities for spouses attending VMworld 2009 in San Francisco, CA, later this year. Last year in Las Vegas, Crystal was joined by a number of other ladies for some great activities that included a tour of the Grand Canyon and a visit to the Hoover Dam. Their itinerary was much more packed with fun and enjoyment than mine, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Need a Favor</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/07/need-a-favor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2008 09:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/07/need-a-favor/</guid>
      <description>Any readers from Australia or New Zealand? If so&amp;mdash;and you have a few minutes to spare&amp;mdash;please contact me (see the About page). My wife and I are thinking of a trip there and could use some advice. Many thanks!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spouses at VMworld</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/06/spouses-at-vmworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 10:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/06/spouses-at-vmworld/</guid>
      <description>For the last two years, my wife has accompanied me on my trips to VMworld. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that she&amp;rsquo;s willing to travel with me and put up with long days (and sometimes long nights) during what is a very busy time for me, particularly in light of the fact that there traditionally have not been any activities designed to include spouses. This, by the way, is not a knock against VMware specifically; it seems to be a little bit of a trend in the industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
