<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Newsgroups on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/newsgroups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Newsgroups on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 16:49:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/newsgroups/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Current Mac Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/27/my-current-mac-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 16:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/27/my-current-mac-applications/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recently bought a MacBook Pro. As a switcher, I figured he would need some recommendations on applications to use on his new Mac, and I know it had been quite some time (3 years!) since I&amp;rsquo;d discussed what Mac applications I use on a day-to-day basis. To kill two birds with one stone, I figured I would post a quick list about some of my recommended Mac OS X applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Tech Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 14:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</guid>
      <description>Every now and then, I like to post out here a list of my current &amp;ldquo;tech projects.&amp;rdquo; These are the things that I&amp;rsquo;m working on for my own network, things that I may or may not start recommending to or supporting for customers.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my current list:
  InterNetNews (INN): I had an installation of INN up and running a short while back, but had to resort to an ugly hack with stunnel in order to make SSL work from a newsreader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split E-Mail Routing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/19/split-e-mail-routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2005 23:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/19/split-e-mail-routing/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have Perdition up and running (although not in the way I really wanted; see my post titled &amp;ldquo;Perdition Working Now&amp;rdquo;), I&amp;rsquo;m moving on to setting up an internal news server.
Before I can get the internal news server up and running, though, I must first address the issue of e-mail submissions to these newsgroups. See, right now I can send an e-mail to newsgroupname@domain.com (this is obviously an invalid address) and that message will be posted to the newsgroup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 22:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</guid>
      <description>In my copious spare time (fellow parents out there know this is a joke), I&amp;rsquo;m working on a couple of miscellaneous technical projects:
  Internal news server: I&amp;rsquo;m having so many problems with NNTP-based access from Unison to Exchange Server 2003 that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to setup an internal NNTP server using Linux and INNd. Linux I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with; INNd is completely new to me. Wish me luck.
  IMAP proxy: This would use Perdition to proxy IMAP4S requests to my mail server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
