<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KVM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/kvm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KVM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/kvm/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 154</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #154! My link of links and articles from around the Internet is a bit light on networking and virtualization this time around, but heftier in the security, cloud, and OS/application sections. I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something that you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful. Enjoy the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 142</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #142! This time around, the Networking section is a bit light, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of cloud computing links and articles for you to enjoy, along with some stuff on OSes and applications, programming, and soft skills. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s something useful here for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 138</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #138. I have what I hope is an interesting and useful set of links to share with everyone this time around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do so well on storage links; apologies to my storage-focused friends! However, there should be something for most everyone else. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 127</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/05/29/technology-short-take-127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 15:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/05/29/technology-short-take-127/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #127! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to collect for you this time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 121</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/06/technology-short-take-121/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/06/technology-short-take-121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #121! This may possibly be the last Tech Short Take of 2019 (not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to squeeze in another one), so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that you find something useful, helpful, or informative in the links that I&amp;rsquo;ve collected. Enjoy some light reading over your festive holiday season!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 112</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/04/19/technology-short-take-112/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/04/19/technology-short-take-112/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #112! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since the last one, as life and work have been keeping me busy. I have, however, finally managed to pull together this list of links and articles from around the Internet, and I hope that something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here proves useful to readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 104</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/07/technology-short-take-104/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/07/technology-short-take-104/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 104! For many of my readers, VMworld 2018 in Las Vegas was &amp;ldquo;front and center&amp;rdquo; for them since the last Tech Short Take. Since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t attending the conference, I won&amp;rsquo;t try to aggregate information from the event; instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on including some nuggets you may have missed amidst all the noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 95</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/24/technology-short-take-95/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 95! This Short Take was a bit more challenging than normal to compile, given that I spent the week leading up to its publication visiting customers in Europe. (My travel schedule in Europe is also why it didn&amp;rsquo;t get published until Saturday instead of the typical Friday.) Nevertheless, I have persevered in order to deliver you this list of links and articles. I hope it proves useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker Machine with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/24/using-docker-machine-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/24/using-docker-machine-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker Machine is, in my opinion, a useful and underrated tool. I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about using Docker Machine with various services/providers; for example, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/22/using-docker-machine-with-aws/&#34;&gt;this article on using Docker Machine with AWS&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/09/24/using-docker-machine-with-openstack/&#34;&gt;this article on using Docker Machine with OpenStack&lt;/a&gt;. Docker Machine also supports local hypervisors, such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/fusion.html&#34;&gt;VMware Fusion&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use Docker Machine with KVM and Libvirt on a Linux host (I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27 as an example).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #78</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #78! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of links and articles from around the Internet discussing various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  The rise of the disaggregated network operating system (NOS) marches on: this time, it&amp;rsquo;s Big Switch Networks announcing expanded hardware support in Open Network Linux (ONL), upon which its own NOS is based. The Pivotal Engineering blog has an article that shows how to use BOSH with the vSphere CPI to automate adding servers to an NSX load balancing pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Virtualization Provider</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/08/linux-migration-virtualization-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/08/linux-migration-virtualization-provider/</guid>
      <description>As part of my migration to Linux as my primary laptop OS, I needed to revisit my choice of virtualization provider. Long-time readers probably know that I was an early adopter of VMware Fusion, starting way back in 2006 with the very first &amp;ldquo;friends and family&amp;rdquo; release (before it was even publicly available). Obviously I can&amp;rsquo;t use Fusion on Linux, but do I use VMware Workstation for Linux? VirtualBox? Or something else?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OVN with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how to use OVN (Open Virtual Network; part of the Open vSwitch project) with KVM and Libvirt to provide virtual networking for KVM-based virtual machines. This post will build on some concepts around OVS and Libvirt that I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed previously; be sure to review the OVS posts and Libvirt posts on this site for more details and prerequisite knowledge.
I&amp;rsquo;ll structure this discussion around 2 key steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #68</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/technology-short-take-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/30/technology-short-take-68/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #68, my erratically-published collection of links, articles, and posts from around the web&amp;mdash;all focused on today&amp;rsquo;s major data center technologies. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to stick to a schedule that has these posts published on a Friday, but given the pending holiday weekend I wanted to get this out a bit early. As always, I hope that something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here proves useful to you.
Networking  Brent Salisbury retweeted a ton of MACVLAN- and IPVLAN-related posts right after I published the last Technology Short Take, so they had to get bumped to this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using KVM with Libvirt and macvtap Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/09/using-kvm-libvirt-macvtap-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/09/using-kvm-libvirt-macvtap-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use KVM with Libvirt and macvtap interfaces for networking (as opposed to a Linux bridge or Open vSwitch). Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide some context around why this sort of approach might be interesting/useful to you.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you are already somewhat familiar with KVM and Libvirt; if you need an introduction to either of those, you might find this post, this post, and this post (all from my site) helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
