<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solaris on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/solaris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solaris on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/solaris/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years of writing here, I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a pretty fair amount of content. To help folks discover older content, I thought it might be fun to revisit what I&amp;rsquo;ve published in October in years past. Here are some &amp;ldquo;posts from the past,&amp;rdquo; all from October of previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #24, another instance of my irregularly-published collection of links, thoughts, and rants on various data center technologies like networking, operating systems, security, hardware, virtualization, and cloud computing. This is a slightly shorter version of my Technology Short Takes; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down since some readers have indicated the previous Short Takes weren&amp;rsquo;t short enough. Anyway, I hope you find something useful.
Networking   This page is a decent reference to the open source software-defined networking (SDN) projects that are out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of Virtualization Short Takes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</guid>
      <description>My irregular &amp;ldquo;Virtualization Short Takes&amp;rdquo; series was put on hold some time ago after I started work on Mastering VMware vSphere 4. Now that work on the book is starting to wind down just a bit, I thought it would be a good time to try to resurrect the series. So, without further delay, welcome to the return of Virtualization Short Takes!
  Trigged by a series of blog posts by Arnim van Lieshout on VMware ESX memory management (Part 1, Part 2, and Part 3), Scott Herold decided to join the fray with this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Pretty Much Answers That Question</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/12/this-pretty-much-answers-that-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 10:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/12/this-pretty-much-answers-that-question/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I posed this question: is Sun preparing to take on Cisco? The question generated some interesting responses in the comments to the article.
Reader Bill had this to say:
 How on earth would Cisco respond if Sun started introducing products with better performance, at a fraction of the price, built on high volume open source adoption?
 As I responded, that&amp;rsquo;s the real $64,000 question, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Sun Preparing to Take on Cisco?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/09/is-sun-preparing-to-take-on-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2009 16:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/09/is-sun-preparing-to-take-on-cisco/</guid>
      <description>A while back in Virtualization Short Take #25 I briefly mentioned Sun&amp;rsquo;s Crossbow network virtualization software, which brings new possibilities to the Solaris networking world. Not being a Solaris expert, it was hard for me at the time to really understand why Solaris fans were so excited about it; since then, though, I&amp;rsquo;ve come to understand that Crossbow brings to Solaris the same kind of full-blown virtual network interfaces and such that I use daily with VMware ESX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #25, the first edition of this series for 2009! Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of articles and posts that I found interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off today&amp;rsquo;s list with some Hyper-V links. First up is this article on how to manually add a VM configuration to Hyper-V. It would be interesting to me to know some of the technical details&amp;mdash;i.e., the design decisions that led Microsoft to architect things in this way&amp;mdash;that might explain why this process is, in my opinion, so complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week I provided a list of virtualization-related items that had made their way into my Inbox in some form or another; today I&amp;rsquo;ll share storage-related items with you in Storage Short Take #4! This post will also be cross-published to the Storage Monkeys Blogs.
  Stephen Foskett has a nice round-up of some of the storage-related changes available to users in VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. Of particular note to many users is the VMDK Recovery Tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Solaris-AD Integration Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/19/no-solaris-ad-integration-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 13:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/19/no-solaris-ad-integration-update/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, folks, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to have the time or the resources to publish an update to my existing instructions for integrating Solaris 10 into Active Directory. Quite some time ago I had posted that I planned on creating an update to the original instructions so as to incorporate some lessons learned, but it keeps get pushed aside for other tasks that are more important and more relevant to my day-to-day work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eG Innovations Now Supporting Multiple Virtualization Platforms</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/08/eg-innovations-now-supporting-multiple-virtualization-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 15:06:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/08/eg-innovations-now-supporting-multiple-virtualization-platforms/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken to the folks at eG Innovations a couple of times. In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, eG Innovations makes a product that is designed around managing virtualization environments. eG claims to be unique in that it gathers information from both inside the guest as well as outside the guest (from the host) and correlates the data from the two views.
Today, eG Innovations announced that eG VM Monitor now supports not only VMware ESX and Solaris Containers, but also Citrix XenServer and Solaris Logical Domains (LDoms).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #13</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/17/virtualization-short-take-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 11:29:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/17/virtualization-short-take-13/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the latest installation of Virtualization Short Takes, my occasionally-weekly view on various virtualization news, reviews, and other happenings. Hopefully I can share something interesting with you!
  Via VMblog.com, I saw that Transitive Corporation is supporting the use of QuickTransit within Hyper-V virtual machines. This is interesting because it extends the ability of Hyper-V to help customers consolidate applications. QuickTransit, in case you aren&amp;rsquo;t aware, allows applications written for Solaris/SPARC environments to run in Linux/x86 environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Works</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/15/in-the-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 23:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/15/in-the-works/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to provide a quick update on some articles I have in the works to be (hopefully) published soon.
  I&amp;rsquo;m working on an article discussing when to use various NIC teaming configurations with VMware ESX. There are some significant repercussions here for a variety of network configurations, but especially so for configurations involving IP-based storage (iSCSI or NFS).
  I&amp;rsquo;m finally wrapping up an article on the Xsigo I/O Director.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation of Misbehaving VMs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/08/isolation-of-misbehaving-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 14:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/08/isolation-of-misbehaving-vms/</guid>
      <description>I came across an interesting paper discussing how various virtualization environments protect well-behaved VMs from misbehaving VMs. The paper is available here.
In the tests described in the paper, researchers used virtual machines on Xen 3.0 (the open source hypervisor, not the commercial XenServer product, as far as I can tell), VMware Workstation 5.5, and &amp;ldquo;Open Solaris 10&amp;rdquo; (quotes mine). As pointed out in the paper, these three environments represent paravirtualization, full virtualization, and OS virtualization (or containers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Things I&#39;m Working On</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/03/some-things-im-working-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 21:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/03/some-things-im-working-on/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to take just a brief moment and let everyone know about a few articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve got &amp;ldquo;in the pipeline&amp;rdquo; for the site. If there is one&amp;mdash;or more&amp;mdash;of these articles that looks particularly interesting, speak up in the comments.
Here are the articles that are currently under development:
  An update to the Solaris-AD integration instructions: Last time I ran through these instructions I came across a number of discrepancies and little &amp;ldquo;gotchas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Notes on Solaris-AD Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/11/27/some-notes-on-solaris-ad-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 16:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/11/27/some-notes-on-solaris-ad-integration/</guid>
      <description>This afternoon, I walked back through my own instructions for integrating Solaris 10 and Active Directory, and I found that the process wasn&amp;rsquo;t as smooth as perhaps I&amp;rsquo;d believed it to be. As a result of walking back through the process again myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected some notes. At some point in the near future, these notes will be integrated into a new version of the Solaris-AD integration instructions.
So, without further ado, here are the notes I collected in no particular order:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apparently, I&#39;m Ahead Too</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/21/apparently-im-ahead-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2007 11:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/21/apparently-im-ahead-too/</guid>
      <description>I used to read Tom Yager&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Ahead of the Curve&amp;rdquo; column when InfoWorld was still a print publication. Every month, without fail, as soon as the magazine arrived I turned right to his column. It was one of my primary reasons for reading the magazine, at least in recent years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s probably safe to say that Yager&amp;rsquo;s affection for Mac OS X led me to perform an evaluation of my own and, eventually, to switch to Mac OS X myself based on the results of that personal evaluation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
