<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Career on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Career on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/career/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Next Step</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/18/the-next-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/18/the-next-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greek philosopher Heraclitus is typically attributed as the creator of the well-known phrase &amp;ldquo;Change is the only constant.&amp;rdquo; Since I left VMware in 2018 to join Heptio, change has been my companion. First, there was the change of focus, moving to a focus on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; and related technologies. Then there was the acquisition of Heptio by VMware, and all the change that comes with an acquisition. Just when things were starting to settle down, along came the acquisition of Pivotal by VMware and several more rounds of changes as a result. Today, I mark the start of another change, as I begin a new role and take the next step in my career journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing out the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019, I announced that I would be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;temporarily relocating to Tokyo for a six-month assignment&lt;/a&gt; to build out a team focused on cloud-native services and offerings. A few months later, I was still in Colorado, and I explained what was happening in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/&#34;&gt;a status update on the Tokyo assignment&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few folks ask me about it, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and share that the Tokyo assignment did not happen and will not happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 15:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right at the end of 2019 I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that in early 2020 I was temporarily relocating to Tokyo, Japan, for a six month work assignment. It&amp;rsquo;s now March, and I&amp;rsquo;m still in Colorado. So what&amp;rsquo;s up with that Tokyo assignment, anyway? Since I&amp;rsquo;ve had several folks ask, I figured it&amp;rsquo;s probably best to post something here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2019 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has been my custom over the last five years or so, in the early part of the year I like to share with my readers a list of personal projects for the upcoming year (here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/&#34;&gt;the 2019 list&lt;/a&gt;). Then, near the end of that same year or very early in the following year, I evaluate how I performed against that list of personal projects (for example, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my project report card for 2018&lt;/a&gt;). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue that pattern with an evaluation of my progress against my 2019 project list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the build-up and jump straight to the whole point of this post: a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity has come up and I&amp;rsquo;m embarking on a new adventure starting in early 2020. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not changing jobs&amp;hellip;but I am changing time zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2019 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while now since I published &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project report card&lt;/a&gt;, which assessed my progress against &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project goals&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving a fair amount of thought to the areas where I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus my professional (technical) development this coming year, and I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with some project goals that align both with where I am professionally right now and where I want to be technically as I grow and evolve. This is a really difficult balance to strike, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see at the end of the year how well I did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 102</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/13/technology-short-take-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/13/technology-short-take-102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 102! I normally try to get these things published biweekly (every other Friday), but this one has taken quite a bit longer to get published. It&amp;rsquo;s no one&amp;rsquo;s fault but my own! In any event, I hope that you&amp;rsquo;re able to find something useful among the links below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future is Containerized</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/02/the-future-is-containerized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/02/the-future-is-containerized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/&#34;&gt;announced my departure from VMware&lt;/a&gt;, and my intention to step away from VMware&amp;rsquo;s products and platforms to focus on a new technology area moving forward. Today marks the &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; start of a journey that&amp;rsquo;s been building for a couple years, a journey that will take me into a future that&amp;rsquo;s containerized. That journey starts in Seattle, Washington.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Evolve</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first started getting into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; around 2003, possibly earlier (I can&amp;rsquo;t recall exactly when it was). I remember thinking that VMware&amp;rsquo;s impact on the industry was going to be significant, and I wanted to be part of this industry change. I was right&amp;mdash;virtualization like what VMware offers has fundamentally changed the industry. However, just as technology evolves, technology careers must evolve as well. Specifically, my technology career must change and grow. It&amp;rsquo;s time to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #79</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/03/technology-short-take-79/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #79! There&amp;rsquo;s lots of interesting links for you this time around.
Networking  I was sure I had mentioned Skydive before, but apparently not (a grep of all my blog posts found nothing), so let me rectify that first. Skydive is (in the project&amp;rsquo;s own words) an &amp;ldquo;open source real-time network topology and protocols analyzer.&amp;rdquo; The project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub repository is here, and documentation for Skydive is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #2: Matt Oswalt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #2 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, my guest is none other than Matt Oswalt. You may know Matt as the primary author at Keeping It Classless, or as @mierdin on Twitter or GitHub (he also has a YouTube channel and a podcast of his own). Matt is primarily focused on network infrastructure, but is really interested in the intersection of network infrastructure and software development. Matt, along with Jason Edelman and yours truly, is one of the co-authors of a new book on network automation and programmability, and as such is a perfect guest for the Full Stack Journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #1: Bart Smith</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</guid>
      <description>In this first-ever episode of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I talk with Bart Smith (old GitHub account migrating to new GitHub account, YouTube channel). Bart shares some details about his journey from being a Microsoft-centric infrastructure engineer to what he calls a cloud-native full-stack engineer. Here are some notes from our conversation, along with some additional resources Bart wanted to share with readers/listeners. Enjoy!
The podcast audio recording is available on Soundcloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching a New Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/07/launching-new-podcast/</guid>
      <description>After quite a bit of deliberation and planning, I&amp;rsquo;m excited (and nervous!) to announce the launch of a new podcast, titled &amp;ldquo;The Full Stack Journey Podcast&amp;rdquo;. Here are the details, structured in a Q&amp;amp;A format.
What topics does this new podcast cover?
The focus of The Full Stack Journey Podcast is to talk about the journey to becoming a full-stack engineer. That term is a bit of a loaded term&amp;mdash;some people like it, some people don&amp;rsquo;t, and there&amp;rsquo;s some disagreement over exactly what it means.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring the Rockstar: A Counterpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re a rockstar!&amp;rdquo; Chances are, you&amp;rsquo;ve either a) been told this as a compliment for some work you&amp;rsquo;d done; b) heard this told to someone else for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done; or c) told someone this for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done. If you said this to someone else&amp;mdash;I just told someone this quite recently&amp;mdash;chances are also very likely that you had nothing but positive intentions behind this statement and your goal was to compliment them on what you saw as outstanding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Handling Career Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</guid>
      <description>As IT pros at the &amp;ldquo;cutting edge&amp;rdquo; of technology and industry change, I think sometimes we forget that not everyone has the same mindset toward learning, growth, and career evolution. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true, I think, for those of us who are bloggers, because it&amp;rsquo;s our passion for the technology that not only drives us to write about it but also drives us to constantly explore new trends, new areas, and new concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
