<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 10:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nfs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enabling and Mounting NFS on CoreOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/20/config-mount-nfs-coreos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/20/config-mount-nfs-coreos/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about CoreOS a fair amount (see here, here, and here), but one of the things that is both good and bad about CoreOS is the automatic update mechanism. It&amp;rsquo;s good because you know your systems will stay up to date, but it&amp;rsquo;s bad if you haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to properly address how automatic updates will affect your environment (for example, you&amp;rsquo;ve manually started some Docker containers instead of using systemd unit files&amp;mdash;when the CoreOS system reboots after an update, your Docker containers will no longer be running).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #28</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #28, the first Technology Short Take for 2013. As always, I hope that you find something useful or informative here. Enjoy!
Networking   Ivan Pepelnjak recently wrote a piece titled &amp;ldquo;Edge and Core OpenFlow (and why MPLS is not NAT)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s an informative piece&amp;mdash;Ivan&amp;rsquo;s stuff is always informative&amp;mdash;but what really drew my attention was his mention of a paper by Martin Casado, Teemu Koponen, and others that calls for a combination of MPLS and OpenFlow (and an evolution of OpenFlow into &amp;ldquo;edge&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; versions) to build next-generation networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere on NFS Design Considerations Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This presentation is one that I gave at the New Mexico, New York City, and Seattle VMUG conferences (this specific deck came from the Seattle conference, as you can tell by the Twitter handle on the first slide). The topic is design considerations for running vSphere on NFS. This isn&amp;rsquo;t an attempt to bash NFS, but rather to educate users on the things to avoid if you&amp;rsquo;re going to build a rock-solid NFS infrastructure for your VMware vSphere environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #36</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/09/virtualization-short-take-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 10:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/09/virtualization-short-take-36/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy couple of weeks! I was in Vienna, Austria, all last week, and I&amp;rsquo;m on the US West Coast this week. Even though I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the go, I&amp;rsquo;ve still been collecting various virtualization-related posts and tidbits. Here they are for you in Virtualization Short Take #36! I hope you find something useful.
  You might recall that in early 2008 I wrote about how thin provisioned VMDKs on NFS storage tend to inflate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using IP-Based Storage with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 09:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me with a couple of questions, one of which I felt warranted a blog post. Paraphrased, the question was this: How do I make IP-based storage work with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS?
At first glance, you might look at this question and scoff. Remember though, that Cisco UCS does&amp;mdash;at this time&amp;mdash;have a few limitations that make this a bit more complicated than at first glance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC Celerra Optimizations for VMware on NFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/31/emc-celerra-optimizations-for-vmware-on-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 18:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/31/emc-celerra-optimizations-for-vmware-on-nfs/</guid>
      <description>Recently Jason Boche posted some storage performance numbers from his EMC Celerra NS-120. Out of those storage performance tests, Jason noted that the NFS performance of the NS-120 seemed a bit off, so he contacted EMC&amp;rsquo;s vSpecialist team (also known as &amp;ldquo;Chad&amp;rsquo;s Army&amp;rdquo;, but I like vSpecialists better) to see if there was something that could or should be done to improve NFS performance on the NS-120. After collaborating internally, one of our team members (a great guy named Kevin Zawodzinski) responded to Jason with some suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for FCoE in Your Data Center Today</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 15:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of attending a Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 class. I have learned a tremendous amount about FCoE this week and after some conversations with Scott about the topic, I wanted to tackle it one more time from a different point of view. I have included a list of some of Scott&amp;rsquo;s FCoE articles at the bottom for those interested in a more in-depth analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republished: Dispelling Some VMware over NFS Myths</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/01/republished-dispelling-some-vmware-over-nfs-myths/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 09:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/01/republished-dispelling-some-vmware-over-nfs-myths/</guid>
      <description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: This content was first published over at Storage Monkeys, but it appears that it has since disappeared and is no longer available. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m republishing it here (with minor edits). Where applicable, I&amp;rsquo;ll also be republishing other old content from that site in the coming weeks. Thanks!
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to tackle what will probably be a sensitive topic for some readers: VMware over NFS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere vDS, VMkernel Ports, and Jumbo Frames</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 13:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</guid>
      <description>In April 2008, I wrote an article on how to use jumbo frames with VMware ESX and IP-based storage (NFS or iSCSI). It&amp;rsquo;s been a pretty popular post, ranking right up there with the ever-popular article on VMware ESX, NIC teaming, and VLAN trunks.
Since I started working with VMware vSphere (now officially available as of 5/21/2009), I have been evaluating how to replicate the same sort of setup using ESX/ESXi 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #25, the first edition of this series for 2009! Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of articles and posts that I found interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off today&amp;rsquo;s list with some Hyper-V links. First up is this article on how to manually add a VM configuration to Hyper-V. It would be interesting to me to know some of the technical details&amp;mdash;i.e., the design decisions that led Microsoft to architect things in this way&amp;mdash;that might explain why this process is, in my opinion, so complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partial Case Sensitivity with esxcfg-advcfg</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/05/partial-case-sensitivity-with-esxcfg-advcfg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 17:44:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/05/partial-case-sensitivity-with-esxcfg-advcfg/</guid>
      <description>I was working on some documentation this afternoon that centered around the use of esxcfg-advcfg to set some NFS-related parameters in VMware ESX. While verifying the command syntax, I noticed something interesting about the esxcfg-advcfg command: it&amp;rsquo;s only partially case-sensitive.
OK, this isn&amp;rsquo;t world-shattering news or a discovery of paramount importance, but I do find this a bit odd given that with the Linux-based Service Console most everything should be entirely case-sensitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s lots of good information flowing around the Internet, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming increasingly difficult to sort through all the useless stuff to find the valuable gems. Hopefully, some of the links that I have collected here will prove to be more useful than useless!
  I came across this VMware KB article titled &amp;ldquo;Dedicating specific NICs to portgroups while maintaining NIC teaming and failover for the vSwitch&amp;rdquo;. I was hoping it would shed new light on some NIC teaming functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
