<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TechEd2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/teched2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TechEd2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 14:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/teched2008/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Melio FS, Hyper-V, and VMware ESX</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/16/melio-fs-hyper-v-and-vmware-esx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 14:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/16/melio-fs-hyper-v-and-vmware-esx/</guid>
      <description>Last week Network World published an article about Sanbolic&amp;rsquo;s announcement to provide VMware virtual machines access to shared application data using their shared file system, Melio FS. This announcement was made last week at Tech-Ed 2008 in Orlando, FL. Sanbolic also announced support for running Melio FS in VMware Infrastructure 3 (VI3) environments as well. Unfortunately, the information in these announcements seems to have gotten jumbled while being reported and now these two very different uses of Sanbolic&amp;rsquo;s products are being intermingled when they really shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One More Tech-Ed Schedule Change</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/one-more-tech-ed-schedule-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 15:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/one-more-tech-ed-schedule-change/</guid>
      <description>I have to swallow my pride and admit defeat: the amount of information at Tech-Ed 2008 has overwhelmed me. I&amp;rsquo;ll be skipping my last session, a session on Server Core, to return back to my resort and prepare to fly home early tomorrow morning. If you were looking for some information on Server Core, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to disappoint you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR350: System Center VMM Advanced Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/vir350-system-center-vmm-advanced-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 13:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/vir350-system-center-vmm-advanced-integration/</guid>
      <description>Yes, yet another System Center VMM session&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that System Center is a major component of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s server virtualization strategy. This session is VIR350, System Center VMM Advanced Integration, so I suppose we will be seeing more PowerShell and more integration with other System Center family members. As with the other liveblogged sessions, I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best to weed out duplicate content.
The presenter for this session is David Armour, a Senior Program Manager at Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Significant Networking Problem with Hyper-V</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/significant-networking-problem-with-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 11:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/significant-networking-problem-with-hyper-v/</guid>
      <description>After the conclusion of VIR358, I went up to the front to speak with the presenters about the question I had during the session: what about NIC bonding or NIC teaming? You&amp;rsquo;ll recall that I wondered about that during the VIR358 session.
Well, it turns out that Hyper-V does not support any form of NIC teaming or NIC bonding. Yes, you read that right: you can&amp;rsquo;t link more than one NIC to a virtual switch in Hyper-V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR358: Hyper-V Architecture, Scenarios, and Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/vir358-hyper-v-architecture-scenarios-and-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 09:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/vir358-hyper-v-architecture-scenarios-and-networking/</guid>
      <description>Day 3 of Tech-Ed 2008 is upon me, and the first session of the day is another session with Jeff Woolsey. This session, VIR358, is titled &amp;ldquo;Windows Server 2008 Hyper-V Architecture, Scenarios, and Networking.&amp;rdquo; I suspect there will be some duplicate content from Jeff&amp;rsquo;s Day 1 session, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to weed that out wherever possible. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in the networking discussions, as I was unable to gather any real information on Hyper-V networking from the Day 1 session or from my private discussion with Jeff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Tech-Ed Schedule Change</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/small-tech-ed-schedule-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2008 09:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/12/small-tech-ed-schedule-change/</guid>
      <description>One quick note to readers following my Tech-Ed 2008 coverage: I&amp;rsquo;m making a small schedule change for today. I&amp;rsquo;ll be skipping the morning sessions except for VIR358 and spending some time in the Partner Expo area instead. Look for an update on some of the discussions from the Partner Expo late tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MGT374: Offline Virtual Machine Servicing Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/mgt374-offline-virtual-machine-servicing-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 18:19:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/mgt374-offline-virtual-machine-servicing-tool/</guid>
      <description>This session couldn&amp;rsquo;t be published live because I had no wireless signal and no cellular signal in the breakout room. However, I did want to capture the information and publish it at the next available opportunity for the benefit of the readers.
This session was hosted by Luis Camara Manoel, Satish Mathew, and Jay Sauls (he was also one of the presenters in the session prior to this one). The focus of the session, quite obviously, is the Offline Virtual Machine Servicing Tool, which is designed to help in the maintenance and patching of offline VMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR361: Introducing MAP for Windows Server 2008 Hyper-V</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir361-introducing-map-for-windows-server-2008-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir361-introducing-map-for-windows-server-2008-hyper-v/</guid>
      <description>Based on rapidly dwindling battery life, I thought that I might not be able to liveblog this session. Fortunately, I was able to find a power plug between the last session and this session, and I was able to find a seat near a power plug in this session. You&amp;rsquo;re in luck!
This session is hosted by Jay Sauls and Baldwin Ng. Jay is a Senior Program Manager; Baldwin is a Senior Product Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR250: Advanced Storage Connectivity for VMs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir250-advanced-storage-connectivity-for-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir250-advanced-storage-connectivity-for-vms/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to liveblog as much content from this session as possible, but I arrived late (you&amp;rsquo;ll understand why soon) and my battery is running low. Sorry all!
I arrived in the session as the speaker was reviewing some Hyper-V architecture with regards to the placement of the storage drivers and the use of Virtualization Service Clients (VSCs) and Virtualization Service Providers (VSPs). I think I covered those in my earlier liveblogging session from Day 1; if I didn&amp;rsquo;t, I&amp;rsquo;ll revise this post with more information later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Liveblogging of Lunch Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/no-liveblogging-of-lunch-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 14:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/no-liveblogging-of-lunch-session/</guid>
      <description>Those of you that reviewed my Tech-Ed schedule saw a session called &amp;ldquo;Do These 10 Things Now or Get 0wn3d!&amp;rdquo;. This was an entertaining session by Steve Riley on security. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, but there&amp;rsquo;s no liveblog for that session. I had to eat lunch, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet figured out how to eat lunch, liveblog, and pay attention to the session at the same time. Tips for doing all three are welcome in the comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR360: Microsoft System Center VMM 2008, Part 2 of 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir360-microsoft-system-center-vmm-2008-part-2-of-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 11:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir360-microsoft-system-center-vmm-2008-part-2-of-2/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re getting ready to start VIR360, the second of two sessions this morning on System Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM) 2008. The first session was liveblogged here. The wireless network in this room isn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as reliable as the signal in the last room, so I may not be able to publish this until after the session ends. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.
This session is being presented by Alan Goodman, Senior Program Manager for Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR253: Microsoft System Center VMM 2008, Part 1 of 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir253-microsoft-system-center-vmm-2008-part-1-of-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 09:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/11/vir253-microsoft-system-center-vmm-2008-part-1-of-2/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s Day 2 of Tech-Ed 2008, and my first session of the day is VIR253, Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager 2008 Overview, Part 1 of 2. Part 2 will be later this morning. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a seat right by the doors to the breakout session, so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that the wireless LAN will hold out for liveblogging the session.
I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been here at the conference center since 7:00 AM this morning; I spent some time in the Hands-On Labs this morning going through Hyper-V setup, configuration, Authorization Manager, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Discussion with Jeff Woolsey</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/a-discussion-with-jeff-woolsey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 21:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/a-discussion-with-jeff-woolsey/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity today to spend a few minutes in a one-on-one conversation with Jeff Woolsey, Senior Program Manager for Hyper-V at Microsoft. During our conversation, Jeff and I discussed the Hyper-V architecture, comparisons to other virtualization solutions, and some common competitive arguments for or against Hyper-V. I&amp;rsquo;d like to publish a summarized version of our conversation here. (Jeff, if you&amp;rsquo;re reading and I&amp;rsquo;ve accidentally misquoted you, please be sure to correct me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR353: Planning for Server Virtualization with Windows Server 2008 Hyper-V</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/vir353-planning-for-server-virtualization-with-windows-server-2008-hyper-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 16:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/vir353-planning-for-server-virtualization-with-windows-server-2008-hyper-v/</guid>
      <description>My final session of the day is VIR353, Planning for Server Virtualization with Windows Server 2008 Hyper-V Using the New Infrastructure Planning and Design Guides. I got into this session about 15 minutes late as I was finishing up a one-on-one interview with Jeff Woolsey, Senior Program Manager for Hyper-V. I&amp;rsquo;ll have more on my interview with him later today or tonight. I&amp;rsquo;m not attending the next session of the day because it turns out that VIR366/VIR367 are essentially identical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VIR367: Hyper-V Security and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/vir367-hyper-v-security-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 11:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/10/vir367-hyper-v-security-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>My first breakout session of Tech-Ed 2008 is a session led by Jeff Woolsey, Senior Program Manager for Hyper-V, and the session is about Hyper-V security and best practices. I&amp;rsquo;ve met Jeff before at VMworld 2007, although he probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember me. I&amp;rsquo;ll have more information from Jeff this afternoon, as I have a meeting scheduled with him. I&amp;rsquo;ll republish what I can from that conversation here this afternoon or this evening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
