<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GuestPost on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/guestpost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GuestPost on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 23:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/guestpost/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMware Lab Manager Design Considerations </title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/04/vmware-lab-manager-design-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2009 23:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/04/vmware-lab-manager-design-considerations/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
I have done a number of VMware Lab Manager white boarding sessions and I want to share a few of my design notes and the reason for each. Most of items come from my installation experience and the version 4 release notes. Here they are in no particular order.
  You need an LDAP server to import groups - Yes, you can set up user IDs in Lab Manager but you CAN NOT create groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for FCoE in Your Data Center Today</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 15:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/22/planning-for-fcoe-in-your-data-center-today/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This week I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of attending a Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 class. I have learned a tremendous amount about FCoE this week and after some conversations with Scott about the topic, I wanted to tackle it one more time from a different point of view. I have included a list of some of Scott&amp;rsquo;s FCoE articles at the bottom for those interested in a more in-depth analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Nehalem Memory</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/11/introduction-to-nehalem-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/11/introduction-to-nehalem-memory/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
I wanted to relay some information regarding choosing memory speeds and types for the new Intel Xeon 5500 (Nehalem family) processors. As stated in my previous article on the Nehalem CPUs, there are some decisions that need to be made when choosing the memory and processor combinations. Lets start off with what the memory architecture looks like.
  The current Xeon 5500 family is a two-socket configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing IBM BladeCenter Open Fabric Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/07/implementing-ibm-bladecenter-open-fabric-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 14:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/07/implementing-ibm-bladecenter-open-fabric-manager/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
A few months ago I implemented the Basic version IBM&amp;rsquo;s BladeCenter Open Fabric Manager (BOFM) and I wanted to share some of my notes with everyone. It has been awhile so this is very high level; most of the small details have since fallen out of my head.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what Open Fabric Manager is, BOFM allows you to virtualize the FC and Ethernet connections coming from a blade server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to &#34;Nehalem&#34; CPUs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/07/introduction-to-nehalem-cpus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 11:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/07/introduction-to-nehalem-cpus/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
Hello everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s Aaron again. Im sorry for falling off the radar for a bit. A new generation of Intel processors is upon us and I felt the need to come out of seclusion to share some recent findings regarding the new architecture. Todays article will explore the new processor offerings. I will be following this up with one (or more depending on the length) about the memory architecture and interconnects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Four, HP Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
Welcome to Part 4 in our series on blades and virtualization. Please note that I will be covering the HP virtualized I/O offerings in a near future post. I plan to cover Virtual Connect, Flex-10, and the BL495 blade at that time.
As always, lets start by reviewing the hardware specification we will be using to compare the rack servers against the blade servers. Here are the portions of the spec that concern us:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Three, IBM Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
UPDATE: I have made some corrections to the 10GB and iSCSI sections based on feedback. Thank you!
Welcome to part 3 of my series on blades and virtualization. I will be breaking the expansion articles into four parts: traditional IBM options, traditional HP options, virtualized IBM options, and virtualized HP options. By &amp;ldquo;virtualized options&amp;rdquo; I mean the IBM and HP blade I/O virtualization solutions (like IBM Blade Open Fabric Manager and HP VirtualConnect), not a server configuration that will run virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Two, IBM Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This is the second part of a series of articles on blades and virtualization. The first article is found here. Today, I will present IBM rack servers versus blade servers and explore the power consumption for each.
In case you need it again, here is the hardware platform I will be using as the standard:
 2 x E5450 3.0 Ghz quad-core processors 32 GB memory in an 8 x 4GB configuration 2 on-board NICs Additional quad NIC card for a total of 6 NICs Dual FC card (assuming FC SAN storage for VMs but it could easily be NFS or iSCSI as well) 2 x 146GB, 10k SAS drives (except the IBM HS21XM blades which only support one HD)  Here is the link to the IBM System x and Blade Power Configuration Tool I used for the numbers below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part One, HP Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
I have seen a lot of misconceptions recently when it comes to blade servers and virtualization. Many seem to think that if you are using blades you can&amp;rsquo;t use virtualization. Most recently, someone shared this article with me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t disagree with this viewpoint more. I will explore the reasons why in the next few articles. For today&amp;rsquo;s article, I will present a foundation for comparison and I will use this basis going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
