<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EMCWorld2010 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/emcworld2010/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EMCWorld2010 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 23:00:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/emcworld2010/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #6</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/01/storage-short-take-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/01/storage-short-take-6/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Storage Short Take #6, the latest installation of my quite irregular collection of storage-related links, posts, and thoughts. You could call this the &amp;ldquo;EMC World&amp;rdquo; edition, since most of the items listed here stemmed from announcements that came out of EMC World a few weeks ago.
  One of the announcements from EMC World was FAST Cache, a new feature that EMC is slated to include in the next version of FLARE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC World 2010: Symmetrix VMAX Auto-Provisioning Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/11/emc-world-2010-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 09:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/11/emc-world-2010-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few notes from another Symmetrix session I attended Monday afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete session blog (the presenter was presenting so much information I couldn&amp;rsquo;t capture it all).
Auto-provisioning groups include storage groups, port groups, and initiator groups. A storage group is just a collection of storage resources that are presented to a cluster of hosts. Similarly, a port group is a collection of front-end ports, and initiator groups are just groups of hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC World 2010 Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 12:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-coverage/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m leaving in just a few hours to head to Boston for the 10th annual EMC user conference, EMC World 2010. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about attending, for a number of reasons. First, this will be my first EMC World; I&amp;rsquo;ve never had the opportunity to attend EMC World in the past. Second, this is my first major conference as an EMC employee (if you don&amp;rsquo;t count VMware Partner Exchange). Third, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to meeting a bunch of the new vSpecialists that have recently joined the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC World 2010: Enginuity 5874 Enhancements for VMAX</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-enginuity-5874-enhancements-for-vmax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 10:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-enginuity-5874-enhancements-for-vmax/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the session titled &amp;ldquo;Performance Improvements and Enhancements of Enginuity 5874 for Symmetrix VMAX: What&amp;rsquo;s New Since Last Year&amp;rdquo;. The presenter&amp;rsquo;s name is John Aurin. (Note: the product branding is changing from &amp;ldquo;V-Max&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;VMAX&amp;rdquo;.)
The session starts with a recap of the Symmetrix VMAX architecture: the directors, front-end ports, the Virtual Matrix connectivity for sharing data between directors, and the various expansion cabinets and drives that are supported.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
