<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SDN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/sdn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SDN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 21:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/sdn/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Carrier-Grade SDN-Based OpenStack Networking Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/07/carrier-grade-sdn-openstack-networking-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/07/carrier-grade-sdn-openstack-networking-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This session was titled &amp;ldquo;Carrier-Grade SDN Based OpenStack Networking Solution,&amp;rdquo; led by Daniel Park and Sangho Shin. Both Park and Shin are from SK Telecom (SKT), and (based on the description) this session is a follow-up to a session from the Boston summit where SK Telecom talked about an SDN-based networking solution they&amp;rsquo;d developed and released for use in their own 5G-based network.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #42</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/11/technology-short-take-42/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #42, another installation in my ongoing series of irregularly published collections of news, items, thoughts, rants, raves, and tidbits from around the Internet, with a focus on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s series on VMware NSX continues with part 5.
  Aaron Rosen, a Neutron contributor, recently published a post about a Neutron extension called Allowed-Address-Pairs and how you can use it to create high availability instances using VRRP (via keepalived).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #38</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 09:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/06/technology-short-take-38/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #38, another installment in my irregularly-published series that collects links and thoughts on data center-related technologies from around the web. But enough with the introduction, let&amp;rsquo;s get on to the content already!
Networking   Jason Edelman does some experimenting with the Python APIs on a Cisco Nexus 3000. In the process, he muses about the value of configuration management tool chains such as Chef and Puppet in a world of &amp;ldquo;open switch&amp;rdquo; platforms such as Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Enabling NFV/SDN with Intel ONP Server Reference Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-enabling-nfvsdn-with-intel-onp-server-reference-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-enabling-nfvsdn-with-intel-onp-server-reference-design/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS003, titled &amp;ldquo;Enabling Network Function Virtualization and Software Defined Networking with the Intel Open Network Platform Server Reference Architecture Design.&amp;rdquo; (How&amp;rsquo;s that for a mouthful!) The speakers are Frank Schapfel, Senior Product Line Manager with Intel, and Brian Skerry, Open Networks System Architect with Intel. This session is slightly related to IDF 2013 session COMS0002, which focused more on the Intel ONP Switch reference design.
Frank kicks the session off with a quick review of the agenda, then dives right into the content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Future of SDN with the Intel ONP Switch Reference Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS002, titled &amp;ldquo;The Future of Software-Defined Networking with the Intel Open Network Platform Switch Reference Design.&amp;rdquo; The speakers are Recep Ozdag, a PME with Intel, and Gershon Schatzberg, a PLM with Wind River Systems. The Intel Open Network Platform (ONP) Switch is the official name for Seacliff Trail, which I talked about last year at IDF 2012.
Recep starts the session with some brief background; he came to Intel through the Fulcrum acquisition a couple of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Virtualizing the Network to Enable SDI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 17:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/11/idf-2013-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</guid>
      <description>This is session EDCS008, &amp;ldquo;Virtualizing the Network to Enable a Software-Defined Infrastructure (SDI).&amp;rdquo; The speakers are Brian Johnson (@thehevy on Twitter) from Intel and Jim Pinkerton from Microsoft. Brian is a Solution Architect; Jim is a Windows Server Architect. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in one of Brian&amp;rsquo;s presentations, you know he does a great job of really diving deep in some of this stuff. (Can you tell I&amp;rsquo;m a fan?)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of VLANs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me how much the idea of a VLAN has invaded the consciousness of data center IT professionals. Data center folks primarily tasked with managing compute workloads are nearly as familiar with VLANs as their colleagues primarily tasked with managing network connectivity. However, as networking undergoes a transformation at the hands of SDN, NFV, and network virtualization, what will happen to the VLAN?
The ubiquity of the VLAN is due, I think, to the fact that it serves as a reasonable &amp;ldquo;common ground&amp;rdquo; for both compute-focused and networking-focused professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #33</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #33, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles discussing various data center technology-related links, articles, rants, thoughts, and questions. I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking   Tom Nolle asks the question, &amp;ldquo;Is virtualization reality even more elusive than virtual reality?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a good read; the key thing that I took away from it was that SDN, NFV, and related efforts are great, but what we really need is something that can pull all these together in a way that customers (and providers) reap the benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #32</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #32, the latest installment in my irregularly-published series of link collections, thoughts, rants, raves, and miscellaneous information. I try to keep the information linked to data center technologies like networking, storage, virtualization, and the like, but occasionally other items slip through. I hope you find something useful.
Networking   Ranga Maddipudi (@vCloudNetSec on Twitter) has put together two blog posts on vCloud Networking and Security&amp;rsquo;s App Firewall (part 1 and part 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Network Virtualization and SDN</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/30/on-network-virtualization-and-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 18:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/30/on-network-virtualization-and-sdn/</guid>
      <description>Is there a difference between network virtualization and Software-Defined Networking (SDN)? If so, what is the relationship between them? Is one a subset of the other? This is a topic that is increasingly being discussed and debated. So, in a similar fashion to my post on network overlays vs. network virtualization, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d weigh in with some thoughts. This post, like all of my posts, is intended to help spark a conversation, so I encourage you to share your thoughts in the comments after you&amp;rsquo;ve finished reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #31</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #31, my irregularly published series that takes a look at links, posts, articles, and thoughts from around the web related to core data center technologies. I hope that you find something useful!
Networking   Umair Hoodbhoy speculates in this post that the inclusion of Cisco&amp;rsquo;s ONE Controller in the recently-announced &amp;ldquo;Daylight&amp;rdquo; effort could mean the end for Big Switch&amp;rsquo;s Floodlight. (Umair&amp;rsquo;s play on words&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;in Daylight there is no need for Floodlights&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;is cute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Targeting the Real Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/03/thinking-out-loud-targeting-the-real-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 09:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/03/thinking-out-loud-targeting-the-real-problem/</guid>
      <description>Two (relatively) independent thought streams collided late last week, and this post is the result.
The first thought stream was about the benefits and drawbacks of OpenFlow. As I&amp;rsquo;ve said on many occasions, every technology decision has benefits and drawbacks. OpenFlow is no exception, in my opinion. Clearly there are some real benefits to using OpenFlow in certain use cases (here&amp;rsquo;s one example), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean OpenFlow&amp;mdash;especially hop-by-hop OpenFlow, where OpenFlow is involved at every &amp;ldquo;hop&amp;rdquo; of the packet forwarding process throughout the network&amp;mdash;is the right solution for all environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/03/05/technology-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 18:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/03/05/technology-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #30. This Technology Short Take is a bit heavy on the networking side, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s understandable given my recent job change. Enjoy!
Networking   Ben Cherian, Chief Strategy Officer for Midokura, helps make a case for network virtualization. (Note: Midokura makes a network virtualization solution.) If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering about network virtualization and why there is a focus on it, this post might help shed some light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #24, another instance of my irregularly-published collection of links, thoughts, and rants on various data center technologies like networking, operating systems, security, hardware, virtualization, and cloud computing. This is a slightly shorter version of my Technology Short Takes; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down since some readers have indicated the previous Short Takes weren&amp;rsquo;t short enough. Anyway, I hope you find something useful.
Networking   This page is a decent reference to the open source software-defined networking (SDN) projects that are out there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
