<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reInvent2017 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/reinvent2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reInvent2017 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/reinvent2017/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2017 Keynote with Andy Jassy</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/29/aws-reinvent-2017-keynote-andy-jassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/29/aws-reinvent-2017-keynote-andy-jassy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the re:Invent 2017 keynote with Andy Jassy, taking place on Wednesday at the Venetian. As fully expected given the long queues and massive crowds, even arriving an hour early to the keynote isn&amp;rsquo;t soon enough; there&amp;rsquo;s already a huge crowd gathered to make it into the venue. Fortunately, I did make it in and scored a reasonable seat from which to write this liveblog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Deep Dive on Amazon Elastic File System</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/28/deep-dive-amazon-elastic-file-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/28/deep-dive-amazon-elastic-file-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent 2017 session titled &amp;ldquo;Deep Dive on Amazon Elastic File System (EFS).&amp;rdquo; The presenters are Edward Naim and Darryl Osborne, both with AWS. This is my last session of day 2 of re:Invent; thus far, most of my time has been spent in hands-on workshops with only a few breakout sessions today. EFS is a topic I&amp;rsquo;ve watched, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to really dig into, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: IPv6 in the Cloud - Protocol and Service Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/28/ipv6-in-cloud-protocol-service-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/28/ipv6-in-cloud-protocol-service-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of an AWS re:Invent 2017 breakout session titled &amp;ldquo;IPv6 in the Cloud: Protocol and Service Overview.&amp;rdquo; The presenter&amp;rsquo;s name is Alan Halachmi, who is a Senior Manager of Solutions Architecture at AWS. As with so many of the other breakout sessions and workshops here at re:Invent this year, the queues to get into the session are long and it&amp;rsquo;s expected that the session will be completely full.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
