<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vCloud on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vcloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vCloud on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vcloud/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #34</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #34, my latest collection of links, articles, thoughts, and ideas from around the web, centered on key data center technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   Henry Louwers has a nice write-up on some of the design considerations that go into selecting a Citrix NetScaler solution.
  Scott Hogg explores jumbo frames and their benefits/drawbacks in a clear and concise manner. It&amp;rsquo;s worth reading if you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with jumbo frames and some of the considerations around their use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #33</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #33, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles discussing various data center technology-related links, articles, rants, thoughts, and questions. I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking   Tom Nolle asks the question, &amp;ldquo;Is virtualization reality even more elusive than virtual reality?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a good read; the key thing that I took away from it was that SDN, NFV, and related efforts are great, but what we really need is something that can pull all these together in a way that customers (and providers) reap the benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #26</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #26! As you might already know, the Technology Short Takes are my irregularly-published collections of links, articles, thoughts, and (sometimes) rants. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   Chris Colotti, as part of a changed focus in his role at VMware, has been working extensively with Nicira NVP. He&amp;rsquo;s had a couple of good posts; this one is a primer on how NVP works, and this one discusses the use of the Open vSwitch (OVS) vApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/05/technology-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/05/technology-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #25, my irregularly-published collection of links, articles, thoughts, and rants. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last Technology Short Take (almost three months!); my apologies for that. This is my first time publishing a Technology Short Take with my new filesystem-based approach of managing resources. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how well it goes
In any case, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with it!
Networking   Some folks from Nicira (now part of VMware) recently published a blog post discussing the OVSDB IETF draft (see here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #19, the first Technology Short Take for 2012. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s first collection of links, articles, and thoughts regarding virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center technology-related topics. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   While configuration limits aren&amp;rsquo;t the most exciting reading, they are important from time to time. Here&amp;rsquo;s some configuration limits for the UCS 6100 and 6200 series.
  Understanding the differences&amp;mdash;both positive and negative&amp;mdash;between the various approaches to solving a particular challenge is a key skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #18</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 23:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #18! I hope you find something useful in this collection of networking, OS, storage, and virtualization links. Enjoy!
Networking The number of articles in my &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo; bucket continues to overflow; I have so many articles on so many topics (soft switching, OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, MPLS) that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get my head wrapped around all of it. Here are a few posts that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining VXLAN</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/02/examining-vxlan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/02/examining-vxlan/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s taken me far too long to write this post, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure. Since the announcement of VXLAN at VMworld earlier in the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been searching for additional information on these questions: &amp;ldquo;What is VXLAN? How does it fit into the broader networking landscape? Why did we need a new standard?&amp;rdquo; I talked to Cisco, I attended a VMworld session about networking futures, I talked to some of the authors of the IETF draft on VXLAN, I read (most of) the VXLAN draft, and I studied some existing protocols that one might think could have been put to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #17</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #17, another of my irregularly-scheduled collections of various data center technology-related links, thoughts, and comments. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   I think it was J Metz of Cisco that posted this to Twitter, but this is a good reference to the various 10 Gigabit Ethernet modules.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken quite a bit about stretched clusters and their potential benefits. For an opposing view&amp;mdash;especially regarding the use of stretched clusters as a disaster avoidance solution&amp;mdash;check out this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #16</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/07/technology-short-take-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/07/technology-short-take-16/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #16. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while since my last Technology Short Take (a month!), and I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing (so readers didn&amp;rsquo;t have to listen to my rambling) or a bad thing (readers missing out on what I hope are useful or interesting links). In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s my latest collection of various data center-related links, articles, and thoughts. Thanks for reading!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #14</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #14, another collection of links and tidbits of information I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last few weeks. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Networking Much of my focus in the networking space recently has been around virtualization-centric initiatives, so the items on this list might seem a bit skewed in that direction. Sorry!
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some reading on 802.1Qbg (Edge Virtual Bridging). I still have a long way to go, but I think that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to better understand this draft and the problem(s) it&amp;rsquo;s attempting to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2011 Monday General Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vmworld-2011-monday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 18:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vmworld-2011-monday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>This is the session blog for the Monday general session. I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to have arrived in time to get a seat at the blogger/press/analyst tables. While the network connectivity is good, the power is&amp;mdash;unfortunately&amp;mdash;not so good.
The general session started with an impressive lightshow across the front of the conference that depicts the change of computing with the advent of virtualization and cloud computing. It was visually appealing and interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware&#39;s Launch Event</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/vmwares-launch-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 13:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/vmwares-launch-event/</guid>
      <description>Today was a big day for VMware. I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide some summary coverage of the products launched today, but only a quick recap; I&amp;rsquo;ll have more in-depth analysis and information on the products and their key features and improvements in future blog posts. No doubt there is going to be plenty of other coverage on the launch as well, and I&amp;rsquo;ll likely produce a special &amp;ldquo;Short Takes&amp;rdquo; episode with a summary of some of the related links, so look for that as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #12: Networking Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve published the Storage Edition of Technology Short Take #12, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Networking Edition. Enjoy, and I hope you find something useful!
  Ron Fuller&amp;rsquo;s ongoing deep dive series on OTV (Overlay Transport Virtualization) has been great for me. I knew about the basics of OTV, but Ron&amp;rsquo;s articles really gave me a better understanding of the technology. Check out the first three articles here: part 1, part 2, and part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #5</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/09/technology-short-take-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2010 11:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/09/technology-short-take-5/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #5, the latest collection of data center technology-related links, articles, blog posts, thoughts, and ideas. Some of this might be useful, some of it might not be helpful, but hopefully it will prove handy to someone out there. Enjoy!
  Brian Norris (of Going Virtual) recently posted a couple of useful &amp;ldquo;gotchas&amp;rdquo; about EMC Avamar and VMware Site Recovery Manager with EMC CLARiiON arrays. The issue with Avamar involves renaming the Default Virtual Machine Group and is a known issue that will be addressed in a future release; for now, the workaround (as also described by Brian) is either to not rename the Default Virtual Machine Group or not use it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
