<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CoreOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/coreos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CoreOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/coreos/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting CentOS Atomic Host</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/25/revisiting-centos-atomic-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/25/revisiting-centos-atomic-host/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, I wrote an article about how I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/08/choosing-coreos-over-atomic/&#34;&gt;choosing CoreOS over Project Atomic&lt;/a&gt; based on some initial testing with CentOS Atomic Host builds. As it turns out&amp;mdash;and as I pointed out in the &amp;ldquo;Update&amp;rdquo; section of that article&amp;mdash;the Atomic Host builds I was using were pre-release builds, and therefore it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really appropriate to form an assessment based on pre-release builds. Now that both &lt;a href=&#34;https://projectatomic.io/&#34;&gt;CentOS Atomic Host&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://coreos.com/&#34;&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt; Container Linux have both grown and matured, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d revisit the topic and see how&amp;mdash;if at all&amp;mdash;things have changed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easily Finding the Latest CoreOS AMI ID</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/29/easily-finding-latest-coreos-ami-id/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/29/easily-finding-latest-coreos-ami-id/</guid>
      <description>It seems as if finding the right Amazon Machine Image (AMI) ID for the workload you&amp;rsquo;d like to deploy can sometimes be a bit of a challenge. Each combination of region and AMI produces a unique ID, so you have to look up the AMI for the particular region where you&amp;rsquo;re going to deploy the workload. This in and of itself wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so bad, but then you have to wade through multiple versions of the same AMI in each region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #71</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #71! As always, I have a list of links related to various data center technologies found below; hopefully something here proves useful.
Networking  Dmitri Kalintsev is back with another article in a series of articles on using hardware VXLAN tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) with VMware NSX. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s on validating HW VTEP deployment for integration with NSX. In particular, Dmitri points out that you need connectivity both on the management plane as well as on the data plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Terraform to Build an etcd2 Cluster on OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/06/using-terraform-etcd2-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/06/using-terraform-etcd2-openstack/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll build on my earlier introduction to Terraform to show a practical example of using Terraform to build a CoreOS-based etcd2 cluster on OpenStack. This information is based upon a demo that I created for a session at the Austin OpenStack Summit in late April, so all the files I reference in this post are available in the GitHub repo for that session.
You may recall that Terraform is a platform-independent orchestration tool that allows you to create configurations (in either Terraform format or JSON format) specifying resources to be created/modified/deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #62</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #62. Sorry for the long delay since the last TST; some global travel has really thrown my schedule off. In any case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until Friday (the day I normally publish these) so I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there sooner. Enjoy!
Networking  PowerNSX is pretty cool&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a set of PowerShell cmdlets for administrators of VMware NSX running in vSphere environments. Check out Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s introductory post on PowerNSX for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #61</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #61. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to find a nice range of articles and links, so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I was successful and that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking  Along with the release of rkt 1.0 (see below in the &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems/Applications&amp;rdquo; section), Metaswitch has announced a Container Networking Interface (CNI) plugin for Project Calico. (This appears to be primarily through the Calico plugin for Kubernetes and Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; support for CNI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #60</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #60. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered what I hope to be a useful but varied collection of articles and links on key data center technologies. I hope something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be helpful&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking  The rise of Linux in importance in the networking industry continues, with Arista announcing enhancements to Arista EOS to support&amp;mdash;among other things&amp;mdash;Docker containers. (See this SDx Central article or this Network World article for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #58</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/18/technology-short-take-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/18/technology-short-take-58/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #58. This will be the last Technology Short Take of 2015, as next week is Christmas and the following week is the New Year&amp;rsquo;s holiday. Before I present this episode&amp;rsquo;s collection of links, articles, and thoughts on various data center technologies, allow me to first wish all of my readers a very merry and very festive holiday season. Now, on to the content!
Networking  Looking for a step-by-step install guide for VMware NSX?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #56</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #56! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a few links on various data center technologies, news, events, and trends. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking  Open Virtual Network (OVN) is really ramping up and getting lots of attention, which I personally think is absolutely well-deserved. Russell Bryant has a couple great articles on OVN&amp;mdash;how to test OVN&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;EZ Bake&amp;rdquo; release with DevStack as well as an article on implementing OpenStack security groups using OVN ACLs (which in turn leverage the integration between Open vSwitch and the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s conntrack module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing CoreOS over Project Atomic</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/08/choosing-coreos-over-atomic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/08/choosing-coreos-over-atomic/</guid>
      <description>Upon hearing the news that Red Hat had released the Atomic Host variant of Red Hat Enterprise Linux, I decided that it would be a good idea for me to take a look at the CentOS flavor of the Atomic Host variant. In case you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar, the Atomic Host variant is the result of Project Atomic, which aimed to provide a container-optimized flavor of RHEL/CentOS/Fedora. This container-optimized flavor would leverage rpm-ostree for atomic system updates (hence the name) and come with Docker preinstalled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling and Mounting NFS on CoreOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/20/config-mount-nfs-coreos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 10:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/20/config-mount-nfs-coreos/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about CoreOS a fair amount (see here, here, and here), but one of the things that is both good and bad about CoreOS is the automatic update mechanism. It&amp;rsquo;s good because you know your systems will stay up to date, but it&amp;rsquo;s bad if you haven&amp;rsquo;t taken the time to properly address how automatic updates will affect your environment (for example, you&amp;rsquo;ve manually started some Docker containers instead of using systemd unit files&amp;mdash;when the CoreOS system reboots after an update, your Docker containers will no longer be running).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Vagrant with CoreOS, etcd, fleet, and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/05/vagrant-coreos-etcd-fleet-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 11:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/05/vagrant-coreos-etcd-fleet-docker/</guid>
      <description>As a follow-up to my recent #vBrownBag session on &amp;ldquo;Docker and Friends,&amp;rdquo; I wanted to provide a quick and relatively easy way for VMware administrators to experiment with some of the technologies I demonstrated. Since not everyone has their own OpenStack cloud running in their basement, Vagrant seemed like a reasonable solution. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use Vagrant to experiment with some of the technologies I demonstrated in the #vBrownBag session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoreOS Continued: Fleet and Docker</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/20/coreos-continued-fleet-and-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/20/coreos-continued-fleet-and-docker/</guid>
      <description>This post is the third in a series of posts on CoreOS, this time focusing on the use of fleet and Docker to deploy containers across a cluster of systems. This post builds on my earlier introduction to CoreOS and the subsequent more in-depth look at etcd.
I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that you&amp;rsquo;re already reasonably familiar with CoreOS, etcd, and Docker. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with CoreOS or etcd, have a look at the links in the previous paragraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoreOS Continued: etcd</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/18/coreos-continued-etcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/18/coreos-continued-etcd/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to build on my earlier introduction to CoreOS by taking a slightly more detailed look at etcd. etcd is a distributed key-value store (more on that in a moment) and is one of the key technologies that I feel distinguishes CoreOS from other Linux distributions.
etcd is not, of course, the only distributed key-value store in town. Zookeeper is another very well-known distributed information store. I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on etcd here for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying CoreOS on OpenStack Using Heat</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/13/deploying-coreos-on-openstack-using-heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/13/deploying-coreos-on-openstack-using-heat/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to illustrate one way to deploy CoreOS on OpenStack using Heat. By no means is this intended to be seen as the only way to use Heat to deploy CoreOS, but rather as one way of using Heat to deploy CoreOS. I&amp;rsquo;m publishing this in the hopes that others will be able to use this as a building block for their own deployments.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t already familiar with OpenStack Heat or CoreOS, you might want to take a moment and refer to this introductory posts for some foundational information:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
