<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2006 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2006/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2006 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 22:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2006/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2006 Day 3 and Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/09/vmworld-2006-day-3-and-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2006 22:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/09/vmworld-2006-day-3-and-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>Given that my employer is a big partner of both VMware and Network Appliance, I was particularly looking forward to the session on using NetApp SnapMirror to provide business continuity/disaster recovery for virtual machines hosted on ESX Server. Unfortunately, the session turned out&amp;mdash;in my opinion, at least&amp;mdash;to be more marketing fluff than solid technical information. I did pick up a couple of useful ideas and a few technical tips, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as technical as I had hoped it would be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2006 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/08/vmworld-2006-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 10:40:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/08/vmworld-2006-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>The majority of the keynote was handled by Mendel Rosenblum, cofounder of VMware and an operating system researcher who also teaches OS classes at Stanford University. Mendel spoke at length about the functions of the virtualization layer and how those functions might be extended and/or enhanced.
While nothing was officially announced, Mendel did demonstrate the idea of using the virtualization layer to capture or record a stream of execution by a virtual machine (VM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2006 Day 1, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/08/vmworld-2006-day-1-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2006 10:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/08/vmworld-2006-day-1-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, here&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; is a relative term. It&amp;rsquo;s just that some of the presentations were really top-notch, and some of the presentations were&amp;hellip;well, not. Some speakers clearly had been &amp;ldquo;on platform&amp;rdquo; before, but others just as clearly had no prior platform experience as a speaker.
After the general session ended this morning, I went into one of my two hands-on labs, this one focused on VMware Consolidated Backup. The lab staff were very technical, very understandable, and appeared to be quite approachable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2006 Day 1, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/07/vmworld-2006-day-1-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 18:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/07/vmworld-2006-day-1-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Diane Greene got up and spoke first during the general session again this morning, going over more of the same information as was discussed yesterday during her presentation. It&amp;rsquo;s good material, yes, but nothing new or original, so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t terribly interesting or helpful to me. More interesting to me were the two panel discussions that took place, one on virtual appliances and one on the industry perspective on virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner Day at VMworld 2006</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/07/partner-day-at-vmworld-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2006 09:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/07/partner-day-at-vmworld-2006/</guid>
      <description>Karthik Rau (the Vice President of Product Management) focused on the technology factors that combined to drive virtualization to today&amp;rsquo;s levels. These were factors such as the increasing adoption of x86-based servers, the continuing progression of Moore&amp;rsquo;s Law, and the emergence of Linux as a viable alternative to Windows. He also discussed emerging trends that will continue to drive the adoption of virtualization, such as multi-core processors. It&amp;rsquo;s quite true that as the hardware scales up to quad-core and 8-core CPUs, no single workload (or application) will generally be able to take full advantage of all that computing power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
