<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DNS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DNS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dns/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 146</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #146! Over the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a few technology-related links for you all. There&amp;rsquo;s some networking stuff, a few security links, and even a hardware-related article. But enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get into the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 134</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/25/technology-short-take-134/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 08:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/25/technology-short-take-134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #134! I&amp;rsquo;m publishing a bit early this time due to the Thanksgiving holiday in the US. So, for all my US readers, here&amp;rsquo;s some content to peruse while enjoying some turkey (or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re having this year). For my international readers, here&amp;rsquo;s some content to peruse while enjoying dramatically lower volumes of e-mail because the US is on holiday. See, something for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 131</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/10/02/technology-short-take-131/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/10/02/technology-short-take-131/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #131! I&amp;rsquo;m back with another collection of articles on various data center technologies. This time around the content is a tad heavy on the security side, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to pull in articles on networking, cloud computing, applications, and some programming-related content. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with Docker, Registrator, and Consul</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/28/experimenting-docker-registrator-consul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/28/experimenting-docker-registrator-consul/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with Docker, Registrator, and Consul in an effort to explore some of the challenges involved in building a robust containerized infrastructure. While I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished fully exploring the idea (and documenting what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned), I did discover one interesting&amp;mdash;and unexpected&amp;mdash;interaction.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick overview of my testing environment:
 I used two OpenStack Heat templates to spin up two clusters of 5 instances each.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
