<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CiscoLive2011 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ciscolive2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CiscoLive2011 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 11:17:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ciscolive2011/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Summary of Cisco Live 2011 Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/15/summary-of-cisco-live-2011-blog-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 11:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/15/summary-of-cisco-live-2011-blog-posts/</guid>
      <description>This past week I had the opportunity to attend Cisco Live 2011 in Las Vegas. Along the way, I was blogging the sessions that I attended. To help make it easy to find the material, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d provide a quick &amp;ldquo;roll-up&amp;rdquo; post that summarizes not only the posts I published but also some posts from other bloggers. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that this list will not be comprehensive, but if you have additional posts/links you think I should add, let me know in the comments and I&amp;rsquo;ll update the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-9131: Mobility and Virtualization with LISP and OTV</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-9131-mobility-and-virtualization-with-lisp-and-otv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-9131-mobility-and-virtualization-with-lisp-and-otv/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKDCT-9131, Mobility and Virtualization in the Data Center with LISP and OTV. This is one of the last, if not the last, session at Cisco Live 2011.
The presenter, Victor Moreno, spends a few minutes at first talking about distributed data center clouds, the goals, and the challenges of building them. Some of the challenges or considerations include:
  L2 domain elasticity (think FabricPath and LAN extensions)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKSAN-3707: Advanced SAN Services</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKSAN-3707, Advanced SAN Services, presented by Mike Dunn.
According to TIP&amp;rsquo;s Storage Research, the top five storage initiatives are deduplication, technology refresh, tiered storage build-out, archiving, and consolidation.
The three main sections of the presentation are SAN consolidation with virtualization, tiered storage and backup design, and Fibre Channel over Ethernet (FCoE).
The presentation starts with SAN consolidation using virtualization. This is really a discussion of virtual SANs (VSANs), which allow you to consolidate SANs onto the same hardware but still providing logical separation of fabrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-3060: Deployment Considerations with Interconnecting DCs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-3060-deployment-considerations-with-interconnecting-dcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-3060-deployment-considerations-with-interconnecting-dcs/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKDCT-3060, Deployment Considerations with Interconnecting Data Centers, presented by Patrice Bellagamba (Distinguished SE) and Max Ardica (Solution Architect). Given that my role in virtualization and storage puts me squarely in the middle of these sorts of designs, I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to this session and gaining some valuable knowledge out of it.
The primary objectives of the session are to identify the business requirements driving DCI (Data Center Interconnect) deployments; understanding the functional components of the Cisco DCI solution; and get a full knowledge of Cisco LAN extension technologies and associated considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-2121: Virtual Device Context Design and Implementation Considerations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/13/brkdct-2121-virtual-device-context-design-and-implementation-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 22:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/13/brkdct-2121-virtual-device-context-design-and-implementation-considerations/</guid>
      <description>I joined this session late (a last minute change from the UCS VM-FEX session). This session is on VDC design considerations with the Nexus 7000, presented by Ron Fuller, CCIE #5851 (@ccie5851 on Twitter).
A VDC (virtual device context) is a &amp;ldquo;superstructure&amp;rdquo; that encapsulates (or encompasses) both VLANs and VRFs. Each VDC maintains its own VLAN table and its own VRF instances. There are some resources that are global (not dedicated to a particular VDC); these would include things like a boot image configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-2081: Cisco FabricPath Technology and Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkdct-2081-cisco-fabricpath-technology-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 16:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkdct-2081-cisco-fabricpath-technology-and-design/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKDCT-2081, Cisco FabricPath Technology and Design. FabricPath is (to my understanding) Cisco&amp;rsquo;s implementation of TRILL, and as a key data center technology this is something I&amp;rsquo;m very interested in learning. Tim Stevenson is the presenter.
FabricPath is a technology to drive Layer 2 in the data center. Why Layer 2 in the data center? Because customers are asking for it! The presenter casually mentions &amp;ldquo;applications that require Layer 2 adjacency,&amp;rdquo; and of course my first thought is the VLAN spanning requirements for vMotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKCOM-3002: Network Redundancy and Load Balancing Designs for UCS Blade Servers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkcom-3002-network-redundancy-and-load-balancing-designs-for-ucs-blade-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2011 11:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/12/brkcom-3002-network-redundancy-and-load-balancing-designs-for-ucs-blade-servers/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKCOM-3002, Network Redundancy and Load Balancing Designs for UCS Blade Servers, presented by none other than M. Sean McGee (available as @mseanmcgee on Twitter; I highly recommend you follow him on Twitter if you are interested in UCS). I was really looking forward to this presentation, as I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken with Sean before and I know that he is a super-sharp UCS guru. Sean also blogs here.
Sean starts out the presentation by asking, &amp;ldquo;Do you know how UCS networking thinks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKMPL-1101: Introduction to MPLS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/11/brkmpl-1101-introduction-to-mpls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 16:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/11/brkmpl-1101-introduction-to-mpls/</guid>
      <description>This session is BRKMPL-1101, Introduction to MPLS (Multiprotocol Label Switching). The presenter is Hari Rakotoranto, a product manager for MPLS at Cisco. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this session as I&amp;rsquo;ve always heard a lot about MPLS, but haven&amp;rsquo;t ever had the opportunity to really learn more about it. Hopefully this session won&amp;rsquo;t be too far over my head.
MPLS is used for a variety of purposes; two of the most common are Layer 3 VPNs and Layer 2 VPNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKCRS-2031: Multilayer Campus Architectures and Design Principles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/11/brkcrs-2031-multilayer-campus-architectures-and-design-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 13:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/11/brkcrs-2031-multilayer-campus-architectures-and-design-principles/</guid>
      <description>This session is BRKCRS-2031, Multilayer Campus Architectures and Design Principles. The presenter is Mark Montaez, a Principal Engineer in the Office of the CTO at Cisco.
The session focuses on the basics of building a rock-solid campus design, providing a foundation for more advanced campus design sessions available later this week at Cisco Live.
One goal of campus design is to drive down convergence, ideally to the 200 ms goal. The human ear will notice drops in 150 to 200 ms, and video is even worse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
