<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2012 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2012 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:02:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2012/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EMEA Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/10/vmworld-emea-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 13:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/10/vmworld-emea-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the keynote at Day 2 of VMworld EMEA in Barcelona, Spain. Sorry for the lack of a liveblog for yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote; I was tied up in other meetings.
At 9:02 AM, Steve Herrod takes the stage. Herrod sets the stage that today will focus primarily on end-user computing, providing a recap of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s discussions around infrastructure and management. He starts out with a review of &amp;ldquo;the old way&amp;rdquo; of doing things versus the increasingly-popular &amp;ldquo;new way&amp;rdquo; (which often involves BYOD, tablets, mobile devices, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A VMworld 2012 Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/10/a-vmworld-2012-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 17:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/10/a-vmworld-2012-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>Now that a week or so has passed, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post a quick &amp;ldquo;link review&amp;rdquo; of VMworld 2012. Think of this like a VMworld-specific version of Technology Short Takes.
Liveblogging Posts A number of folks were liveblogging the conference keynotes and conference sessions. As I have in years past, I also posted a few liveblogs where possible. Here are some links:
Rick Scherer: VMworld 2012 San Francisco - Live Blogging</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APP-CAP2956: Inside the Hadoop Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/30/app-cap2956-inside-the-hadoop-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/30/app-cap2956-inside-the-hadoop-machine/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for APP-CAP2956, Inside The Hadoop Machine. Presenting are Jeff Buell (VMware), Richard McDougall (VMware), and Sanjay Radia (Hortonworks).
Some use cases for Hadoop include log processing, click stream analysis, machine learning, web crawling, and image/XML processing. But what is Hadoop? Hadoop is a programming framework for enabling parallel processing; this enables distributed processing of large data sets across clusters of computers. Hadoop also incorporates that machines will fail, and is tolerant of those failures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INF-BCO2655: FT for SMP VMs Tech Preview</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/inf-bco2655-ft-for-smp-vms-tech-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 16:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/inf-bco2655-ft-for-smp-vms-tech-preview/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for INF-BCO2655, titled &amp;ldquo;VMware vSphere Fault Tolerance for Multiprocessor Virtual Machines - Technical Preview.&amp;rdquo; The presenters are both from VMware (naturally); they are Jim Chow and Shrinand Javadekar. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what progress has been made on this front since the last time VMware spoke about the possibility of multi-vCPU FT.
The session starts with a quick review of the various vSphere protection mechanisms: NIC teaming, storage multipathing (component failure); HA, FT (host failure), SRM (site failure).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APP-CAP2165: Operating Cloud Foundry</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/app-cap2165-operating-cloud-foundry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 13:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/app-cap2165-operating-cloud-foundry/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for APP-CAP2165, Operating Cloud Foundry. The speakers are Mark Kropf, Brian McClain, and Dave McCrory (formerly of VMware and now with Warner Music Group). I have no previous experience with Cloud Foundry so I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to this session.
The agenda reveals that the majority of the discussion today will focus on BOSH, which is an open source project that was developed largely with Cloud Foundry in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2012 Keynote, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/vmworld-2012-keynote-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 10:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/28/vmworld-2012-keynote-day-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a live (or reasonably live) blog for the day 2 keynote at VMworld 2012 in San Francisco, CA.
At 8:35 AM, Steve Herrod takes the stage, after joining in with the VMworld 2012 drummers. He sets the stage by indicating that a pretty significant portion of this morning&amp;rsquo;s keynote will be focused on VMware&amp;rsquo;s end-user computing (EUC) vision and the delivery of that vision. Recall that VMware has talked about a number of different components in their EUC vision: mobile phone virtualization, virtual desktop infrastructure, application virtualization, application management, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INF-VSP1423: esxtop for Advanced Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/inf-vsp1423-esxtop-for-advanced-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/inf-vsp1423-esxtop-for-advanced-users/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for INF-VSP1423, esxtop for Advanced Users, at VMworld 2012 in San Francisco, CA. The presenter is Krishna Raj Raja from VMware.
The presenter starts out the session with an explanation of how the session is going to proceed. This year&amp;mdash;this session has been presented multiple years at multiple VMworld conferences&amp;mdash;he&amp;rsquo;s choosing to focus on exposing the inner workings of the ESXi hypervisor through esxtop. High-level topics include NUMA, CPU usage, host cache, SR-IOV, and managing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2012 Keynote, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/vmworld-2012-keynote-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 10:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/vmworld-2012-keynote-day-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog from the keynote on Day 1 of VMworld 2012 in San Francisco, CA.
As usual, the keynote starts out with a video playing across the massive screens in Hall D of Moscone North. Michael Dell kicks off the vidoes, followed by the predictably flashy and well-produced EMC segment on transforming IT. Next up are videos by HP and NetApp. Apparently part of the package for a Platinum/Diamond sponsorship is a free video at the top of the day 1 keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VMworld 2012 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/21/my-vmworld-2012-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 09:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/21/my-vmworld-2012-schedule/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year again&amp;mdash;time for VMworld! As I&amp;rsquo;ve done in years past (although I&amp;rsquo;m late getting this information published this year), I&amp;rsquo;m posting my VMworld schedule here. I do this for two reasons. First, it may spur someone to look at a session that perhaps they hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered before (or it may spur me to look at a different session due to feedback!). Second, I often get requests to meet, and posting my schedule here along with a link to my Google calendar helps streamline that process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spouse Activities at VMworld 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/27/spouse-activities-at-vmworld-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 19:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/27/spouse-activities-at-vmworld-2012/</guid>
      <description>As most of you are well aware, VMworld 2012 in San Francisco, CA, is nearly upon us. I, for one, am really looking forward to the conference. And along with VMworld comesthat&amp;rsquo;s right, Spousetivities!
I wanted to take only a moment to highlight some of the stuff that Crystal has planned for this year at VMworld. This is the fifth year that Crystal is running activities for spouses, family members, and friends traveling with conference attendees, and she has some really great tours and activities planned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on a VMworld Unconference</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thoughts-on-a-vmworld-unconference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 18:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thoughts-on-a-vmworld-unconference/</guid>
      <description>So the &amp;ldquo;good news/bad news&amp;rdquo; that is the VMworld submission acceptance/denial notifications happened today. As is typically the case, lots of very talented people submitted proposals for what I&amp;rsquo;m sure are very informative and useful sessions were turned down. As a result, a lot of ideas were being tossed around about some sort of &amp;ldquo;unconference&amp;rdquo; where speakers whose sessions were not accepted could have an opportunity to speak.
Here are some of the ideas that were/are being tossed about:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
