<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consul on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/consul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consul on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/consul/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HashiConf 2017 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/hashiconf-2017-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/hashiconf-2017-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog from the day 1 keynote (general session) at HashiConf 2017 in Austin, TX. I&amp;rsquo;m attending HashiConf this year as an &amp;ldquo;ordinary attendee&amp;rdquo; (not working or speaking), and so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being able to actually sit in on sessions for a change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 84</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #84! This episode is a bit late (sorry about that!), but I figured better late than never, right? OK, bring on the links!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 82</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #82! This issue is a bit behind schedule; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty heads-down on some projects. That work will come to fruition in a couple weeks, so I should be able to come up for some air soon. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links and articles for your reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #74</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #74! The end of 2016 is nearly upon us, and it looks as if there will be only one more Technology Short Take before the end of the year. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with the content&amp;mdash;time is short!
Networking  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apstra, David Varnum has a great introduction to Apstra available on his site. Will Robinson talks about how to structure your Ansible playbooks in the context of using Ansible to control your network gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #64</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #64. Normally, I try to publish Short Takes on Friday, but this past Friday was April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day. Given the propensity for &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; information to get lost among all the pranks, I decided to push this article back to today. Unlike most of what is published around April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day, hopefully everything here is helpful, informative, and useful!
Networking  Phil Gervasi has an article on fate sharing in the network core, where he discusses some of the advantages&amp;mdash;and disadvantages&amp;mdash;of centralizing the control plane in network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Scaling New Services</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/scaling-new-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/23/scaling-new-services/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the DockerCon 2015 session titled &amp;ldquo;Scaling New Services: From Container Creation to Automated Deployments&amp;rdquo;. This session is being led by the Disney Systems Engineering team and will feature a discussion/demo involving Docker, Mesos, Chef, Consul, and HAProxy.
The session starts with an introduction by Alex Williams, founder of The New Stack, who quickly turns it over to the Disney staff&amp;mdash;Brian Scott and Patrick O&amp;rsquo;Connor. Brian starts with an overview of all the various companies within Disney, and the challenges that breadth creates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
