<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bladevrack on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/bladevrack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bladevrack on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 16:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/bladevrack/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Four, HP Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
Welcome to Part 4 in our series on blades and virtualization. Please note that I will be covering the HP virtualized I/O offerings in a near future post. I plan to cover Virtual Connect, Flex-10, and the BL495 blade at that time.
As always, lets start by reviewing the hardware specification we will be using to compare the rack servers against the blade servers. Here are the portions of the spec that concern us:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Three, IBM Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
UPDATE: I have made some corrections to the 10GB and iSCSI sections based on feedback. Thank you!
Welcome to part 3 of my series on blades and virtualization. I will be breaking the expansion articles into four parts: traditional IBM options, traditional HP options, virtualized IBM options, and virtualized HP options. By &amp;ldquo;virtualized options&amp;rdquo; I mean the IBM and HP blade I/O virtualization solutions (like IBM Blade Open Fabric Manager and HP VirtualConnect), not a server configuration that will run virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Two, IBM Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This is the second part of a series of articles on blades and virtualization. The first article is found here. Today, I will present IBM rack servers versus blade servers and explore the power consumption for each.
In case you need it again, here is the hardware platform I will be using as the standard:
 2 x E5450 3.0 Ghz quad-core processors 32 GB memory in an 8 x 4GB configuration 2 on-board NICs Additional quad NIC card for a total of 6 NICs Dual FC card (assuming FC SAN storage for VMs but it could easily be NFS or iSCSI as well) 2 x 146GB, 10k SAS drives (except the IBM HS21XM blades which only support one HD)  Here is the link to the IBM System x and Blade Power Configuration Tool I used for the numbers below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part One, HP Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
I have seen a lot of misconceptions recently when it comes to blade servers and virtualization. Many seem to think that if you are using blades you can&amp;rsquo;t use virtualization. Most recently, someone shared this article with me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t disagree with this viewpoint more. I will explore the reasons why in the next few articles. For today&amp;rsquo;s article, I will present a foundation for comparison and I will use this basis going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
