<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMwareFT on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwareft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMwareFT on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 16:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwareft/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuing the Consolidation Discussion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/26/continuing-the-consolidation-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 16:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/26/continuing-the-consolidation-discussion/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick post inspired by Mike Laverick&amp;rsquo;s recent &amp;ldquo;Stupid IT&amp;rdquo; post, in which he weighed in on the blog discussion between Steve Chambers and I regarding &amp;ldquo;putting all your eggs in one basket,&amp;rdquo; the most common argument against high consolidation ratios and, in some cases, against consolidation in general.
Mike&amp;rsquo;s articles&amp;ndash;part 1 and part 2&amp;ndash;are excellent articles. The interesting thing here is that, when you really boil it down, my viewpoint is not that far off from both Steve and Mike (spoiler warning: Mike agrees with Steve).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware HA, VMware FT, and OS Clustering</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/30/vmware-ha-vmware-ft-and-os-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/30/vmware-ha-vmware-ft-and-os-clustering/</guid>
      <description>With the release of VMware vSphere 4 earlier this year, VMware officially introduced VMware Fault Tolerance (VMware FT), a new mechanism for providing extremely high levels of availability to virtual machine workloads. As I&amp;rsquo;ve talked with customers, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a growing number of customers who are unaware of the differences between the types of high availability that VMware provides (in the form of VMware HA and VMware FT) and operating system-level clustering (such as Microsoft Windows Failover Clustering).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 12:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #30, my irregularly posted collection of links and thoughts on virtualization. I hope you find something useful here!
  I believe Jason Boche already mentioned this on his own blog (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link) and also started this VMware Communities thread discussing the fact that the 8/6 patch breaks FT compatibility between ESX and ESXi hosts in the same cluster. This VMware KB article is now available with more information on the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Reason Not to Use PVSCSI or VMXNET3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/05/another-reason-not-to-use-pvscsi-or-vmxnet3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2009 14:54:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/05/another-reason-not-to-use-pvscsi-or-vmxnet3/</guid>
      <description>You might have read the article I wrote here titled vSphere Virtual Machine Upgrade Process, in which I described a process whereby you could upgrade your VMs to VM hardware version 7 (the version used with vSphere) as well as use the latest paravirtualized network and SCSI drivers (VMXNET3 and PVSCSI). Both PVSCSI and VMXNET3 offer greater performance with the same CPU utilization.
Rightfully so, some readers and other bloggers pointed out that PVSCSI isn&amp;rsquo;t supported for boot disks (Rich Brambley put up a really good post, for example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>everRun VM, VMware HA, and VMware FT</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/everrun-vm-vmware-ha-and-vmware-ft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 11:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/everrun-vm-vmware-ha-and-vmware-ft/</guid>
      <description>Having previously discussed Marathon Technologies&amp;rsquo; everRun VM product in conjunction with XenServer HA as part of XenServer 5, I think that I have some useful information to bring to the recent discussion that has come to light about everRun VM vs. VMware HA vs. VMware FT.
Apparently, this discussion started with a blog entry by Marathon titled VMware FT - The Top Four Reasons it&amp;rsquo;s Kinda Sorta Fault Tolerance. Mike DiPetrillo of VMware responded from his personal blog, first tackling Marathon&amp;rsquo;s blog post and then again tackling comparisons posted on Marathon&amp;rsquo;s web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Keynote - Automating DR with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>There is no general session this morning at VMworld 2008; instead, a &amp;ldquo;keynote&amp;rdquo; will be delivered about automating disaster recovery (DR) using VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM). This is similar to the way in which other vendors have delivered various &amp;ldquo;keynotes&amp;rdquo; throughout the conference instead of all the announcements being crammed into the morning general sessions.
The speaker this morning is Jay Judkowitz, the product manager for VMware SRM. I&amp;rsquo;ve met Jay before; he&amp;rsquo;s a good guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC2621: Fault-Tolerant VMs in VI: Operations and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc2621-fault-tolerant-vms-in-vi-operations-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc2621-fault-tolerant-vms-in-vi-operations-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Well, it looks like wireless coverage pretty much stinks, so this will have to be published post-session as well.
This session is BC2621, titled &amp;ldquo;Fault Tolerant VMs in VMware Infrastructure: Operations and Best Practices&amp;rdquo;, presented by Dan Scales, Principal Engineer with VMware. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty full session, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky (unlucky?) enough to get a seat toward the front of the session.
This is a technical preview of VMware FT, a new feature that is slated to be included in VDC-OS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
