<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 09:04:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2008/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hyper9 Beta Invitations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/24/hyper9-beta-invitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 09:04:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/24/hyper9-beta-invitations/</guid>
      <description>Regular readers may recall that I met with Hyper9 during VMworld 2008 in Las Vegas. Check here for a summary of my discussion with Hyper9. Since that meeting, during which I had a chance to see the beta product, I&amp;rsquo;ve been in communication with David Marshall (of vmblog.com, who also works at Hyper9) and the rest of the Hyper9 crew about getting some private beta invitations for my readers.
Today I am happy to announce that I do have some beta invitations available to readers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take - VMworld 2008 Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/27/virtualization-short-take-vmworld-2008-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2008 12:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/27/virtualization-short-take-vmworld-2008-edition/</guid>
      <description>This edition of Virtualization Short Takes is mainly a collection of items from the VMworld 2008 conference in Las Vegas. Some of these are session transcripts from various bloggers; some are just VMworld-related blog posts.
  Blogger Rich Brambley has some great coverage of various VMworld sessions: BC3819, BC2370, PO2575, and VD3261, among others. Excellent work, Rich.
  The whole vStorage thing has prompted quite a flurry of attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PO2061: VMware VirtualCenter 2.5 Database Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/po2061-vmware-virtualcenter-25-database-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 18:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/po2061-vmware-virtualcenter-25-database-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>This is PO2061, VMware VirtualCenter 2.5 Database Best Practices. The presenter is Bruce McCready with VMware. My battery is starting to run low, so I may lose some or all of the rest of this session partly through the session. I have another battery that I can swap in if necessary.
The session starts out with the standard disclaimer. Most of this stuff is already out there, but the disclaimer is required anyway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PO1644: VMware Update Manager Performance and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/po1644-vmware-update-manager-performance-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 16:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/po1644-vmware-update-manager-performance-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>This is PO1644, VMware Update Manager Performance and Best Practices. The presenter is John Liang.
Covering some terminology before moving forward, the presenter covered the idea of a patch store (a location where patches are stored), baseline, compliance (the state of the host or VM when compared to the baseline; falls into compliant/not compliant/unknown/not applicable), scan (either VM scan or host scan; VM scans can be either online or offline); and remediation (the idea of applying patches to a host or VM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Liveblog for TA2441</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/no-liveblog-for-ta2441/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 14:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/no-liveblog-for-ta2441/</guid>
      <description>I originally had TA2441, VI3 Networking Concepts and Best Practices, on my schedule, but upon a close review of the agenda it looks like this is all stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. In fact, it looks like stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve written about quite extensively, so I&amp;rsquo;m skipping out on this session. Sorry to disappoint anyone!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA2644: Networking I/O Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/ta2644-networking-io-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 12:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/ta2644-networking-io-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>This is the liveblog for TA2644, Networking I/O Virtualization, presented by Pankaj Thakkar, Howie Xu, and Sean Varley.
The session starts out with yet another overview of VDC-OS. This session will focus on technologies that fall into the vNetwork infrastructure vService. The agenda for the session includes networking I/O virtualization, virtualized I/O, and VMDirectPath.
Starting out, the presenter first defines what exactly networking I/O virtualization is. Networking I/O virtualization is providing muxing/demuxing packets among VMs and the physical network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Keynote - Automating DR with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>There is no general session this morning at VMworld 2008; instead, a &amp;ldquo;keynote&amp;rdquo; will be delivered about automating disaster recovery (DR) using VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM). This is similar to the way in which other vendors have delivered various &amp;ldquo;keynotes&amp;rdquo; throughout the conference instead of all the announcements being crammed into the morning general sessions.
The speaker this morning is Jay Judkowitz, the product manager for VMware SRM. I&amp;rsquo;ve met Jay before; he&amp;rsquo;s a good guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More VMworld 2008 Day 2 Coverage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/more-vmworld-2008-day-2-coverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 21:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/more-vmworld-2008-day-2-coverage/</guid>
      <description>As I fully expected, another day at VMworld 2008 has passed and I seriously, seriously was not able to keep up with everything. I even blew off a session this afternoon that I really wanted to attend as well. Somebody, please&amp;mdash;can you give me good session notes on TA2275, VMware Infrastructure Virtual Networking Future Directions? I&amp;rsquo;d be very grateful!
In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s a round-up of more coverage of VMworld 2008 from various places around the Internet:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OVF Format Released, VMAN Initiative Launched</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/ovf-format-released-vman-initiative-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 20:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/ovf-format-released-vman-initiative-launched/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, September 16, 2008, the Distributed Management Task Force (DMTF) announced the release of the Open Virtualization Format (OVF) standard, along with a new management initiative called the Virtualization Management Initiative (VMAN). The full details are found here in the official press release.
&amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;Now, personally, I think they should have called it the vMan initiative so that we could continue the lowercase &amp;ldquo;v&amp;rdquo; thing that&amp;rsquo;s going on here at VMworld this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA2659: Managing ESX in a COS-less World</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/ta2659-managing-esx-in-a-cos-less-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 16:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/ta2659-managing-esx-in-a-cos-less-world/</guid>
      <description>This is TA2659, Managing ESX in a COS-less World. The focus here is on tools that allow you to manage ESX without using the Service Console.
When I arrived at the session, the presenter was discussing VMware&amp;rsquo;s goal to drive parity between the &amp;ldquo;actual&amp;rdquo; CLI present in the Service Console and the Remote CLI. There is a desire to ensure that any command that can be run on ESX or ESXi can also be run on the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VD2422: Offline VDI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/vd2422-offline-vdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 16:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/vd2422-offline-vdi/</guid>
      <description>This is VD2422, and the presenter is Chris Leroy from VMware.
I arrived at this session late (about 15 minutes late) after running into a customer in the Solutions Exchange. This session is about offline VDI, which is the ability for users to check out VMs and run them while disconnected from the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; VI environment.
As I came in, the presenter was showing off the check-out process, in which the user uses the VDM Client to check out a VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very Brief Thoughts on the Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/very-brief-thoughts-on-the-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 12:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/very-brief-thoughts-on-the-keynote/</guid>
      <description>Now that the keynote has wrapped up, I just wanted to post a few very brief thoughts, perhaps questions, about the keynote and the technologies and initiatives discussed.
First off, as I have seen others point out on the VMworld Twitter broadcast channel, I wonder how well AppSpeed&amp;rsquo;s remediation functionality would work with applications other than web-based applications. Not all applications can scale using additional VMs. Sure, you can generally scale web-based applications by throwing on more web server VMs, but what about Microsoft Exchange 2007?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2008 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/vmworld-2008-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2008 10:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/17/vmworld-2008-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>Today promises to be an easier keynote, since I actually managed to find the bloggers&amp;rsquo; tables (they actually exist) and get good wireless connectivity. In addition, today&amp;rsquo;s keynote should be more technical and feature-focused than Paul&amp;rsquo;s keynote yesterday. Refresh this page often, as I&amp;rsquo;ll be updating this post throughout the keynote.
The keynote starts off with a series of video testimonials about VMware&amp;rsquo;s drive forward in technology, about how applications are served better, about how availability is improved, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other VMworld 2008 Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/other-vmworld-2008-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 21:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/other-vmworld-2008-resources/</guid>
      <description>Clearly, I am having a much harder time covering VMworld 2008 than I had covering Tech-Ed or VMworld 2007. There&amp;rsquo;s just so much going on! In an effort to try to broaden the coverage, here are some links from other bloggers and resources:
Duncan Epping
vCenter (good overview of what vCenter is)
Expand Virtual Desktops with VMware View
Chad Sakac
So, what does vStorage really mean?
Rich Brambley
New VMware VDI features enable VMware View VMware View enables new vision of VDI with a Universal Client</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC1693: Architecting DR Solutions with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc1693-architecting-dr-solutions-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc1693-architecting-dr-solutions-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>Late again! Man, I need to get on the ball! Fortunately, I only missed the first part of the agenda. Once again, no Wi-Fi access in the session breakout, so I&amp;rsquo;ll publish this at the first available opportunity.
This is BC1693, Architecting DR Solutions with VMware SRM. The presenters are John Arrasjid and Will Crittenden; these are two solid guys that know DR and know SRM very well.
John starts the session with an overview of the influencing factors that affect a DR solution using SRM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
