<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exchange on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/exchange/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exchange on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/exchange/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 in a series of posts describing how I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated my Fedora Linux laptop into my employer&amp;rsquo;s corporate communication and collaboration systems. Part 1 tackled e-mail; this post tackles the topic of calendaring and scheduling. Unlike e-mail, which was solved relatively easily, this issue is one that I don&amp;rsquo;t consider fully solved.
As I mentioned in part 1, my employer uses Office 365 (O365). While O365 supports standard protocols like IMAP and STMP for mail, it does not support standard protocols like CalDAV for calendaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</guid>
      <description>One major aspect of my migration to Linux as my primary desktop OS is how well it integrates with corporate communication and collaboration systems. Based on the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten from others on Twitter, this is a major concern for a lot of folks out there. In fact, a number of folks have indicated that this is the only thing keeping them from migrating to Linux. There are a number of different aspects to &amp;ldquo;corporate communication and collaboration,&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m breaking this down into multiple posts (each post will discuss one particular aspect).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware, Zimbra, and Why I&#39;m Not an Analyst</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/05/vmware-zimbra-and-why-im-not-an-analyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 09:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/05/vmware-zimbra-and-why-im-not-an-analyst/</guid>
      <description>The rumors are swirling that VMware is going to buy Zimbra, an open source e-mail platform currently owned by Yahoo. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably all read the various news articles about the rumors and the events leading up to the rumored acquisition, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother you with them again.
Yesterday on Twitter, I mentioned that the Zimbra acquisition didn&amp;rsquo;t quite make sense to me. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one; several others mentioned it, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growl Notifications with Snow Leopard Mail and Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/10/growl-notifications-with-snow-leopard-mail-and-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 10:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/10/growl-notifications-with-snow-leopard-mail-and-exchange/</guid>
      <description>Like many Mac users, I use Growl to provide customizable, centralized notifications for events occurring on my system. Rather than use the Growl team&amp;rsquo;s GrowlMail plug-in, I use a custom AppleScript that I wrote that provide new message notifications via Growl. It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly advanced script; it just provides per-message notifications for each message received, unless I receive more than 5 messages at a time in which case the script just provides a summary notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any iPhone App Recommendations?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/01/any-iphone-app-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 12:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/01/any-iphone-app-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I bought my iPhone 3G. When the original iPhone was released, I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy one because it lacked 3G network connectivity, and the Samsung BlackJack 2 I was using was already 3G capable. In addition, the BlackJack supported ActiveSync for connectivity to my corporate Exchange infrastructure, and the iPhone didn&amp;rsquo;t. After the iPhone 3G was released, my two primary complaints had now been removed, and I said that I would get one&amp;mdash;but not right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Text Messages with Mail.app</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/16/plain-text-messages-with-mailapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 09:31:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/16/plain-text-messages-with-mailapp/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure where or when it started, but over the last couple of years I started taking a strong preference to plain text communications. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s an increased amount of time spent on Usenet newsgroups (I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting for Panic to release a substantive update to Unison!), or perhaps its due to the annoyance of HTML e-mail that include more pictures than text; I don&amp;rsquo;t know. In any case, I set my e-mail client (Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ActiveSync on the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/06/activesync-on-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/06/activesync-on-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Apple has just given me one more reason to possibly switch to an iPhone&amp;hellip;
iPhone opens to Exchange e-mail
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a Samsung BlackJack II, a Windows Mobile 6-based device with 3G connectivity. The e-mail functionality is great, but not having an easy way to keep my Address Book contacts in sync with my phone is a major hassle. It looks like using an iPhone would help address that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/03/virtualization-short-take-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 22:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/03/virtualization-short-take-3/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time again, folks&amp;hellip;time for another Virtualization Short Take!
  VMware&amp;rsquo;s performance team published some interesting information on running Exchange Server 2007 on VMware ESX Server 3.5. 16,000 mailboxes on 1 physical server, eh? Now all we need is for Microsoft to actually support running Exchange Server on top of ESX Server and we&amp;rsquo;ll be good to go.
  Speaking of vendor support, Simon Gallagher at vinf.net has started an open discussion of vendor support for virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned About Exchange Server 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/31/lessons-learned-about-exchange-server-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 23:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/31/lessons-learned-about-exchange-server-2007/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the midst of a non-virtualization-related project right now, which is a bit odd; a great majority of my work these days is centered around virtualization. Nevertheless, I try to view every project as one from which I can learn. I have definitely learned some things with this project, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure.
Here are a few tidbits that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far this week, most of them centered around the installation of Microsoft Exchange Server 2007.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Nickname Cache in Exchange Migrations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/15/preserving-nickname-cache-in-exchange-migrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2007 23:57:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/15/preserving-nickname-cache-in-exchange-migrations/</guid>
      <description>Migrating from one Microsoft Exchange organization to another Exchange organization is always a troublesome task. There&amp;rsquo;s free/busy time, public folders, the Global Address List (GAL), permissions, mailbox data, etc., to be worried out during the migration. With recent versions of the Outlook client, there&amp;rsquo;s also the nickname cache to worry about, too.
The nickname cache is that functionality in Outlook that lets you start typing a recipient&amp;rsquo;s name (one that you&amp;rsquo;ve used before) and Outlook will &amp;ldquo;auto-complete&amp;rdquo; the name for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erroneous Mail Relay Error with Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/24/erroneous-mail-relay-error-with-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2006 16:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/24/erroneous-mail-relay-error-with-exchange/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;ve probably all run into the &amp;ldquo;Unable to relay&amp;rdquo; error message before. The usual fixes to this problem are pretty straightforward:
  Add the address space to a recipient policy in Exchange System Manager; this tell Exchange to accept the messages as inbound; or
  Add IP addresses, subnets, or host names to the SMTP virtual server in Exchange System Manager as allowed to relay through this host;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices Analyzers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/31/best-practices-analyzers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2006 14:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/31/best-practices-analyzers/</guid>
      <description>The Exchange Best Practices Analyzer (ExBPA) has been around for a while now, and is a very useful tool in making sure that your Exchange implementation is following recommended best practices from Microsoft for optimal performance, reliability, and scalability. The ExBPA was recently updated to include the ability to check the overall Exchange topology for readiness to upgrade to Exchange Server 2007. The Exchange team blog has full details on the new &amp;ldquo;Readiness Check&amp;rdquo; in this posting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache as an OWA Front-End</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 11:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/24/apache-as-an-owa-front-end/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I discussed the use of Apache to protect OWA from web-based attacks. This configuration placed an Apache HTTP server in front of a server running Microsoft Exchange Server 2003 to protect it against web-based attacks, offload SSL encryption, and enable name-based virtual hosts (for the conservation of public DNS hostnames, especially important for smaller organizations). While this is a useful configuration, it is not without its drawbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mass-Creating Exchange Mailboxes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/13/mass-creating-exchange-mailboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2006 18:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/13/mass-creating-exchange-mailboxes/</guid>
      <description>While performing some testing and research at the office today, I found myself in need of a way to mass-create some Exchange mailboxes. A very quick Google search revealed just the tool I needed to perform the task: ExchMbx, a freeware utility by the same author of AdFind and AdMod.
The real power of ExchMbx is demonstrated when combined with dsquery (a Microsoft-supplied command-line tool for pulling lists of objects from Active Directory) or AdFind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May Security Vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/11/may-security-vulnerabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 23:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/11/may-security-vulnerabilities/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, Microsoft released a couple of patches on its standard monthly schedule. These patches are designed to plug a couple of critical security flaws, including what appears to be a very serious problem with Microsoft Exchange Server.
The two Windows flaws are not terribly serious, in my opinion. One, MS06-020, is rated &amp;ldquo;Critical&amp;rdquo; and plugs a problem with the Flash player. So, technically, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem with Windows but with Flash, and Adobe has also released a security bulletin as well.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
