<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenFlow on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/openflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenFlow on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/openflow/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #62</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #62. Sorry for the long delay since the last TST; some global travel has really thrown my schedule off. In any case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until Friday (the day I normally publish these) so I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there sooner. Enjoy!
Networking  PowerNSX is pretty cool&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a set of PowerShell cmdlets for administrators of VMware NSX running in vSphere environments. Check out Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s introductory post on PowerNSX for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #48</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/10/technology-short-take-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/10/technology-short-take-48/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #48, another installation in my irregularly-published series that collects links, articles, and thoughts from around the web. This time around, the content is a bit heavier on cloud management and applications/operating systems, but still lots of good content all the way around (I hope, anyway).
Networking  Matt Oswalt recently wrapped up his 3-part &amp;ldquo;DevOps for Networking&amp;rdquo; series. I referenced part 1 of the series back in TST #46, and parts 2 and 3 are just as good as the first one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #44</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #44, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles, links, ideas, and thoughts about various data center-related technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   One of the original problems with the VXLAN IETF specification was that it (deliberately) didn&amp;rsquo;t include any control plane information; as a result, the process of mapping MAC addresses to VTEPs (VXLAN Tunnel Endpoints) wasn&amp;rsquo;t defined, and the early implementations relied on multicast to handle this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #43</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/08/technology-short-take-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/08/technology-short-take-43/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #43, another episode in my irregularly-published series of articles, links, and thoughts from around the web, focusing on data center technologies like networking, virtualization, storage, and cloud computing. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful.
Networking   Jason Edelman recently took a look at Docker networking. While Docker is receiving a great deal of attention, I have to say that I feel Docker networking is a key area that hasn&amp;rsquo;t received the amount of attention that it probably needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #41, the latest in my series of random thoughts, articles, and links from around the Internet. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) is a networking topic that is starting to get more and more attention (some may equate &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;hype&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to draw your own conclusion there). In any case, I liked how this article really hit upon what I personally feel is something many people are overlooking in NFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #40. The content is a bit light this time around; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give you, my readers, a little break. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s still some useful and interesting stuff here. Enjoy!
Networking   Bob McCouch has a nice write-up on options for VPNs to AWS. If you&amp;rsquo;re needing to build out such a solution, you might want to read his post for some additional perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #36</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/23/technology-short-take-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/10/23/technology-short-take-36/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #36. In this episode, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a variety of links from around the web, along with some random thoughts and ideas along the way. I try to keep things related to the key technology areas you&amp;rsquo;ll see in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers, though I do stray from time to time. In any case, enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;bring on the content! I hope you find something useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2013: Future of SDN with the Intel ONP Switch Reference Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 13:36:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/12/idf-2013-future-of-sdn-with-the-intel-onp-switch-reference-design/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS002, titled &amp;ldquo;The Future of Software-Defined Networking with the Intel Open Network Platform Switch Reference Design.&amp;rdquo; The speakers are Recep Ozdag, a PME with Intel, and Gershon Schatzberg, a PLM with Wind River Systems. The Intel Open Network Platform (ONP) Switch is the official name for Seacliff Trail, which I talked about last year at IDF 2012.
Recep starts the session with some brief background; he came to Intel through the Fulcrum acquisition a couple of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #35</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/03/technology-short-take-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/03/technology-short-take-35/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #35, another in my irregular series of posts that collect various articles, links and thoughts regarding data center technologies. I hope that something in here is useful to you.
Networking   Art Fewell takes a deeper look at the increasingly important role of the virtual switch.
  A discussion of &amp;ldquo;statefulness&amp;rdquo; brought me again to Ivan&amp;rsquo;s post on the spectrum of firewall statefulness. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy sometimes just to revert to &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s stateful&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not stateful,&amp;rdquo; but the reality is that it&amp;rsquo;s not quite so black-and-white.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 2: NVP Controllers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/16/learning-nvp-part-2-nvp-controllers/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to part 2 of the Learning NVP blog series. In part 1 of the series, I provided a high-level overview of the NVP architecture and components. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive into a bit more detail on one key component of the architecture: the NVP controllers and controller cluster.
(Just a quick reminder: although I&amp;rsquo;m talking about NVP 3.1&amp;ndash;our publicly available, GA product already running in production with customers&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that the NVP architecture serves as the basis for the upcoming VMware NSX product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #34</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #34, my latest collection of links, articles, thoughts, and ideas from around the web, centered on key data center technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   Henry Louwers has a nice write-up on some of the design considerations that go into selecting a Citrix NetScaler solution.
  Scott Hogg explores jumbo frames and their benefits/drawbacks in a clear and concise manner. It&amp;rsquo;s worth reading if you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with jumbo frames and some of the considerations around their use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning NVP, Part 1: High-Level Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2013 16:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/21/learning-nvp-part-1-high-level-architecture/</guid>
      <description>This blog post kicks off a new series of posts describing my journey to become more knowledgeable about the Nicira Network Virtualization Platform (NVP). NVP is, in my opinion, an awesome platform, but there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a great deal of information shared about the product, how it works, how you configure it, etc. That&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to address in this series of posts. In this first post, I&amp;rsquo;ll start with a high-level description of the NVP architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #32</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #32, the latest installment in my irregularly-published series of link collections, thoughts, rants, raves, and miscellaneous information. I try to keep the information linked to data center technologies like networking, storage, virtualization, and the like, but occasionally other items slip through. I hope you find something useful.
Networking   Ranga Maddipudi (@vCloudNetSec on Twitter) has put together two blog posts on vCloud Networking and Security&amp;rsquo;s App Firewall (part 1 and part 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #31</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2013 16:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/08/technology-short-take-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #31, my irregularly published series that takes a look at links, posts, articles, and thoughts from around the web related to core data center technologies. I hope that you find something useful!
Networking   Umair Hoodbhoy speculates in this post that the inclusion of Cisco&amp;rsquo;s ONE Controller in the recently-announced &amp;ldquo;Daylight&amp;rdquo; effort could mean the end for Big Switch&amp;rsquo;s Floodlight. (Umair&amp;rsquo;s play on words&amp;ndash;&amp;ldquo;in Daylight there is no need for Floodlights&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;is cute.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
