<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RedHat on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/redhat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RedHat on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/redhat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 81</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #81! I have another collection of links, articles, and thoughts about key data center technologies, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something here that will prove useful or thought-provoking. Enjoy!
Networking  Matt Oswalt has a great post on the need for networking professionals to learn basic scripting skills&amp;mdash;something he (rightfully) distinguishes from programming as a full-time occupation. This is a post well worth spending a few minutes to read, and I wholeheartedly agree with Matt&amp;rsquo;s position here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #71</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #71! As always, I have a list of links related to various data center technologies found below; hopefully something here proves useful.
Networking  Dmitri Kalintsev is back with another article in a series of articles on using hardware VXLAN tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) with VMware NSX. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s on validating HW VTEP deployment for integration with NSX. In particular, Dmitri points out that you need connectivity both on the management plane as well as on the data plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #32</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #32, the latest installment in my irregularly-published series of link collections, thoughts, rants, raves, and miscellaneous information. I try to keep the information linked to data center technologies like networking, storage, virtualization, and the like, but occasionally other items slip through. I hope you find something useful.
Networking   Ranga Maddipudi (@vCloudNetSec on Twitter) has put together two blog posts on vCloud Networking and Security&amp;rsquo;s App Firewall (part 1 and part 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/03/05/technology-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 18:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/03/05/technology-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #30. This Technology Short Take is a bit heavy on the networking side, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s understandable given my recent job change. Enjoy!
Networking   Ben Cherian, Chief Strategy Officer for Midokura, helps make a case for network virtualization. (Note: Midokura makes a network virtualization solution.) If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering about network virtualization and why there is a focus on it, this post might help shed some light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Open vSwitch Configuration with Puppet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/26/automating-open-vswitch-configuration-with-puppet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/26/automating-open-vswitch-configuration-with-puppet/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you a way to automate the configuration of Open vSwitch (OVS) using Puppet. While this method will work, it is not without its drawbacks (which I&amp;rsquo;ll explain later in the post). I freely admit that there might be better ways of accomplishing this task; this is one simple way that I discovered.
I wish I could say that this method of automating OVS with Puppet was clever, but&amp;mdash;to be honest&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s really more of a brutish hack that anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2013 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/07/looking-ahead-my-2013-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 10:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/02/07/looking-ahead-my-2013-projects/</guid>
      <description>In early January 2012, I posted a list of my 2012 projects. Those projects included learning to script in Perl, learning German, becoming more familiar with Xen/Open vSwitch/OpenStack, and pursuing CCNP. In late June 2012, my mid-year project update let you know that I was dropping the Perl efforts, but sticking it out with German, Xen/OVS/OpenStack, and CCNP. (I later dropped Xen in favor of KVM.) Finally, in early January 2013 I graded myself on my progress on my 2012 goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #27! This is my usual collection of links, thoughts, rants, and ideas about data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about OpenFlow and software-defined networking but need to do this on a shoestring budget in your home lab, a number of guides have been written to help out. I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally used any of these guides yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m working my way in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #26</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #26! As you might already know, the Technology Short Takes are my irregularly-published collections of links, articles, thoughts, and (sometimes) rants. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   Chris Colotti, as part of a changed focus in his role at VMware, has been working extensively with Nicira NVP. He&amp;rsquo;s had a couple of good posts; this one is a primer on how NVP works, and this one discusses the use of the Open vSwitch (OVS) vApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: OVS and the Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/18/thinking-out-loud-ovs-and-the-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/18/thinking-out-loud-ovs-and-the-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been unsuccessfully trying to get Open vSwitch (OVS) running on Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 6.3 (as well as CentOS 6.3). The rationale behind this is that RHEL/CentOS are the sort of battle-tested, well-supported Linux distributions that enterprises will (and do) deploy in their data centers. OVS, of course, is central to the strategy and functionality of several network virtualization players and projects:
  Nicira</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iSCSI and ESX Server 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/10/iscsi-and-esx-server-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2006 09:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/10/iscsi-and-esx-server-3/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I wrote about trying to use NetApp&amp;rsquo;s ONTAP Simulator as a VM under ESX Server so that I could do some testing with the new NAS and iSCSI functionality in ESX Server 3.0. I finally got that working, but later had to shut it down when I started working with ESX Server 3. As it turns out, the ProLiant 6400R servers I was using for my VMware lab (running ESX 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Quality vs. Just Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2006 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article discussing Novell&amp;rsquo;s leadership change, one analyst was quoted regarding the change as being positive for Novell in that they (Novell) could stop building very high quality products and instead build products that are just good enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but this spirit of mediocrity is exactly the wrong kind of thinking for IT vendors.
Specifically, the quote stated this:
 &amp;ldquo;Ron Hovsepian appears to be an astute business person, one who will be able to quickly take stock of the environment and Novell&amp;rsquo;s position within that environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux-AD Integration With Windows Server 2003 R2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/27/linux-ad-integration-with-windows-server-2003-r2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2006 11:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/27/linux-ad-integration-with-windows-server-2003-r2/</guid>
      <description>The integration of (what was formerly called) Services for UNIX into Windows Server 2003 R2 also brought some other changes. To accommodate those changes, I&amp;rsquo;ve updated my Linux-AD integration instructions (the previous instructions are here for pre-R2 versions of Windows). If you need to integrate Linux systems for authentication into Active Directory with Windows Server 2003 R2, these instructions should get you there.
Overall, the instructions are very similar to the instructions for pre-R2 versions of Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xen Momentum Growing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/03/xen-momentum-growing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2006 11:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/03/xen-momentum-growing/</guid>
      <description>There is an incredible amount of momentum growing around the open source Xen hypervisor, and it is increasingly looking like market leaders VMware and Microsoft should be less worried about each other and more worried about Xen.
Check out some of the recent news articles regarding Xen:
&amp;ldquo;Novell to integrate Xen 3.0 in the next Open Enterprise Server&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;http://searchopensource.techtarget.com/columnItem/0,294698,sid39_gci1176440,00.html&amp;gt;
&amp;ldquo;Virtual Iron annonces 3.0 commercial and free editions based on Xen&amp;rdquo; &amp;lt;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonjour on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/31/bonjour-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 19:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/31/bonjour-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>A while back, I experimented with a multicast DNS (mDNS) responder for Linux. (For those not already &amp;ldquo;in the know,&amp;rdquo; so to speak, multicast DNS is one of the key components of Bonjour, Apple&amp;rsquo;s automatic service discovery functionality&amp;mdash;formerly known as Rendezvous). For some strange reason, I had an urge to try it again today. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I found.
First, I started looking for an official RPM package for a CentOS 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSX Upgrade Much Smoother This Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/gsx-upgrade-much-smoother-this-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 14:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/gsx-upgrade-much-smoother-this-time/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today I completed another GSX Server upgrade (from version 2.5 to version 3.2.1) for a customer, and fortunately this upgrade was much smoother than the last GSX Server upgrade.
No BSODs (Blue Screens of Death) this time during the uninstallation, and the previous version uninstalled itself cleanly. The installation of the new version went quickly and smoothly, and in practically no time we were booting up &amp;ldquo;legacy&amp;rdquo; VMs under the new version of GSX Server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
