<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/docker/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 154</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #154! My link of links and articles from around the Internet is a bit light on networking and virtualization this time around, but heftier in the security, cloud, and OS/application sections. I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something that you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful. Enjoy the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 149</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #149! I&amp;rsquo;ll have one more Technology Short Take in 2021, scheduled for three weeks from now (on the last day of the year!). For now, though, I have a small collection of articles and links for your reading pleasure&amp;mdash;not as many as I usually include in a Technology Short Take, but better than nothing at all (I hope!). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 147</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #147! The list of articles is a bit shorter than usual this time around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a good collection of articles and posts covering topics in networking, hardware (mostly focused on Apple&amp;rsquo;s processors), cloud computing, and virtualization. There&amp;rsquo;s bound to be something in here for most everyone! (At least, I hope so.) Enjoy your weekend reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 135</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/11/technology-short-take-135/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/11/technology-short-take-135/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #135! This will likely be the last Technology Short Take of 2020, so it&amp;rsquo;s a tad longer than usual. Sorry about that! You know me&amp;mdash;I just want to make sure everyone has plenty of technical content to read during the holidays. And speaking of holidays&amp;hellip;whatever holidays you do (or don&amp;rsquo;t) celebrate, I hope that the rest of the year is a good one for you. Now, on to the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assigning Node Labels During Kubernetes Cluster Bootstrapping</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/30/assigning-node-labels-during-kubernetes-cluster-bootstrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/30/assigning-node-labels-during-kubernetes-cluster-bootstrapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given that &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; is a primary focus of my day-to-day work, I spend a fair amount of time in &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.slack.com/&#34;&gt;the Kubernetes Slack community&lt;/a&gt;, trying to answer questions from users and generally be helpful. Recently, someone asked about assigning node labels while bootstrapping a cluster with &lt;code&gt;kubeadm&lt;/code&gt;. I answered the question, but afterward started thinking that it might be a good idea to also share that same information via a blog post&amp;mdash;my thinking being that others who also had the same question aren&amp;rsquo;t likely to be able to find my answer on Slack, but would be more likely to find a published blog post. So, in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to assign node labels while bootstrapping a Kubernetes cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 134</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/25/technology-short-take-134/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 08:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/25/technology-short-take-134/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #134! I&amp;rsquo;m publishing a bit early this time due to the Thanksgiving holiday in the US. So, for all my US readers, here&amp;rsquo;s some content to peruse while enjoying some turkey (or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re having this year). For my international readers, here&amp;rsquo;s some content to peruse while enjoying dramatically lower volumes of e-mail because the US is on holiday. See, something for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 133</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/06/technology-short-take-133/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/06/technology-short-take-133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #133! This time around, I have a collection of links featuring the new Raspberry Pi 400, some macOS security-related articles, information on AWS Nitro Enclaves and gVisor, and a few other topics. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 132</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/10/23/technology-short-take-132/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/10/23/technology-short-take-132/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #132! My list of links and articles from around the web seems to be a bit heavy on security-related topics this time. Still, there&amp;rsquo;s a decent collection of networking, cloud computing, and virtualization articles as well as a smattering of other topics for you to peruse. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 130</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #130! I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post sitting in my Drafts folder waiting to be published for almost a month, and I kept forgetting to actually make it live. Sorry! So, here it is&amp;mdash;better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 129</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/17/technology-short-take-129/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/17/technology-short-take-129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #129, where I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a bunch of links and references to technology-centric resources around the Internet. This collection is (mostly) data center- and cloud-focused, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to curate a list that has some useful information for readers. Sorry this got published so late; it was supposed to go live this morning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Around Docker Desktop&#39;s Outdated Kubernetes Version</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/08/working-around-docker-desktops-outdated-kubernetes-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 11:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/08/working-around-docker-desktops-outdated-kubernetes-version/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of the time that I published this blog post in early July 2020, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/products/docker-desktop&#34;&gt;Docker Desktop&lt;/a&gt; for macOS was at version 2.2.0.4 (for the &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; channel). That version includes a relatively recent version of the Docker engine (19.03.8, compared to 19.03.12 on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 31 box), but a quite outdated version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; (1.15.5, which isn&amp;rsquo;t supported by upstream). Now, this may not be a problem for users who &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; use Kubernetes via Docker Desktop. For me, however, the old version of Kubernetes&amp;mdash;specifically the old version of &lt;code&gt;kubectl&lt;/code&gt;&amp;mdash;causes problems. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I worked around the old version that Docker Desktop supplies. (Also, see the update at the bottom for some additional details that emerged after this post was originally published.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
