<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photon on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/photon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photon on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/photon/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 90</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/10/technology-short-take-90/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/10/technology-short-take-90/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 90! This post is a bit shorter than most, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been on the road quite a bit recently. Nevertheless, there&amp;rsquo;s hopefully something here you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 81</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/07/technology-short-take-81/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #81! I have another collection of links, articles, and thoughts about key data center technologies, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something here that will prove useful or thought-provoking. Enjoy!
Networking  Matt Oswalt has a great post on the need for networking professionals to learn basic scripting skills&amp;mdash;something he (rightfully) distinguishes from programming as a full-time occupation. This is a post well worth spending a few minutes to read, and I wholeheartedly agree with Matt&amp;rsquo;s position here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 80</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/24/technology-short-take-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/24/technology-short-take-80/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #80! This post is a week late (I try to publish these every other Friday), so my apologies for the delay. However, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to gather together some articles with useful information for you. Enjoy!
Networking  Biruk Mekonnen has an introductory article on using Netmiko for network automation. It&amp;rsquo;s short and light on details, but it does provide an example snippet of Python code to illustrate what can be done with Netmiko.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #78</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #78! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of links and articles from around the Internet discussing various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  The rise of the disaggregated network operating system (NOS) marches on: this time, it&amp;rsquo;s Big Switch Networks announcing expanded hardware support in Open Network Linux (ONL), upon which its own NOS is based. The Pivotal Engineering blog has an article that shows how to use BOSH with the vSphere CPI to automate adding servers to an NSX load balancing pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vagrant-Photon OS Bug and Workaround</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/20/vagrant-photon-bug-workaround/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/20/vagrant-photon-bug-workaround/</guid>
      <description>I recently came across a bug in using VMware Photon OS with Vagrant, and so in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to point out this bug and provide a workaround. The bug is, fortunately, pretty innocuous, and only affects Vagrant environments that configure additional network interfaces to Photon OS VMs. The workaround is equally easy, thankfully.
First, I&amp;rsquo;ll point out that the fix for this bug has already been pushed to Vagrant, but it hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet (as of this writing) made it into a release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #65</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/22/technology-short-take-65/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #65! As usual, I gathered an odd collection of links and articles from around the web on key data center technologies and trends. I hope you find something useful!
Networking  Michael Ryom has a nice (but short) article on using Log Insight along with a NetFlow proxy to help provide more detailed visibility into traffic flows between VMs on NSX logical networks. Brent Salisbury has an article on GoBGP, a Go-based BGP implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #61</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/12/technology-short-take-61/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #61. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to find a nice range of articles and links, so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I was successful and that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking  Along with the release of rkt 1.0 (see below in the &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems/Applications&amp;rdquo; section), Metaswitch has announced a Container Networking Interface (CNI) plugin for Project Calico. (This appears to be primarily through the Calico plugin for Kubernetes and Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; support for CNI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker Machine with Photon TP2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/15/docker-machine-photon-tp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/15/docker-machine-photon-tp2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use Docker Machine in conjunction with VMware Photon OS Technical Preview 2 (aka &amp;ldquo;TP2&amp;rdquo;). Given that Photon was designed to host containers, this is&amp;mdash;for the most part&amp;mdash;pretty straightforward. There are a couple of glitches that I need to point out, though, that might hang up new users.
First off, kudos to Fabio Rapposelli for taking some time at VMworld to help me work through the details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Photon on Fusion via Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/21/running-photon-fusion-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/21/running-photon-fusion-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>Most of you have probably picked up on the news of VMware&amp;rsquo;s new container-optimized Linux distribution, code-named &amp;ldquo;Photon&amp;rdquo;. (More details here.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a very quick walkthrough on running Photon on VMware Fusion via Vagrant. This walkthrough will leverage a Vagrant box for Photon that has already been created.
To make things easier, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a photon directory to my GitHub &amp;ldquo;learning-tools&amp;rdquo; repository. Feel free to pull those files down to make it easier to follow along.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
