<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:24:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/music/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some New Christian Music</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/21/some-new-christian-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/21/some-new-christian-music/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased some new Christian music to add to my iTunes library; I had a credit with iTunes from some iTunes Gift Cards that my kids gave me for Christmas. After six months, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d better go ahead and use the iTunes credit or it would disappear.
After browsing for a while, I ended up selecting the following albums:
  Unbreakable by Fireflight - I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished listening to the entire album, but so far my favorite track is &amp;ldquo;Forever&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Error with Firefly Media Server, iTunes, and Avahi</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/23/strange-error-with-firefly-media-server-itunes-and-avahi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 20:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/23/strange-error-with-firefly-media-server-itunes-and-avahi/</guid>
      <description>Over the 2008-2009 holiday season, I rebuilt my home network. I included the notes and information from my home network rebuild in an article that described the Mac OS X-Ubuntu integration resulting from the rebuild. Since that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a larger hard drive to the home server to make more room for Time Machine backups, movies, music, and other files. Things seemed to be working very well. Until the other day&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ubuntu-Mac Article is Popular, I Guess</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/08/my-ubuntu-mac-article-is-popular-i-guess/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2009 16:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/08/my-ubuntu-mac-article-is-popular-i-guess/</guid>
      <description>Apparently my Ubuntu-Mac integration article is quite popular; it&amp;rsquo;s been picked up for re-publication on a couple of different sites:
http://linux.sys-con.com/node/803618
http://opensource.sys-con.com/node/803618
Cool! I hope the article is useful to others.
As a quick follow-up to that article, you may recall that I ran into a strange issue with OpenVPN and mt-daapd prior to the home network rebuild. I just finished installing OpenVPN last night and, anticipating the problem, did some digging to see how I&amp;rsquo;d fix the problem this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu and Mac OS X Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/02/ubuntu-and-mac-os-x-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 12:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/02/ubuntu-and-mac-os-x-integration/</guid>
      <description>One of my projects over the Christmas holiday has been to rebuild the home network. You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d want to avoid that sort of thing since I&amp;rsquo;ve been on vacation from work for the past two weeks, but working on a home network is a different sort of beast than working on a network for a company. There are different challenges to be addressed.
My primary goals for this &amp;ldquo;home network rebuild&amp;rdquo; were the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN and mt-daapd</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/26/openvpn-and-mt-daapd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 18:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/26/openvpn-and-mt-daapd/</guid>
      <description>I have a system at home with an &amp;ldquo;older&amp;rdquo; Linux distribution for mundane tasks like DHCP and content filtering on my broadband connection (no need for the kids to see something they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be seeing, if you know what I mean). I&amp;rsquo;ve thought frequently about rebuilding it with a newer distribution, perhaps Ubuntu, but&amp;mdash;to be perfectly honest&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m just too lazy. It generally just works, and overall doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a great deal of care and feeding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Altar and the Door by Casting Crowns</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/10/the-altar-and-the-door-by-casting-crowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 16:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/10/the-altar-and-the-door-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
      <description>A fellow believer contacted me recently asking if I&amp;rsquo;d listened to any recent Casting Crowns albums. He&amp;rsquo;d stumbled across the site, entirely accidentally, and saw my post about Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; Lifesong album. I followed that post up a couple of months later with another take, in which I took a deeper look at their music&amp;mdash;not just their musical style, but the words and the emotions behind their music&amp;mdash;and I realized that there was so much more to be heard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Quicksilver</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/06/the-power-of-quicksilver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2007 19:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/06/the-power-of-quicksilver/</guid>
      <description>So the other day I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in my office, working on my laptop, when my seven year old son came up to me and asked a question. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall exactly what I was doing at the time (probably working on a blog post!), but as I frequently do when working in my office I was listening to some Christian music with iTunes (and GrowlTunes). So that I could hear my son ask his question, I quickly pulled up Quicksilver and paused iTunes with only a few keystrokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Josh Bates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/23/josh-bates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 10:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/23/josh-bates/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a really good CD, actually, and I&amp;rsquo;m particularly enjoying a couple of the tracks. He&amp;rsquo;s got a great voice, and the music and lyrics are good. So far, the title track (&amp;ldquo;Perfect Day&amp;rdquo;) is a favorite of mine, and I&amp;rsquo;m also enjoying &amp;ldquo;Alive&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;You Say Come.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;King of Glory&amp;rdquo; is another great song, and I believe that it&amp;rsquo;s a hit single on the charts right now.
When you&amp;rsquo;re feeling down, or feeling like you aren&amp;rsquo;t quite &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo;, then the track &amp;ldquo;Less&amp;rdquo; will certainly speak to your heart, and remind you of the unfailing love of God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krystal Meyers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/04/krystal-meyers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 21:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/04/krystal-meyers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write about this young Christian rock artist for a while now, but keep forgetting. Finally, here it is.
I picked up Krystal Meyers&amp;rsquo; debut self-titled CD a few months ago from Sound and Spirit (one of the BMG Music clubs&amp;mdash;you know, where they send you constant reminders to buy CDs from them and then ship them to you the instant you forget to tell them you don&amp;rsquo;t want them).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Take on Life(song)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 12:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier posting about Lifesong, the second CD by the Christian group Casting Crowns, I spoke primarily about their musical style and their sound. At the time, I was so wrapped up in how the music sounded in comparison with their debut album that I was disappointed in this latest effort.
I continued listening to the CD, concentrating mostly on the tracks that I really enjoyed&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Lifesong&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Praise You in This Storm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifesong by Casting Crowns</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 09:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
      <description>I received a copy of the new album by Casting Crowns today, Lifesong. There are a couple of really good tracks, like the title track &amp;ldquo;Lifesong,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free.&amp;rdquo; Most of the songs, though, are a very different style than Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; debut album. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed. After so thoroughly enjoying their first CD, I was really looking forward to their next album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew West&#39;s New Album</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 12:03:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</guid>
      <description>I stopped by the local LifeWay yesterday to spend a gift card the kids had purchased for me as a Father&amp;rsquo;s Day gift. While I was there, I found that the latest album from Matthew West, History, was available, so I picked up a copy. Good stuff! I&amp;rsquo;d heard the latest single from the album, &amp;ldquo;Next Thing You Know,&amp;rdquo; on the radio, but as I was listening to it again this morning on the way to church God really blessed me again.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
