<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OVS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ovs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OVS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ovs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 153</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/15/technology-short-take-153/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #153! My personal and professional life has kept me busy over the last couple of months, so things have been quiet here on the blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve still been collecting links to share with you, though, and here&amp;rsquo;s the latest collection. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re able to find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 129</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/17/technology-short-take-129/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/17/technology-short-take-129/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #129, where I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a bunch of links and references to technology-centric resources around the Internet. This collection is (mostly) data center- and cloud-focused, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to curate a list that has some useful information for readers. Sorry this got published so late; it was supposed to go live this morning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 122</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/27/technology-short-take-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/27/technology-short-take-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #122! Luckily I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; manage to get another Tech Short Take squeezed in for 2019, just so all my readers could have some reading materials for the holidays. I&amp;rsquo;m kidding! No, I mean I really am kidding&amp;mdash;don&amp;rsquo;t read stuff over the holidays. Spend time with your family instead. The investment in your family will pay off in later years, trust me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, May 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/18/posts-from-the-past-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/18/posts-from-the-past-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;mdash;May 2018&amp;mdash;marks &lt;strong&gt;thirteen years&lt;/strong&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve been generating content here on this site. It&amp;rsquo;s been a phenomenal 13 years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the opportunity to share information with readers around the world. To celebrate, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick &amp;ldquo;Posts from the Past&amp;rdquo; and highlight some content from previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running OVS on Fedora Atomic Host</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/30/running-ovs-fedora-atomic-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/30/running-ovs-fedora-atomic-host/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the results of some testing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://openvswitch.org/&#34;&gt;Open vSwitch&lt;/a&gt; (OVS) in containers on a container-optimized Linux distribution such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.projectatomic.io/&#34;&gt;Atomic Host&lt;/a&gt; (Fedora Atomic Host, specifically). I&amp;rsquo;m still relatively early in my exploration of this topic, but I felt like sharing what I&amp;rsquo;ve found so far might be helpful to others, and might help spark conversations within the relevant communities about how this experience might be improved.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Primer for Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/06/ipv6-primer-for-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/06/ipv6-primer-for-deployments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the OpenStack Summit Sydney session titled &amp;ldquo;IPv6 Primer for Deployments&amp;rdquo;, led by Trent Lloyd from Canonical. IPv6 is a topic with which I know I need to get more familiar, so attending this session seemed like a reasonable approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 89</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 89! I have a collection of newer materials and some older materials this time around, but hopefully all of them are still useful. (I needed to do some housekeeping on my Instapaper account, which is where I bookmark stuff that frequently lands here.) Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years of writing here, I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a pretty fair amount of content. To help folks discover older content, I thought it might be fun to revisit what I&amp;rsquo;ve published in October in years past. Here are some &amp;ldquo;posts from the past,&amp;rdquo; all from October of previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open vSwitch Day at OpenStack Summit 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/10/ovs-day-openstack-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/10/ovs-day-openstack-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &amp;ldquo;liveblog&amp;rdquo; (not quite live, but you get the idea) of the Open vSwitch Open Source Day happening at the OpenStack Summit in Boston. Summaries of each of the presentations are included below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 82</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/05/technology-short-take-82/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #82! This issue is a bit behind schedule; I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty heads-down on some projects. That work will come to fruition in a couple weeks, so I should be able to come up for some air soon. In the meantime, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links and articles for your reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canceling the OVS Cookbook Project</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/28/canceling-ovs-cookbook-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/28/canceling-ovs-cookbook-project/</guid>
      <description>In my list of proposed 2017 projects, I mentioned that I wanted to launch an open source book project. In late February, I launched The Open vSwitch Cookbook, an unofficial&amp;mdash;as in not formally affiliated with the Open vSwitch (OVS) project&amp;mdash;effort to gather together OVS &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; into an open source book. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m shutting down that project, and here&amp;rsquo;s why.
It really comes down to wanting to be a better member of the OVS community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching an Open Source Book Project</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/21/launching-open-source-book-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/21/launching-open-source-book-project/</guid>
      <description>In my list of planned 2017 projects, I mentioned that one thing I&amp;rsquo;d like to do this year is launch an open source book project. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce The Open vSwitch Cookbook, an Apache 2.0-licensed book project aimed at providing &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; recipes for Open vSwitch (OVS).
Portions of the book are already available, with more content being added soon (more on that in a moment).
I&amp;rsquo;m using GitBook as the publishing platform; this allows me to write in Markdown and publish to a variety of formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlating OVS and Guest Domain Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/16/correlating-ovs-guest-domain-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/16/correlating-ovs-guest-domain-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a fair amount about Open vSwitch (OVS), including some articles on using it with KVM and Libvirt. One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t discussed in such environments, though, is the potential challenge of mapping network interfaces in a guest domain to the corresponding OVS interface (for the purposes of troubleshooting, for example). There is no single command that will provide a guest-to-OVS interface map (as far as I know), but this information is easily gathered using a couple commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #76</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #76, the first Technology Short Take of 2017. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but due to extenuating circumstances (my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow) I&amp;rsquo;m posting it today. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking  As of Vagrant 1.9.1, the Cumulus plugin for Vagrant is no longer needed. See this post for more details. Ivan Pepelnjak (one of my absolutely favorite folks in the IT industry) has a great post on using regex filters in Ansible to parse text printouts from network devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OVN with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how to use OVN (Open Virtual Network; part of the Open vSwitch project) with KVM and Libvirt to provide virtual networking for KVM-based virtual machines. This post will build on some concepts around OVS and Libvirt that I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed previously; be sure to review the OVS posts and Libvirt posts on this site for more details and prerequisite knowledge.
I&amp;rsquo;ll structure this discussion around 2 key steps:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
