<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xen on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/xen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xen on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/xen/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #34</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #34, my latest collection of links, articles, thoughts, and ideas from around the web, centered on key data center technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   Henry Louwers has a nice write-up on some of the design considerations that go into selecting a Citrix NetScaler solution.
  Scott Hogg explores jumbo frames and their benefits/drawbacks in a clear and concise manner. It&amp;rsquo;s worth reading if you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with jumbo frames and some of the considerations around their use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2012 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/07/looking-back-2012-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 19:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/07/looking-back-2012-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>About a year ago, I posted a look at my planned projects for 2012. Now, a year later, it&amp;rsquo;s time to review my progress (or lack thereof) and measure myself on how well I did (or didn&amp;rsquo;t) do on those projects.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s review the original project list:
  Learn to script in Perl.
  Learn to speak German.
  Become more familiar with Xen (and Open vSwitch and OpenStack).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #27! This is my usual collection of links, thoughts, rants, and ideas about data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about OpenFlow and software-defined networking but need to do this on a shoestring budget in your home lab, a number of guides have been written to help out. I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally used any of these guides yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m working my way in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #26</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #26! As you might already know, the Technology Short Takes are my irregularly-published collections of links, articles, thoughts, and (sometimes) rants. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   Chris Colotti, as part of a changed focus in his role at VMware, has been working extensively with Nicira NVP. He&amp;rsquo;s had a couple of good posts; this one is a primer on how NVP works, and this one discusses the use of the Open vSwitch (OVS) vApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #24, another instance of my irregularly-published collection of links, thoughts, and rants on various data center technologies like networking, operating systems, security, hardware, virtualization, and cloud computing. This is a slightly shorter version of my Technology Short Takes; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down since some readers have indicated the previous Short Takes weren&amp;rsquo;t short enough. Anyway, I hope you find something useful.
Networking   This page is a decent reference to the open source software-defined networking (SDN) projects that are out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Tools and Projects I Should Learn</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/06/open-source-tools-and-projects-i-should-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 17:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/06/open-source-tools-and-projects-i-should-learn/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday on Twitter I asked this question:
 If you had to pick the top 5 open source tools/projects to learn in order to stay sharp/relevant, what would they be?
 A number of people expressed interest in the answers to that question, so I thought I post it here. My reason for asking isn&amp;rsquo;t just academic; I plan to use this feedback (as well as any feedback in the comments to this blog post) to further tweak my 2012 projects (see here and here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing XCP-XAPI on Ubuntu Server 12.04 LTS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/28/installing-xcp-xapi-on-ubuntu-server-12-04-lts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 10:19:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/28/installing-xcp-xapi-on-ubuntu-server-12-04-lts/</guid>
      <description>As part of my 2012 projects (see here plus an update here), I&amp;rsquo;ve been familiarizing myself with the Xen hypervisor. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working to get XCP (Xen Cloud Platform, the open source version of XenServer) running on a test system in my home office. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a struggle, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally got it, and I wanted to share the information here.
Here are the steps that I followed to install XCP-XAPI on a system running Ubuntu Server 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid-Year Project Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/25/mid-year-project-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/25/mid-year-project-update/</guid>
      <description>In early January, I posted a 2012 project list. To summarize, here are the four broad goals that I set for myself for 2012:
 Learn to script in Perl. Learn to speak German. Become very familiar with the Xen hypervisor. Pursue CCNP certification.  Now that we are halfway through the year, where do things stand? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick update.
  My Perl skills are still really elementary. The biggest challenge I&amp;rsquo;ve found is that without some sort of task or process to try to automate, trying to write code in Perl is kind of &amp;ldquo;disconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #23</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 13:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/12/technology-short-take-23/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #23, another collection of links and thoughts related to data center technologies like networking, storage, security, cloud computing, and virtualization. As usual, we have a fairly wide-ranging collection of items this time around. Enjoy!
Networking   A couple of days ago I learned that there are a couple open source implementations of LISP (Locator/ID Separation Protocol). There&amp;rsquo;s OpenLISP, which runs on FreeBSD, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a project called LISPmob that brings LISP to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Projects for 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/02/some-projects-for-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 10:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/02/some-projects-for-2012/</guid>
      <description>Rather than posting some sort of &amp;ldquo;2011 in review&amp;rdquo; article where I talk about how many visitors the site had or how many RSS subscribers there are, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d instead focus on the upcoming year and some of the projects in which I&amp;rsquo;ll be involved. By describing some of the projects that I&amp;rsquo;m undertaking this year in 2012, that gives you&amp;mdash;the readers&amp;mdash;a rough idea of some of the types of content that will likely appear in the coming year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #17</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/28/technology-short-take-17/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #17, another of my irregularly-scheduled collections of various data center technology-related links, thoughts, and comments. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   I think it was J Metz of Cisco that posted this to Twitter, but this is a good reference to the various 10 Gigabit Ethernet modules.
  I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken quite a bit about stretched clusters and their potential benefits. For an opposing view&amp;mdash;especially regarding the use of stretched clusters as a disaster avoidance solution&amp;mdash;check out this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 11:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>It has been a busy week since I last posted, and the blogging/micro-blogging world has been quite busy. I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered quite the collection of links and posts over the last week or so; here are a few that caught my eye. Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #41!
  About a month ago Rick Vanover posted a quick note about the use of Disk.SchedNumReqOutstanding as a potential performance tweak. As Rick mentions at the end of his article, it&amp;rsquo;s important to &amp;ldquo;test before and after with an intensive workload&amp;rdquo;; otherwise, you could find yourself actually hurting performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bit Harsh, Don&#39;t You Think?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/23/a-bit-harsh-dont-you-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2009 22:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/23/a-bit-harsh-dont-you-think/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, Alex Barrett of TechTarget posted a tweet about her predictions for 2010:
 No wishy washy 2010 predictions from me: VMware will cut prices, and Citrix will give up on XenServer: http://bit.ly/75vDxc
 The link in the tweet corresponds to this TechTarget article in which Alex predicts that VMware will cut prices and Citrix will dump XenServer and focus instead on its management products like Citrix Essentials. Citrix Essentials, as you probably know, already supports Microsoft Hyper-V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is SR-IOV?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/02/what-is-sr-iov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 23:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/02/what-is-sr-iov/</guid>
      <description>I/O virtualization is a topic that has received a fair amount of attention recently, due in no small part to the attention given to Xsigo Systems after their participation in the Gestalt IT Tech Field Day. While Xsigo uses InfiniBand as their I/O virtualization mechanism, there are other I/O virtualization technologies out there as well. One of these technologies is Single Root I/O Virtualization (SR-IOV).
So what is SR-IOV? The short answer is that SR-IOV is a specification that allows a PCIe device to appear to be multiple separate physical PCIe devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Is VMware Legitimizing the Competition?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 09:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a completely unrelated post on Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s site this morning about how VKernel is reacting to VMware&amp;rsquo;s release of CapacityIQ when a thought occurred to me: is VMware legitimizing the competition?
Here&amp;rsquo;s the excerpt from Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s post that started me thinking:
 And of course VKernel now is also in hurry to clarify that support for Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer is coming.
 Now, let me ask you this question: what is one of the largest complaints about products like Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
