<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wireless on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wireless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wireless on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wireless/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 109</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #109! This is the first Technology Short Take of 2019. It may be confirmation bias, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed of number of sites adding &amp;ldquo;Short Take&amp;rdquo;-type posts to their content lineup. I&amp;rsquo;ll take that as flattery, even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily intended that way. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Dell Latitude E7370</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/30/review-dell-latitude-e7370/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/30/review-dell-latitude-e7370/</guid>
      <description>As part of my Linux migration (see my initial progress report), late this past week I started setting up my first non-Apple laptop since 2003. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts on my new laptop, a Dell Latitude E7370.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s get the specs&amp;mdash;the &amp;ldquo;speeds and feeds&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;out of the way:
 Intel Core m7 CPU 16 GB of RAM 512 GB NVMe SSD 3200x1800 touchscreen Intel HD graphics and Intel 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures of OmniFocus Bonjour Sync</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/02/the-adventures-of-omnifocus-bonjour-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/02/the-adventures-of-omnifocus-bonjour-sync/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve made no secret of the fact that I use and enjoy OmniFocus, a GTD application from the fine folks at OmniGroup. (Just for the record, I also use and enjoy OmniGraffle and OmniOutliner. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that qualify me for a free license to OmniPlan?) In fact, one of the driving factors for purchasing my iPhone&amp;mdash;aside from the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s cool and I wanted one&amp;mdash;was the fact that OmniGroup also had an iPhone version of OmniFocus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ActiveSync on the iPhone</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/06/activesync-on-the-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 15:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/06/activesync-on-the-iphone/</guid>
      <description>Apple has just given me one more reason to possibly switch to an iPhone&amp;hellip;
iPhone opens to Exchange e-mail
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a Samsung BlackJack II, a Windows Mobile 6-based device with 3G connectivity. The e-mail functionality is great, but not having an easy way to keep my Address Book contacts in sync with my phone is a major hassle. It looks like using an iPhone would help address that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Wi-Fi</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/09/linux-wi-fi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2006 18:20:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/09/linux-wi-fi/</guid>
      <description>Wi-Fi on Linux is about to get much better, thanks to the release of an advanced Wi-Fi driver stack to the Linux community under the GPL.
As reported by eWeek (here&amp;rsquo;s the full article) and LinuxDevices.com (read the full article), Devicescape has released their advanced Wi-Fi driver stack under the GPL (read the press release) in order to speed the adoption of Linux-based Wi-Fi devices. Having wrestled with Wi-Fi support on Linux on more than a few occasions, I can attest to the difficulty of trying to get online with a less-than-perfectly-supported Wi-Fi card.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pair of Asterisk Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/20/a-pair-of-asterisk-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 21:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/20/a-pair-of-asterisk-articles/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of an Asterisk convergence recently, or at least for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a couple of articles that share one thing in common: the open source Asterisk VoIP PBX software. From wireless routers to virtual machines, Asterisk is making some noise.
First, there was this article from Nerd Vittles about a prebuilt Asterisk@Home virtual machine (instead to be used with the free VMware Player, but conceivably also usable with the upcoming free VMware Server) available from vmwarez.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
