<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ESX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/esx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ESX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/esx/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hypervisor is Only Part of the Picture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</guid>
      <description>The question of VMware&amp;rsquo;s future in the face of increasing competition is not a new one; it&amp;rsquo;s been batted around by quite a few folks. So Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols&amp;rsquo; article &amp;ldquo;Does VMware Have a Real Future?&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t really open any new doors or expose any new secrets that haven&amp;rsquo;t already been discussed elsewhere. What it does do, in my opinion, is show that the broader market hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet fully digested VMware&amp;rsquo;s long-term strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PXE Booting VMware ESX 4.0</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/02/pxe-booting-vmware-esx-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 18:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/02/pxe-booting-vmware-esx-40/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to work on a proof of concept (PoC) in which we wanted to help a customer streamline the processes needed to deploy new hosts and reduce the amount of time it took overall. One of the tools we used in the PoC for this purpose was PXE booting VMware ESX for an automated installation. Here are the details on how we made this work.
Before I get into the details, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide this disclaimer: there are probably easier ways of making this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resetting the Root Password on VMware ESX 4.0</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/13/resetting-the-root-password-on-vmware-esx-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 16:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/13/resetting-the-root-password-on-vmware-esx-40/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, I had to reset the root password on a lab server running VMware ESX 4.0 Update 1. For some reason, the password we assigned yesterday when we built the server from scratch wasn&amp;rsquo;t working this morning. OK, no big deal, right? Just reboot the server into single user mode and away you go. I won&amp;rsquo;t bother to repeat the steps for getting into single user mode; go to this article and it will give you what you need (the article is written for ESX 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 12:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #30, my irregularly posted collection of links and thoughts on virtualization. I hope you find something useful here!
  I believe Jason Boche already mentioned this on his own blog (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link) and also started this VMware Communities thread discussing the fact that the 8/6 patch breaks FT compatibility between ESX and ESXi hosts in the same cluster. This VMware KB article is now available with more information on the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCS Class Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/02/ucs-class-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 23:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/02/ucs-class-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>Last week&amp;rsquo;s partner boot camp for the Cisco Unified Computing System (UCS) was very helpful. It has really helped me gain a better understanding of the solution, how it works, and its advantages and disadvantages. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some random bits of information I gathered during the class here in the hopes that it will serve as a useful add-on to the formal training. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry the thoughts aren&amp;rsquo;t better organized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVVP Certifications for VMware vSphere</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/24/svvp-certifications-for-vmware-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 18:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/24/svvp-certifications-for-vmware-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>VMware has completed Microsoft Server Virtualization Validation Program (SVVP) certifications for both VMware vSphere 4.0 as well as ESX/ESXi 3.5 Update 4. This brings the list of SVVP-certified products to include:
 VMware vSphere 4.0 (ESX 4.0 and ESXi 4.0) VMware ESX 3.5 Update 4 VMware ESXi 3.5 Update 4 VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 VMware ESXi 3.5 Update 3 VMware ESX 3.5 Update 2  According to my contacts within VMware&amp;mdash;and many of you have probably heard the same&amp;mdash;the company is seeking to achieve SVVP certification for every ESX and ESXi release from 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New User&#39;s Guide to Configuring VMware ESX Networking via CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/23/new-user-networking-config-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 15:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/23/new-user-networking-config-guide/</guid>
      <description>A lot of the content on this site is oriented toward VMware ESX/ESXi users who have a pretty fair amount of experience. As I was working with some customers today, though, I realized that there really isn&amp;rsquo;t much content on this site for new users. That&amp;rsquo;s about to change. As the first in a series of posts, here&amp;rsquo;s some new user information on creating vSwitches and port groups in VMware ESX using the command-line interface (CLI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adaptec Support in vSphere Revoked?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/adaptec-support-in-vsphere-revoked/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 14:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/adaptec-support-in-vsphere-revoked/</guid>
      <description>It would appear (I have not yet been able to reliably verify this information) that VMware has removed support for the Adaptec aacraid driver from VMware vSphere. The driver was apparently listed on the Hardware Compatibility List (HCL) as supported at release, but shortly after release support was pulled. Apparently the aacraid driver is in such bad shape with vSphere that you can&amp;rsquo;t even install vSphere on systems using the aacraid driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Review in the Works</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/04/vmware-vsphere-review-in-the-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2009 11:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/04/vmware-vsphere-review-in-the-works/</guid>
      <description>Over the next couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll start posting a multi-part review of VMware vSphere 4.
Because this is such a large product with so many different features, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to break it into three or four sections. As the different parts go live on the site, the list below will be modified to link to the appropriate part of the review:
  Overview and installation
  Networking and storage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere vDS, VMkernel Ports, and Jumbo Frames</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2009 13:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/21/vmware-vsphere-vds-vmkernel-ports-and-jumbo-frames/</guid>
      <description>In April 2008, I wrote an article on how to use jumbo frames with VMware ESX and IP-based storage (NFS or iSCSI). It&amp;rsquo;s been a pretty popular post, ranking right up there with the ever-popular article on VMware ESX, NIC teaming, and VLAN trunks.
Since I started working with VMware vSphere (now officially available as of 5/21/2009), I have been evaluating how to replicate the same sort of setup using ESX/ESXi 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Generates Insane Amounts of I/O</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/vmware-vsphere-generates-insane-amounts-of-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 17:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/vmware-vsphere-generates-insane-amounts-of-io/</guid>
      <description>The news has hit the Internet in various places, but I wanted to point it out here because it does help to debunk the myth that virtualization can&amp;rsquo;t handle all workload. What&amp;rsquo;s the news? EMC and VMware have jointly demonstrated that a single VMware vSphere host running just three virtual machines can drive just above 350,000 I/O operations per second (IOPS).
I&amp;rsquo;ll let that sink in for just a moment. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t understand just how significant that number is, consider that a typical Fibre Channel drive can sustain somewhere just below 200 IOPS (and that&amp;rsquo;s being a bit generous).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper9 Virtualization Mobile Manager Beta Invitations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/14/hyper9-virtualization-mobile-manager-beta-invitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2009 12:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/14/hyper9-virtualization-mobile-manager-beta-invitations/</guid>
      <description>The fine folks over at Hyper9 recently offered me a very limited number of special beta invitations for Hyper9&amp;rsquo;s new Virtualization Mobile Manager (VMM) product. As you may already know, VMM is the brainchild of Andrew Kutz, who recently joined Hyper9 and has already released a few snippets of code via H9Labs.
Here are some highlights of VMM:
  Supports all major hypervisors: VMware Server 2, VMware Infrastructure 3 (VMware ESX and VMware ESXi 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyTrust Appliance Community Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/hytrust-appliance-community-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 22:11:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/hytrust-appliance-community-edition/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit behind the times on this one, as I know that several other bloggers have already made the announcement about the HyTrust Appliance Community Edition. This is a free version of the HyTrust Appliance that supports up to 3 ESX hosts and provides centralized access management and audit logging.
In any case, if you want more information on the HyTrust Appliance Community Edition, go have a look here at the HyTrust web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double-Take Software&#39;s Workload Optimization Suite</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/06/double-take-softwares-workload-optimization-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 15:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/06/double-take-softwares-workload-optimization-suite/</guid>
      <description>Today Double-Take Software announces their new Workload Optimization Suite. All of Double-Take&amp;rsquo;s flagship software products are now organized and unified within the idea of workload optimization, and new products are being announced to help provide a more complete set of solutions.
The products in the Workload Optimization Suite include:
 Double-Take Move Double-Take Flex Double-Take Backup Double-Take Availability  Of these four products, two of them&amp;mdash;Move and Flex&amp;mdash;are new products also being announced today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
