<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ESXi on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/esxi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ESXi on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/esxi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 142</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #142! This time around, the Networking section is a bit light, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of cloud computing links and articles for you to enjoy, along with some stuff on OSes and applications, programming, and soft skills. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s something useful here for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #37</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/06/technology-short-take-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/06/technology-short-take-37/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #37, the latest in my irregularly-published series in which I share interesting articles from around the Internet, miscellaneous thoughts, and whatever else I feel like throwing in. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Ivan does a great job of describing the difference between the management, control, and data planes, as well as providing examples. Of course, the distinction between control plane protocols and data plane protocols isn&amp;rsquo;t always perfectly clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>INF-VSP1423: esxtop for Advanced Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/inf-vsp1423-esxtop-for-advanced-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 15:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/27/inf-vsp1423-esxtop-for-advanced-users/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for INF-VSP1423, esxtop for Advanced Users, at VMworld 2012 in San Francisco, CA. The presenter is Krishna Raj Raja from VMware.
The presenter starts out the session with an explanation of how the session is going to proceed. This year&amp;mdash;this session has been presented multiple years at multiple VMworld conferences&amp;mdash;he&amp;rsquo;s choosing to focus on exposing the inner workings of the ESXi hypervisor through esxtop. High-level topics include NUMA, CPU usage, host cache, SR-IOV, and managing data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hypervisor is Only Part of the Picture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</guid>
      <description>The question of VMware&amp;rsquo;s future in the face of increasing competition is not a new one; it&amp;rsquo;s been batted around by quite a few folks. So Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols&amp;rsquo; article &amp;ldquo;Does VMware Have a Real Future?&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t really open any new doors or expose any new secrets that haven&amp;rsquo;t already been discussed elsewhere. What it does do, in my opinion, is show that the broader market hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet fully digested VMware&amp;rsquo;s long-term strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi Local Disks Showing as Remote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/27/vmware-esxi-local-disks-showing-as-remote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2011 09:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/27/vmware-esxi-local-disks-showing-as-remote/</guid>
      <description>A little over a month ago, I was installing VMware ESXi on a Cisco UCS blade and noticed something odd during the installation. I posted a tweet about the incident. Here&amp;rsquo;s the text of the tweet in case the link above stops working:
 Interesting&amp;hellip;this #UCS blade has local disks but all disks are showing as remote during #ESXi install. Odd&amp;hellip;
 Several people responded, indicating they&amp;rsquo;d run into similar situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing ESXi though UCSM KVM via RDC on OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/25/installing-esxi-though-ucsm-kvm-via-rdc-on-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 20:05:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/03/25/installing-esxi-though-ucsm-kvm-via-rdc-on-os-x/</guid>
      <description>How&amp;rsquo;s that for acronyms?
In all seriousness, though, as I was installing VMware ESXi this evening onto some remote Cisco UCS blades, I ran into some interesting keymapping issues and I thought it might be handy to document what worked for me in the event others run into this issue as well.
So here&amp;rsquo;s the scenario: I&amp;rsquo;m running Mac OS X 10.6.7 on my MacBook Pro, and using VMware View 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MA6580: Bridge the ESX/ESXi Management Gap with vMA</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/01/ma6580-bridge-the-esxesxi-management-gap-with-vma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 11:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/01/ma6580-bridge-the-esxesxi-management-gap-with-vma/</guid>
      <description>This is MA6580, titled &amp;ldquo;Bridge the ESX/ESXi Management Gap with the vSphere Management Assistant (vMA), Tips and Tricks Included&amp;rdquo;. The presenters are Chris Monfet and Tim Murnane. This is my first session of Day 3 of VMworld 2010 in San Francisco. Following this is a whirlwind of vendor meetings, video interviews, a book signing, and more sessions this afternoon.
The focus on the vMA is due to the shift in focus from VMware from VMware ESX (vSphere 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New User&#39;s Guide to Configuring VMware ESXi Networking via CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/23/new-users-guide-to-configuring-vmware-esxi-networking-via-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/23/new-users-guide-to-configuring-vmware-esxi-networking-via-cli/</guid>
      <description>This is one article in a series of articles focused toward new users. Some other New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide articles include:
  New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Configuring VMware ESX Networking via CLI
  New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Configuring Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
  New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Managing Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
  This particular article is a follow-up of sorts to the first article listed above.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/18/virtualization-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2010 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/18/virtualization-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 40th post in the Virtualization Short Take series, where I share with you various virtualization-related links, thoughts, and news tidbits. (Occasionally, I throw in some stuff that&amp;rsquo;s not virtualization related just to see if you are paying attention.) Enjoy!
  There have been a couple of posts now discussing Storage IO Control, a new feature that is possibly slated for inclusion in a future release of VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #33</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/07/virtualization-short-take-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 13:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/07/virtualization-short-take-33/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #33, the first installation of the Virtualization Short Take series for 2010! This installation will be a bit lean, but I hope that you find something useful among these nuggets of information.
  This article by Kenneth Van Ditmarsch, backed up by this post by Chad Sakac, underscore the need for proper operational documentation for your virtualization environment. Organizations that have taken the time to prepare operational procedures and train their staff on using the documented procedures will, in my opinion, be far less likely to fall victim to this vSphere storage bug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #31</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/18/virtualization-short-take-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/18/virtualization-short-take-31/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to yet another Virtualization Short Take! Here is a collection of virtualization-related items&amp;mdash;some recent, some not, but hopefully all interesting and/or useful.
  Matt Hensley posted a link to this VIOPS document on how to setup VMware SRM 4.0 with an EMC Celerra storage array. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to read through it yet.
  Jason Boche informs us that both Lab Manager 3 and Lab Manager 4 have problems with the VMXNET3 virtual NIC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #30</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 12:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/01/virtualization-short-take-30/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #30, my irregularly posted collection of links and thoughts on virtualization. I hope you find something useful here!
  I believe Jason Boche already mentioned this on his own blog (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link) and also started this VMware Communities thread discussing the fact that the 8/6 patch breaks FT compatibility between ESX and ESXi hosts in the same cluster. This VMware KB article is now available with more information on the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/25/virtualization-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 10:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/25/virtualization-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s Virtualization Short Take #27, a collection of news, tidbits, thoughts, articles, and useless trivia I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last week or so. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ll find a diamond in the rough among these items!
  Interested in more information on how it is, exactly, that Cisco is going to provide so much memory in their UCS blades and rack mount servers to make them ideal virtualization hosts? This article from CommsDesign and this &amp;ldquo;Catalina&amp;rdquo; article by Rodos Haywood both provide some great information on how Cisco is working around the Intel reference architecture limitations introduced with the Xeon 5500 and Quick Path Interconnect (QPI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SVVP Certifications for VMware vSphere</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/24/svvp-certifications-for-vmware-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 18:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/24/svvp-certifications-for-vmware-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>VMware has completed Microsoft Server Virtualization Validation Program (SVVP) certifications for both VMware vSphere 4.0 as well as ESX/ESXi 3.5 Update 4. This brings the list of SVVP-certified products to include:
 VMware vSphere 4.0 (ESX 4.0 and ESXi 4.0) VMware ESX 3.5 Update 4 VMware ESXi 3.5 Update 4 VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 VMware ESXi 3.5 Update 3 VMware ESX 3.5 Update 2  According to my contacts within VMware&amp;mdash;and many of you have probably heard the same&amp;mdash;the company is seeking to achieve SVVP certification for every ESX and ESXi release from 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
