<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OTV on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/otv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OTV on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/otv/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Examining Some Networking-Virtualization Chimeras</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</guid>
      <description>I like to spend time examining the areas where different groups of technologies intersect. Personally, I find this activity fascinating, and perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the reason that I find myself pursing knowledge and experience in virtualization, networking, storage, and other areas simultaneously&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s an effort to spend more time &amp;ldquo;on the border&amp;rdquo; between various technologies.
One border, in particular, is very interesting to me: the border between virtualization and networking. Time spent thinking about the border between networking and virtualization is what has generated posts like this one, this one, or this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation from South Florida VMUG</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/02/presentation-from-south-florida-vmug/</guid>
      <description>Back in early March I was invited to speak at the South Florida VMUG, and I gave this presentation on vSphere networking challenges and solutions. The idea behind the presentation was to give attendees some visibility into IEEE and IETF efforts at creating new network technologies and protocols. I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here just in case someone might find it useful or helpful.
Here is a link to the presentation.
As always, your questions, corrections, or clarifications are welcome in the comments below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTV and VXLAN Layer 3 Connectivity Compared</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/22/otv-and-vxlan-layer-3-connectivity-compared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/22/otv-and-vxlan-layer-3-connectivity-compared/</guid>
      <description>Building large-scale L2 networks, including stretched L2 networks, seems to be all the rage these days, driven in part by virtual machine mobility (aka vMotion in VMware vSphere environments or XenMotion in Citrix XenServer environments). While this isn&amp;rsquo;t always a good idea&amp;mdash;some might say it&amp;rsquo;s never a good idea&amp;ndash;it is still something that many organizations are evaluating.
With the announcement of VXLAN at VMworld 2011, a new question seems to have arisen: can I use VXLAN instead of (insert some other protocol here) to create my stretched L2 networks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting VXLAN and Layer 3 Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/07/revisiting-vxlan-and-layer-3-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 23:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/07/revisiting-vxlan-and-layer-3-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>In my earlier post on VXLAN and Layer 3 connectivity, I had a fatal flaw in my thinking and in my diagrams that was corrected for me in the comments to that post. In this post, I want to revisit the idea of Layer 3 connectivity with VXLAN and include the corrected information (and new diagrams).
The &amp;ldquo;fatal flaw&amp;rdquo; was that I was working under the impression that we&amp;rsquo;d have to change network address translation (NAT) mappings on the vShield Edge (VSE) instance that was handling NAT for a particular VXLAN segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VXLAN and Layer 3 Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/30/vxlan-and-layer-3-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 11:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/30/vxlan-and-layer-3-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Note: I&amp;rsquo;ve posted a follow-up to this article with some corrected information. Please read here.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing quite a bit of networking-related reading over the last few weeks, and VXLAN has been a key topic of this networking-related reading (along with OTV, MPLS, and OpenFlow). Since VXLAN&amp;rsquo;s announcement at VMworld US 2011, there have been some pretty good articles written and published about VXLAN. Here are a few, for example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #15</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #15, the latest in my irregular series of posts on various articles and links on networking, servers, storage, and virtualization&amp;mdash;everything a growing data center engineer needs!
Networking My thoughts this time around are pretty heavily focused on VXLAN, which continues to get lots of attention. I talked about posting a dissection of VXLAN, but I have failed miserably; fortunately, other people smarter than me have stepped up to the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #13</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 10:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #13. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last Technology Short Take, and much has happened (vSphere 5 was announced, HP discontinued the TouchPad and webOS, and I announced my move to Denver). Here are a few data center technology-related links that stood out to me over the last few weeks. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   Here&amp;rsquo;s a good post by Jeremy Waldrop on Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 FEX (fabric extender) topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-9131: Mobility and Virtualization with LISP and OTV</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-9131-mobility-and-virtualization-with-lisp-and-otv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 19:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-9131-mobility-and-virtualization-with-lisp-and-otv/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKDCT-9131, Mobility and Virtualization in the Data Center with LISP and OTV. This is one of the last, if not the last, session at Cisco Live 2011.
The presenter, Victor Moreno, spends a few minutes at first talking about distributed data center clouds, the goals, and the challenges of building them. Some of the challenges or considerations include:
  L2 domain elasticity (think FabricPath and LAN extensions)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKDCT-3060: Deployment Considerations with Interconnecting DCs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-3060-deployment-considerations-with-interconnecting-dcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 12:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brkdct-3060-deployment-considerations-with-interconnecting-dcs/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKDCT-3060, Deployment Considerations with Interconnecting Data Centers, presented by Patrice Bellagamba (Distinguished SE) and Max Ardica (Solution Architect). Given that my role in virtualization and storage puts me squarely in the middle of these sorts of designs, I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to this session and gaining some valuable knowledge out of it.
The primary objectives of the session are to identify the business requirements driving DCI (Data Center Interconnect) deployments; understanding the functional components of the Cisco DCI solution; and get a full knowledge of Cisco LAN extension technologies and associated considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #12: Networking Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/16/technology-short-take-12-networking-edition/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve published the Storage Edition of Technology Short Take #12, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Networking Edition. Enjoy, and I hope you find something useful!
  Ron Fuller&amp;rsquo;s ongoing deep dive series on OTV (Overlay Transport Virtualization) has been great for me. I knew about the basics of OTV, but Ron&amp;rsquo;s articles really gave me a better understanding of the technology. Check out the first three articles here: part 1, part 2, and part 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
