<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IBM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ibm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IBM on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ibm/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon EU 2017 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/18/dockercon-eu-2017-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/18/dockercon-eu-2017-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the day 2 keynote/general session here in Copenhagen, Denmark, at DockerCon EU 2017. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/dockercon-eu-day-1-keynote/&#34;&gt;the liveblog here&lt;/a&gt;) featured the hotly-anticipated Kubernetes announcement (I shared &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/some-thoughts-on-docker-kubernetes-announcement/&#34;&gt;some thoughts here&lt;/a&gt;), so it will be interesting to see what Docker has in store for today&amp;rsquo;s general session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware, This is Wrong</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/28/vmware-this-is-wrong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2009 09:12:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/28/vmware-this-is-wrong/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: VMware has clarified their position; they will allow competitors to exhibit at VMworld. The text in the exhibitors agreement was legalese&amp;mdash;supposedly consistent with other major vendor-sponsored conferences&amp;mdash;meant to give them an out in the event an exhibitor behaves inappropriately.
I sincerely hope that Brian Madden is wrong about the recent change to vendor policies for VMworld.
This is exactly the wrong thing to do in this sort of competitive landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing IBM BladeCenter Open Fabric Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/07/implementing-ibm-bladecenter-open-fabric-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 14:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/07/implementing-ibm-bladecenter-open-fabric-manager/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
A few months ago I implemented the Basic version IBM&amp;rsquo;s BladeCenter Open Fabric Manager (BOFM) and I wanted to share some of my notes with everyone. It has been awhile so this is very high level; most of the small details have since fallen out of my head.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what Open Fabric Manager is, BOFM allows you to virtualize the FC and Ethernet connections coming from a blade server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of Viewpoints on Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/03/a-collection-of-viewpoints-on-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2009 17:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/03/a-collection-of-viewpoints-on-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks have passed since the announcement of Cisco&amp;rsquo;s Unified Computing System (UCS), and in that timeframe I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a number of links to articles and blog posts about UCS. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d collect them here and try to get a feel from all of the various viewpoints where the industry stands on UCS.
I&amp;rsquo;ll start with Robin Harris aka StorageMojo and his initial take on UCS. The one thing that jumped out at me about his article was this statement:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Four, HP Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 16:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/16/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-four-hp-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
Welcome to Part 4 in our series on blades and virtualization. Please note that I will be covering the HP virtualized I/O offerings in a near future post. I plan to cover Virtual Connect, Flex-10, and the BL495 blade at that time.
As always, lets start by reviewing the hardware specification we will be using to compare the rack servers against the blade servers. Here are the portions of the spec that concern us:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Three, IBM Traditional Expansion Options</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/13/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-three-ibm-traditional-expansion-options/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
UPDATE: I have made some corrections to the 10GB and iSCSI sections based on feedback. Thank you!
Welcome to part 3 of my series on blades and virtualization. I will be breaking the expansion articles into four parts: traditional IBM options, traditional HP options, virtualized IBM options, and virtualized HP options. By &amp;ldquo;virtualized options&amp;rdquo; I mean the IBM and HP blade I/O virtualization solutions (like IBM Blade Open Fabric Manager and HP VirtualConnect), not a server configuration that will run virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alas, BladeVault is No More</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/08/alas-bladevault-is-no-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2009 22:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/08/alas-bladevault-is-no-more/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take long these days: yesterday the bladevault.info and bladevault.com domains, owned by friend and colleague Aaron Delp, expired. Today they were picked up by an unknown registrant and are serving up ads.
Fortunately, Aaron&amp;rsquo;s moved most of his content over to his new blog, and is also contributing great blade-related material here, such as these two recent articles:
Blades and Virtualization Aren&amp;rsquo;t Mutually Exclusive: Part One, HP Power Sizing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part Two, IBM Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 15:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/07/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-two-ibm-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
This is the second part of a series of articles on blades and virtualization. The first article is found here. Today, I will present IBM rack servers versus blade servers and explore the power consumption for each.
In case you need it again, here is the hardware platform I will be using as the standard:
 2 x E5450 3.0 Ghz quad-core processors 32 GB memory in an 8 x 4GB configuration 2 on-board NICs Additional quad NIC card for a total of 6 NICs Dual FC card (assuming FC SAN storage for VMs but it could easily be NFS or iSCSI as well) 2 x 146GB, 10k SAS drives (except the IBM HS21XM blades which only support one HD)  Here is the link to the IBM System x and Blade Power Configuration Tool I used for the numbers below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blades and Virtualization Aren&#39;t Mutually Exclusive: Part One, HP Power Sizing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 19:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/04/blades-and-virtualization-arent-mutually-exclusive-part-one-hp-power-sizing/</guid>
      <description>By Aaron Delp
I have seen a lot of misconceptions recently when it comes to blade servers and virtualization. Many seem to think that if you are using blades you can&amp;rsquo;t use virtualization. Most recently, someone shared this article with me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t disagree with this viewpoint more. I will explore the reasons why in the next few articles. For today&amp;rsquo;s article, I will present a foundation for comparison and I will use this basis going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P2V With IBM Blades</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/03/p2v-with-ibm-blades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2008 12:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/03/p2v-with-ibm-blades/</guid>
      <description>A colleague and a customer passed me some information late last week about performing physical-to-virtual (P2V) conversions on with blades in an IBM blade chassis. (This was with an older BladeCenter chassis, not the BladeCenter H chassis.)
Apparently, if you run a P2V on a blade in the chassis without first selecting the blade on the chassis&amp;rsquo; KVM, then the resulting virtual machine does not have a CD-ROM drive. Users will have to shutdown the VM, add the CD-ROM drive to the VM, and then boot it back up again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/31/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2008 16:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/31/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>A friend and colleague of mine recently launched a blog of his own, The Blade Blog. If the useful information that&amp;rsquo;s been posted there so far is any indication, this will be a definite addition to your RSS subscriptions. Keep up the good work, Aaron!
UPDATE: After some great feedback on the launch of his site, Aaron&amp;rsquo;s moved away from Blogger to a hosted WordPress solution and has gotten a new domain name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link State Tracking in Blade Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/22/link-state-tracking-in-blade-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2007 13:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/22/link-state-tracking-in-blade-deployments/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s common in blade deployments to use multiple Ethernet switches in the blade chassis to provide network redundancy (I&amp;rsquo;ll refer to these as &amp;ldquo;in-chassis switches&amp;rdquo; moving forward). For example, in both the IBM BladeCenter H and the HP BladeSystem c-Class, we can provision multiple in-chassis switches so that half of the NICs on the blades connect to one in-chassis switch and the other half connect to the other switch. Within the OS, we load NIC teaming software to provide automatic failover if one of the links goes down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BladeCenter H Woes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/02/bladecenter-h-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2007 22:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/02/bladecenter-h-woes/</guid>
      <description>This IBM BladeCenter H installation I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on with another engineer for the last couple of days is not going as smoothly as we both would have liked. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is indicative of the BladeCenter H chassis itself, or if it&amp;rsquo;s just me. While some would say it&amp;rsquo;s just me, I suspect it&amp;rsquo;s a little of both.
For example, we ran into issues with the Management Modules &amp;ldquo;freaking out,&amp;rdquo; and failing over between the modules didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Very High Quality vs. Just Good Enough</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2006 15:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/25/very-high-quality-vs-just-good-enough/</guid>
      <description>In a recent article discussing Novell&amp;rsquo;s leadership change, one analyst was quoted regarding the change as being positive for Novell in that they (Novell) could stop building very high quality products and instead build products that are just good enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but this spirit of mediocrity is exactly the wrong kind of thinking for IT vendors.
Specifically, the quote stated this:
 &amp;ldquo;Ron Hovsepian appears to be an astute business person, one who will be able to quickly take stock of the environment and Novell&amp;rsquo;s position within that environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows and OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/25/windows-and-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2006 11:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/25/windows-and-os-x/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of industry pundits out there proclaiming that the introduction of Boot Camp&amp;mdash;Apple&amp;rsquo;s new beta application that simplifies and streamlines the installation of Windows XP (and presumably Windows Vista as well) on Intel-based Macs&amp;mdash;is simply the first step in a complex scheme that will eventually culminate in something much bigger. I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure about that.
The predictions range the whole gamut of possibilities. Some are predicting that Apple will begin reselling Windows XP pre-loaded on its Intel-based Macs, much in the way that MacMall is now doing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
