<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IDF2014 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2014/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IDF2014 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2014/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Intel Rack-Scale Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard of Intel Rack-Scale Architecture (RSA), a new approach to designing data center hardware. This is an idea that was discussed extensively a couple of weeks ago at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014 in San Francisco, which I had the opportunity to attend. (Disclaimer: Intel paid my travel and hotel expenses to attend IDF.)
Of course, IDF 2014 wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I&amp;rsquo;d heard of Intel RSA; it was also discussed last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014: Architecting for SDI, a Microserver Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/11/idf-2014-architecting-for-sdi-a-microserver-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/11/idf-2014-architecting-for-sdi-a-microserver-perspective/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for session DATS013, on microservers. I was running late to this session (my calendar must have been off&amp;mdash;thought I had 15 minutes more), so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to capture the titles or names of the speakers.
The first speaker starts out with a review of exactly what a microserver is; Intel sees microservers as a natural evolution from rack-mounted servers to blades to microservers. Key microserver technologies include: Intel Atom C2000 family of processors; Intel Xeon E5 v2 processor family; and Intel Ethernet Switch FM6000 series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014: Open Source Storage Optimizations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/11/idf-2014-open-source-storage-optimizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 11:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/11/idf-2014-open-source-storage-optimizations/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of IDF 2014 session DATS009, titled &amp;ldquo;Ceph: Open Source Storage Software Optimizations on Intel Architecture for Cloud Workloads.&amp;rdquo; (That&amp;rsquo;s a mouthful.) The speaker is Anjaneya &amp;ldquo;Reddy&amp;rdquo; Chagam, a Principal Engineer in the Intel Data Center Group.
Chagam starts by reviewing the agenda, which&amp;mdash;as the name of the session implies&amp;mdash;is primarily focused on Ceph. He next transitions into a review of the problem with storage in data centers today; specifically, that storage needs &amp;ldquo;are growing at a rate unsustainable with today&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure and labor costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014 Day 2 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-day-2-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 23:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-day-2-recap/</guid>
      <description>Following on from my IDF 2014 Day 1 recap, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap of day 2.
Data Center Mega-Session You can read the liveblog here if you want all the gory details. If we boil it down to the essentials, it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty simple. First, deliver more computing power in the hardware, either through the addition of FPGAs to existing CPUs or through the continued march of CPU power (via more cores or faster clock speeds or both).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014: Data Center Mega-Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-data-center-mega-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 11:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-data-center-mega-session/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Data Center Mega-Session from day 2 of Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014 in San Francisco.
Diane Bryant, SVP and GM of the Data Center Group takes the stage promptly at 9:30am to kick off the data center mega-session. Bryant starts the discussion by setting out the key drivers affecting the data center: new devices (and new volumes of devices) and new services (AWS, Netflix, Twitter, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014 Day 1 Recap</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-day-1-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 09:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/10/idf-2014-day-1-recap/</guid>
      <description>In case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, I&amp;rsquo;m at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014 this week in San Francisco. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap of day 1 (I should have published this last night&amp;mdash;sorry for not getting it out sooner).
Day 1 Keynote Here&amp;rsquo;s a liveblog of the IDF 2014 day 1 keynote.
The IDF keynotes are always a bit interesting for me. Intel has a very large consumer presence: PCs, ultrabooks, tablets, phones, 2-in-1/convertibles, all-in-1 devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014: Bare Metal, Docker Containers, and Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf2014-bare-metal-docker-containers-and-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 17:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf2014-bare-metal-docker-containers-and-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>This is a live blog of session DATS004, titled &amp;ldquo;Bare-Metal, Docker Containers, and Virtualization: The Growing Choices for Cloud Applications.&amp;rdquo; The speaker is Nicholas Weaver (yes, that Nick Weaver, who now works at Intel).
Weaver starts his presentation by talking about &amp;ldquo;how we got here&amp;rdquo;, discussing the various technological shifts that have affected the computing landscape over the years. Weaver includes a discussion of the drivers behind virtualization as well as the pros and cons of virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014: Virtualizing the Network to Enable SDI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf-2014-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 15:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf-2014-virtualizing-the-network-to-enable-sdi/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of IDF 2014 session DATS002, titled &amp;ldquo;Virtualizing the Network to Enable a Software-Defined Infrastructure (SDI)&amp;rdquo;. The speakers are Brian Johnson (Solutions Architect, Intel) and Jim Pinkerton (Windows Server Architect, Microsoft). I attended a similar session last year; I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for some new information this year.
Pinkerton starts the session with a discussion of why Microsoft is able to speak to network virtualization via their experience with large-scale web properties (Bing, XBox Live, Outlook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2014 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf-2014-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 11:25:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/09/idf-2014-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the day 1 keynote at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014. The keynote starts with an interesting musical piece that shows how technology can be used to allow a single performer to emulate the sound of a full band, and then kicks off with a &amp;ldquo;pocket avatar&amp;rdquo; presentation by Brian Krzanich, CEO of Intel Corporation. Krzanich takes the stage in person a few minutes later.
Krzanich starts with a recap of some of the discussions from last year&amp;rsquo;s IDF, and he points out some of the results over the last year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
