<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interop2015 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/interop2015/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interop2015 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 12:28:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/interop2015/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: The Post-Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/the-post-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/the-post-cloud/</guid>
      <description>This session is titled &amp;ldquo;The Post-Cloud,&amp;rdquo; and the speaker is Nick Weaver, Director of SDI-X at Intel.
Nick starts his presentation with a summary of our society: some people produce goods through an effort, and others consume what is produced. Things have changed over the years that have affected this production-consumption model, but Nick quickly turns his focus to the use of machines in the production portion of this cycle. As production efficiency increased, the level of consumption also increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: Thursday Cloud Connect Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/cloud-connect-keynote-liveblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/cloud-connect-keynote-liveblog/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Thursday morning Cloud Connect keynote at Interop 2015 in Las Vegas. The title of the presentation is &amp;ldquo;Doing it Live,&amp;rdquo; and the speaker is Jared Wray (@jaredwray on Twitter; he&amp;rsquo;s Cloud CTO and SVP of Platform at CenturyLink).
As the session kicks off, Wray shares that his presentation was drastically altered, a nod to the drastic changes that he is seeing at CenturyLink. He then shares a bit of background on him, his history in IT, and the events that brought him to CenturyLink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: Techniques of a Network Detective</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/29/techniques-network-detective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/29/techniques-network-detective/</guid>
      <description>This is &amp;ldquo;Techniques of a Network Detective,&amp;rdquo; led by Denise &amp;ldquo;Fish&amp;rdquo; Fishburne (@DeniseFishburne on Twitter). Denise starts the session with a quick introduction, in which she discloses that she is a &amp;ldquo;troubleshooting junkie.&amp;rdquo; She follows up with a short description of what life looks like in her role in the customer proof-of-concept lab at Cisco.
Denise kicks off the main content of the session by drawing an analogy between solving crimes and solving network performance/behavior problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: IPv6 Microsegmentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/29/ipv6-microsegmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/29/ipv6-microsegmentation/</guid>
      <description>This session was titled &amp;ldquo;IPv6 Microsegmentation,&amp;rdquo; and the speaker was Ivan Pepelnjak. Ivan is, of course, a well-known figure in the networking space, and publishes content at http://ipspace.net.
The session starts with a discussion of the problems found in Layer 2 IPv6 networks. Some of the problems include spoofing RA (Router Advertisement) messages, NA (Neighbor Advertisement) messages, DHCPv6 spoofing, DAD (Duplicate Address Detection) DoS attacks, and ND (Neighbor Discovery) DoS attacks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
