<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2011 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2011/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2011 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 14:27:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2011/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at VMworld EMEA 2011</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/21/spousetivities-at-vmworld-emea-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 14:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/21/spousetivities-at-vmworld-emea-2011/</guid>
      <description>In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard already, the registration page for Spousetivities at VMworld EMEA 2011 is live and open for sign-ups! Crystal made the announcement about Spousetivities at VMworld EMEA on her site already, but I wanted to include it here as well so that everyone knew. Most of the activities sold out at VMworld US in Las Vegas, and Crystal&amp;rsquo;s hoping for similar success this year in Copenhagen. If you are going to be attending VMworld EMEA in Copenhagen and bringing your spouse/partner/significant other/family member, here are some of the things that are planned:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exclusion or Not?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 17:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/20/exclusion-or-not/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago I read Stephen Foskett&amp;rsquo;s article &amp;ldquo;Alas, VMware, Whither HDS?&amp;rdquo;, and I felt like I really needed to respond to this growing belief&amp;mdash;stated in Stephen&amp;rsquo;s article and in the sources to his article&amp;mdash;that VMware is, for whatever reason, somehow excluding certain storage vendors from future virtualization-storage integration development. From my perspective, this is just bogus.
As far as I can tell, Stephen&amp;rsquo;s post&amp;mdash;which is just one of several I&amp;rsquo;ve seen on this subject&amp;mdash;is based on two sources: my session blog of VSP3205 and an article by The Register.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining an Optimal Design</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/19/determining-an-optimal-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/19/determining-an-optimal-design/</guid>
      <description>I had an interesting e-mail conversation last week with fellow EMC vSpecialist Clint Kitson. Now, if you&amp;rsquo;ve never met Clint, he&amp;rsquo;s a super-sharp fellow, no questions about it. I love conversations with super-sharp folks as they invariably lead to new thoughts and new ideas, and this conversation was no different. The topic of the conversation, in generalized terms, was this: when crafting designs for customers, what defines an &amp;ldquo;optimal design&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Couple Vendor Meetings at VMworld 2011</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/31/a-couple-vendor-meetings-at-vmworld-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 20:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/31/a-couple-vendor-meetings-at-vmworld-2011/</guid>
      <description>Over the last couple of days at VMworld, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to meet up with a couple of vendors to discuss their product initiatives and offerings. I had lined up several more meetings, but due to my hectic schedule I was unable to make those meetings. To those companies that I missed, I apologize. There just aren&amp;rsquo;t enough hours in the day!
Bluesocket One company that I met with is Bluesocket, whose link to VMware is through their vWLAN (virtual wireless LAN) product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSP2117: Virtualization-Aware Datacenter Networks</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/31/vsp2117-virtualization-aware-datacenter-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 16:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/31/vsp2117-virtualization-aware-datacenter-networks/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for VSP 2117, titled Virtualization-Aware Datacenter Networks. The presenter is Milin Desai, Group Product Manager for Networking at VMware. This is the session where I will, hopefully, get the answers I need for VXLAN.
Milin indicates that customers&amp;mdash;he says he&amp;rsquo;s talked to over 1,000 customers&amp;mdash;want mobility. They want planned migrations, disaster recovery, and live migrations. So how is the datacenter network going to evolve to meet these customer requirements?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2011 Tuesday General Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/30/vmworld-2011-tuesday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 11:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/30/vmworld-2011-tuesday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for the Day 2 general session at VMworld 2011 in Las Vegas. Today everyone here at VMworld is looking forward to the in-depth technical discussions that typically follow after Paul Maritz&amp;rsquo; more high-level presentation the previous day. VMware CTO, Steve Herrod, should be one of the primary if not the primary speaker today.
The session begins with some videos from various VMware employees discussing their products: vCenter Operations, vFabric and vFabric Data Director, vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2011 Monday General Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vmworld-2011-monday-general-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 18:45:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vmworld-2011-monday-general-session/</guid>
      <description>This is the session blog for the Monday general session. I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to have arrived in time to get a seat at the blogger/press/analyst tables. While the network connectivity is good, the power is&amp;mdash;unfortunately&amp;mdash;not so good.
The general session started with an impressive lightshow across the front of the conference that depicts the change of computing with the advent of virtualization and cloud computing. It was visually appealing and interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSP3205: Tech Preview, vStorage APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vsp3205-tech-preview-vstorage-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 13:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vsp3205-tech-preview-vstorage-apis/</guid>
      <description>This is a session blog for VSP3205, titled &amp;ldquo;Tech Preview: vStorage APIs for VM and Application Granular Data Management.&amp;rdquo; The presenters are Satyam Vaghani and Vijay Ramachandran, both with VMware.
This session will be repeated tomorrow at 1PM and Wednesday (didn&amp;rsquo;t catch the time). As usual, the presentation starts out with the VMware disclaimer, followed by a quick review of the &amp;ldquo;state of the union&amp;rdquo; with vStorage APIs for Array Integration (VAAI) and vStorage APIs for Storage Awareness (VASA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VSP1682: VMware vSphere Clustering Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vsp1682-vmware-vsphere-clustering-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 10:51:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/29/vsp1682-vmware-vsphere-clustering-qa/</guid>
      <description>This is the session almost-live-blog (no wireless signal available in the session room) of VSP1682, VMware vSphere Clustering Q&amp;amp;A. The panelists are Duncan Epping, Frank Denneman, and Chris Colotti, all of VMware.
Lots of notable names were present in the session&amp;mdash;Jason Boche, Kendrick Coleman, Mike Foley, Andy Banta, fellow co-authors Forbes Guthrie and Maish Saidel-Keesing were among the ones I noticed, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure that there were even more that I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2011 Spousetivities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/26/vmworld-2011-spousetivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/26/vmworld-2011-spousetivities/</guid>
      <description>Spousetivities is now in its fourth year at VMworld, and Crystal (my wife and the founder of Spousetivities) has some great stuff planned for VMworld US this year. Thanks to her sponsors (in alphabetical order: eGroup, EMC, HP, HyTrust, Train Signal, and VMUG), she&amp;rsquo;s been able to pull together a great collection of activities for spouses or significant others traveling with you to VMworld in Las Vegas.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick look at some of the stuff she has planned:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
