<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Telephony on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/telephony/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Telephony on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/telephony/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</guid>
      <description>In discussing support for corporate communication and collaboration systems as part of my Linux migration, I&amp;rsquo;ve so far covered e-mail in part 1 and calendaring in part 2. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the last few remaining aspects of corporate collaboration: instant messaging/chat, meetings and teleconferences, and document sharing.
Teleconferences and meetings The topic of teleconferences and meetings is closely related to calendaring&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to access your calendar or others&amp;rsquo; calendars when coordinating meetings or teleconferences&amp;mdash;so I encourage you to read part 2 to get a better feel for the challenges around calendaring/scheduling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pair of Asterisk Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/20/a-pair-of-asterisk-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2006 21:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/02/20/a-pair-of-asterisk-articles/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of an Asterisk convergence recently, or at least for me. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a couple of articles that share one thing in common: the open source Asterisk VoIP PBX software. From wireless routers to virtual machines, Asterisk is making some noise.
First, there was this article from Nerd Vittles about a prebuilt Asterisk@Home virtual machine (instead to be used with the free VMware Player, but conceivably also usable with the upcoming free VMware Server) available from vmwarez.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
