<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UNIX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/unix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UNIX on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 15:11:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/unix/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running Synergy on OS X Mavericks</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/13/running-synergy-on-os-x-mavericks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 15:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/01/13/running-synergy-on-os-x-mavericks/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you a workaround to running Synergy on OS X Mavericks. If you visit the official Synergy page, you&amp;rsquo;ll note that the site indicates that full Mavericks support is still pending. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re willing to &amp;ldquo;get your hands dirty,&amp;rdquo; you can run Synergy on OS X Mavericks right now.
If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with Synergy, read this write-up (from 2 years ago) on how I use Synergy in my home office setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using pf on OS X Mountain Lion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/15/using-pf-on-os-x-mountain-lion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/15/using-pf-on-os-x-mountain-lion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written before about adding an extra layer of network security to your Macintosh by leveraging the BSD-level ipfw firewall, in addition to the standard GUI firewall and additional third-party firewalls (like Little Snitch). In OS X Lion and OS X Mountain Lion, though, ipfw was deprecated in favor of pf, the powerful packet filter that I believe originated on OpenBSD. (OS X&amp;rsquo;s version of pf is ported from FreeBSD.) In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use pf on OS X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #26</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #26! As you might already know, the Technology Short Takes are my irregularly-published collections of links, articles, thoughts, and (sometimes) rants. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   Chris Colotti, as part of a changed focus in his role at VMware, has been working extensively with Nicira NVP. He&amp;rsquo;s had a couple of good posts; this one is a primer on how NVP works, and this one discusses the use of the Open vSwitch (OVS) vApp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Network Redesign</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/03/open-source-network-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 10:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/08/03/open-source-network-redesign/</guid>
      <description>As you might have noticed in recent blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;m spending a fair amount of time working with open source solutions like Ubuntu Linux, OpenBSD, Puppet, and similar. As part of the effort to make myself more familiar with these and other open source projects, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to re-architect my home network using predominantly open source software.
Here are the open source software projects that I know for sure I&amp;rsquo;ll end up using:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Hiera Working</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/24/getting-hiera-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 20:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/24/getting-hiera-working/</guid>
      <description>As I mentioned in a previous post, the next iteration of my Puppet explorations involves the use of Hiera. Hiera, a project also managed by Puppet Labs, is described as &amp;ldquo;a simple pluggable hierarchical database.&amp;rdquo; In the Puppet world, what that means is we can use Hiera to store data values outside of the manifests, then look them up dynamically as the configurations are being compiled and applied to the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Feedback on Infrastructure Coders Denver</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/22/seeking-feedback-on-infrastructure-coders-denver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 18:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/22/seeking-feedback-on-infrastructure-coders-denver/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I posted this to Twitter:
 I need to find (or maybe start?) something like @infracoders here in the Denver area.
 The @Infracoders (or Infrastructure Coders) Twitter account is for an &amp;ldquo;infrastructure as code&amp;rdquo; meetup group in the Melbourne, Australia, area (here&amp;rsquo;s their website). Shortly after that post, Matthew Jones&amp;mdash;one of the co-founders of the original Melbourne-based Infracoders meetup group&amp;mdash;contacted me. We exchanged a few e-mails, and the end result of our conversation is that we will be starting up a Denver-based version of Infrastructure Coders!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Multi-OS Puppet Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/09/updated-multi-os-puppet-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/09/updated-multi-os-puppet-configuration/</guid>
      <description>I received some great feedback on my post about using Puppet with multiple operating systems. One of the suggestions was to do a better job of following the &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; Puppet style guide for syntax and file layout. With that in mind, I installed puppet-lint on my Puppet master server using apt-get install rubygems followed by gem install puppet-lint.
Using puppet-lint, I was able to correct all &amp;ldquo;errors&amp;rdquo; in the manifest, but was left with one warning regarding line length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Puppet with Multiple Operating Systems</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/05/using-puppet-with-multiple-operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2012 17:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/05/using-puppet-with-multiple-operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with the open source edition of Puppet, the configuration management/automation tool. I&amp;rsquo;ve learned quite a bit, but I still have a long, long way to go. What I wanted to share in this post is what I learned in using Puppet with clients using different operating systems (OSes). If you are a Puppet expert, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear any tips and tricks you might have to help me improve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up ipfw on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/05/setting-up-ipfw-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 22:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/05/setting-up-ipfw-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>Using multiple layers of security has long been recognized as a useful strategy in hardening your computers against attack or exploit. In this post, I want to explain how to set up and configure the BSD-level ipfw firewall that is present in Mac OS X. While ipfw is certainly not a security panacea, it can be a solid part of a broader security strategy.
Setting up ipfw on Mac OS X has three basic steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Switching to EagleFiler</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/07/switching-to-eaglefiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 23:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/07/switching-to-eaglefiler/</guid>
      <description>Over the last month or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a strong interest in moving a fair number of my files that are predominantly text-based back to &amp;ldquo;standards-based&amp;rdquo; formats such as RTF and plain text. I&amp;rsquo;ve started using Markdown as a means of storing formatting information in plain text files, and then using tools like Pandoc to convert these Markdown files into the desired destination format. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely discuss this in more detail in a future post, but what I wanted to discuss here was the affect of this decision on my software usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Useful UNIX Commands on your Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/25/some-useful-unix-commands-on-your-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/25/some-useful-unix-commands-on-your-mac/</guid>
      <description>Over the last day or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been messing around at the UNIX command line on my Mac, trying to find a workaround for a VPN policy that doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow split tunneling. (Just as a stupid side question, what is the security issue with split tunneling, anyway?) Along the way, I uncovered some handy commands for gathering information about the networking configuration of your Mac.
I can&amp;rsquo;t take credit for all of these; most of them were shared with me by Matt Cowger, fellow VCDX and vSpecialist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GNU Screen with SSH</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/23/using-gnu-screen-with-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2011 15:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/23/using-gnu-screen-with-ssh/</guid>
      <description>This post is probably old news to experienced UNIX sys admins, but I thought the information might be useful to less knowledgeable folks like me. I also hope that the resulting conversation will help uncover even more knowledge we can all put to good use.
I&amp;rsquo;ve messed around with the screen utility off and on for a while. One thing I&amp;rsquo;d never quite figured out, though, was how using screen helped with SSH sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying iTerm2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/17/trying-iterm2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/17/trying-iterm2/</guid>
      <description>In 2007 I posted an article about iTerm, an open source terminal application for Mac OS X. At that time, I gave up on iTerm and switched back to the Apple-supplied Terminal.app. For a while, it seemed as if iTerm was stagnating and development had stalled.
However, I recently learned that some developers forked the original iTerm to create iTerm2. Like the original iTerm, iTerm2 supports AppleScript and tabbed terminals. The tabbed terminals I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about (I don&amp;rsquo;t use tabs, generally speaking), but I do like AppleScript support (in case you hadn&amp;rsquo;t picked that up already).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Allegations Regarding FBI Involvement with OpenBSD</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/14/allegations-regarding-fbi-involvement-with-openbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 20:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/14/allegations-regarding-fbi-involvement-with-openbsd/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s get right to the point and set the record straight: I am not, nor have I ever been, affiliated with or employed by the FBI or any other government agency.
That&amp;rsquo;s why I was surprised when word surfaced that I had been implicated in some sort of conspiracy regarding a plan to place secret backdoors into an OpenBSD cryptographic framework, and that my recent advocacy of OpenBSD was based on my alleged involvement with the FBI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortening URLs via bit.ly from the CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/20/shortening-urls-via-bitly-from-the-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 18:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/20/shortening-urls-via-bitly-from-the-cli/</guid>
      <description>I was experimenting tonight with some ways to add more automation to my workflow. One process that is (relatively) time-consuming is the process of generating short URLs via bit.ly. This site had a brief tutorial on how to use curl to do it, but the shortened link didn&amp;rsquo;t show up in my link history. Upon browsing the bit.ly API documentation, though, I was able to fairly quickly piece together a command line that will shorten a URL via bit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
