<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/writing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 144</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #144! I have a fairly diverse set of links for readers this time around, covering topics from microchips to improving your writing, with stops along the way in topics like Kubernetes, virtualization, Linux, and the popular JSON-parsing tool &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MultiMarkdown 6 on Ubuntu 19.10</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/04/03/installing-mmd6-on-ubuntu-1910/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 18:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/04/03/installing-mmd6-on-ubuntu-1910/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; is a core part of many of my workflows. For quite a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve used Fletcher Penny&amp;rsquo;s MultiMarkdown processor (available on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fletcher/MultiMarkdown-6/&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;) on my various systems. Fletcher offers binary builds for Windows and macOS, but not a Linux binary. Three years ago, I wrote a post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/25/installing-mmd6-on-fedora-27/&#34;&gt;how to compile MultiMarkdown 6 for a Fedora-based system&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how to compile it on an Ubuntu-based system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Updated Look at My Multi-Platform Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/30/updated-look-at-multi-platform-toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/30/updated-look-at-multi-platform-toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2017 I posted about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/03/my-evolving-multi-platform-toolbelt/&#34;&gt;my (evolving) multi-platform toolbelt&lt;/a&gt;, describing some of the applications, standards, and services that I use across my Linux and macOS systems. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide an updated review of that toolbelt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2017 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has become my custom for the past several years, I wanted to take a look  at how well I fared on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2017 project list&lt;/a&gt;. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this before the end of 2017, but during this past holiday season I decided to more fully &amp;ldquo;unplug&amp;rdquo; and focus on the truly important things in life (like my family). So, here&amp;rsquo;s a look back at my 2017 projects and a report card on my progress (or lack thereof, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Creating Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October of this year, I published a blog post talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/&#34;&gt;a sample &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for publishing blog articles&lt;/a&gt;. That post focused on the use of &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the process of a publishing a blog post. This post is a companion to that post, and focuses on the use of a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the creation of blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing MultiMarkdown 6 on Fedora 27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/25/installing-mmd6-on-fedora-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/25/installing-mmd6-on-fedora-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long-time readers are probably aware that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt;. Specifically, I prefer the MultiMarkdown variant that adds some additional extensions beyond &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; Markdown. As such, I&amp;rsquo;ve long used Fletcher Penny&amp;rsquo;s MultiMarkdown processor (the latest version, version 6, is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fletcher/MultiMarkdown-6/&#34;&gt;available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;). While Fletcher offers binary builds for Windows and macOS, the Linux binary has to be compiled from source. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide the steps I followed to compile a MultiMarkdown binary for &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sublime Text Keymap for Bracketeer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/02/sublime-text-keymap-bracketeer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/02/sublime-text-keymap-bracketeer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made no secret of the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; (ST). I&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated other editors, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io/&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, but still find that ST offers the right blend of performance, functionality, customizability, and cross-platform support. One nice thing about ST (other editors have this too) is the ability to extend it via packages. &lt;a href=&#34;https://packagecontrol.io/packages/Bracketeer&#34;&gt;Bracketeer&lt;/a&gt; is one of many packages that can be used to customize ST&amp;rsquo;s behavior; in this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a keymap I&amp;rsquo;m using with Bracketeer that I&amp;rsquo;ve found very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Publishing Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some readers may already know, this site has been running on a static site generator since late 2014/early 2015, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;I migrated from WordPress to Jekyll on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve since migrated again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;this time to Hugo on S3/CloudFront&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken an interest in using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help automate certain tasks at the CLI. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I&amp;rsquo;m using a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help with publishing blog articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Q&amp;A About the Migration to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/18/some-qa-about-migration-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/18/some-qa-about-migration-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may already know, I recently completed the migration of this site from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; (generated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;) to S3/CloudFront and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for static site generation. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked with a few readers who had additional questions about the site migration. I thought others might have the same questions, so I decided to gather the most common questions here and share the answers with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 85</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #85! This is my irregularly-published collection of links and articles from around the Internet related to the major data center technologies: networking, hardware, security, cloud computing, applications/OSes, storage, and virtualization. Plus, just for fun, I usually try to include a couple career-related links as well. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information on the Recent Site Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I completed the migration of this site to an entirely new platform, marking the third or fourth platform migration for this site in its 12-year history. Prior to the migration, the site was generated using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;a previous migration in late 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to that, I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; for about 9 years. So what is it running now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using a Makefile with Markdown Documents</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/08/using-makefile-with-markdown-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/08/using-makefile-with-markdown-documents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of using &lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.com/markdown/&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; (specifically, &lt;a href=&#34;http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/&#34;&gt;MultiMarkdown&lt;/a&gt;) for the vast majority of all the text-based content that I create. Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve created used various tools and created scripts to help &amp;ldquo;reduce the friction&amp;rdquo; involved with outputting Markdown source files into a variety of destination formats (HTML, RTF, or DOCX, for example). Recently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.codybunch.com/2017/04/17/On-Computerized-Note-Taking/&#34;&gt;thanks to Cody Bunch&lt;/a&gt;, I was pointed toward the use of a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to assist in this area. After a short period of experimentation, I&amp;rsquo;m finding that I really like this workflow, and I wanted to share some details here with my readers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canceling the OVS Cookbook Project</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/28/canceling-ovs-cookbook-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/28/canceling-ovs-cookbook-project/</guid>
      <description>In my list of proposed 2017 projects, I mentioned that I wanted to launch an open source book project. In late February, I launched The Open vSwitch Cookbook, an unofficial&amp;mdash;as in not formally affiliated with the Open vSwitch (OVS) project&amp;mdash;effort to gather together OVS &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; into an open source book. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m shutting down that project, and here&amp;rsquo;s why.
It really comes down to wanting to be a better member of the OVS community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launching an Open Source Book Project</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/21/launching-open-source-book-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/21/launching-open-source-book-project/</guid>
      <description>In my list of planned 2017 projects, I mentioned that one thing I&amp;rsquo;d like to do this year is launch an open source book project. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce The Open vSwitch Cookbook, an Apache 2.0-licensed book project aimed at providing &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; recipes for Open vSwitch (OVS).
Portions of the book are already available, with more content being added soon (more on that in a moment).
I&amp;rsquo;m using GitBook as the publishing platform; this allows me to write in Markdown and publish to a variety of formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2017 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing my list of projects for each year (here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2012, the list for 2013, 2015&amp;rsquo;s list, and last year&amp;rsquo;s list&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a list for 2014). Toward the end of each year, I also publish a &amp;ldquo;report card&amp;rdquo; assessing my performance against that year&amp;rsquo;s list (here&amp;rsquo;s the 2016 assessment). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share my list of planned projects for 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
