<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backup on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/backup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backup on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:25:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/backup/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Velero to Protect Cluster API</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/11/using-velero-to-protect-cluster-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 10:25:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/11/using-velero-to-protect-cluster-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api.sigs.k8s.io/&#34;&gt;Cluster API&lt;/a&gt; (also known as CAPI) is, as you may already know, an effort within the upstream &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; community to apply Kubernetes-style APIs to cluster lifecycle management&amp;mdash;in short, to use Kubernetes to manage the lifecycle of Kubernetes clusters. If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with CAPI, I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/08/26/an-introduction-to-kubernetes-cluster-api/&#34;&gt;my introduction to Cluster API&lt;/a&gt; before proceeding. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://velero.io&#34;&gt;Velero&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Heptio Ark) to backup and restore Cluster API objects so as to protect your organization against an unrecoverable issue on your Cluster API management cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Populating New Namespaces Using Heptio Ark</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/22/populating-new-namespaces-using-heptio-ark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/22/populating-new-namespaces-using-heptio-ark/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/heptio/ark&#34;&gt;Heptio Ark&lt;/a&gt; is a tool designed to backup and restore &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; cluster resources and persistent volumes. As such, it enables users to do a bunch of very useful things like copy cluster resources across cloud providers or replicate environments for development, staging, testing, QA, etc. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a slightly different use case for Ark: populating resources into new Kubernetes namespaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Snow Leopard and Time Machine on an Iomega ix4-200d</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/09/revisiting-snow-leopard-and-time-machine-on-an-iomega-ix4-200d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2011 14:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/04/09/revisiting-snow-leopard-and-time-machine-on-an-iomega-ix4-200d/</guid>
      <description>In late 2009, I posted a how-to on making Snow Leopard work with an Iomega ix4-200d for Time Machine backups. I&amp;rsquo;ll recommend you refer back to that article for full details, but the basic steps are as follows:
  Use the hdiutil command to create the sparse disk image with the correct name (a concatenation of the computer&amp;rsquo;s name and the MAC address for the Ethernet interface).
  Create a special file inside the sparse disk image (the com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some EMC Data Domain Announcements Today</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/some-emc-data-domain-announcements-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 10:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/some-emc-data-domain-announcements-today/</guid>
      <description>EMC Data Domain made a couple of significant product announcements today. First, EMC announced the EMC Data Domain Global Deduplication Array (GDA). Second, EMC also announced a doubling of the logical capacity for the high-end Data Domain DD880.
The full press release for the GDA announcement is available here. The &amp;ldquo;speeds and feeds&amp;rdquo; of the new multi-controller architecture of the GDA include throughput of up to 12.8 TB/hour, up to 270 concurrent backup operations, and up to 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow Leopard, Time Machine, and Iomega ix4-200d</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/09/snow-leopard-time-machine-and-iomega-ix4-200d/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2009 23:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/09/snow-leopard-time-machine-and-iomega-ix4-200d/</guid>
      <description>Chad Sakac of EMC (visit his weblog here) recently sent me an Iomega ix4-200d storage unit. Considering that I didn&amp;rsquo;t need it for my VMware lab&amp;mdash;which runs both EMC and NetApp storage arrays&amp;mdash;I pressed it into service at home. I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how useful it&amp;rsquo;s been, especially the built-in Time Machine support. Making my three-year-old MacBook Pro running Leopard (Mac OS X 10.5) work with the Iomega&amp;rsquo;s Time Machine implementation was a piece of cake: point it at the ix4-200d and you&amp;rsquo;re all set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMFS Isn&#39;t the Problem Here</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/22/vmfs-isnt-the-problem-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 18:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/22/vmfs-isnt-the-problem-here/</guid>
      <description>I was reading this article by Eric Gray about CSV and followed his link to this ZDNet post about VMFS-3. I was a little taken aback.
One of the first questions that popped into my head was, &amp;ldquo;Why not use VMware Converter?&amp;rdquo; After all, it&amp;rsquo;s the tool that was expressly designed to do exactly what Jason Perlow was attempting to do in the DR exercise with his customer: import data back into a VMware vSphere environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Version of esXpress Supports vSphere</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/22/new-version-of-esxpress-supports-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 11:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/22/new-version-of-esxpress-supports-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>PHD Virtual Technologies, maker of the esXpress backup solution, are today announcing the availability of the latest version of their backup product. esXpress version 3.6 offers support for VMware vSphere 4 and, according to PHD Virtual, also offers improvements for all versions of VMware ESX since version 3.0.2.
esXpress 3.6 features a new deduplication engine that provides substantial new performance levels, based on information provided by PHD Virtual. For example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snapshot Issue with VMware Data Recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/29/snapshot-issue-with-vmware-data-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 10:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/29/snapshot-issue-with-vmware-data-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Reader Kyle Ross shared with me a potential issue with VMware&amp;rsquo;s new backup product, VMware Data Recovery. Others within the VMware blogging scene have also covered this, but I wanted to mention it as well so that others didn&amp;rsquo;t run into the problem. Here&amp;rsquo;s Kyle&amp;rsquo;s write-up:
 I was made aware of a serious (in my opinion) bug with VDR during a call with VMware support that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen discussed anywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 VCB Solutions Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-vcb-solutions-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 16:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-vcb-solutions-session/</guid>
      <description>This session is titled &amp;ldquo;Best Practices for Architecting VMware Consolidated Backup Enabled Solutions,&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s being led by a couple of different presenters, one of whom is Dan Anderson, who also led the VCB session on Partner Day and leads the VCB labs (and led the VCB labs last year at VMworld 2006). So far, it looks like this session won&amp;rsquo;t be a repeat of Monday&amp;rsquo;s Partner Day session, which is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Partner Day Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/10/vmworld-2007-partner-day-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 19:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/10/vmworld-2007-partner-day-sessions/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to attend three Partner Day sessions today, all three from the &amp;ldquo;Advanced In-Depth Technical Track.&amp;rdquo;
The first was this morning, and it was focused on an in-depth technical review of VMware Consolidated Backup. I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few articles about VMware Consolidated Backup before:
  VMware Consolidated Backup
  Restoring VCB Full Backups with VMware Converter
  Strange VCB Error
  The presenter was very knowledgeable; in fact, he was the one running the VCB labs at VMworld (and ran the labs at VMworld last year, which I attended).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange VCB Error</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/07/strange-vcb-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 12:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/08/07/strange-vcb-error/</guid>
      <description>While in the process of verifying the operation of VMware Consolidated Backup (version 1.0.3) today using the command-line vcbMounter.exe utility, I kept receiving an error from vcbMounter and the full VM backups would fail. Nothing seemed obvious at first, so I added the &amp;ldquo;-L 6&amp;rdquo; parameter to the command line, which was something like this:
vcbmounter -h vcserver.example.com -u username -p password -r e:\mnt -a ipaddr:10.1.1.107 -t fullvm -L 6  Nothing terribly complicated there, just a simple full VM backup of the VM whose IP address is 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Various VMware Links</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/18/various-vmware-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 16:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/18/various-vmware-links/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before that I use NetNewsWire for subscribing to various RSS and Atom feeds for various topics. Of course, given my interest in virtualization, VMware and VMware-related tags are things that are included in my feed list, and quite often I come across a link from a tag search or del.icio.us subscription that I find interesting. It may not justify a dedicated blog post about that particular item, though, because it may not be anything about which I can contribute useful information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restoring VCB Full Backups with VMware Converter</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/06/restoring-vcb-full-backups-with-vmware-converter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 11:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/06/restoring-vcb-full-backups-with-vmware-converter/</guid>
      <description>When performing full VM backups with VMware Consolidated Backup (VCB), the end result of the backup operation is a copy of the VMs VMDK files, in 2GB blocks. This format is similar to the format used by VMware Server and VMware Workstation, VMware&amp;rsquo;s hosted virtualization products. Given that VMware Converter can convert VMs between ESX Server and the hosted virtualization products, I thought, &amp;ldquo;Why not use VMware Converter to restore VCB backups?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
