<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VPN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vpn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VPN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vpn/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starting WireGuard Interfaces Automatically with Launchd on macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/04/starting-wireguard-interfaces-automatically-launchd-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/04/starting-wireguard-interfaces-automatically-launchd-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late June of this year, I wrote a piece on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/&#34;&gt;using WireGuard on macOS via the CLI&lt;/a&gt;, where I walked readers using macOS through how to configure and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard VPN&lt;/a&gt; from the terminal (as opposed to using the GUI client, which I discussed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). In that post, I briefly mentioned that I was planning to explore how to have macOS&amp;rsquo; &lt;code&gt;launchd&lt;/code&gt; automatically start WireGuard interfaces. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WireGuard on macOS via the CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few different posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;simple yet fast and modern VPN&amp;rdquo; (as described by the WireGuard web site) that aims to supplant tools like IPSec and OpenVPN. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/&#34;&gt;first post on WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; showed how to configure WireGuard on Linux, both on the client side as well as on the server side. After that, I followed it up with posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;using the GUI WireGuard app to configure WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;mdash;most recently&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/&#34;&gt;making WireGuard from Homebrew work on an M1-based Mac&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a look at using WireGuard on macOS again, but this time via the CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WireGuard from Homebrew Work on an M1 Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;the post on using WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; (using the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; GUI app from the Mac App Store), I found the GUI app&amp;rsquo;s behavior to be less than ideal. For example, tunnels marked as on-demand would later show up as no longer configured as an on-demand tunnel. When I decided to set up WireGuard on my M1-based MacBook Pro (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/02/review-2020-m1-based-macbook-pro/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt; of the M1 MacBook Pro), I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use the GUI app. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; has formulas for WireGuard. Unfortunately, the WireGuard tools as installed by Homebrew on an M1-based Mac won&amp;rsquo;t work. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WireGuard on macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 17:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short while ago I published a post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/&#34;&gt;setting up WireGuard for AWS VPC access&lt;/a&gt;. In that post, I focused on the use of Linux on both the server side (on an EC2 instance in your AWS VPC) as well as on the client side (using the GNOME Network Manager interface). However, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; is not limited to Linux, and I recently configured one of my macOS systems to take advantage of this WireGuard infrastructure for access to the private subnets in my AWS VPC. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk readers through configuring macOS to use WireGuard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WireGuard for AWS VPC Access</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeking more streamlined access to AWS EC2 instances on private subnets, I recently implemented &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; for VPN access. WireGuard, if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, is a relatively new solution that is baked into recent Linux kernels. (There is also support for other OSes.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share what I learned in setting up WireGuard for VPN access to my AWS environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 136</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/15/technology-short-take-136/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/15/technology-short-take-136/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #136, the first Short Take of 2021! The content this time around seems to be a bit more security-focused, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to include a few links in other areas. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 130</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #130! I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post sitting in my Drafts folder waiting to be published for almost a month, and I kept forgetting to actually make it live. Sorry! So, here it is&amp;mdash;better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 127</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/05/29/technology-short-take-127/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 15:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/05/29/technology-short-take-127/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #127! Let&amp;rsquo;s see what I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to collect for you this time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 121</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/06/technology-short-take-121/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/06/technology-short-take-121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #121! This may possibly be the last Tech Short Take of 2019 (not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to squeeze in another one), so here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that you find something useful, helpful, or informative in the links that I&amp;rsquo;ve collected. Enjoy some light reading over your festive holiday season!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Split Tunneling with vpnc</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/12/split-tunneling-with-vpnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/12/split-tunneling-with-vpnc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;vpnc&lt;/code&gt; is a fairly well-known VPN connectivity package available for most Linux distributions. Although &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unix-ag.uni-kl.de/%7Emassar/vpnc/&#34;&gt;the &lt;code&gt;vpnc&lt;/code&gt; web site&lt;/a&gt; describes it as a client for the Cisco VPN Concentrator, it works with a wide variety of IPSec VPN solutions. I&amp;rsquo;m using it to connect to a Palo Alto Networks-based solution, for example. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share how to set up split tunneling for &lt;code&gt;vpnc&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on VPNs for Road Warriors</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/28/thoughts-on-vpns-for-road-warriors/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/02/28/thoughts-on-vpns-for-road-warriors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I was talking with a few folks on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and the topic of using VPNs while traveling came up. For those that travel regularly, using a VPN to bypass traffic restrictions is not uncommon. Prompted by my former manager &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/martin_casado/&#34;&gt;Martin Casado&lt;/a&gt;, I thought I might share a few thoughts on VPN options for road warriors. This is by no means a comprehensive list, but hopefully something I share here will be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 87</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/22/technology-short-take-87/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/22/technology-short-take-87/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #87! I have a mix of newer and older items for you this time around. While I&amp;rsquo;m a bit short on links in some areas, hopefully this is outweighed by some good content in other areas. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #40</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2014 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/08/technology-short-take-40/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #40. The content is a bit light this time around; I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give you, my readers, a little break. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s still some useful and interesting stuff here. Enjoy!
Networking   Bob McCouch has a nice write-up on options for VPNs to AWS. If you&amp;rsquo;re needing to build out such a solution, you might want to read his post for some additional perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: DIY Network Virtualization?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 11:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Following on the heels of this week&amp;rsquo;s VMware NSX announcement at VMworld 2013, I had someone contact me about a statement this person had heard. The statement claimed NSX was nothing more than a collection of tools, and that it was possible to get the equivalent of NSX using completely free (as in speech and as in beer) open source tools&amp;mdash;specifically, IPTables, StrongSwan, OpenVPN, and Open vSwitch (OVS). Basically, the statement was that it was possible to create do-it-yourself network virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Your Home DNS Servers with Corporate VPNs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/14/using-your-home-dns-servers-with-corporate-vpns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/14/using-your-home-dns-servers-with-corporate-vpns/</guid>
      <description>Among IT pros, it&amp;rsquo;s quite common these days to have a home lab/home network complete with DNS, DHCP, hypervisors, storage, etc. As IT pros, it&amp;rsquo;s also quite common to have to use a virtual private network (VPN) solution to connect back to our employers&amp;rsquo; corporate networks in order to get work done. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how you can reconcile these two (sometimes conflicting) situations with a relatively little-known feature in OS X.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
