<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macintosh on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/macintosh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macintosh on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 17:07:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/macintosh/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Computing as a Collection of VMs?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/28/personal-computing-as-a-collection-of-vms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 17:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/28/personal-computing-as-a-collection-of-vms/</guid>
      <description>There appear to be basically two views on how virtualization will affect the future development of operating systems and computing environments in the personal computing space. One camp believes that virtualization functionality will be present within the operating system. Whether that virtualization functionality comes bundled with the operating system or is a third-party add-on to the operating system is, quite frankly, irrelevant to this particular discussion. The other camp believes that virtualization will be outside the operating system, perhaps in the form of a hypervisor or thin virtualization layer that resides &amp;ldquo;below&amp;rdquo; the OS and governs access to hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Agnosticism</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/26/application-agnosticism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2006 22:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/26/application-agnosticism/</guid>
      <description>I coined the term &amp;ldquo;application agnosticism&amp;rdquo; in the context of the discussion surrounding virtualization and its impact on the future of the operating system. Virtualization proponents, such as VMware, say that virtualization means the end of the general purpose operating system and instead point to the rise of virtual appliances. In the virtual appliance realm, the operating system exists to provide services to the application, and unnecessary components of the operating system are stripped away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Fusion Public Beta</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/22/vmware-fusion-public-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2006 11:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/22/vmware-fusion-public-beta/</guid>
      <description>Rumors had been building for the last few days, and in response VMware finally released the public beta for VMware Fusion, the Mac desktop virtualization product. I&amp;rsquo;d written about my first impressions earlier; now I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts on the public beta build.
Keep in mind that this is still a beta; it&amp;rsquo;s too early to make any sort of performance comparisons. (Having said that, I&amp;rsquo;m not really worried about performance; Windows XP Professional seems to run just fine for what I need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM Portability, Round 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/12/vm-portability-round-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2006 12:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/12/vm-portability-round-3/</guid>
      <description>Having first tested VM portability from VMware Workstation (on Windows) to VMware Fusion (on Mac OS X), then portability from ESX Server to VMware Fusion, the next logical step was VMware Fusion to ESX Server. I ran into one surprise but, as I expected, the process worked without any major hiccups.
The first step was to get the virtual disk files from my MacBook Pro over to ESX Server. Last time, when I ran this process in reverse, I used the open source SFTP client Cyberduck to copy the VMDK files down from ESX Server to my laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.1x Integration with Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/07/8021x-integration-with-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 14:36:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/07/8021x-integration-with-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>The idea behind 802.1x is to provide Layer 2 authentication; that is, to authenticate LAN clients at the Ethernet layer. (This is before the client gets a DHCP lease or anything of that nature.) With 802.1x in place, rogue users can&amp;rsquo;t just tap into a physical connection on the network. In order to gain network connectivity, the device must authenticate before network traffic is allowed.
The idea here is to configure 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM Portability Again</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/06/vm-portability-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 17:02:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/06/vm-portability-again/</guid>
      <description>The idea was to take a VM running Windows Server 2003 R2 off one of the ESX servers and port it over to VMware Fusion on my MacBook Pro. If that worked (and I fully expected that it would), then I&amp;rsquo;d try reversing the process. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;d love to move that same VM I moved last week over to the VI3 server farm from my MBP (it&amp;rsquo;s running the NetApp Data ONTAP Simulator and I could really use it running on the servers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of the OS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/05/the-future-of-the-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2006 11:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/05/the-future-of-the-os/</guid>
      <description>Over at Virtualization Daily, Kimbro Staken pulls together a variety of views about the future of the operating system. Citing such forces as Web applications, virtualization, and ever-increasing hardware power, he and others believe that the general purpose operating system as we know it has no future.
I do agree with these conclusions on at least one point: The general purpose operating system as we know it will cease to exist in the next 5 to 10 years, perhaps sooner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macintosh Virtualization Heating Up</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/04/macintosh-virtualization-heating-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2006 09:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/04/macintosh-virtualization-heating-up/</guid>
      <description>Parallels Desktop for Mac took the prize as the first virtualization solution for Intel-based Macs (OK, the first commercial solution). Even so, heavyweight VMware&amp;rsquo;s entry into the Mac market caused many to say, &amp;ldquo;Well, there goes Parallels.&amp;rdquo;
Not so fast. I&amp;rsquo;m a huge VMware fan and make no secret of it. But in perusing the list of features for this latest beta, I see a couple of features that VMware ought to be worried about:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solaris 10 x86 on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/29/solaris-10-x86-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 22:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/29/solaris-10-x86-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the chance to finish installing Solaris 10 yet, as I ran out of time trying to copy down the ISO images before I left to go to Atlanta for some Network Appliance training. (By the way, have I mentioned how cool NetApp&amp;rsquo;s stuff is? No? It is.)
After first running into the problem with the Solaris 10 VM, I inquired with other private beta testers and later filed a bug report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM Portability</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/29/vm-portability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2006 21:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/29/vm-portability/</guid>
      <description>The article at virtualizationdaily.com is pretty cool, but I&amp;rsquo;d be much more interested if it were written the other way around&amp;mdash;converting a Parallels VM to run under VMware. Of course, that&amp;rsquo;s not likely to happen until VMware Fusion hits public beta. If I had a copy of Parallels (or a Parallels VM), I&amp;rsquo;d try it myself. Anyone out there with a Parallels VM they want to donate? Hey, wait a minute&amp;hellip;I could just try one of the prebuilt Parallels appliances also made available at virtualizationdaily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Consoles Inside Virtual Machines</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/20/virtual-consoles-inside-virtual-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2006 17:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/20/virtual-consoles-inside-virtual-machines/</guid>
      <description>Using VMware Fusion (or I suppose that other Intel-based Mac virtualization application, Parallels Desktop), we can now run a Windows instance on our Mac (I&amp;rsquo;m running it on a Core 2 Duo-based MacBook Pro, for example). Like all other VMware hosted products (VMware Workstation or VMware Server, both on either Windows or Linux), the close-enough-to-native performance allows us to use this instance in order to host an installation of the Virtual Infrastructure (VI) client without an unacceptable performance impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MacBook Pro EFI Firmware Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/16/macbook-pro-efi-firmware-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2006 17:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/16/macbook-pro-efi-firmware-update/</guid>
      <description>The Apple Support page that describes the firmware update states that after the update, the Boot ROM Version will be reported by System Profiler as MBP11.0055.B08 (for 15-inch MacBook Pros) or MBP12.0061.B03 (for the 17-inch MacBook Pros).
OK, fair enough&amp;mdash;but System Profiler on my 15-inch Core 2 Duo-based MacBook Pro reports the Boot ROM Version as MBP22.00A5.B00. Now, unless I&amp;rsquo;m reading that wrong, that would appear to be a newer version than what the firmware update is reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Few Weeks with the MacBook Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/15/my-first-few-weeks-with-the-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 22:48:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/15/my-first-few-weeks-with-the-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>There were two concerns I had about buying a MacBook Pro, neither of them huge concerns but sufficient enough nevertheless. The first was the heat; there were just so many reports of MBPs running hot. (Yes, I know that this was primarily early-run MBPs.) The second was the performance of non-Universal applications.
I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that both of these concerns are unfounded. I&amp;rsquo;ve had my MBP under some fairly significant loads in the last few days; just today, for example, I had VMware Fusion running (with a Windows XP Professional VM running Visio 2002 Professional), Mail, iCal, Camino, NetNewsWire, Address Book, Terminal, Microsoft Word, ecto, and four Remote Desktop Connection sessions all running simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full-Text Indexing in Mail.app Broken</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/10/full-text-indexing-in-mailapp-broken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2006 23:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/10/full-text-indexing-in-mailapp-broken/</guid>
      <description>Of course, I&amp;rsquo;ve done the requisite Google search, which turned up a few hits. Most of them suggested a rebuild of the mailbox, which I&amp;rsquo;ve done. No change. I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried forcing Spotlight to re-index the mail data (via mdimport -f ~/Library/Mail). Also no change. It&amp;rsquo;s funny because using the Spotlight menu works just fine, and will return mail messages that contain the requested text. It&amp;rsquo;s just the search filter in Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Fusion First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/04/vmware-fusion-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2006 20:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/11/04/vmware-fusion-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I installed VMware Fusion earlier today and immediately set out to install Windows XP Professional. Despite the fact that once I switched to Mac OS X I haven&amp;rsquo;t ever really looked back, I still have the rare occasion when I need to run some Windows application (usually Visio). So, it made sense to me to install Windows first, then to move on to more exotic subjects such as Solaris or OpenBSD.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
