<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VDI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vdi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VDI on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vdi/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 114</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/17/technology-short-take-114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/17/technology-short-take-114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #114! There will be a longer gap than usual before the next Tech Short Take (more details to come on Monday), but in the meantime here&amp;rsquo;s some articles and links to feed your technical appetite. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing the VMware Horizon Client on Fedora 27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/13/installing-vmware-horizon-client-fedora-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/13/installing-vmware-horizon-client-fedora-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll outline the steps necessary to install the VMware Horizon client for Linux on &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27. Although VMware provides an &amp;ldquo;install bundle,&amp;rdquo; the bundle does not, unfortunately, address any of the prerequisites that are necessary in order for the Horizon client to work. Fortunately, some other folks shared their experiences, and building on their knowledge I was able to make it work. I hope that this post will, in turn, help others who may find themselves in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #22</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 13:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #22! Once again, I find myself without too many articles to share with you this time around. I guess that will make things a bit easier for you, the reader, but it does make me question whether or not I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;listening&amp;rdquo; to the right communities. If any readers have suggestions on sources of information to which I should be subscribing or I should be following, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware End-User Computing Virtual Conference</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/26/vmware-end-user-computing-virtual-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 16:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/04/26/vmware-end-user-computing-virtual-conference/</guid>
      <description>VMware is holding an &amp;ldquo;End User Computing Virtual Conference&amp;rdquo; next week. Here&amp;rsquo;s the text of the announcement/invitation that I saw (and yes, I made sure that VMware was OK with me posting it here so that others could attend if interested):
 Please join VMware as we discuss the next step forward in end-user computing for the post-PC era.
Watch Vittorio Viarengo, VP of End-User Computing, discuss the latest advancements in the VMware End-User Computing Platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware View Client for Mac with PCoIP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/16/vmware-view-client-for-mac-with-pcoip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 13:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/16/vmware-view-client-for-mac-with-pcoip/</guid>
      <description>VMware just released the PCoIP-enabled version of the VMware View client for Mac OS X (download here; login required). After having used it this morning to connect to my corporate View desktop, I must say that I am quite impressed.
The responsiveness of my View desktop is significantly improved over RDP. Under RDP, browsing any sort of Web site&amp;mdash;and accessing various internal-only sites is a key use for my corporate View desktop&amp;mdash;was just downright painful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #18</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 23:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/11/technology-short-take-18/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #18! I hope you find something useful in this collection of networking, OS, storage, and virtualization links. Enjoy!
Networking The number of articles in my &amp;ldquo;Networking&amp;rdquo; bucket continues to overflow; I have so many articles on so many topics (soft switching, OpenFlow, Open vSwitch, MPLS) that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get my head wrapped around all of it. Here are a few posts that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Right vSphere Design Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2011 11:09:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/16/the-right-vsphere-design-perspective/</guid>
      <description>I was on a conference call the other day where the topic of the call was VMware View 5.0. If you attended VMworld&amp;mdash;or even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t, it&amp;rsquo;s been kind of hard to miss&amp;mdash;you know already that VMware made significant improvements to PCoIP in View 5. For one reason or another, the topic of the Teradici PCoIP offload card came up on the call, and other participants in the call were immediately asking about the availability of the card in mezzanine card format for blade server implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDP Printer Redirection with VMware View on a Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/22/rdp-printer-redirection-with-vmware-view-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 12:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/06/22/rdp-printer-redirection-with-vmware-view-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>Last July I wrote an article about editing the vmware-view.rdp file inside the VMware View Open Client for Mac OS X in order to customize the RDP settings. It was one of those articles that I thought would probably appeal to only a very small group but would otherwise go mostly unnoticed.
As it turns out, one reader named Patrick Fergus picked up on that article and started experimenting with it to see if he could enable printer redirection using a similar technique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DV7706: View Composer Technical Deep Dive and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/dv7706-view-composer-technical-deep-dive-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 18:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/dv7706-view-composer-technical-deep-dive-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of VMworld 2010 session DV7706, titled &amp;ldquo;View Composer Technical Deep Dive and Best Practices,&amp;rdquo; in Moscone West 2004. The presenter(s) are Jeff Whitman and Jim Yanik, both with VMware.
We start out the session with a quick review of some limitations. View Composer has a limit of eight ESX/ESXi hosts in a cluster. This is a VMFS limit involving the number of hosts that are accessing a read-only file at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Announcements, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/vmworld-announcements-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 20:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/vmworld-announcements-day-1/</guid>
      <description>A flurry of virtualization-related product announcements flew into my Inbox today, thoroughly disrupting the empty Inbox I&amp;rsquo;d cultivated before the show. Anyway, I thought readers might be interested in some of the announcements, so here they are:
  Akorri announced they&amp;rsquo;ve achieved VMware Ready status with their BalancePoint product. If you&amp;rsquo;re at VMworld and want to talk to Akorri, stop by booth 1331.
  Similarly, Avere Systems has also been awarded VMware Ready status for its FXT 2700 appliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing RDP Settings in VMware View Open Client for Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/21/changing-rdp-settings-in-vmware-view-open-client-for-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 19:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/21/changing-rdp-settings-in-vmware-view-open-client-for-mac/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the VMware View Open Client for Mac OS X for a few weeks now, ever since I was approved to participate in EMC&amp;rsquo;s pilot VDI program. The one thing that I don&amp;rsquo;t like about the View Open Client is how it leverages the Mac-native Remote Desktop Connection application to make connections to the View hosted desktops. It does so in a way that makes it impossible to customize the behavior of the RDP session&amp;mdash;or so I thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 11:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/25/virtualization-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>It has been a busy week since I last posted, and the blogging/micro-blogging world has been quite busy. I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered quite the collection of links and posts over the last week or so; here are a few that caught my eye. Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #41!
  About a month ago Rick Vanover posted a quick note about the use of Disk.SchedNumReqOutstanding as a potential performance tweak. As Rick mentions at the end of his article, it&amp;rsquo;s important to &amp;ldquo;test before and after with an intensive workload&amp;rdquo;; otherwise, you could find yourself actually hurting performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partner Exchange 2010 Session TECHDV0721</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/11/partner-exchange-2010-session-techdv0721/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 18:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/11/partner-exchange-2010-session-techdv0721/</guid>
      <description>This is a two-hour session on VMware View security architecture and security benefits titled &amp;ldquo;VMware View Security Benefits, Architecture, and Best Practices&amp;rdquo;.
So what is VMware&amp;rsquo;s security strategy? First, start with core platform security. This encompasses all the various features and functions of the hypervisor like memory protection and isolation, kernel module protections, hypervisor attack surface, etc. Next, continue with operational security. This is about integrating VMware&amp;rsquo;s products into your organization&amp;rsquo;s existing operational security policies and includes things like the vSphere Security Hardening Guide that was recently released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Republished: FlexClones or Deduplication?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/03/republished-flexclones-or-deduplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 23:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/07/03/republished-flexclones-or-deduplication/</guid>
      <description>Author&amp;rsquo;s Note: This content was first published over at Storage Monkeys, but it appears that it has since disappeared and is no longer available. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m republishing it here (with minor edits). Where applicable, I&amp;rsquo;ll also be republishing other old content from that site in the coming weeks. Thanks!
I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed this topic before, but I felt like it was a topic that needed to be revisited again. Storage admins need to know how their choices in storage technologies may or may not impact virtualization efforts, and this particular choice&amp;mdash;leveraging pointer-based snapshots or deduplication&amp;mdash;is particularly important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citrix Synergy Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/citrix-synergy-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 21:52:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/citrix-synergy-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>In advance of speaking at Virtualization Congress 2009 on Thursday, I&amp;rsquo;m attending Citrix Synergy. The Internet connection here in the main conference call is unavailable, so I&amp;rsquo;ll publish this as soon as I have connectivity back to the site.
The keynote starts with Garr Reynolds, an associate professor at Kansai Gaidai in Japan. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit unsure why he is on-stage getting the keynote started, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good presentation. After leading the audience through a self-introduction in Japanese, Garr Reynolds launches into a discussion of simplicity, the beginner&amp;rsquo;s mind, and nakedness (no, not that kind!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
