<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/python/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 94</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/09/technology-short-take-94/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/02/09/technology-short-take-94/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 94! Ready for another round of links, articles, and thoughts on data center technologies? (Who knows, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll throw a rant or two in there.) OK, enough rambling&amp;hellip;here&amp;rsquo;s the good stuff!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 92</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/05/technology-short-take-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/05/technology-short-take-92/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 92, the first Technology Short Take of 2018. This one was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be the last Tech Short Take of 2017, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it published in time (I decided to spend time with my family instead&amp;mdash;some things are just more important). In any case, hopefully the delay of one additional week hasn&amp;rsquo;t caused any undue stress&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s jump right in!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tag Docker Images with Git Commit Information</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/08/how-tag-docker-images-git-commit-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/08/how-tag-docker-images-git-commit-information/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working on a very simple Flask application that can be used as a demo application in containerized environments (here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/scottslowe/flask-web-svc&#34;&gt;the GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;). It&amp;rsquo;s nothing special, but it&amp;rsquo;s been useful for me as a learning exercise&amp;mdash;both from a Docker image creation perspective as well as getting some additional Python knowledge. Along the way, I wanted to be able to track versions of the Docker image (and the &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; used to create those images), and link those versions back to specific Git commits in the source repository. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a way I&amp;rsquo;ve found to tag Docker images with Git commit information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 89</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 89! I have a collection of newer materials and some older materials this time around, but hopefully all of them are still useful. (I needed to do some housekeeping on my Instapaper account, which is where I bookmark stuff that frequently lands here.) Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #75</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #75, the final Technology Short Take for 2016. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not the final Technology Short Take ever, as I&amp;rsquo;ll be back in 2017 with more content. Until then, here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related articles and links for your enjoyment.
Networking  Ajay Chenampara has some observations about running Ansible at scale against network devices. Andrey Khomyakov shares some information on automating the setup of whitebox switches running Cumulus Linux in part 2 of this series on learning network automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2016 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the last few years, in early 2016 I published a list of my planned personal projects for the year. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to look back on that list of projects and grade myself on my progress (or lack of progress, if that is the case). Even though 2016 isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet, it&amp;rsquo;s close enough to the end of the year that things won&amp;rsquo;t change that much before 2017 is upon us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ansible 2.2 on Ubuntu 16.04</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/14/installing-ansible-ubuntu-1604/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/14/installing-ansible-ubuntu-1604/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I wrote a post about installing Ansible 2.2 on Fedora 25; today, I&amp;rsquo;d like to tackle what&amp;rsquo;s involved in installing Ansible 2.2 on Ubuntu 16.04. This post, like its Fedora counterpart, stems from my ongoing evaluation of Linux distributions and desktop environments. While the information here is very similar to the information in the Fedora post, I&amp;rsquo;m putting it in its own post in the hopes of making the information easier for readers to find.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ansible 2.2 on Fedora 25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/25/installing-ansible-fedora-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/25/installing-ansible-fedora-25/</guid>
      <description>As part of my ongoing investigation of the usability of various Linux distributions and desktop environments, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Fedora 25. As part of the investigation I need to see how to perform certain tasks, one of which is working with Ansible. As a result, I needed to install Ansible 2.2 on Fedora 25, and it turns out it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as simple as pip install ansible.
I generally prefer to run Ansible in a Python virtualenv, but I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that it will make any difference to this procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ansible 2.x in a Python Virtualenv on OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/30/installing-ansible-in-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/30/installing-ansible-in-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through the steps to install Ansible 2.x into a Python virtual environment (virtualenv) on OS X. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing terribly hard or unusual about this process, but I wanted to document it here for folks who might be new to the process (or who might be interested in why using this approach could be beneficial).
I&amp;rsquo;m stumbled into this process because I had been using Ansible 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #3: Jonathan Frappier</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/full-stack-journey-ep003/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #3 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I have the pleasure of speaking with none other than Jonathan Frappier. Jonathan blogs at VirtXpert, and is probably quite well-known for his role in wrangling speakers for the vBrownBag podcasts. Jonathan is @jfrappier on Twitter, and uses the same username on GitHub as well. Jonathan&amp;rsquo;s been in the IT industry for, as he puts it, &amp;ldquo;somewhere between 16 and 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #2: Matt Oswalt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/03/full-stack-journey-ep002/</guid>
      <description>In Episode #2 of the Full Stack Journey podcast, my guest is none other than Matt Oswalt. You may know Matt as the primary author at Keeping It Classless, or as @mierdin on Twitter or GitHub (he also has a YouTube channel and a podcast of his own). Matt is primarily focused on network infrastructure, but is really interested in the intersection of network infrastructure and software development. Matt, along with Jason Edelman and yours truly, is one of the co-authors of a new book on network automation and programmability, and as such is a perfect guest for the Full Stack Journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2016 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/21/looking-ahead-2016-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/21/looking-ahead-2016-projects/</guid>
      <description>Almost every year since 2012, I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing a list of projects/goals for the upcoming year (here&amp;rsquo;s the original list for 2012, then 2013, I skipped 2014, and here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2015). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you the list of projects/goals for 2016.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2016. For some of the items below, I&amp;rsquo;m also going to include a stretch goal, something I&amp;rsquo;ll aim toward but won&amp;rsquo;t count against myself if I don&amp;rsquo;t actually attain it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
