<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Policy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/policy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Policy on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 08:35:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/policy/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Update on OpenStack Congress</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/12/quick-update-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/12/quick-update-congress/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Congress, a project aimed at providing &amp;ldquo;policy as a service&amp;rdquo; for OpenStack clouds, is a project I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of being involved in from very early days. I first mentioned Congress almost a year ago, and since then the developers have been hard at work on the project. Recently, one of the lead developers posted a summary of some pretty impressive performance improvements that have been made with Congress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining the Needs of a Policy Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</guid>
      <description>In April of this year, we started a series of articles at Network Heresy on the topic of policy in the data center. The first of these articles, which I mentioned in this post, focused on the problem of policy in the data center. This was a great introduction to the need for policy and the challenges with the current ways of addressing policy in the data center.
A short while ago, we published the second of our series on policy, titled &amp;ldquo;On Policy in the Data Center: The solution space&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Policy Discussion Into High Gear</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 12:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</guid>
      <description>Most IT vendors agree that more extensive use of automation and orchestration in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers are beneficial to customers. The vendors may vary in their approach to providing this automation and orchestration&amp;mdash;some may prefer to do it in software (VMware would be one of these, along with other software companies like Microsoft and Red Hat), while others want to do it in hardware. There are advantages and disadvantages to each approach, naturally, and customers need to evaluate the various solutions against their own requirements to find the best fit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
