<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Insight2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/insight2008/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Insight2008 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/insight2008/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3183: VMware SRM on NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 09:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/11/3183-vmware-srm-on-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>This session described VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM) on NetApp storage. The session started out with a review of VMware SRM, its features and functionality, and some of the requirements. I was not aware, for example, that SRM cannot use SQL Server Express like VirtualCenter can; you must use a full-blown instance of SQL Server. Given VMware&amp;rsquo;s development history, I should not have been surprised to find that Perl 5.8 is required (it&amp;rsquo;s included in the distribution and installed automatically).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031: Enhancements to NetApp Cloning Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on enhancements to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s cloning functionality. These enhancements are due to be released along with Data ONTAP 7.3.1, which is expected out in December. Of course, that date may shift, but that&amp;rsquo;s the expected release timeframe.
The key focus of the session was new functionality that allows for Data ONTAP to clone individual files without a backing Snapshot. This new functionality is an extension of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s deduplication functionality, and is enabled by changes within Data ONTAP that enable block sharing, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4198: Hyper-V on NetApp Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/01/4198-hyper-v-on-netapp-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 11:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/01/4198-hyper-v-on-netapp-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on running Hyper-V with NetApp storage. The first part of the session focused primarily on Hyper-V basics, such as VHD types (dynamically-expanding, fixed-size, passthrough, differencing), partition alignment (which can only be guaranteed with fixed-size VHDs, by the way), SCVMM 2008, Windows Failover Clustering support, and such. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in details on those topics, I suggest you have a look at my coverage of Microsoft Tech-Ed 2008 back in the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Insight Session Briefs Coming</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/01/netapp-insight-session-briefs-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 10:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/01/netapp-insight-session-briefs-coming/</guid>
      <description>On November 10 through November 13, NetApp held their annual technical conference&amp;mdash;formerly known as Fall Classic, this year renamed to Insight&amp;mdash;for SEs and partner SEs in Los Angeles. I had the opportunity to attend the conference by virtue of the fact that I was also presenting (look for session 3173; that&amp;rsquo;s me!). Normally the information shared at this conference is covered by non-disclosure agreement (NDA), but I&amp;rsquo;ve been given special dispensation to discuss the sessions I attended and the information shared in those sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
