<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Office on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/office/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Office on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/office/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Office 2008 Icons</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/23/replacing-office-2008-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/23/replacing-office-2008-icons/</guid>
      <description>In the last few days, I upgraded my work laptop to Office 2008, the latest version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s office suite for Mac OS X. I was looking forward to the Universal binaries (no more sluggish performance due to Rosetta) and Office 2007 file format compatibility. I did get those, but what I also got were some really ugly icons.
So, I did what any enterprising Mac user would do. I replaced them with a new set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Excel Zero-Day Attack</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/06/new-excel-zero-day-attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 12:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/02/06/new-excel-zero-day-attack/</guid>
      <description>This past Friday, the Microsoft Security Response Center blog posted a notification about Microsoft Security Advisory 932553, which describes the specific issue and the attacks around that issue.
More information on the issue is also available from this Secunia advisory and from US-CERT.
There are two interesting things to note (interesting to me, at least):
  First, this is an Office vulnerability, not a Windows vulnerability. Therefore, as correctly pointed out in the security advisories, Office 2004 for the Mac is also affected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking Diagramming on the Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/18/networking-diagramming-on-the-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2007 17:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/01/18/networking-diagramming-on-the-mac/</guid>
      <description>I spent the entire day trying to create a professional looking network diagram for a customer who recently installed an iSCSI-based SAN (a Network Appliance storage system, by the way). I didn&amp;rsquo;t want generic rectangles and boxes; I wanted nice icons. Preferably vendor-specific icons. Is that so much to ask?
I visited Graffletopia, which is to OmniGraffle (I use OmniGraffle Professional) what Visio Cafe is to Visio. Unfortunately, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find very many helpful stencils.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Three Word Zero-Day Exploits</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/15/now-three-word-zero-day-exploits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2006 12:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/15/now-three-word-zero-day-exploits/</guid>
      <description>More information on the various zero-day exploits can be found at the following web sites:
New Report of A Word Zero Day &amp;lt;http://blogs.technet.com/msrc/archive/2006/12/10/
new-report-of-a-word-zero-day.aspx&amp;gt;
Double Trouble: Microsoft Confirms Another Word Zero-Day Flaw &amp;lt;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,2071558,00.asp&amp;gt;
Third MS Word Code Execution Exploit Posted &amp;lt;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,2072969,00.asp&amp;gt;
Exploit Code Targets Third Microsoft Zero-Day Word Bug &amp;lt;http://www.darkreading.com/document.asp?doc_id=112974
&amp;amp;f;_src=darkreading_section_318&amp;gt;
As before, the advice on protecting yourself is don&amp;rsquo;t open Word documents from any source, trusted or untrusted. Kind of puts the kibosh on the whole sharing-documents-via-email thing, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Zero-Day Attack Alert</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/06/word-zero-day-attack-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2006 14:36:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/12/06/word-zero-day-attack-alert/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has started alerting customers of the new Word zero-day attack via a posting on the MSRC blog and by posting Microsoft Security Advisory 929433, which describes the attack, the vulnerability, and suggested actions.
Unfortunately, at this time, there are no workarounds for the attack other than &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t open untrusted Word documents.&amp;rdquo;
There is no indication currently if Microsoft will release a patch for the vulnerability being exploited in this attack in next week&amp;rsquo;s scheduled monthly patch release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Office and IE Under Fire (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/28/office-and-ie-under-fire-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 23:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/28/office-and-ie-under-fire-again/</guid>
      <description>News of the unpatched PowerPoint vulnerability (via eWeek) comes after a summer-long struggle to contain vulnerabilities in Microsoft Office, the office suite that maintains a venerable monopoly in the market. As with previous PowerPoint exploits, this one uses a rigged PowerPoint file to install a backdoor application. I found some additional information available from Symantec; read that here.
Similarly, another exploit has surfaced for Internet Explorer. This exploit takes advantage of a flaw that was supposedly brought to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s attention back in July and apparently still remains unpatched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crude Document Management System</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/26/a-crude-document-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2006 17:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/26/a-crude-document-management-system/</guid>
      <description>My rudimentary &amp;ldquo;document management system&amp;rdquo; is comprised of a variety of technologies, some built into Mac OS X and some added on via separate third-party applications. At the core of the system is Spotlight, the search engine that is the object of a love-hate relationship with many Mac users. Despite Spotlight&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings, it is still a very useful tool to have. (I will have to admit that I am sure I am still not taking full advantage of Spotlight&amp;rsquo;s abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Zero-Day Word Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/07/new-zero-day-word-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2006 09:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/07/new-zero-day-word-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>This new zero-day vulnerability has only been confirmed on Word 2000, but may also work on newer versions of Word as well. Security firm Secunia has issued an advisory with more information. eWeek is also providing information on the newly discovered vulnerability.
Fortunately, anti-virus vendors are on top of this one; Symantec already has information on the malicious software that is being installed by the exploit of this vulnerability. The threat factor posed by this malware is fairly low, but could rise if this vulnerability continues to be exploited actively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Patches for August</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/15/microsoft-patches-for-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2006 18:13:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/08/15/microsoft-patches-for-august/</guid>
      <description>This MSRC blog posting outlines the patches that were released last Tuesday, and provides links to the security bulletins for each patch.
&amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;An interesting statistic: according to this article, Microsoft has released more patches in the first 8 months of 2006 than in all of 2004 and 2005 combined. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that makes me feel more secure&amp;mdash;in that they are patching more vulnerabilities instead of not patching them&amp;mdash;or less secure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerPoint Zero-Day Exploit</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/19/powerpoint-zero-day-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2006 11:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/19/powerpoint-zero-day-exploit/</guid>
      <description>The zero-day exploit takes advantage of a previous unknown vulnerability in PowerPoint to install a Trojan Horse application. The vulnerability affects PowerPoint 2000, 2002, and 2003 running on various flavors of Microsoft Windows; it is unclear at this time whether Macintosh versions of Office are affected. Based on what is known of exploit, it seems unlikely that Macs could be affected by the exploit, but that is not to say that the vulnerability doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in the Mac versions of Office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Excel Flaws</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/22/more-excel-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 23:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/22/more-excel-flaws/</guid>
      <description>A third Excel flaw has been uncovered in a week, giving Excel users one more thing to worry about and opening one more door for hackers to get into corporate networks.
Here are more details on the third flaw; more details on the second flaw are also available from this article. This posting also has additional information on the latest vulnerability.
Unfortunately, this new flaw is more critical than the second flaw discovered earlier in the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero-Day Excel Exploit</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/19/zero-day-excel-exploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2006 13:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/19/zero-day-excel-exploit/</guid>
      <description>Less than a month after the disclosure of a zero-day exploit in Microsoft Word, another zero-day exploit has been found in Microsoft Excel and is being exploited in a highly targeted attack. As with the Word vulnerability, this one has shown up in attacks against a single customer, but it has gotten the attention of many of the major security vendors.
Brought to my attention by this eWeek article and this posting on Thincomputing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Word Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/24/microsoft-word-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 17:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/24/microsoft-word-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Security researchers recently uncovered a zero-day vulnerability in Microsoft Word that allows attackers to install a backdoor Trojan horse on the affected computers.
More information on this vulnerability can be obtained from the following links:
Alert Raised for MS Word Zero-Day Attack &amp;lt;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1965042,00.asp&amp;gt;
Microsoft Word Malformed Object Code Execution Vulnerability &amp;lt;http://secunia.com/advisories/20153/&amp;gt;
Microsoft Security Advisory (919637): Vulnerability in Word Could Allow Remote Code Execution &amp;lt;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/919637.mspx&amp;gt;
SecuriTeam Blogs: Mitigating Newly-Reported Word Vulnerability &amp;lt;http://blogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Innovation Equal Increased Productivity?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/21/does-innovation-equal-increased-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2006 19:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/03/21/does-innovation-equal-increased-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Paul Thurrott, a longtime reporter on Microsoft and its products, wrote today in &amp;ldquo;Windows IT Pro UPDATE&amp;rdquo; (I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a link to the article online) that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s innovation in their upcoming products, Windows Vista and Office 2007, will lead to a decrease in productivity, not an increase.
The basis for his argument (a position with which I agree, personally) is that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s innovation in both Windows Vista and Office 2007 will cause confusion and disorientation for experienced users in an effort to actually make things easier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
