<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/oss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OSS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/oss/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 151</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #151, the first Technology Short Take of 2022. I hope everyone had a great holiday season and that 2022 is off to a wonderful start! I have a few more links than normal this time around, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t find articles in a couple categories. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my eyes peeled and my RSS reader ready to pull in new articles in those categories for next time. And now for the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2019 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has been my custom over the last five years or so, in the early part of the year I like to share with my readers a list of personal projects for the upcoming year (here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/&#34;&gt;the 2019 list&lt;/a&gt;). Then, near the end of that same year or very early in the following year, I evaluate how I performed against that list of personal projects (for example, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my project report card for 2018&lt;/a&gt;). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue that pattern with an evaluation of my progress against my 2019 project list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2019 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while now since I published &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project report card&lt;/a&gt;, which assessed my progress against &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project goals&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving a fair amount of thought to the areas where I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus my professional (technical) development this coming year, and I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with some project goals that align both with where I am professionally right now and where I want to be technically as I grow and evolve. This is a really difficult balance to strike, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see at the end of the year how well I did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2018 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last five years or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared with my readers an annual list of projects along with&amp;mdash;at the year&amp;rsquo;s end&amp;mdash;a &amp;ldquo;project report card&amp;rdquo; on how I fared against the projects I&amp;rsquo;d set for myself. (For example, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my project report card for 2017&lt;/a&gt;.) Following that same pattern, then, here is my project report card for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 102</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/13/technology-short-take-102/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/13/technology-short-take-102/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 102! I normally try to get these things published biweekly (every other Friday), but this one has taken quite a bit longer to get published. It&amp;rsquo;s no one&amp;rsquo;s fault but my own! In any event, I hope that you&amp;rsquo;re able to find something useful among the links below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2018 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last six years or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing a list of projects/goals for the upcoming year (followed by a year-end review of how I did with those projects/goals). For example, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my goals for 2017&lt;/a&gt;, and here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my year-end review&lt;/a&gt; of my progress in 2017. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you my list of projects/goals for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2017 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has become my custom for the past several years, I wanted to take a look  at how well I fared on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2017 project list&lt;/a&gt;. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this before the end of 2017, but during this past holiday season I decided to more fully &amp;ldquo;unplug&amp;rdquo; and focus on the truly important things in life (like my family). So, here&amp;rsquo;s a look back at my 2017 projects and a report card on my progress (or lack thereof, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Under the Hood: containerD</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/18/looking-under-hood-containerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/18/looking-under-hood-containerd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the session titled &amp;ldquo;Looking Under the Hood: containerD&amp;rdquo;, presented by Scott Coulton with Puppet (and also a Docker Captain). It&amp;rsquo;s part of the Edge track here at DockerCon EU 2017, where I&amp;rsquo;m attending and liveblogging as many sessions as I&amp;rsquo;m able.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon EU 2017 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/dockercon-eu-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/17/dockercon-eu-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the day 1 keynote/general session at DockerCon EU 2017 in Copenhagen, Denmark. Prior to the start of the keynote, attendees are &amp;ldquo;entertained&amp;rdquo; by occasional clips of some Monty Python-esque production.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: OpenStack Summit Keynote, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/09/openstack-summit-keynote-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/09/openstack-summit-keynote-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the day 2 keynote of the OpenStack Summit in Boston, MA. (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to liveblog yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote due to a schedule conflict.) It looks as if today&amp;rsquo;s keynote will have an impressive collection of speakers from a variety of companies, and&amp;mdash;judging from the number of laptops on the stage&amp;mdash;should feature a number of demos (hopefully all live).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlating OVS and Guest Domain Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/16/correlating-ovs-guest-domain-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/16/correlating-ovs-guest-domain-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a fair amount about Open vSwitch (OVS), including some articles on using it with KVM and Libvirt. One thing I haven&amp;rsquo;t discussed in such environments, though, is the potential challenge of mapping network interfaces in a guest domain to the corresponding OVS interface (for the purposes of troubleshooting, for example). There is no single command that will provide a guest-to-OVS interface map (as far as I know), but this information is easily gathered using a couple commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2017 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing my list of projects for each year (here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2012, the list for 2013, 2015&amp;rsquo;s list, and last year&amp;rsquo;s list&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a list for 2014). Toward the end of each year, I also publish a &amp;ldquo;report card&amp;rdquo; assessing my performance against that year&amp;rsquo;s list (here&amp;rsquo;s the 2016 assessment). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share my list of planned projects for 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #75</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #75, the final Technology Short Take for 2016. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not the final Technology Short Take ever, as I&amp;rsquo;ll be back in 2017 with more content. Until then, here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related articles and links for your enjoyment.
Networking  Ajay Chenampara has some observations about running Ansible at scale against network devices. Andrey Khomyakov shares some information on automating the setup of whitebox switches running Cumulus Linux in part 2 of this series on learning network automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2016 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the last few years, in early 2016 I published a list of my planned personal projects for the year. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to look back on that list of projects and grade myself on my progress (or lack of progress, if that is the case). Even though 2016 isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet, it&amp;rsquo;s close enough to the end of the year that things won&amp;rsquo;t change that much before 2017 is upon us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
