<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interoperability on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/interoperability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interoperability on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/interoperability/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: OpenStack Summit Keynote, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/09/openstack-summit-keynote-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/09/openstack-summit-keynote-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the day 2 keynote of the OpenStack Summit in Boston, MA. (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to liveblog yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote due to a schedule conflict.) It looks as if today&amp;rsquo;s keynote will have an impressive collection of speakers from a variety of companies, and&amp;mdash;judging from the number of laptops on the stage&amp;mdash;should feature a number of demos (hopefully all live).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Handy GUI Tool for Working with APIs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/14/handy-gui-tool-working-apis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/14/handy-gui-tool-working-apis/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you an OS X graphical application I found that makes it easier to work with RESTful APIs. The topic of RESTful APIs has come up here before (see this post on using cURL to interact with RESTful APIs), and RESTful APIs have been a key part of a number of other posts (like my recent post on using jq to work with JSON).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Heat Template for Docker Containers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/22/a-heat-template-for-docker-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 17:10:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/22/a-heat-template-for-docker-containers/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share a simple template for deploying Docker containers in an OpenStack environment using Heat. Given that Docker is targeted at application deployment, then I felt that using Heat was a more appropriate way of leveraging Docker in an OpenStack environment as opposed to treating Docker as a form of a hypervisor. Later in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll compare this approach to using a more container-aware solution such as fleet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Arista vEOS on KVM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/11/running-arista-veos-on-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/11/running-arista-veos-on-kvm/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how I got Arista&amp;rsquo;s vEOS software running under KVM to create a virtualized Arista switch. There are a number of other articles that help provide instructions on how to do this, but none of those that I found included the use of libvirt and/or Open vSwitch (OVS).
In order to run vEOS, you must first obtain a copy of vEOS. I can&amp;rsquo;t provide you with a copy; you&amp;rsquo;ll have to register on the Arista Networks site (see here) in order to gain access to the download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining the Needs of a Policy Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</guid>
      <description>In April of this year, we started a series of articles at Network Heresy on the topic of policy in the data center. The first of these articles, which I mentioned in this post, focused on the problem of policy in the data center. This was a great introduction to the need for policy and the challenges with the current ways of addressing policy in the data center.
A short while ago, we published the second of our series on policy, titled &amp;ldquo;On Policy in the Data Center: The solution space&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Look at an OpenStack Heat Template</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/02/another-look-at-an-openstack-heat-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/02/another-look-at-an-openstack-heat-template/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier post, I provided an introduction to OpenStack Heat, and provided an example Heat template that launched two instances with a logical network and a logical router. Here I am going to provide another view of a Heat template that does the same thing, but uses YAML and the HOT format instead of JSON and the CFN format.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the full template (click here for this code as a GitHub Gist):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to OpenStack Heat</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/01/an-introduction-to-openstack-heat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/01/an-introduction-to-openstack-heat/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a quick introduction to OpenStack Heat, the orchestration service that allows you to spin up multiple instances, logical networks, and other cloud services in an automated fashion. Note that this is only an introductory post&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert on Heat, but I did want to share at least some basic information to help others get started as well.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with some terminology, so that there is no confusion about the terms later when we start using them in specific examples:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere Network Health Check and Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/30/vsphere-network-health-check-and-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 09:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/30/vsphere-network-health-check-and-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>Reader Brian Markussen&amp;mdash;with whom I had the pleasure to speak at the Danish VMUG in Copenhagen earlier this month&amp;mdash;brought to my attention an issue between VMware vSphere&amp;rsquo;s health check feature and Cisco UCS when using Cisco&amp;rsquo;s VIC cards. His findings, confirmed by VMware support and documented in this KB article, show that the health check feature doesn&amp;rsquo;t work properly with Cisco UCS and the VIC cards.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quote from the KB article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Policy Discussion Into High Gear</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 12:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</guid>
      <description>Most IT vendors agree that more extensive use of automation and orchestration in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers are beneficial to customers. The vendors may vary in their approach to providing this automation and orchestration&amp;mdash;some may prefer to do it in software (VMware would be one of these, along with other software companies like Microsoft and Red Hat), while others want to do it in hardware. There are advantages and disadvantages to each approach, naturally, and customers need to evaluate the various solutions against their own requirements to find the best fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Curl to Interact with a RESTful API</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/19/using-curl-to-interact-with-a-restful-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 16:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/02/19/using-curl-to-interact-with-a-restful-api/</guid>
      <description>It seems as if APIs are popping up everywhere these days. While this isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad thing, it does mean that IT professionals need to have a better understanding of how to interact with these APIs. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how to use the popular command line utility curl to interact with a couple of RESTful APIs&amp;mdash;specifically, the OpenStack APIs and the VMware NSX API.
Before I go any further, I want to note that to work with the OpenStack and VMware NSX APIs you&amp;rsquo;ll be sending and receiving information in JSON (JavaScript Object Notation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namespaces, VLANs, Open vSwitch, and GRE Tunnels</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/09/namespaces-vlans-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/09/09/namespaces-vlans-open-vswitch-and-gre-tunnels/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you how I combined Linux network namespaces, VLANs, Open vSwitch (OVS), and GRE tunnels to do something interesting. Well, I found it interesting, even if no one else does. However, I will provide this disclaimer up front: while I think this is technically interesting, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it has any real, practical value in a production environment. (I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be proven wrong, BTW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential Fix for Kerberos, SSH, LDAP, and Active Directory Issue</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/02/potential-fix-for-kerberos-ssh-ldap-and-active-directory-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 17:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/02/potential-fix-for-kerberos-ssh-ldap-and-active-directory-issue/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me with a question on using Kerberos and LDAP for authentication into Active Directory, based on Active Directory integration work I did many years ago. I was unable to help him, but he did find the solution to the problem, and I wanted to share it here in case it might help others.
The issue was that he was experiencing a problem using native Kerberos authentication against Active Directory with SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Some Networking-Virtualization Chimeras</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</guid>
      <description>I like to spend time examining the areas where different groups of technologies intersect. Personally, I find this activity fascinating, and perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the reason that I find myself pursing knowledge and experience in virtualization, networking, storage, and other areas simultaneously&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s an effort to spend more time &amp;ldquo;on the border&amp;rdquo; between various technologies.
One border, in particular, is very interesting to me: the border between virtualization and networking. Time spent thinking about the border between networking and virtualization is what has generated posts like this one, this one, or this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update on Markdown and BoxCryptor on iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/10/update-on-markdown-and-boxcryptor-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/10/update-on-markdown-and-boxcryptor-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>A short while ago, I talked about how to add client-side encryption to Dropbox using EncFS. In that post, I suggested using BoxCryptor to access your encrypted files. A short time later, though, I uncovered a potential issue with (what I thought to be) BoxCryptor. I have an update on that issue.
In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the comments to the article about the potential BoxCryptor-Markdown problem, it turns out that the problem with using Markdown files with BoxCryptor doesn&amp;rsquo;t lie with BoxCryptor&amp;mdash;it lies with Byword, the Markdown editor I was using on iOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Markdown Files in BoxCryptor on iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago, I published an article showing you how to use EncFS and BoxCryptor to provide client-side encryption of Dropbox data. After working with this configuration for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve run across a problem (at least, a problem for me&amp;mdash;it might not be a problem for you). The problem lies on the iPad end of things.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the earlier post, the basic gist of the idea is to use EncFS&amp;mdash;an open source encrypting file system&amp;mdash;and OSXFUSE to provide file-level encryption of Dropbox data on your OS X system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
