<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Celerra on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/celerra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Celerra on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 09:53:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/celerra/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Changing IP Addresses on an EMC Celerra NS-960</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/changing-ip-addresses-on-an-emc-celerra-ns-960/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 09:53:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/12/changing-ip-addresses-on-an-emc-celerra-ns-960/</guid>
      <description>Changing the IP addresses on an EMC Celerra unified storage array is generally a pretty straightforward process. EMC supplies a script called clariion_mgmt that you can use to change the IP addresses on the back-end CLARiiON storage processors (SPs). In the large majority of cases, the process for changing the IP addresses on an EMC Celerra using this script looks something like this:
  Change the IP address of the Control Station using Celerra Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC Celerra Optimizations for VMware on NFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/31/emc-celerra-optimizations-for-vmware-on-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 18:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/31/emc-celerra-optimizations-for-vmware-on-nfs/</guid>
      <description>Recently Jason Boche posted some storage performance numbers from his EMC Celerra NS-120. Out of those storage performance tests, Jason noted that the NFS performance of the NS-120 seemed a bit off, so he contacted EMC&amp;rsquo;s vSpecialist team (also known as &amp;ldquo;Chad&amp;rsquo;s Army&amp;rdquo;, but I like vSpecialists better) to see if there was something that could or should be done to improve NFS performance on the NS-120. After collaborating internally, one of our team members (a great guy named Kevin Zawodzinski) responded to Jason with some suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
