<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/zfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 10:28:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/zfs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This Pretty Much Answers That Question</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/12/this-pretty-much-answers-that-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 10:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/12/this-pretty-much-answers-that-question/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I posed this question: is Sun preparing to take on Cisco? The question generated some interesting responses in the comments to the article.
Reader Bill had this to say:
 How on earth would Cisco respond if Sun started introducing products with better performance, at a fraction of the price, built on high volume open source adoption?
 As I responded, that&amp;rsquo;s the real $64,000 question, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week I provided a list of virtualization-related items that had made their way into my Inbox in some form or another; today I&amp;rsquo;ll share storage-related items with you in Storage Short Take #4! This post will also be cross-published to the Storage Monkeys Blogs.
  Stephen Foskett has a nice round-up of some of the storage-related changes available to users in VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. Of particular note to many users is the VMDK Recovery Tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Short Take is a collection of links and articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last few weeks (or longer ago, in some cases!) that I thought others might find interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  Alessandro broke the news to the general public about some anticipated new virtualization features that are expected to make their debut in Windows Server 2008 R2, expected sometime in 2010. Microsoft announced live migration for Hyper-V back at the beginning of September, so that part was already known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is What Snow Leopard Needs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/this-is-what-snow-leopard-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 21:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/this-is-what-snow-leopard-needs/</guid>
      <description>Before the release of Mac OS X 10.5 &amp;ldquo;Leopard,&amp;rdquo; the computing world was abuzz with the possible inclusion of ZFS&amp;mdash;Zettabyte File System&amp;mdash;into the new operating system. That rumor was largely fueled by the rumors swirling around about what would officially become known as Time Machine. It turns out that ZFS did make its way into Leopard, albeit on a read-only basis, and it isn&amp;rsquo;t the technology behind Time Machine.
Now, the next version of Mac OS X, version 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Suing Sun over ZFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2007 21:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/05/netapp-suing-sun-over-zfs/</guid>
      <description>I was on the road most of the day today, so I must have missed this news earlier. Apparently, Sun Microsystems and Network Appliance have had a little spat over ZFS and WAFL, and now NetApp is suing Sun for patent infringement.
Dave Hitz explained the situation in a blog entry:
 This morning, NetApp filed an IP (intellectual property) lawsuit against Sun. It has two parts. The first is a &amp;ldquo;declaratory judgment&amp;rdquo;, asking the court to decide whether we infringe a set of patents that Sun claims we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of WAFL and ZFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/12/comparison-of-wafl-and-zfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2007 17:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/12/comparison-of-wafl-and-zfs/</guid>
      <description>This comparison of ZFS (Zettabyte File System) and WAFL (Write Anywhere File Layout) by Network Appliance (no direct link for WAFL) is an interesting comparison of these two advanced filesystems and their feature set. Be sure to read the comments for some additional insight on the comparison of the two filesystems and some clarification about supported features.
One distinction raised in the comments that&amp;rsquo;s worthy to be noted here is that any comparison of this sort also, by its very nature, takes into account the operating system that runs the filesystem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
