<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oracle on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/oracle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oracle on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 10:12:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/oracle/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Again I Ask: Isn&#39;t There a Better Way?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/again-i-ask-isnt-there-a-better-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2006 10:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/24/again-i-ask-isnt-there-a-better-way/</guid>
      <description>Last summer, I wrote about my concerns with regards to fourth-generation rootkits and their supposed beneficial intentions. Now that the same approach is being applied to Oracle databases, I ask again: isn&amp;rsquo;t there a better way?
A security researcher recently announced that he has created a better &amp;ldquo;rootkit&amp;rdquo; for Oracle that improves upon the earlier version unveiled last year at the Black Hat Conference in Amsterdam. This new version makes it more difficult for database administrators and security professionals to locate the rootkit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Flurry of Security Patches</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/20/a-flurry-of-security-patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 09:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/20/a-flurry-of-security-patches/</guid>
      <description>Over this past week, a wide collection of vendors have released patches for various vulnerabilities and flaws in their applications. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap of some of the security patches released this past week.
  Oracle: Oracle released patches for more than 100 flaws in their database and application server products.
  Symantec/Veritas: Symantec released patches for its NetBackup application (acquired with Veritas) after exploit code was released on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
