<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IDF2012 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IDF2012 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 13:19:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/idf2012/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SFTS012: Designing a Trusted Cloud with OpenStack</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/13/sfts012-designing-a-trusted-cloud-with-openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 13:19:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/13/sfts012-designing-a-trusted-cloud-with-openstack/</guid>
      <description>This is session SFTS012, titled &amp;ldquo;Designing a Trusted Cloud with OpenStack.&amp;rdquo; It is, unfortunately, my last session of the conference; I&amp;rsquo;m leaving from here to head to the airport to catch my flight home. The speaker for the session is Vin Sharma, who helps lead open source software strategies at Intel. The focus of this session, as you can tell from the title, is on security and trust (presumably talking about how to leverage Intel TXT with OpenStack).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2012 Day 2 Summary and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/idf-2012-day-2-summary-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 23:04:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/idf-2012-day-2-summary-and-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Now that day 2 of Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2012 is behind me, here&amp;rsquo;s a quick summary of the day. Most of today was taken up by meetings; some of these were meetings with various Intel folk to get my feedback on the event, others were meetings that I&amp;rsquo;m not at liberty to discuss. (Sorry folks!) I did, however, manage to capture a couple of sessions:
DATS002: Big Data Meets High-Performance Computing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2012 Day 1 Summary and Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/idf-2012-day-1-summary-and-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 20:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/idf-2012-day-1-summary-and-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I just completed day 1 of Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2012 in San Francisco. I tried to blog about as much as I possibly could. Here are the links to what I was able to capture during the day:
IDF 2012 Day 1 Keynote
Next-Generation Microarchitecture, code-named &amp;ldquo;Haswell&amp;rdquo;
Data Plane Virtualization
ODCA and Cloud Usage Models
One thing that really stuck out to me was an announcement made during a data center-focused press briefing directly after lunch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLDS006: Exploring New Xeon E5 Optimizations for 10 Gb Ethernet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/clds006-exploring-new-xeon-e5-optimizations-for-10-gb-ethernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 19:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/clds006-exploring-new-xeon-e5-optimizations-for-10-gb-ethernet/</guid>
      <description>This is session CLDS006, &amp;ldquo;Exploring New Intel Xeon Processor E5 Based Platform Optimizations for 10 Gb Ethernet Network Infrastructures.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s a long title! The speakers are Brian Johnson from Intel and Alex Rodriguez with Expedient.
The session starts with Rodriguez giving a (thankfully) brief overview of Expedient and then getting into the evolution of networking with 10 Gigabit Ethernet (GbE). Rodriguez provides the usual &amp;ldquo;massive growth&amp;rdquo; numbers that necessitated Expedient&amp;rsquo;s relatively recent migration to 10 GbE in their data center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DATS002: Big Data Meets High Performance Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/dats002-big-data-meets-high-performance-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 18:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/12/dats002-big-data-meets-high-performance-computing/</guid>
      <description>This is session DATS002, titled &amp;ldquo;Big Data Meets High Performance Computing.&amp;rdquo; The speakers are John Hengeveld from Intel and Micahel Franklin from UC Berkeley. The title sounds like this might be a marketing session, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that this material will be substantial instead of just fluff.
Hengeveld starts the session by reminding attendees that Big Data is really about the insights that are gained from the data. Big Data isn&amp;rsquo;t about the data, it&amp;rsquo;s about the insight and understanding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLDS001: ODCA and Usage Models for Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/clds001-odca-and-usage-models-for-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 18:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/clds001-odca-and-usage-models-for-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>This is session CLDS001, titled &amp;ldquo;The Open Data Center Alliance and Developing a Usage Model Roadmap for Cloud Computing.&amp;rdquo; The presenters are Mario Mueller, VP of IT Infrastructure at BMW Group and John Pereira, a marketing director at Intel. Both Mueller and Pereira are also involved with the Open Data Center Alliance (ODCA).
The session starts out with some background on ODCA. The ODCA is driven by customer requirements and customer demands, and the requirements are not guided by any vendor bias (at least, that&amp;rsquo;s the goal).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMS002: Next Generation Cloud Infrastructure with Data Plane Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/coms002-next-generation-cloud-infrastructure-with-data-plane-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 16:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/coms002-next-generation-cloud-infrastructure-with-data-plane-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>This is session COMS002, titled &amp;ldquo;Next Generation Cloud Infrastructure with Data Plane Virtualization.&amp;rdquo; The speaker is Edwin Verplanke, a System Architect with Intel.
Verplanke believes that DPDK (Data Plane Development Kit) and virtualization are key to virtualizing workloads that move around lots and lots of packets, such as firewalls, routers, and other similar functions. Late in the session Verplanke will discuss some Open vSwitch optimizations.
Verplanke first goes over some of the challenges that are driving the industry to look at data plane and control plane virtualization solutions in next-generation infrastructure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPCS001: Intel Next-Generation Haswell Microarchitecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/spcs001-intel-next-generation-haswell-microarchitecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 13:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/spcs001-intel-next-generation-haswell-microarchitecture/</guid>
      <description>This is session SPCS001, titled &amp;ldquo;Technology Insight: Intel Next Generation Microarchitecture Code Name Haswell&amp;rdquo;. The speakers are Tom Piazza, Hong Jiang, Per Hammarlund, and Ronak Singhal, Sr.
Haswell is a &amp;ldquo;tock&amp;rdquo; as opposed to a &amp;ldquo;tick&amp;rdquo; (referring to Intel&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;tick/tock&amp;rdquo; release cycle); this means it is a significant change at the platform and microarchitecture levels. It is a 22nm platform (Ivy Bridge was also 22nm). Haswell will retain key features from the Sandy Bridge/Ivy Bridge platform, like Hyper-Threading, Turbo Boost, and Ring Interconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IDF 2012 Keynote, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/idf-2012-keynote-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 10:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/11/idf-2012-keynote-day-1/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the day 1 keynote at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2012 at Moscone West in San Francisco, CA. This is my first time attending IDF, and I appreciate the invitation to attend from Intel. (Disclosure: My travel expenses are being reimbursed and I was given a pass to attend, but I am not receiving any other form of compensation.)
Prior to the start of the keynote, they show a video talking about &amp;ldquo;What misconception about engineers bothers you most?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
