<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ToL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/tol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ToL on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/tol/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/09/thinking-out-loud-future-of-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/09/thinking-out-loud-future-of-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just wrapped up KubeCon/CloudNativeCon 2016 in Seattle, WA. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt the Kubernetes community is active and engaged, and the project itself is charging forward. As both the community and the project grow, though, what does that mean for the future of Kubernetes?
Here are my thoughts, hopefully presented in a somewhat logical fashion.
It seems to me that Kubernetes has been successful thus far because of a strong focus on the problem it&amp;rsquo;s trying to solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Thought About Mesos-DNS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/17/quick-thought-mesos-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/17/quick-thought-mesos-dns/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recently pointed me to the recent Mesosphere announcement of Mesos-DNS, a DNS-based service discovery mechanism for Apache Mesos clusters. A comment made in the announcement got me thinking, and I wanted to briefly share my thoughts.
The comment that got me thinking was this:
 Mesos-DNS is simple and stateless. Unlike Consul and SkyDNS, it does not require consensus mechanisms, persistent storage, or a replicated log.
 If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along here on my site, you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Consul before (see here), and I have more Consul content planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Does Docker on Windows Matter?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/30/thinking-out-loud-does-docker-on-windows-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 11:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/30/thinking-out-loud-does-docker-on-windows-matter/</guid>
      <description>Nigel Poulton recently posted an article titled &amp;ldquo;ESXi vs. Hyper-V - Could Docker Support Be Significant,&amp;rdquo; in which he contemplates whether Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s announcement of Docker support on Windows will be a factor in the hypervisor battle between ESXi and Hyper-V. His post got me thinking&amp;mdash;which is a good thing, I&amp;rsquo;d say&amp;mdash;and I wanted to share my thoughts on the topic here.
Naturally, it&amp;rsquo;s worth pointing out that I work for VMware, although I do work in a business unit that makes a multi-hypervisor product (NSX).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Handling Career Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/09/thinking-out-loud-handling-career-evolution/</guid>
      <description>As IT pros at the &amp;ldquo;cutting edge&amp;rdquo; of technology and industry change, I think sometimes we forget that not everyone has the same mindset toward learning, growth, and career evolution. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true, I think, for those of us who are bloggers, because it&amp;rsquo;s our passion for the technology that not only drives us to write about it but also drives us to constantly explore new trends, new areas, and new concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: DIY Network Virtualization?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 11:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/30/thinking-out-loud-diy-network-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Following on the heels of this week&amp;rsquo;s VMware NSX announcement at VMworld 2013, I had someone contact me about a statement this person had heard. The statement claimed NSX was nothing more than a collection of tools, and that it was possible to get the equivalent of NSX using completely free (as in speech and as in beer) open source tools&amp;mdash;specifically, IPTables, StrongSwan, OpenVPN, and Open vSwitch (OVS). Basically, the statement was that it was possible to create do-it-yourself network virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: The Future of VLANs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/20/thinking-out-loud-the-future-of-vlans/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me how much the idea of a VLAN has invaded the consciousness of data center IT professionals. Data center folks primarily tasked with managing compute workloads are nearly as familiar with VLANs as their colleagues primarily tasked with managing network connectivity. However, as networking undergoes a transformation at the hands of SDN, NFV, and network virtualization, what will happen to the VLAN?
The ubiquity of the VLAN is due, I think, to the fact that it serves as a reasonable &amp;ldquo;common ground&amp;rdquo; for both compute-focused and networking-focused professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Targeting the Real Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/03/thinking-out-loud-targeting-the-real-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 09:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/03/thinking-out-loud-targeting-the-real-problem/</guid>
      <description>Two (relatively) independent thought streams collided late last week, and this post is the result.
The first thought stream was about the benefits and drawbacks of OpenFlow. As I&amp;rsquo;ve said on many occasions, every technology decision has benefits and drawbacks. OpenFlow is no exception, in my opinion. Clearly there are some real benefits to using OpenFlow in certain use cases (here&amp;rsquo;s one example), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean OpenFlow&amp;mdash;especially hop-by-hop OpenFlow, where OpenFlow is involved at every &amp;ldquo;hop&amp;rdquo; of the packet forwarding process throughout the network&amp;mdash;is the right solution for all environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: OVS and the Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/18/thinking-out-loud-ovs-and-the-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 09:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/18/thinking-out-loud-ovs-and-the-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve been unsuccessfully trying to get Open vSwitch (OVS) running on Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) 6.3 (as well as CentOS 6.3). The rationale behind this is that RHEL/CentOS are the sort of battle-tested, well-supported Linux distributions that enterprises will (and do) deploy in their data centers. OVS, of course, is central to the strategy and functionality of several network virtualization players and projects:
  Nicira</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Why Not MPLS-in-IP?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thinking-out-loud-why-not-mpls-in-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 09:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thinking-out-loud-why-not-mpls-in-ip/</guid>
      <description>As I was reviewing my list of actions in OmniFocus this morning, I saw an action I&amp;rsquo;d added a while back to review RFC 4023. RFC 4023 is the RFC that defines MPLS-in-IP and MPLS-in-GRE encapsulations, and was written in 2005. I thought, &amp;ldquo;Let me just read this real quick.&amp;rdquo; So I did.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly long RFC (only about 13 pages or so), but I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to summarize it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Is A dvFabric Closer Than We Think?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/08/thinking-out-loud-is-a-dvfabric-closer-than-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 16:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/08/thinking-out-loud-is-a-dvfabric-closer-than-we-think/</guid>
      <description>This is a short post, but one that I hope will stir some discussion.
Earlier this evening, I read Maish&amp;rsquo;s blog post titled My Wish for dvFabric&amp;mdash;a dvSwitch for Storage. In that blog post Maish describes a self-configuring storage fabric that would simplify how we provision storage in a vSphere environment. Here&amp;rsquo;s how Maish describes the dvFabric:
 So how do I envision this dvFabric? Essentially the same as a dvSwitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Logical Link Multiplexing (Sort Of)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/15/thinking-out-loud-logical-link-multiplexing-sort-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/15/thinking-out-loud-logical-link-multiplexing-sort-of/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to some episodes of the excellent Packet Pushers Podcast, trying to learn about such things as Shortest Path Bridging (SPB) and 802.1Qbg. It&amp;rsquo;s this second item&amp;ndash;802.1Qbg&amp;mdash;that this blog post is about (indirectly).
If you&amp;rsquo;re unfamiliar with 802.1Qbg, I highly recommend Ivan Pepelnjak&amp;rsquo;s articles on the topic:
Edge Virtual Bridging (EVB; 802.1Qbg) Eases VLAN Configuration Pains
EVB (802.1Qbg) The S Component
This second article, in particular, contained a statement which really prompted this &amp;ldquo;Thinking Out Loud&amp;rdquo; post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: What if vSphere Supported FabricPath?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/08/thinking-out-loud-what-if-vsphere-supported-fabricpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/08/thinking-out-loud-what-if-vsphere-supported-fabricpath/</guid>
      <description>Since attending Cisco Live 2011 in Las Vegas earlier this year (see my summary list of blog posts), my mind has been swirling with ideas about how various technologies might work (or not work) together. In the first of a series of &amp;ldquo;Thinking Out Loud&amp;rdquo; posts in which I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to explore&amp;mdash;and spur discussion regarding&amp;mdash;how certain networking technologies might integrate with virtualization technologies, I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore this question: &amp;ldquo;What if vSphere had FabricPath support?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: What is multi-hop FCoE?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/21/thinking-out-loud-what-is-multi-hop-fcoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 09:09:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/21/thinking-out-loud-what-is-multi-hop-fcoe/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last posted a &amp;ldquo;Thinking Out Loud&amp;rdquo; post, but a Twitter discussion this morning prompted me to post this one. Last night, I posted a question to Brad Hedlund (@bradhedlund on Twitter and a great data center networking resource) regarding the Nexus 2232PP fabric extender. My tweet to Brad was this: does the Nexus 2232PP make &amp;ldquo;multi-hop FCoE&amp;rdquo; possible via NIV?
(If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already read my post on the relationship between FCoE and NIV, go read it now as it provides a good background and context for this discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: It&#39;s Not Just the Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/19/thinking-out-loud-its-not-just-the-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 11:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/19/thinking-out-loud-its-not-just-the-technology/</guid>
      <description>I had a quick thought this morning while browsing this post by Lori MacVittie. She, in turn, was referring back to a post published on VMBlog.com about a virtualization prediction that 2010 would be the year that the network becomes fluid and virtual. (As a side note, the original article on VMBlog.com appears to be primarily a marketing exercise for a company that purports to help make the network fluid and virtual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Is VMware Legitimizing the Competition?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 09:13:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/16/thinking-out-loud-is-vmware-legitimizing-the-competition/</guid>
      <description>I was reading a completely unrelated post on Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s site this morning about how VKernel is reacting to VMware&amp;rsquo;s release of CapacityIQ when a thought occurred to me: is VMware legitimizing the competition?
Here&amp;rsquo;s the excerpt from Alessandro&amp;rsquo;s post that started me thinking:
 And of course VKernel now is also in hurry to clarify that support for Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer is coming.
 Now, let me ask you this question: what is one of the largest complaints about products like Microsoft Hyper-V and Citrix XenServer?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
