<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VCB on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vcb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VCB on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 22:43:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vcb/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Source VMFS Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/26/open-source-vmfs-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 22:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/26/open-source-vmfs-driver/</guid>
      <description>It looks like my post discussing a universal cluster file system may have been prescient. Shared with me first via Twitter, it appears that a company has already started building an open source VMFS driver. It was also covered here and here.
As we discussed in the post about cross-hypervisor cluster file systems, the implications of hypervisors potentially being able to share clustered storage are quite significant. Of course, there are many hurdles to yet overcome, but what if this project develops and matures and becomes a valid tool?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow Up on the VDC-OS Announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/follow-up-on-the-vdc-os-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 13:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/follow-up-on-the-vdc-os-announcement/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten through the first part of discussing VMware&amp;rsquo;s VDC-OS announcement&amp;mdash;making sure that the message and vision is a bit clearer&amp;mdash;I can focus on some of the specifics contained within the announcement. In other words, I can talk about new features. (That should make Duncan happier.)
  VMware Fault Tolerance (FT), formerly &amp;ldquo;Continuous Availability,&amp;rdquo; (demoed at VMworld 2007, described in my liveblog here) provides real-time VM mirroring between two different hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #16</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/11/virtualization-short-take-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 23:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/11/virtualization-short-take-16/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of good information being shared out there! With all due credit to the original authors, here&amp;rsquo;s a few links that I found particularly interesting or useful. I hope you agree!
  The VI Team Blog posted a list of interesting things in Update 2. They identify things like Enhanced VMotion Compatibility (EVC) and monitoring and availability enhancements. For example, did you know that VM failure monitoring is now fully supported and not experimental?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Releases Update 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/vmware-releases-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/vmware-releases-update-2/</guid>
      <description>VMware has released Update 2 for VMware Infrastructure 3 version 3.5, which includes updates to VMware ESX, VMware ESXi, VirtualCenter, and VMware Consolidated Backup (VCB). Check the Release Notes for the full details; I won&amp;rsquo;t reproduce them here, but instead I&amp;rsquo;ll just point out the particularly interesting details.
Also reporting this information (at the time of this writing) are David from VMblog.com, Rich from VM /ETC, and Duncan at Yellow Bricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/18/virtualization-short-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/18/virtualization-short-take-2/</guid>
      <description>Before I begin the second installation of Virtualization Short Takes, I thought it was interesting to note that Thomas Bishop over at ScaleTheMind.com has adopted a similar strategy. There&amp;rsquo;s just so much happening that it&amp;rsquo;s truly impossible to discuss everything in depth. Even so, it&amp;rsquo;s often helpful to at least provide the readers with the links and some additional thoughts. It seems like this approach may be the best one to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Consolidated Backup</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/05/vmware-consolidated-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 15:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/05/vmware-consolidated-backup/</guid>
      <description>VMware Consolidated Backup (VCB) is a new component of Virtual Infrastructure 3, and is designed to facilitate both full-VM and file-level backups of ESX-hosted virtual machines on a SAN. In its current release, it only supports Fibre Channel SANs, but support for iSCSI is supposedly coming in the next release. When used in conjunction with a third-party backup application (such as Backup Exec) and the appropriate integration software, VCB can provide the ability to backup VMs across the SAN (instead of across the network) without the need to install backup agents on every VM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
