<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/personal/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Next Step</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/18/the-next-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/18/the-next-step/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greek philosopher Heraclitus is typically attributed as the creator of the well-known phrase &amp;ldquo;Change is the only constant.&amp;rdquo; Since I left VMware in 2018 to join Heptio, change has been my companion. First, there was the change of focus, moving to a focus on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; and related technologies. Then there was the acquisition of Heptio by VMware, and all the change that comes with an acquisition. Just when things were starting to settle down, along came the acquisition of Pivotal by VMware and several more rounds of changes as a result. Today, I mark the start of another change, as I begin a new role and take the next step in my career journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing out the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/13/closing-out-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2019, I announced that I would be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;temporarily relocating to Tokyo for a six-month assignment&lt;/a&gt; to build out a team focused on cloud-native services and offerings. A few months later, I was still in Colorado, and I explained what was happening in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/&#34;&gt;a status update on the Tokyo assignment&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few folks ask me about it, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and share that the Tokyo assignment did not happen and will not happen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Update on the Tokyo Assignment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 15:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/09/an-update-on-the-tokyo-assignment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right at the end of 2019 I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/&#34;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; that in early 2020 I was temporarily relocating to Tokyo, Japan, for a six month work assignment. It&amp;rsquo;s now March, and I&amp;rsquo;m still in Colorado. So what&amp;rsquo;s up with that Tokyo assignment, anyway? Since I&amp;rsquo;ve had several folks ask, I figured it&amp;rsquo;s probably best to post something here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2019 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 08:43:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/01/01/looking-back-2019-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has been my custom over the last five years or so, in the early part of the year I like to share with my readers a list of personal projects for the upcoming year (here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/&#34;&gt;the 2019 list&lt;/a&gt;). Then, near the end of that same year or very early in the following year, I evaluate how I performed against that list of personal projects (for example, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my project report card for 2018&lt;/a&gt;). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue that pattern with an evaluation of my progress against my 2019 project list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/30/new-year-new-adventure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll skip the build-up and jump straight to the whole point of this post: a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity has come up and I&amp;rsquo;m embarking on a new adventure starting in early 2020. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not changing jobs&amp;hellip;but I am changing time zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2019 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/looking-ahead-2019-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a little while now since I published &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project report card&lt;/a&gt;, which assessed my progress against &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2018 project goals&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been giving a fair amount of thought to the areas where I&amp;rsquo;d like to focus my professional (technical) development this coming year, and I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with some project goals that align both with where I am professionally right now and where I want to be technically as I grow and evolve. This is a really difficult balance to strike, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see at the end of the year how well I did.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2018 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/28/looking-back-2018-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last five years or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared with my readers an annual list of projects along with&amp;mdash;at the year&amp;rsquo;s end&amp;mdash;a &amp;ldquo;project report card&amp;rdquo; on how I fared against the projects I&amp;rsquo;d set for myself. (For example, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my project report card for 2017&lt;/a&gt;.) Following that same pattern, then, here is my project report card for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future is Containerized</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/02/the-future-is-containerized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/02/the-future-is-containerized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/&#34;&gt;announced my departure from VMware&lt;/a&gt;, and my intention to step away from VMware&amp;rsquo;s products and platforms to focus on a new technology area moving forward. Today marks the &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; start of a journey that&amp;rsquo;s been building for a couple years, a journey that will take me into a future that&amp;rsquo;s containerized. That journey starts in Seattle, Washington.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Evolve</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/26/time-to-evolve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first started getting into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; around 2003, possibly earlier (I can&amp;rsquo;t recall exactly when it was). I remember thinking that VMware&amp;rsquo;s impact on the industry was going to be significant, and I wanted to be part of this industry change. I was right&amp;mdash;virtualization like what VMware offers has fundamentally changed the industry. However, just as technology evolves, technology careers must evolve as well. Specifically, my technology career must change and grow. It&amp;rsquo;s time to evolve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2018 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last six years or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing a list of projects/goals for the upcoming year (followed by a year-end review of how I did with those projects/goals). For example, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my goals for 2017&lt;/a&gt;, and here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/&#34;&gt;my year-end review&lt;/a&gt; of my progress in 2017. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you my list of projects/goals for 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2017 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/03/looking-back-2017-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As has become my custom for the past several years, I wanted to take a look  at how well I fared on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2017 project list&lt;/a&gt;. Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this before the end of 2017, but during this past holiday season I decided to more fully &amp;ldquo;unplug&amp;rdquo; and focus on the truly important things in life (like my family). So, here&amp;rsquo;s a look back at my 2017 projects and a report card on my progress (or lack thereof, in some cases).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2017 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/31/looking-ahead-2017-projects/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing my list of projects for each year (here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2012, the list for 2013, 2015&amp;rsquo;s list, and last year&amp;rsquo;s list&amp;mdash;I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a list for 2014). Toward the end of each year, I also publish a &amp;ldquo;report card&amp;rdquo; assessing my performance against that year&amp;rsquo;s list (here&amp;rsquo;s the 2016 assessment). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share my list of planned projects for 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2016 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/22/looking-back-2016-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve done for the last few years, in early 2016 I published a list of my planned personal projects for the year. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to look back on that list of projects and grade myself on my progress (or lack of progress, if that is the case). Even though 2016 isn&amp;rsquo;t over yet, it&amp;rsquo;s close enough to the end of the year that things won&amp;rsquo;t change that much before 2017 is upon us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead: My 2016 Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/21/looking-ahead-2016-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/21/looking-ahead-2016-projects/</guid>
      <description>Almost every year since 2012, I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing a list of projects/goals for the upcoming year (here&amp;rsquo;s the original list for 2012, then 2013, I skipped 2014, and here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2015). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you the list of projects/goals for 2016.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the list for 2016. For some of the items below, I&amp;rsquo;m also going to include a stretch goal, something I&amp;rsquo;ll aim toward but won&amp;rsquo;t count against myself if I don&amp;rsquo;t actually attain it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back: 2015 Project Report Card</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/31/looking-back-2015-project-report-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/12/31/looking-back-2015-project-report-card/</guid>
      <description>In early 2015, I posted a look ahead at my planned 2015 projects, where I took a quick look at some of the self-development projects I set out for myself over the course of 2015. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to review my progress on those 2015 projects.
The 2015 projects were as follows:
 Complete a new book Make more open source contributions Expand to a new configuration management solution Complete a &amp;ldquo;wildcard project&amp;rdquo;  So, how well did I do?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
