<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KDE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/kde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in KDE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 21:52:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/kde/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Updating Kubuntu to KDE 3.5</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/01/updating-kubuntu-to-kde-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 21:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/01/updating-kubuntu-to-kde-35/</guid>
      <description>Kubuntu 5.10, the KDE-based variant of Ubuntu, normally comes with KDE 3.4.3. With KDE 3.5.0 just recently released, however, I wanted to update Kubuntu to use the latest version of KDE. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I had to do to make it work.
First, from this page, I downloaded and added the appropriate GPG key. Once that was done, I used apt-get update to download the latest package information and apt-get upgrade to upgrade packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubuntu 5.10</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/01/kubuntu-510/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 17:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/01/kubuntu-510/</guid>
      <description>After wrestling with installing, configuring, and supporting Fedora Core 3 on an older Compaq Armada E500 laptop, I decided to break with my Red Hat/Fedora legacy and try Kubuntu, the KDE-based Ubuntu variation. Ubuntu itself is a relative newcomer to the Linux distribution arena, based on (as I understand it) Debian.
In previous stints using Linux as my desktop OS, I&amp;rsquo;d always been partial to KDE instead of GNOME. Some would say that it&amp;rsquo;s because KDE has traditionally been more &amp;ldquo;Windows-like&amp;rdquo; than the other Linux graphical environments; perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
