<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>macOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in macOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/macos/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 155</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #155, just in time for the 2022 Memorial Day holiday weekend! (Here in the US, at least.) I mean, don&amp;rsquo;t you want to spend this weekend catching up on some technology-related articles instead of cooking on the grill and gathering with friends and family? I certainly hope not! Still, for those who need a little technology fix over the weekend, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve included something useful in the list of articles below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 154</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/04/29/technology-short-take-154/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #154! My link of links and articles from around the Internet is a bit light on networking and virtualization this time around, but heftier in the security, cloud, and OS/application sections. I hope that I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to include something that you&amp;rsquo;ll find useful. Enjoy the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 152</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #152! Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish a Technology Short Take in the morning on a Friday, but I really wanted to get this one out so I&amp;rsquo;m making it live late in the day on a Monday. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve included some content below that you find useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 151</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #151, the first Technology Short Take of 2022. I hope everyone had a great holiday season and that 2022 is off to a wonderful start! I have a few more links than normal this time around, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t find articles in a couple categories. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my eyes peeled and my RSS reader ready to pull in new articles in those categories for next time. And now for the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 150</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/31/technology-short-take-150/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #150! This is the last Technology Short Take of 2021, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll close the year out &amp;ldquo;with a bang&amp;rdquo; with this collection of links and articles on various technology areas. Bring on the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/23/review-owc-thunderbolt-dock/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/23/review-owc-thunderbolt-dock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About six months ago I purchased an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owcdigital.com/products/thunderbolt-3-dock-14-port&#34;&gt;OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock&lt;/a&gt; to replace my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anker.com/a8396launch&#34;&gt;Anker PowerElite Thunderbolt 3 Dock&lt;/a&gt; (see my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2020/07/24/review-anker-powerexpand-elite-thunderbolt-3-dock/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). While there was nothing necessarily wrong with the Anker PowerElite, it lacked a digital audio port that I could use to send audio to a soundbar positioned under my monitor. (I&amp;rsquo;d grown accustomed to using a soundbar when my 2012 Mac Pro was my primary workstation.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide a brief review of the OWC Thunderbolt 3 Dock.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 149</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #149! I&amp;rsquo;ll have one more Technology Short Take in 2021, scheduled for three weeks from now (on the last day of the year!). For now, though, I have a small collection of articles and links for your reading pleasure&amp;mdash;not as many as I usually include in a Technology Short Take, but better than nothing at all (I hope!). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 147</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #147! The list of articles is a bit shorter than usual this time around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a good collection of articles and posts covering topics in networking, hardware (mostly focused on Apple&amp;rsquo;s processors), cloud computing, and virtualization. There&amp;rsquo;s bound to be something in here for most everyone! (At least, I hope so.) Enjoy your weekend reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 144</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #144! I have a fairly diverse set of links for readers this time around, covering topics from microchips to improving your writing, with stops along the way in topics like Kubernetes, virtualization, Linux, and the popular JSON-parsing tool &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting WireGuard Interfaces Automatically with Launchd on macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/04/starting-wireguard-interfaces-automatically-launchd-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/04/starting-wireguard-interfaces-automatically-launchd-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late June of this year, I wrote a piece on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/&#34;&gt;using WireGuard on macOS via the CLI&lt;/a&gt;, where I walked readers using macOS through how to configure and use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard VPN&lt;/a&gt; from the terminal (as opposed to using the GUI client, which I discussed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). In that post, I briefly mentioned that I was planning to explore how to have macOS&amp;rsquo; &lt;code&gt;launchd&lt;/code&gt; automatically start WireGuard interfaces. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to do exactly that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WireGuard on macOS via the CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few different posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;simple yet fast and modern VPN&amp;rdquo; (as described by the WireGuard web site) that aims to supplant tools like IPSec and OpenVPN. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/&#34;&gt;first post on WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; showed how to configure WireGuard on Linux, both on the client side as well as on the server side. After that, I followed it up with posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;using the GUI WireGuard app to configure WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;mdash;most recently&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/&#34;&gt;making WireGuard from Homebrew work on an M1-based Mac&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a look at using WireGuard on macOS again, but this time via the CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Older Versions of Kumactl on an M1 Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/25/installing-older-versions-of-kumactl-on-an-m1-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 15:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/25/installing-older-versions-of-kumactl-on-an-m1-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kuma community &lt;a href=&#34;https://kuma.io/blog/2021/kuma-1-2-0/&#34;&gt;recently released version 1.2.0&lt;/a&gt; of the open source Kuma service mesh, and along with it a corresponding version of &lt;code&gt;kumactl&lt;/code&gt;, the command-line utility for interacting with Kuma. To make it easy for macOS users to get &lt;code&gt;kumactl&lt;/code&gt;, the Kuma community maintains a &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; formula for the CLI utility. That includes providing M1-native (ARM64) macOS binaries for &lt;code&gt;kumactl&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, installing an earlier version of &lt;code&gt;kumactl&lt;/code&gt; on an M1-based Mac using Homebrew is somewhat less than ideal. Here&amp;rsquo;s one way&amp;mdash;probably not the only way&amp;mdash;to work around some of the challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WireGuard from Homebrew Work on an M1 Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;the post on using WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; (using the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; GUI app from the Mac App Store), I found the GUI app&amp;rsquo;s behavior to be less than ideal. For example, tunnels marked as on-demand would later show up as no longer configured as an on-demand tunnel. When I decided to set up WireGuard on my M1-based MacBook Pro (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/02/review-2020-m1-based-macbook-pro/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt; of the M1 MacBook Pro), I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use the GUI app. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; has formulas for WireGuard. Unfortunately, the WireGuard tools as installed by Homebrew on an M1-based Mac won&amp;rsquo;t work. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
