<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Messaging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/messaging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Messaging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/messaging/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 138</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #138. I have what I hope is an interesting and useful set of links to share with everyone this time around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do so well on storage links; apologies to my storage-focused friends! However, there should be something for most everyone else. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: December 2018 Progress Report</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2016, I kicked off a migration from macOS to Linux as my primary laptop OS. Throughout 2017, I chronicled my progress and challenges along the way; links to all those posts are found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although I stopped the migration in August 2017, I restarted it in April 2018 when I left VMware to join Heptio. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to recap where things stand as of December 2018, after 8 months of full-time use of Linux as my primary laptop OS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Updated Look at My Multi-Platform Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/30/updated-look-at-multi-platform-toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/30/updated-look-at-multi-platform-toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2017 I posted about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/03/my-evolving-multi-platform-toolbelt/&#34;&gt;my (evolving) multi-platform toolbelt&lt;/a&gt;, describing some of the applications, standards, and services that I use across my Linux and macOS systems. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide an updated review of that toolbelt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</guid>
      <description>In discussing support for corporate communication and collaboration systems as part of my Linux migration, I&amp;rsquo;ve so far covered e-mail in part 1 and calendaring in part 2. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the last few remaining aspects of corporate collaboration: instant messaging/chat, meetings and teleconferences, and document sharing.
Teleconferences and meetings The topic of teleconferences and meetings is closely related to calendaring&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to access your calendar or others&amp;rsquo; calendars when coordinating meetings or teleconferences&amp;mdash;so I encourage you to read part 2 to get a better feel for the challenges around calendaring/scheduling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</guid>
      <description>One major aspect of my migration to Linux as my primary desktop OS is how well it integrates with corporate communication and collaboration systems. Based on the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten from others on Twitter, this is a major concern for a lot of folks out there. In fact, a number of folks have indicated that this is the only thing keeping them from migrating to Linux. There are a number of different aspects to &amp;ldquo;corporate communication and collaboration,&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m breaking this down into multiple posts (each post will discuss one particular aspect).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #78</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/17/technology-short-take-78/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #78! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of links and articles from around the Internet discussing various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  The rise of the disaggregated network operating system (NOS) marches on: this time, it&amp;rsquo;s Big Switch Networks announcing expanded hardware support in Open Network Linux (ONL), upon which its own NOS is based. The Pivotal Engineering blog has an article that shows how to use BOSH with the vSphere CPI to automate adding servers to an NSX load balancing pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My (Evolving) Multi-Platform Toolbelt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/03/my-evolving-multi-platform-toolbelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/03/my-evolving-multi-platform-toolbelt/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I posted a tweet about a new tool I&amp;rsquo;d (re-)discovered called jrnl. Someone replied to that tweet, asking me to list my &amp;ldquo;multi-platform toolbelt.&amp;rdquo; While it&amp;rsquo;s still evolving (every day!), I thought it might make for a good blog post. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of my still-evolving multi-platform toolbelt.
  Sublime Text: Over the last few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to creating the vast majority of my content in Markdown (MultiMarkdown, to be more specific).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #64</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #64. Normally, I try to publish Short Takes on Friday, but this past Friday was April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day. Given the propensity for &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; information to get lost among all the pranks, I decided to push this article back to today. Unlike most of what is published around April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day, hopefully everything here is helpful, informative, and useful!
Networking  Phil Gervasi has an article on fate sharing in the network core, where he discusses some of the advantages&amp;mdash;and disadvantages&amp;mdash;of centralizing the control plane in network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Friction: Training a Spam Filter</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/20/reducing-the-friction-training-a-spam-filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/20/reducing-the-friction-training-a-spam-filter/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back with another &amp;ldquo;Reducing the Friction&amp;rdquo; blog post, this time to talk about training an e-mail spam filter. As you may recall if you read one of the earlier posts (may I suggest this one and this one?), I use the phrase &amp;ldquo;reducing the friction&amp;rdquo; to talk about streamlining and simplifying commonly-performed tasks so as to allow you to improve your own personal efficiency and/or adopt more efficient habits or workflows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divorcing Google</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/04/divorcing-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/04/divorcing-google/</guid>
      <description>The time has come; all good things must come to an end. So it is with my relationship with Google and the majority of their online services. As of right now, I&amp;rsquo;m in the midst of separating myself from the majority of Google&amp;rsquo;s services. I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this several times on Twitter, and a number of people asked me to write about the process. So, here are the details so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the Friction: Processing E-Mail, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/19/reducing-the-friction-processing-e-mail-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/19/reducing-the-friction-processing-e-mail-part-2/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks ago I published a Reducing the Friction blog post centered on helping to streamline the tasks involved in processing e-mail. (Recall that there is a distinction between managing e-mail and processing e-mail.) In this Reducing the Friction post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to revisit the idea of processing e-mail with a slightly different take: using text expanders to streamline composing and replying to e-mail messages.
As much as we all love to bash e-mail as a productivity killer, it has become something of a necessary evil in most professional environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware, Zimbra, and Why I&#39;m Not an Analyst</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/05/vmware-zimbra-and-why-im-not-an-analyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 09:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/01/05/vmware-zimbra-and-why-im-not-an-analyst/</guid>
      <description>The rumors are swirling that VMware is going to buy Zimbra, an open source e-mail platform currently owned by Yahoo. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably all read the various news articles about the rumors and the events leading up to the rumored acquisition, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother you with them again.
Yesterday on Twitter, I mentioned that the Zimbra acquisition didn&amp;rsquo;t quite make sense to me. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only one; several others mentioned it, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growl Notifications with Snow Leopard Mail and Exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/10/growl-notifications-with-snow-leopard-mail-and-exchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 10:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/12/10/growl-notifications-with-snow-leopard-mail-and-exchange/</guid>
      <description>Like many Mac users, I use Growl to provide customizable, centralized notifications for events occurring on my system. Rather than use the Growl team&amp;rsquo;s GrowlMail plug-in, I use a custom AppleScript that I wrote that provide new message notifications via Growl. It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly advanced script; it just provides per-message notifications for each message received, unless I receive more than 5 messages at a time in which case the script just provides a summary notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Tried to Like Postbox, I Really Did</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/01/i-tried-to-like-postbox-i-really-did/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 15:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/01/i-tried-to-like-postbox-i-really-did/</guid>
      <description>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet heard about Postbox, it&amp;rsquo;s a new Mac OS X e-mail application built on Mozilla technology that intends to offer a new and different way of working with e-mail. From the Postbox web site, you can look at some of the features the application offers as well as see some screenshots.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been testing Postbox off and on since I was first invited into the beta, and at first I was really excited about Postbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Mail.app and iPhone with Google IMAP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/20/configuring-mailapp-and-iphone-with-google-imap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 12:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/20/configuring-mailapp-and-iphone-with-google-imap/</guid>
      <description>So I recently moved almost all of my personal e-mail domains over to Google Apps. A couple of people have asked, &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; My answer is simple: it&amp;rsquo;s easier. The e-mail functionality of my current hosting provider is lacking in a couple of key areas:
  Rather than using the emerging standard of having e-mail clients connect to TCP port 587 (Submission) to send e-mail, they used a very non-standard practice of using TCP port 26.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
