<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:55:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/general/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Site Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/01/some-site-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/01/some-site-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last three years, the site has been largely unchanged with regard to the structure and overall function even while I continue to work to provide quality technical content. However, time was beginning to take its toll, and some &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo; work was needed. Over the Thanksgiving holiday, I spent some time updating the site, and there are a few changes I wanted to mention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/23/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/23/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the US, today (Thursday, November 23) is Thanksgiving. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a moment to reflect on the meaning of Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website Features</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/new-website-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/new-website-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/&#34;&gt;migrated this site to Hugo&lt;/a&gt; a little over a month ago was that &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; offered the ability to do things with the site that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t (easily) do with Jekyll (via GitHub Pages). Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken advantage of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s flexibility to add a couple new features to the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information on the Recent Site Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I completed the migration of this site to an entirely new platform, marking the third or fourth platform migration for this site in its 12-year history. Prior to the migration, the site was generated using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;a previous migration in late 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to that, I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; for about 9 years. So what is it running now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/28/podcast-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/28/podcast-update/</guid>
      <description>As many of you probably know, I launched a new podcast, called the Full Stack Journey Podcast, back in January. (Here&amp;rsquo;s the blog post announcing the new podcast.) In this post, I wanted to provide a quick update on the podcast.
Dedicated Website Now Up First, the podcast now has its own website! Like this site, the Full Stack Journey site is a Jekyll-powered site hosted on GitHub (here&amp;rsquo;s the site&amp;rsquo;s repository).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Site Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/07/brief-site-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/07/brief-site-update/</guid>
      <description>As many of you may already know, GitHub recently upgraded GitHub Pages to use Jekyll 3.0, and along with that upgrade comes a few (relatively) minor changes to the site as a result. Here are the details of what&amp;rsquo;s changed here.
The most notable difference is a change in the site&amp;rsquo;s feed URL. Whereas the feed used to be available at http://blog.scottlowe.org/feed/, changes in how Jekyll 3.0 handles permalinks mean that URL is no longer sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling All Switchers</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/03/calling-all-switchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/03/calling-all-switchers/</guid>
      <description>Are you a switcher? That is, are you someone who has transitioned from one IT discipline to an entirely new IT discipline? Perhaps you were a storage gal for a long time, and now you&amp;rsquo;ve successfully transitioned into a networking career. Maybe you used to be a Windows admin, and now Linux is your thing. Or perhaps you were a networking guy, and now you&amp;rsquo;re coding like a madman. If this sounds like you, please read on!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Git, now Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/03/first-git-now-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 08:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/03/first-git-now-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>When I shared the story behind migrating the blog to Jekyll and GitHub, I mentioned that one of the reasons for the migration was to embrace Git as a part of my regular workflow. I&amp;rsquo;d been recommending to folks that they learn and use Git, and now I needed to &amp;ldquo;walk the walk&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;talk the talk.&amp;rdquo; This post describes another step in my effort to &amp;ldquo;walk the walk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Comments Aren&#39;t Available Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 09:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</guid>
      <description>A number of readers have asked&amp;mdash;via e-mail, of course, given the subject of this post&amp;mdash;why comments aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet on the new site. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a quick moment to explain the current situation.
First and foremost, it&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t want feedback from readers. I would love to continue to have the outstanding feedback from readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the last 9 years of this site. It&amp;rsquo;s also not because it&amp;rsquo;s too much trouble (too much comment spam, too much time to moderate, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/06/the-story-behind-the-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/06/the-story-behind-the-migration/</guid>
      <description>A number of people have asked me why I migrated from WordPress&amp;mdash;which powered my blog for 9 years&amp;mdash;to Jekyll and GitHub Pages. Now that the migration is finally complete, I can share with you the story behind the migration: why I migrated, the process I followed, and some of the tools I used.
Why I Migrated &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; is a question I heard quite a bit as I was sharing updates on the progress of the blog migration over the Christmas/New Year holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Migration Complete</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/</guid>
      <description>The blog migration is finally complete! It&amp;rsquo;s taken quite a while, but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally managed to migrate the over 1,600 posts from my original WordPress installation over to Jekyll hosted on GitHub Pages. I&amp;rsquo;ll have another post later that goes into more detail on the process that I followed (and why) as well as some of the tools that I used in the migration.
As of right now, there are 2 outstanding issues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Migration in the Works</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/12/18/blog-migration-in-the-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/12/18/blog-migration-in-the-works/</guid>
      <description>You might have noticed that blog content has been a bit sparse over the last few weeks. The reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t generated any new content is because all my spare time is taken up with preparing to migrate this site to a new hosting platform.
Sometime over the holiday season, I&amp;rsquo;ll be migrating this site from a hosted WordPress installation to Jekyll running on GitHub Pages. Given that I have 9 years of content (over 1,600 blog posts), this is a pretty fair amount of work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Comments on Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/23/closing-comments-on-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 17:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/23/closing-comments-on-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about this site is the interaction I enjoy with readers. It&amp;rsquo;s always great to get comments from readers about how an article was informative, answered a question, or helped solve a problem. Knowing that what I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is helpful to others is a very large part of why I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing here for over 9 years.
Until today, I&amp;rsquo;ve left comments (and sometimes trackbacks) open on very old blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving 2013</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/28/happy-thanksgiving-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/11/28/happy-thanksgiving-2013/</guid>
      <description>In the United States, today is Thanksgiving&amp;mdash;a day to give thanks for the many things we have in our lives. I just wanted to take a moment today to give thanks for a few of the most important things in my life:
  My Lord and Savior, Jesus Christ
  My beautiful and loving wife, Crystal
  My awesome kids (Summer, Johnny, Elizabeth, Michael, Rhys, Sean, and Cameron)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Dry Spell</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/07/a-short-dry-spell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 09:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/08/07/a-short-dry-spell/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of weeks since I published anything here, so I wanted to just provide a brief update. I know that posting something about why I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted something isodd, I guess you could say. In any case, a number of factors&amp;mdash;some personal, some professional&amp;mdash;have contributed to why I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to generate some useful new content in the last couple of weeks. Of course, there are blogs that go for months between posts, so a small gap of a couple weeks isn&amp;rsquo;t really a big deal.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
