<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cumulus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cumulus on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cumulus/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 124</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #124! It seems like the natural progression of the Tech Short Takes is moving toward monthly articles, since it&amp;rsquo;s been about a month since my last one. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that I&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful for you. Enjoy! (And yes, normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but I messed up and forgot. So, I decided to publish on Monday instead of waiting for Friday.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issue with VMware-Formatted Cumulus VX Vagrant Box</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/11/issue-with-vmware-cumulus-vx-vagrant-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/11/issue-with-vmware-cumulus-vx-vagrant-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a need to revisit the use of Cumulus VX (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cumulusnetworks.com&#34;&gt;Cumulus Networks&lt;/a&gt; virtual appliance running Cumulus Linux) in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; environment, and I wanted to be sure to test what I was doing on multiple virtualization platforms. Via &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.vagrantup.com/boxes/search&#34;&gt;Vagrant Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, Cumulus distributes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virtualbox.org/&#34;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;Libvirt&lt;/a&gt; versions of Cumulus VX, and there is a slightly older version that also provides a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmware.com/products/personal-desktop-virtualization.html&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;-formatted box. Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s a simple error in the VMware-formatted box that prevents it from working. Here&amp;rsquo;s the fix.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a VMware-Formatted Cumulus VX Vagrant Box</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/04/building-vmw-cumulus-vx-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/04/building-vmw-cumulus-vx-box/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through the process I used to build a Vagrant box for Cumulus VX that will work with VMware desktop hypervisors (like VMware Fusion or VMware Workstation). Although Cumulus Networks offers several different versions of Cumulus VX to download, they do not (strangely enough) offer a Vagrant box that will work with VMware&amp;rsquo;s desktop hypervisors.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Cumulus VX, it&amp;rsquo;s a virtual appliance version of Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #62</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #62. Sorry for the long delay since the last TST; some global travel has really thrown my schedule off. In any case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until Friday (the day I normally publish these) so I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there sooner. Enjoy!
Networking  PowerNSX is pretty cool&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a set of PowerShell cmdlets for administrators of VMware NSX running in vSphere environments. Check out Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s introductory post on PowerNSX for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Trunking with Cumulus Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/25/vlan-trunking-cumulus-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/25/vlan-trunking-cumulus-linux/</guid>
      <description>Following up on my earlier post on Cumulus Linux networking concepts, I wanted to build on that information with a guide on configuring VLAN trunking. This would be useful in a number of different scenarios: supporting multiple (VLAN-backed) port groups on vSphere hosts, or connecting an Open vSwitch (OVS) bridge on a KVM or Xen hypervisor to multiple VLANs. You might also need to use a VLAN trunking configuration to connect a Cumulus Linux-powered switch to another switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Cumulus Linux Networking Concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/01/cumulus-networking-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/06/01/cumulus-networking-concepts/</guid>
      <description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve recently had the opportunity to start working with Cumulus Linux (running on a Dell S6000-ON switch), in this post I wanted to share a few concepts I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about networking with Cumulus Linux.
I&amp;rsquo;m not a networking guru, but I&amp;rsquo;m also not new to configuring network equipment&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ve configured GRE tunnels on a Cisco router, set up link-state tracking, and enabled jumbo frames on a Nexus 5000 (to name a few examples).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
