<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IMAP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/imap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IMAP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2005 20:47:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/imap/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>STARTTLS and IMAP in Mail.app</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/02/starttls-and-imap-in-mailapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2005 20:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/02/starttls-and-imap-in-mailapp/</guid>
      <description>I blogged earlier about my frustration with the Mac OS X Mail.app mail client and its apparent lack of STARTTLS support with IMAP4. Well, on a whim today I decided to take this issue back up again.
Since Microsoft Exchange does not support STARTTLS, I had to use Perdition as an IMAP proxy in front of Exchange. Earlier attempts to get Mail.app to do STARTTLS had failed (not sure why), but today I decided to try changing the IMAP port from 993 (the default when you check the &amp;ldquo;Use SSL&amp;rdquo; box) to 143 (the standard IMAP4 port).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perdition Working Now</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 16:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</guid>
      <description>I finally managed to get Perdition working. Still unable to confirm if Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s Mail.app supports STARTTLS (my experience thus far says No), I had to resort to using Stunnel to wrap IMAP inside an SSL tunnel, then forward the IMAP traffic to Perdition on the same host. The Perdition proxy then passes the traffic to the back-end mail server. It&amp;rsquo;s not the solution that I really wanted, but it will do for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonstandard Implementations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2005 22:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</guid>
      <description>In my experiments with Perdition, I learned a couple of very interesting facts. First, the IMAP4 implementation on Exchange Server 2003 does not support the STARTTLS command, as described in RFC 2595 and re-affirmed in RFC 3501. Instead, Exchange expects an SSL session to be established immediately, and then IMAP is spoken. This is similar to the smtpd_tls_wrappermode directive that Postfix supports.
Second, it appears that the Mac OS X Mail application (commonly referred to as Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
