<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FibreChannel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fibrechannel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FibreChannel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fibrechannel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #60</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #60. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered what I hope to be a useful but varied collection of articles and links on key data center technologies. I hope something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be helpful&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking  The rise of Linux in importance in the networking industry continues, with Arista announcing enhancements to Arista EOS to support&amp;mdash;among other things&amp;mdash;Docker containers. (See this SDx Central article or this Network World article for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 13:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/30/technology-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #24, another instance of my irregularly-published collection of links, thoughts, and rants on various data center technologies like networking, operating systems, security, hardware, virtualization, and cloud computing. This is a slightly shorter version of my Technology Short Takes; I&amp;rsquo;m trying to pare down since some readers have indicated the previous Short Takes weren&amp;rsquo;t short enough. Anyway, I hope you find something useful.
Networking   This page is a decent reference to the open source software-defined networking (SDN) projects that are out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Is A dvFabric Closer Than We Think?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/08/thinking-out-loud-is-a-dvfabric-closer-than-we-think/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 16:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/02/08/thinking-out-loud-is-a-dvfabric-closer-than-we-think/</guid>
      <description>This is a short post, but one that I hope will stir some discussion.
Earlier this evening, I read Maish&amp;rsquo;s blog post titled My Wish for dvFabric&amp;mdash;a dvSwitch for Storage. In that blog post Maish describes a self-configuring storage fabric that would simplify how we provision storage in a vSphere environment. Here&amp;rsquo;s how Maish describes the dvFabric:
 So how do I envision this dvFabric? Essentially the same as a dvSwitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 09:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/20/technology-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #20, the latest collection of various data center-related links, articles, and thoughts. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking   For all the writing and thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve done on VXLAN (here, here, and here), someone (thanks Ed!) mentioned something to me recently that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even considered. (It&amp;rsquo;s so simple I&amp;rsquo;m embarrassed that I overlooked it.) VXLAN uses UDP for its encapsulation. What about dropped packets, lack of sequencing, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #19, the first Technology Short Take for 2012. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s first collection of links, articles, and thoughts regarding virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center technology-related topics. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   While configuration limits aren&amp;rsquo;t the most exciting reading, they are important from time to time. Here&amp;rsquo;s some configuration limits for the UCS 6100 and 6200 series.
  Understanding the differences&amp;mdash;both positive and negative&amp;mdash;between the various approaches to solving a particular challenge is a key skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #13</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 10:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/08/25/technology-short-take-13/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #13. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last Technology Short Take, and much has happened (vSphere 5 was announced, HP discontinued the TouchPad and webOS, and I announced my move to Denver). Here are a few data center technology-related links that stood out to me over the last few weeks. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   Here&amp;rsquo;s a good post by Jeremy Waldrop on Cisco Nexus 5000/7000 FEX (fabric extender) topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRKSAN-3707: Advanced SAN Services</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 15:08:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/07/14/brksan-3707-advanced-san-services/</guid>
      <description>This is BRKSAN-3707, Advanced SAN Services, presented by Mike Dunn.
According to TIP&amp;rsquo;s Storage Research, the top five storage initiatives are deduplication, technology refresh, tiered storage build-out, archiving, and consolidation.
The three main sections of the presentation are SAN consolidation with virtualization, tiered storage and backup design, and Fibre Channel over Ethernet (FCoE).
The presentation starts with SAN consolidation using virtualization. This is really a discussion of virtual SANs (VSANs), which allow you to consolidate SANs onto the same hardware but still providing logical separation of fabrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FCoE through a Nexus to a MDS-Attached Storage Array</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/15/fcoe-through-a-nexus-to-a-mds-attached-storage-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/15/fcoe-through-a-nexus-to-a-mds-attached-storage-array/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I want to pull together all the steps necessary to take a Converged Network Adapter (CNA)-equipped server and connect it, using FCoE, to a Fibre Channel-attached storage array. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot of &amp;ldquo;net new&amp;rdquo; information in this post, but rather I&amp;rsquo;m summarizing previous posts, organizing the information, and showing how these steps relate to each other. I hope that this helps someone understand the &amp;ldquo;big picture&amp;rdquo; of how FCoE and Fibre Channel relate to each other and how they interoperate (which, quite frankly, is one of the key factors for the adoption of FCoE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Device Aliases on a Cisco MDS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/08/using-device-aliases-on-a-cisco-mds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 20:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/12/08/using-device-aliases-on-a-cisco-mds/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I posted a couple of articles on configuring and managing Cisco MDS Fibre Channel zones via the CLI:
New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Configuring Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
New User&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Managing Cisco MDS Zones via CLI
In those posts, I discussed the use of the fcalias command to create aliases for World Wide Port Names (WWPNs) on the fabric. A couple of people suggested via Twitter and blog comments that I should use device aliases instead of the the fcalias command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAN Port Channels from Nexus 5010 to MDS 9134</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 09:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/11/30/san-port-channels-from-nexus-5010-to-mds-9134/</guid>
      <description>As part of an ongoing effort to expand the functionality of the vSpecialist lab in the EMC RTP facility, we recently added a pair of Cisco MDS 9134 Fibre Channel switches. These Fibre Channel switches are connected to a pair of Cisco Nexus 5010 switches, which handle Unified Fabric connections from a collection of CNA-equipped servers. To connect the Nexus switches to the MDS switches, we used SAN port channels to bond multiple Fibre Channel interfaces together for both redundancy and increased aggregate throughput.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Inactive New Paths on an EMC CLARiiON</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/20/fixing-inactive-new-paths-on-an-emc-clariion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/20/fixing-inactive-new-paths-on-an-emc-clariion/</guid>
      <description>I ran into an issue in the lab today with some VMware ESX 4.0 hosts and some older CLARiiON CX3 arrays. I&amp;rsquo;d been working to fix up the lab so that it more properly reflects a &amp;ldquo;best practices&amp;rdquo; configuration with dual SAN fabrics, dual-homed HBAs and CNAs, network connections spread across multiple physical switches, etc.&amp;mdash;you know, all the wonderful things that we recommend to our customers.
As a result of cross-connecting both the HBAs and the CLARiiON&amp;rsquo;s storage processors to both SAN fabrics, I ended up with more paths to the LUNs than I had previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure NPV on a Nexus 5000</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/28/how-to-configure-npv-on-a-nexus-5000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/28/how-to-configure-npv-on-a-nexus-5000/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I posted a &amp;ldquo;how to&amp;rdquo; article on how to configure FCoE on a Nexus 5000 switch. At that time, I did not put the Nexus 5000 into NPV mode but rather connected it to a Cisco MDS Fibre Channel switch without using NPV. In this entry, I&amp;rsquo;d like to follow up on that article and show you how to configure NPV on a Nexus 5000.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with NPV (N_Port Virtualization) and how it&amp;rsquo;s different than NPIV (N_Port ID Virtualization), check out this article titled &amp;ldquo;Understanding NPIV and NPV&amp;rdquo;; It should help clear things up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of FCoE Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/04/a-collection-of-fcoe-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 11:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/04/a-collection-of-fcoe-posts/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had these FCoE-related articles sitting around in my Yojimbo database for a while, but I&amp;rsquo;m only now getting around to doing something with them. There&amp;rsquo;s some great information in these posts, but be sure to check the comments to the posts as well&amp;mdash;there&amp;rsquo;s some equally good information to be found there as well.
FCoE Multi-hop: Why wait?
Re-examining FCoE and iSCSI Pros and Cons
FCoE vs. iSCSI: The Cagefight!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESX, EMC CLARiiON Arrays, and Multiple Protocols</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/05/vmware-esx-emc-clariion-arrays-and-multiple-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 10:01:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/03/05/vmware-esx-emc-clariion-arrays-and-multiple-protocols/</guid>
      <description>I was browsing through an EMC technical document titled &amp;ldquo;EMC CLARiiON Integration with VMware ESX Server&amp;rdquo; (download it here) a little while ago and I came across a phrase in the document that caught my attention:
 &amp;ldquo;VMware ESX/ESXi support both Fibre Channel and iSCSI storage. However, VMware and EMC do not support connecting VMware ESX/ESXi servers to CLARiiON Fibre Channel and iSCSI devices on the same array simultaneously.&amp;rdquo;
 What?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding NPIV and NPV</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/27/understanding-npiv-and-npv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 10:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/11/27/understanding-npiv-and-npv/</guid>
      <description>Two technologies that seem to have come to the fore recently are NPIV (N_Port ID Virtualization) and NPV (N_Port Virtualization). Judging just by the names, you might think that these two technologies are the same thing. While they are related in some aspects and can be used in a complementary way, they are quite different. What I&amp;rsquo;d like to do in this post is help explain these two technologies, how they are different, and how they can be used.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
