<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2007 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2007/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2007 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 20:56:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2007/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finally Home from VMworld 2007</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/15/finally-home-from-vmworld-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2007 20:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/15/finally-home-from-vmworld-2007/</guid>
      <description>After hitting VMworld 2007 in San Francisco hot and heavy (and trying to liveblog as many sessions as possible, as well as the keynotes), my wife and I took yesterday to do some additional sightseeing beyond what we&amp;rsquo;d done on Sunday prior.
Armed with one day MUNI pass for each of us, it was on the buses and the cable cars all over San Francisco, hitting the major highlights along the way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Top Support Issues Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-top-support-issues-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 22:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-top-support-issues-session/</guid>
      <description>My last session of Day 3, and of the entire conference, was a super-session on the top support issues and how to resolve them. For someone who wasn&amp;rsquo;t already familiar with some of the Service Console command-line utilities (such as esxcfg-vswitch, esxcfg-vmknic, esxcfg-vswif, etc.), this was a great session. For someone already pretty comfortable with these tools, the session was less helpful.
The session centered around six or seven top support issues:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 IP-Based Storage Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-ip-based-storage-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 17:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-ip-based-storage-sessions/</guid>
      <description>I just wrapped up two different sessions on IP-based storage, one on iSCSI configuration and one on performance characteristics and comparisons between iSCSI and NFS.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t liveblog the first session because it was too crowded (no room to type on my laptop) and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get a wireless signal from the VMworld 2007 network. There are, however, a couple key points from the session that stick out in my mind:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 VCB Solutions Session</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-vcb-solutions-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 16:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-vcb-solutions-session/</guid>
      <description>This session is titled &amp;ldquo;Best Practices for Architecting VMware Consolidated Backup Enabled Solutions,&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s being led by a couple of different presenters, one of whom is Dan Anderson, who also led the VCB session on Partner Day and leads the VCB labs (and led the VCB labs last year at VMworld 2006). So far, it looks like this session won&amp;rsquo;t be a repeat of Monday&amp;rsquo;s Partner Day session, which is good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Day 3 Keynote Liveblog</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-day-3-keynote-liveblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2007 11:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/13/vmworld-2007-day-3-keynote-liveblog/</guid>
      <description>Here we are again back in the Moscone Center for the keynote of Day 3 of VMworld 2007. Unlike yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote from Cisco&amp;rsquo;s John Chambers, today&amp;rsquo;s keynote is expected to be much more exciting and more revealing. (Make no mistake: John Chambers is a very skilled speaker, but my personal opinion is that yesterday&amp;rsquo;s keynote was long on hype and short on reality.) Taking the stage today is VMware co-founder and Chief Scientist, Mendel Rosenblum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced VMotion Announcement</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/enhanced-vmotion-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 18:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/enhanced-vmotion-announcement/</guid>
      <description>I was supposed to be in this session! I&amp;rsquo;m so mad&amp;hellip;I had another obligation, someone to whom I&amp;rsquo;d committed to do something, so I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make the 5:00PM session yesterday during which VMware announced &amp;ldquo;Enhanced VMotion,&amp;rdquo; which is designed to alleviate some of the CPU compatibility concerns that have become a bit more visible in the last few months.
In reading the SearchServerVirtualization.com article on this announcement (which is the only reference I&amp;rsquo;ve seen thus far to the new capabilites), it looks like this may build on top of already-announced enhancements by Intel and AMD (Intel calls theirs FlexMigration, and I think AMD is calling theirs AMD-V Extended or similar).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Collection of VMworld 2007 Links</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/a-collection-of-vmworld-2007-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/a-collection-of-vmworld-2007-links/</guid>
      <description>Here are some VMworld links that I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting over the last day or so. As I have time, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to expand upon them and add my own thoughts and views, but wanted to mention them here briefly, at least:
  VMworld 2007: Embedded ESX a can of worms: Alex Barrett of SearchServerVirtualization.com comments on the release of ESX Server 3i and what impact it may have on the usage of ESX Server in the enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Session on Advanced Diagnostics Log Analysis</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-session-on-advanced-diagnostics-log-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 16:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-session-on-advanced-diagnostics-log-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I signed up for this session (titled &amp;ldquo;Advanced ESX 3.0.x Diagnostics Log Analysis&amp;rdquo;) with the hope of getting some in-depth, useful information on log analysis and troubleshooting. As a field person, out there in the trenches installing and supporting this stuff, having detailed information on the information that&amp;rsquo;s being logged by the system is incredibly helpful. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope that this session provides exactly that.
The presenter is Mostafa Khalil, a member of VMware Product Support Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Session on ESX Patch Management</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-session-on-esx-patch-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-session-on-esx-patch-management/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting ready to start another session (another super-session) on ESX patch management, presented by Brian Gallob. Incidentally, I met Brian on Monday night at the VMTN Communities get-together around the corner at the Thirsty Bear (username is BrianG on the forums). I think I heard there&amp;rsquo;s about 1200 people registered for this session over in Room 103 of Moscone South, the same room used yesterday for the VC bullet-proofing session I attended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Day 2 Keynote Liveblog</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-day-2-keynote-liveblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 11:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/vmworld-2007-day-2-keynote-liveblog/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 is here, and along with it is my liveblog. Thanks for reading, and I hope that today&amp;rsquo;s content is useful to you. Feel free to add your thoughts in the comments below!
Pre-Keynote I had a great conversation with Mike Laverick of RTFM Education before the keynote started.
Again, about 8:08 AM, the keynote started. This time, it was no professionally produced video with dramatic natural scenes and inspiring music; no, it was a home-produced amateur video about VMware sung by an as-yet-unannounced gentleman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other VMworld News and Views</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/other-vmworld-news-and-views/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2007 09:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/12/other-vmworld-news-and-views/</guid>
      <description>I was so busy yesterday with meetings, VMworld sessions, and other obligations here in San Francisco that I missed out on some important news and posts:
  Thanks to fellow liveblogger Eric Sloof, I learned that VMware has released the majority of the VMware Tools as open source. A SourceForge site (http://open-vm-tools.sourceforge.net/) has been established for the project. The official VMware press release is here.
  Mike Laverick of RTFM Education published a great post on VMware Site Recovery Manager, with more details on how VMware SRM works and how it interoperates and integrates with VirtualCenter and the rest of VI3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Session of VMworld 2007, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/first-session-of-vmworld-2007-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 19:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/first-session-of-vmworld-2007-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The morning of Day 1 of VMworld 2007 was filled with meetings, training sessions, and a self-inflicted mandatory visit to the Solutions Exchange (more on that tomorrow, at which time you&amp;rsquo;ll understand why I can&amp;rsquo;t say anything now and why I referred to it as a &amp;ldquo;self-inflicted mandatory visit&amp;rdquo;). In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s now 2PM on Day 1 here in San Francisco and I just finished standing in line for about 15 minutes to get into a session on protecting VirtualCenter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Day 1 Keynote Liveblog</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/vmworld-2007-day-1-keynote-liveblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 11:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/vmworld-2007-day-1-keynote-liveblog/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a great deal of buzz surrounding the VMworld 2007 Day 1 keynote address, in which VMware is expected to make a number of product announcements as well as shed some additional details on product announcements already made, such as ESX Server 3i, VMware Site Recovery Manager, and Virtual Desktop Manager 2.0. I mentioned all these things in a post yesterday, after completing the first half of Partner Day. Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll be trying to liveblog the keynote, so stay tuned for additional details and information as it is presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Acquires Dunes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/vmware-acquires-dunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2007 10:47:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/11/vmware-acquires-dunes/</guid>
      <description>VMware has announced that it has acquired Dunes Technologies, a company that provides process automation and workflow in virtualized environments (the Dunes announcement is here). Virtualization.info broke the news about this several days ago, and it was confirmed today with this press release. Presumably Dunes&amp;rsquo; technologies and products will be used to bulk up VMware Site Recovery Manager, Virtual Desktop Manager, and related VMware products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2007 Partner Day Sessions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/10/vmworld-2007-partner-day-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2007 19:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/10/vmworld-2007-partner-day-sessions/</guid>
      <description>I had the opportunity to attend three Partner Day sessions today, all three from the &amp;ldquo;Advanced In-Depth Technical Track.&amp;rdquo;
The first was this morning, and it was focused on an in-depth technical review of VMware Consolidated Backup. I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few articles about VMware Consolidated Backup before:
  VMware Consolidated Backup
  Restoring VCB Full Backups with VMware Converter
  Strange VCB Error
  The presenter was very knowledgeable; in fact, he was the one running the VCB labs at VMworld (and ran the labs at VMworld last year, which I attended).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
