<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christianity on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/christianity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christianity on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/christianity/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2019 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/23/vmworld-2019-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/23/vmworld-2019-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last several years, I&amp;rsquo;ve organized a brief morning prayer time at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmworld.com/&#34;&gt;VMworld&lt;/a&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend the conference last year, but organized a prayer time nevertheless (and was able to join one morning for prayer). This year, now that I&amp;rsquo;m back at VMware (via the Heptio acquisition) and speaking at the conference, I&amp;rsquo;d once again like to coordinate a time for believers to meet. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re a Christian interested in gathering together with other Christians for a brief time of prayer, here are the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2018 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/12/vmworld-2018-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/12/vmworld-2018-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last several years, I&amp;rsquo;ve organized a brief morning prayer time at VMworld. This year, I won&amp;rsquo;t be at the conference, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to help coordinate a time for believers to meet nevertheless. So, if you&amp;rsquo;re a Christian interested in gathering together with other Christians for a brief time of prayer, here are the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/23/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/23/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the US, today (Thursday, November 23) is Thanksgiving. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a moment to reflect on the meaning of Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2017 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/27/vmworld-2017-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/27/vmworld-2017-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmworld.com&#34;&gt;VMworld 2017&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas, I&amp;rsquo;m organizing&amp;mdash;as I have in previous years&amp;mdash;a gathering of Christians for a brief time of prayer while at the conference. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining us, here are the details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2016 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/vmworld-2016-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/vmworld-2016-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve helped organize a gathering of Christians for a brief time of prayer while at VMworld. This year, I’d like to again offer fellow believers attending VMworld 2016 the same opportunity to gather together for a time of prayer before starting the day. If you’re interested in attending, here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer
Where: Mandalay Bay Convention Center, level 1 (same level as the food court), at the bottom of the escalators heading upstairs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Time at the Austin Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/25/prayer-time-austin-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/25/prayer-time-austin-summit/</guid>
      <description>A large portion of the OpenStack community is gathered in Austin this week for the Spring 2016 OpenStack Summit. As I&amp;rsquo;ve done at previous Summits (and other events), I&amp;rsquo;m offering to gather with other Christian believers for a brief time of prayer in the mornings before the sessions kick off each day.
Normally I get these arranged much earlier, so I apologize for not getting this out there sooner. That being said, if you&amp;rsquo;re a Christian and interested in gathering for a brief time of prayer, we will be meeting outside the Austin Convention Center at 8:30 am.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Time at Tokyo Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/21/tokyo-summit-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/10/21/tokyo-summit-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of organizing at VMworld over the last couple of years, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to start doing it at the OpenStack Summits as well. So, next week in Tokyo, I&amp;rsquo;d like to offer Christians attending the Summit the opportunity to gather together for a brief time of prayer before the day&amp;rsquo;s activities get started.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in attending, here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2015 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/08/13/vmworld-2015-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/08/13/vmworld-2015-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>Last year, a group of believers gathered for a brief time of prayer while at VMworld 2014. This year, I&amp;rsquo;d like to again offer believers attending VMworld 2015 the same opportunity to gather together for a time of prayer before starting the day. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in attending, here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer
Where: Yerba Buena Gardens, behind Moscone North (by the waterfall)
When: Monday 8/31 through Wednesday 9/2 at 7:45am (this should give everyone enough time to grab breakfast before the keynotes start at 9am)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2014 Prayer Time</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/15/vmworld-2014-prayer-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 10:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/15/vmworld-2014-prayer-time/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned this on Twitter a few days ago, but wanted to go ahead and formalize some of the details. A blog reader/Twitter follower contacted me with the idea of getting together briefly at VMworld 2014 for some prayer time. I thought it was a great idea (thanks David!), so here are the details.
What: A brief time of prayer
Where: Yerba Buena Gardens, behind Moscone North
When: Monday 8/25 through Wednesday 8/27 at 7:45am (this should give everyone enough time to grab breakfast before the keynotes start at 9am)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some New Christian Music</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/21/some-new-christian-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 10:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/21/some-new-christian-music/</guid>
      <description>I recently purchased some new Christian music to add to my iTunes library; I had a credit with iTunes from some iTunes Gift Cards that my kids gave me for Christmas. After six months, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d better go ahead and use the iTunes credit or it would disappear.
After browsing for a while, I ended up selecting the following albums:
  Unbreakable by Fireflight - I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished listening to the entire album, but so far my favorite track is &amp;ldquo;Forever&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/25/merry-christmas-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 14:51:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/25/merry-christmas-2/</guid>
      <description>Let us never forget the true reason behind Christmas:
 In those days Caesar Augustus issued a decree that a census should be taken of the entire Roman world. (This was the first census that took place while Quirinius was governor of Syria.) And everyone went to his own town to register.
So Joseph also went up from the town of Nazareth in Galilee to Judea, to Bethlehem the town of David, because he belonged to the house and line of David.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Finished Fireproof</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/just-finished-fireproof/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 20:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/just-finished-fireproof/</guid>
      <description>My wife, a couple of the kids, and I just got back home after watching Fireproof at the local movie theater. You&amp;rsquo;ll recall that I first mentioned Fireproof back in August, and today was the opening day. I thoroughly enjoyed the movie. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it, make plans to go see it right away! The movie is great, but the Message in the movie is even greater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fireproof</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/16/fireproof/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 21:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/16/fireproof/</guid>
      <description>A new movie from the producers of &amp;ldquo;Facing the Giants&amp;rdquo; is set to open on September 26, 2008. The movie, &amp;ldquo;Fireproof&amp;rdquo;, stars Kirk Cameron, and focuses on the story of a firefighter and his efforts to save a crumbling marriage. I absolutely love the tagline: &amp;ldquo;Never leave your partner behind.&amp;rdquo;
The movie&amp;rsquo;s web site is here, and there&amp;rsquo;s also a Fireproof blog available as well.
Marriage resources based on the movie are available at fireproofmymarriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Altar and the Door by Casting Crowns</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/10/the-altar-and-the-door-by-casting-crowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2008 16:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/10/the-altar-and-the-door-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
      <description>A fellow believer contacted me recently asking if I&amp;rsquo;d listened to any recent Casting Crowns albums. He&amp;rsquo;d stumbled across the site, entirely accidentally, and saw my post about Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; Lifesong album. I followed that post up a couple of months later with another take, in which I took a deeper look at their music&amp;mdash;not just their musical style, but the words and the emotions behind their music&amp;mdash;and I realized that there was so much more to be heard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Testimony of Love</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/07/a-testimony-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 13:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/07/a-testimony-of-love/</guid>
      <description>Over three years ago, I blogged about Shaohannah&amp;rsquo;s Hope, a charity founded by Steven Curtis Chapman and his wife, Mary Beth Chapman. Shaohannah&amp;rsquo;s Hope is dedicated to helping further the love of Christ through the ministry of adoption.
As most everyone knows, the Chapman family recently suffered a tragic loss. Yet, even after that tragic loss, Steven Curtis Chapman, his wife, and their family still trust in God and still believe in adoption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
