<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMFS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmfs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #70</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/technology-short-take-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/08/12/technology-short-take-70/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #70! In this post you&amp;rsquo;ll find a collection of links to articles discussing the major data center technologies&amp;mdash;networking, hardware, security, cloud computing, applications, virtualization&amp;hellip;you name it! (If there&amp;rsquo;s a topic you think I&amp;rsquo;m missing, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you.)
Networking  MTU in OpenStack Neutron has been, as this article by Sam Yaple points out, a bit of a touchy subject. Fortunately, it looks like progress has been made on that front, so check out Sam&amp;rsquo;s post for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #34</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/07/22/technology-short-take-34/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #34, my latest collection of links, articles, thoughts, and ideas from around the web, centered on key data center technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   Henry Louwers has a nice write-up on some of the design considerations that go into selecting a Citrix NetScaler solution.
  Scott Hogg explores jumbo frames and their benefits/drawbacks in a clear and concise manner. It&amp;rsquo;s worth reading if you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with jumbo frames and some of the considerations around their use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of Virtualization Short Takes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</guid>
      <description>My irregular &amp;ldquo;Virtualization Short Takes&amp;rdquo; series was put on hold some time ago after I started work on Mastering VMware vSphere 4. Now that work on the book is starting to wind down just a bit, I thought it would be a good time to try to resurrect the series. So, without further delay, welcome to the return of Virtualization Short Takes!
  Trigged by a series of blog posts by Arnim van Lieshout on VMware ESX memory management (Part 1, Part 2, and Part 3), Scott Herold decided to join the fray with this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source VMFS Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/26/open-source-vmfs-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 22:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/26/open-source-vmfs-driver/</guid>
      <description>It looks like my post discussing a universal cluster file system may have been prescient. Shared with me first via Twitter, it appears that a company has already started building an open source VMFS driver. It was also covered here and here.
As we discussed in the post about cross-hypervisor cluster file systems, the implications of hypervisors potentially being able to share clustered storage are quite significant. Of course, there are many hurdles to yet overcome, but what if this project develops and matures and becomes a valid tool?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #25, the first edition of this series for 2009! Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of articles and posts that I found interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off today&amp;rsquo;s list with some Hyper-V links. First up is this article on how to manually add a VM configuration to Hyper-V. It would be interesting to me to know some of the technical details&amp;mdash;i.e., the design decisions that led Microsoft to architect things in this way&amp;mdash;that might explain why this process is, in my opinion, so complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Got to be Kidding Me</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 14:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</guid>
      <description>Via jtroyer on Twitter, I learned of this post comparing Hyper-V and VMware ESX.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit that I&amp;rsquo;m a VMware fan, but as others in the virtualization industry know I also recognize that VMware is not a &amp;ldquo;one size fits all&amp;rdquo; solution. There are many places where other virtualization solutions, Hyper-V included, may be a better solution for the customer. It really all depends upon the customer&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #22</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/11/virtualization-short-take-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 11:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/11/virtualization-short-take-22/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m out of town this week at NetApp Insight, I wanted to go ahead and get out the latest installation of Virtualization Short Takes&amp;mdash;my sometimes-weekly collection of interesting or useful links and tidbits.
  Much ado has been made about VMware&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of Trango and the announcement of VMware MVP (Mobile Virtualization Platform). Rich Brambley has a great write-up, and I completely agree with Rich and Alex Barrett about what this really means: don&amp;rsquo;t expect to see Windows XP on your smartphone any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/14/virtualization-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 21:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/14/virtualization-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Virtualization Short Take #19 is here, with news, headlines, and commentary on a few things that have passed my way over the last few weeks. Feel free to share your own interesting tidbits in the comments!
  Rick Blythe, aka VMwarewolf, regales us with a tale of a new &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; in VirtualCenter 2.5 Update 2. This new feature prevents VM migrations when putting a VMware ESX server into maintenance mode if it will violate the VMware HA failover level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA2668: VMware ESX Architectural Directions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/ta2668-vmware-esx-architectural-directions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/ta2668-vmware-esx-architectural-directions/</guid>
      <description>Once again, there&amp;rsquo;s no wireless signal in the breakout session, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to publish this in a delayed fashion. Ugh! Someone needs to work on this wireless network.
This is session TA2668, VMware ESX Architectural Directions. This is another session that provides forward-looking information at future versions of VMware ESX.
The presenter started out the presentation by giving an overview of VMware ESX, what it&amp;rsquo;s designed to do, what features it has currently, what it&amp;rsquo;s capable of doing, what it knows, how it manages CPU scheduling and other resources like memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #14</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/23/virtualization-short-take-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2008 15:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/23/virtualization-short-take-14/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to another installation of Virtualization Short Takes!
  For you Quicksilver lovers out there that also run VMware Fusion, here&amp;rsquo;s a handy trick to allow you to launch Windows apps to run under Fusion via Quicksilver.
  Duncan of Yellow Bricks points out this VMware Communities Forums thread discussing how to determine which host has a lock on a LUN. This thread also makes brief mention of the new VMFS version, version 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/18/virtualization-short-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2008 14:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/18/virtualization-short-take-2/</guid>
      <description>Before I begin the second installation of Virtualization Short Takes, I thought it was interesting to note that Thomas Bishop over at ScaleTheMind.com has adopted a similar strategy. There&amp;rsquo;s just so much happening that it&amp;rsquo;s truly impossible to discuss everything in depth. Even so, it&amp;rsquo;s often helpful to at least provide the readers with the links and some additional thoughts. It seems like this approach may be the best one to use.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
