<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reInvent2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/reinvent2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reInvent2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/reinvent2016/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2016 Keynote with Werner Vogels</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/01/aws-reinvent-keynote-werner-vogels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/01/aws-reinvent-keynote-werner-vogels/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Thursday keynote at AWS re:Invent 2016. Today&amp;rsquo;s keynote is led by Werner Vogels, CTO of Amazon Web Services. Unlike yesterday, today I opted not to attend the keynote in the main hall, viewing the keynote instead from an &amp;ldquo;overflow&amp;rdquo; area. Turns out the &amp;ldquo;overflow&amp;rdquo; area has drinks, tables, and power! That&amp;rsquo;s a far better option that being crammed in the main hall, though in the past I&amp;rsquo;ve found it more difficult to liveblog when not viewing the keynote directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Introduction to Managed Database Services on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/intro-managed-db-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/intro-managed-db-services/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Managed Database Services on AWS&amp;rdquo; (DAT307). The speakers for the session are Steve Hunt, Alan Murray, and Robin Spira, all of FanDuel; and Darin Briskman, from AWS Database Services.
Briskman kicks off the session with a quick review of AWS&amp;rsquo; managed database offerings. These fall into four categories, which Briskman reviewed so quickly I couldn&amp;rsquo;t capture. I think they were SQL, NoSQL, data warehousing, and something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: How News UK Centralized Cloud Governance</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/centralized-governance-policy-mgmt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/centralized-governance-policy-mgmt/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;How News UK Centralized Cloud Governance Using Policy Management&amp;rdquo; (DEV306). The speakers for the session are Joe Kinsella from CloudHealth Technologies and Iain Caldwell of News UK/News Corp EMEA.
Kinsella kicks things off by indicating that the session will attempt to tackle the burning question: how does one maintain the agility that brought you to the cloud in the beginning, but enforce the proper level of governance and control?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Automating Cloud Mgmt and Deployment</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/automating-cloud-mgmt-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/automating-cloud-mgmt-deployment/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;Automating Cloud Management and Deployment for a Diverse Enterprise Application Portfolio&amp;rdquo; (DEV319). The speakers for the session are David Lowry and Amul Merchant, both from Infor Global.
Merchant kicks the session off with a brief overview of Infor and its cloud strategy. Infor&amp;rsquo;s CEO, Charles Phillips, was quoted from AWS re:Invent 2014 as having said, &amp;ldquo;Friends don&amp;rsquo;t let friends build data centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS re:Invent 2016 Keynote with Andy Jassy</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/aws-reinvent-keynote-andy-jassy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/30/aws-reinvent-keynote-andy-jassy/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Wednesday keynote at AWS re:Invent 2016. Today&amp;rsquo;s keynote is led by Andy Jassy, CEO of Amazon Web Services. The crowd gathered for the keynote is pretty immense, despite the availability of numerous overflow locations spread across the multiple re:Invent venues.
At precisely 9am, the DJ rocking the pre-keynote music leaves the stage and AWS welcomes Andy Jassy, CEO, to the stage. This is only the 5th re:Invent conference, and Jassy confirms that this year&amp;rsquo;s attendance is 32,000 with another 50,000 listening in via the live stream.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on AWS re:Invent Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/thoughts-aws-reinvent-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/thoughts-aws-reinvent-day-1/</guid>
      <description>As I wrap up Day 1 of AWS re:Invent 2016 in Las Vegas (can I consider today to be day 1?), I wanted to capture a quick summary of thoughts about the sessions, the content, the attendees, and the event (not necessarily in that order).
First, here are some links to the liveblogs I posted from today&amp;rsquo;s sessions:
Liveblog: Scaling to Your First 10 Million Users
Liveblog: Hybrid Architectures, Bridging the Gap to the Cloud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Getting the Most Bang for Your Buck with EC2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/getting-bang-buck-ec2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/getting-bang-buck-ec2/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;Getting the Most Bang for Your Buck With #EC2 #Winning&amp;rdquo; (CMP202). The speaker for the session is Joshua Burgin, General Manager, EC2 Spot Business. According to the abstract, this session is supposed to focus on effectively using on-demand instances versus spot instances and reserved instances.
As a matter of quick introduction, there are three purchasing options for EC2:
 On-demand: &amp;ldquo;pay as you go&amp;rdquo;; no long-term commitments Reserved: good for steady-state workloads, used with 1 yr or 3 yr commitment Spot: pay market price for unused compute capacity  How do you choose which one to use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Hybrid Architectures, Bridging the Gap to the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/hybrid-bridging-gap-to-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/hybrid-bridging-gap-to-cloud/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;Hybrid Architectures: Bridging the Gap to the Cloud&amp;rdquo; (ARC208). The line to get into this session, as with the previous session, was quite long&amp;mdash;and that was for attendees who&amp;rsquo;d already registered for the session. Feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve heard from folks who weren&amp;rsquo;t registered for sessions was that they weren&amp;rsquo;t getting in, period. The speaker for the session is Jamie Butler, Manager of Solutions Architecture at AWS (focused on state/local government).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liveblog: Scaling to Your First 10 Million Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/scaling-first-10mil-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/29/scaling-first-10mil-users/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the AWS re:Invent session titled &amp;ldquo;Scaling to Your First 10 Million Users.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s my first session of the week here at re:Invent; yesterday&amp;rsquo;s sessions were full and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into anything. (The crowds here at the event are pretty significant; I think I heard 32K attendees total.) The speaker for the session is Joel Williams, an AWS Solutions Architect.
Williams starts out with a brief blurb about how this session is a perennial favorite at re:Invent, and how the principles are fundamental to working in building solutions in/on AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
