<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IOS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ios/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review: CPLAY2air Wireless CarPlay Adapter</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/10/review-cplay2air-wireless-carplay-adapter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/10/review-cplay2air-wireless-carplay-adapter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late September, I was given a CPLAY2air wireless CarPlay adapter as a gift. Neither of my vehicles support wireless CarPlay, and so I was looking forward to using the CPLAY2air device to enable the use of CarPlay without having to have my phone plugged into a cable. Here&amp;rsquo;s my feedback on the CPLAY2air device after about six weeks of use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem with Markdown Files in BoxCryptor on iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/problem-with-markdown-files-in-boxcryptor-on-ios/</guid>
      <description>About a week ago, I published an article showing you how to use EncFS and BoxCryptor to provide client-side encryption of Dropbox data. After working with this configuration for a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve run across a problem (at least, a problem for me&amp;mdash;it might not be a problem for you). The problem lies on the iPad end of things.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the earlier post, the basic gist of the idea is to use EncFS&amp;mdash;an open source encrypting file system&amp;mdash;and OSXFUSE to provide file-level encryption of Dropbox data on your OS X system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a CCNA Study Environment with GNS3 and VMware</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/22/setting-up-a-ccna-study-environment-with-gns3-and-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 10:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/22/setting-up-a-ccna-study-environment-with-gns3-and-vmware/</guid>
      <description>If you were following my tweets over the last few days, you probably already know that I have been working on setting up a CCNA study environment using Ubuntu Linux, GNS3, and VMware Workstation. After a couple days of difficulties, I finally managed to make it work last night. Here are the steps that I took to make it work.
Before we start, there is the standard disclaimer: these are the steps that worked for me; these steps might or might not work for you, and are almost guaranteed not to work with different Linux distributions or different versions of the associated software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Potential Use for the iPad</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/22/a-potential-use-for-the-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2010 22:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/22/a-potential-use-for-the-ipad/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hype surrounding the Apple iPad. Some people are proclaiming it&amp;rsquo;s the end of traditional media like newspapers, magazines, and books. I&amp;rsquo;m not so sure about that, but I have found one potential use for the iPad that&amp;mdash;for me, at least&amp;mdash;might be compelling enough to make me go buy one later this year.
One task that I&amp;rsquo;m finding as a member of EMC&amp;rsquo;s vSpecialist team is that there is a lot of reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on vSwitch Load Balancing</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/24/more-on-vswitch-load-balancing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2009 12:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/09/24/more-on-vswitch-load-balancing/</guid>
      <description>I had a customer contact me about scaling network throughput when using NFS datastores. Specifically, this customer was interested in knowing if it was possible to utilize more than 1 NIC with IP-based storage. The customer is currently using link aggregation (EtherChannel on a Cisco switch). I pointed the customer to my post on NIC utilization, in which I explain the prerequisites for utilizing more than 1 NIC in this sort of configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change the Delay for iPhone Voicemail</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/11/change-the-delay-for-iphone-voicemail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2009 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/08/11/change-the-delay-for-iphone-voicemail/</guid>
      <description>For a couple of different reasons&amp;mdash;one of them being a desire to have Google Voice take over voicemail responsibilities&amp;mdash;I needed to find a way to make my iPhone wait longer before sending an unanswered call to voicemail. As it turns out, this thread has the answer I needed. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works. (Note: Do this at your own risk. I&amp;rsquo;m not responsible for any problems you might create as a result of this information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary of CDP Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/summary-of-cdp-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2009 10:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/18/summary-of-cdp-articles/</guid>
      <description>For all you data storage guys and gals out there, CDP here means &amp;ldquo;Cisco Discovery Protocol&amp;rdquo;, not &amp;ldquo;Continuous Data Protection.&amp;rdquo; Sorry.
It seems that interest in VMware ESX&amp;rsquo;s support for CDP is gaining interest and attention; fellow blogger Rich Brambley of VM /ETC recently covered the topic as well.
To help summarize some of the content that I&amp;rsquo;ve generated around VMware ESX and CDP, here is a list of the articles available on this site:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viewing CDP Data on VMware ESX</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/24/viewing-cdp-data-on-vmware-esx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2009 15:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/24/viewing-cdp-data-on-vmware-esx/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago I wrote about enabling Cisco Discovery Protocol (CDP) on next-gen ESX/ESXi and made the comment that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet found a way to view CDP data from the ESX side. One of the great things about writing a blog is that insightful and knowledgeable readers share some great information with you, and you learn a lot! That&amp;rsquo;s the situation here.
Viewing CDP data from the Cisco switch is easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Mail.app and iPhone with Google IMAP</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/20/configuring-mailapp-and-iphone-with-google-imap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 12:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/20/configuring-mailapp-and-iphone-with-google-imap/</guid>
      <description>So I recently moved almost all of my personal e-mail domains over to Google Apps. A couple of people have asked, &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; My answer is simple: it&amp;rsquo;s easier. The e-mail functionality of my current hosting provider is lacking in a couple of key areas:
  Rather than using the emerging standard of having e-mail clients connect to TCP port 587 (Submission) to send e-mail, they used a very non-standard practice of using TCP port 26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle and OmniFocus Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/20/omnigraffle-and-omnifocus-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 10:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/20/omnigraffle-and-omnifocus-updates/</guid>
      <description>Two of my most-used applications have been updated to new versions. OmniGraffle is now updated to version 5.1, and OmniFocus is now updated to version 1.5. (Funny, I just noticed how the versions numbers are reversed&amp;ndash;5.1 and 1.5.)
The OmniGraffle update brings one feature that I have especially been anticipating: the ability to import Windows Metafile images in Visio diagrams. This extremely useful feature, first hinted at here back in March, will tremendously ease Visio compatibility and should open up lots of Visio shapes to be used in OmniGraffle that previously were not usable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on VMware ESX NIC Utilization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/08/more-on-vmware-esx-nic-utilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 16:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/08/more-on-vmware-esx-nic-utilization/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year, I wrote an article about NIC utilization in VMware ESX in which I discussed some of the details around how VMware ESX uses NICs in various configurations. The testing that prompted that article was primarily centered around IP-based storage (software-based iSCSI and NFS), so naturally the discussion primarily centered around IP-based storage as well.
As a follow up to that article, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running some additional tests with a focus this time on the behavior of virtual machines (VMs) in configurations both with and without link aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniFocus for iPhone First Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/29/omnifocus-for-iphone-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 21:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/29/omnifocus-for-iphone-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>For those that follow me on Twitter, you may have noticed that I purchased and installed OmniFocus for iPhone over the weekend. If you are a GTD lover and a Mac user, you are no doubt familiar with the &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; OmniFocus application from The Omni Group. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using OmniFocus for quite some time now (I wrote about that back in February), and I was really excited about the possibility of taking it mobile with me on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any iPhone App Recommendations?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/01/any-iphone-app-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 12:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/01/any-iphone-app-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I bought my iPhone 3G. When the original iPhone was released, I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy one because it lacked 3G network connectivity, and the Samsung BlackJack 2 I was using was already 3G capable. In addition, the BlackJack supported ActiveSync for connectivity to my corporate Exchange infrastructure, and the iPhone didn&amp;rsquo;t. After the iPhone 3G was released, my two primary complaints had now been removed, and I said that I would get one&amp;mdash;but not right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In-Depth Look at the ASR Router</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/12/in-depth-look-at-the-asr-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 19:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/12/in-depth-look-at-the-asr-router/</guid>
      <description>Back on March 5 blogger extraordinaire Alessandro Perilli of virtualization.info revealed that Cisco had chosen KVM as the virtualization platform for IOS-XE, the new Linux-based version of IOS that runs on the recently introduced ASR series of routers.
If you were like me, you may have been wondering exactly how Cisco was putting KVM to use. No need to wonder any longer! Colleague and fellow blogger Colin McNamara has written up a detailed and in-depth discussion of the ASR1000 and how it uses KVM to provide virtualized instances of IOS-XE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration for Protecting VMotion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/07/configuration-for-protecting-vmotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2008 10:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/07/configuration-for-protecting-vmotion/</guid>
      <description>As a follow-up to my earlier post about using VLANs with VMotion, I wanted to also share a brief configuration snippet (based on a Cisco IOS-based switch) that aligns with the recommendations in that article. This is nothing new to those who are familiar with IOS, but for those readers who are not it may provide some helpful information.
For the purposes of this configuration, I&amp;rsquo;m making the following assumptions:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
