<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Encryption on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/encryption/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Encryption on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 08:45:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/encryption/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using cert-manager with Kuma for mTLS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/17/using-cert-manager-with-kuma-mtls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 08:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/17/using-cert-manager-with-kuma-mtls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When configuring mutual TLS (mTLS) on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kuma.io/&#34;&gt;the open source Kuma service mesh&lt;/a&gt;, users have a couple of different options. They can use a &amp;ldquo;builtin&amp;rdquo; certificate authority (CA), in which Kuma itself will generate a CA certificate and key for use in creating service-specific mTLS certificates. Users also have the option of using a &amp;ldquo;provided&amp;rdquo; CA, in which they must supply a CA certificate and key for Kuma to use when creating service-specific mTLS certificates. Both of these options are described &lt;a href=&#34;https://kuma.io/docs/1.4.x/policies/mutual-tls/&#34;&gt;on this page in the Kuma documentation&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://cert-manager.io/&#34;&gt;cert-manager&lt;/a&gt; as a &amp;ldquo;provided&amp;rdquo; CA for mTLS on Kuma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Certificate Details from HashiCorp Vault</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/12/getting-certificate-details-from-hashicorp-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/12/getting-certificate-details-from-hashicorp-vault/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems there are lots of tutorials on setting up a PKI (public key infrastructure) using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vaultproject.io/&#34;&gt;HashiCorp Vault&lt;/a&gt;. What I&amp;rsquo;ve found missing from most of these tutorials, however, is how to get details on certificates issued by a Vault-driven PKI &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the initial creation. For example, someone other than you issued a certificate, but now you need to get the details for said certificate. How is that done? In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you a couple ways to get details on certificates issued and stored in HashiCorp Vault.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WireGuard on macOS via the CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 08:05:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/28/using-wireguard-on-mac-via-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few different posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;simple yet fast and modern VPN&amp;rdquo; (as described by the WireGuard web site) that aims to supplant tools like IPSec and OpenVPN. My &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/&#34;&gt;first post on WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; showed how to configure WireGuard on Linux, both on the client side as well as on the server side. After that, I followed it up with posts on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;using the GUI WireGuard app to configure WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;mdash;most recently&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/&#34;&gt;making WireGuard from Homebrew work on an M1-based Mac&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a look at using WireGuard on macOS again, but this time via the CLI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making WireGuard from Homebrew Work on an M1 Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/22/making-wireguard-from-homebrew-work-on-an-m1-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After writing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/&#34;&gt;the post on using WireGuard on macOS&lt;/a&gt; (using the official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; GUI app from the Mac App Store), I found the GUI app&amp;rsquo;s behavior to be less than ideal. For example, tunnels marked as on-demand would later show up as no longer configured as an on-demand tunnel. When I decided to set up WireGuard on my M1-based MacBook Pro (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/02/review-2020-m1-based-macbook-pro/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt; of the M1 MacBook Pro), I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use the GUI app. Fortunately, &lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh&#34;&gt;Homebrew&lt;/a&gt; has formulas for WireGuard. Unfortunately, the WireGuard tools as installed by Homebrew on an M1-based Mac won&amp;rsquo;t work. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WireGuard on macOS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 17:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/04/01/using-wireguard-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short while ago I published a post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/&#34;&gt;setting up WireGuard for AWS VPC access&lt;/a&gt;. In that post, I focused on the use of Linux on both the server side (on an EC2 instance in your AWS VPC) as well as on the client side (using the GNOME Network Manager interface). However, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; is not limited to Linux, and I recently configured one of my macOS systems to take advantage of this WireGuard infrastructure for access to the private subnets in my AWS VPC. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk readers through configuring macOS to use WireGuard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up WireGuard for AWS VPC Access</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/02/22/setting-up-wireguard-for-aws-vpc-access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeking more streamlined access to AWS EC2 instances on private subnets, I recently implemented &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wireguard.com/&#34;&gt;WireGuard&lt;/a&gt; for VPN access. WireGuard, if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, is a relatively new solution that is baked into recent Linux kernels. (There is also support for other OSes.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share what I learned in setting up WireGuard for VPN access to my AWS environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 136</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/15/technology-short-take-136/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/15/technology-short-take-136/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #136, the first Short Take of 2021! The content this time around seems to be a bit more security-focused, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to include a few links in other areas. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 128</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #128! It looks like I&amp;rsquo;m settling into a roughly monthly cadence with the Technology Short Takes. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a (hopefully) interesting collection of links. The collection seems a tad heavier than normal in the hardware and security sections, probably due to new exploits discovered in Intel&amp;rsquo;s speculative execution functionality. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered for you. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Name to the Kubernetes API Server Certificate</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/30/adding-a-name-to-kubernetes-api-server-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/30/adding-a-name-to-kubernetes-api-server-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk you through how to add a name (specifically, a Subject Alternative Name) to the TLS certificate used by the Kubernetes API server. This process of updating the certificate to include a name that wasn&amp;rsquo;t included could find use for a few different scenarios. A couple of situations come to mind, such as adding a load balancer in front of the control plane, or using a new or different URL/hostname used to access the API server (both situations taking place &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the cluster was bootstrapped).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating the CA Certificate Hash for Kubeadm</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/12/calculating-ca-certificate-hash-for-kubeadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/12/calculating-ca-certificate-hash-for-kubeadm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When using &lt;code&gt;kubeadm&lt;/code&gt; to set up a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; cluster, the output of the &lt;code&gt;kubeadm init&lt;/code&gt; command that sets up the control plane for the first time contains some important information on joining additional nodes to the cluster. One piece of information in there that (until now) I hadn&amp;rsquo;t figured out how to replicate was the CA certificate hash. (Primarily I hadn&amp;rsquo;t figured it out because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t tried.) In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how to calculate the CA certificate hash for &lt;code&gt;kubeadm&lt;/code&gt; to use when joining additional nodes to an existing cluster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 116</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #116! This one is a bit shorter than usual, due to holidays in the US and my life being busy. Nevertheless, I hope that I managed to capture something you find useful or helpful. As always, your feedback is welcome, so if you have suggestions, corrections, or comments, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe&#34;&gt;contact me via Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 115</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/06/21/technology-short-take-115/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/06/21/technology-short-take-115/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #115! I&amp;rsquo;m back from my much-needed vacation in Bali, and getting settled back into work and my daily routine (which, for the last few weeks, was mostly swimming in the pool and sitting on the beach). Here&amp;rsquo;s a fresh new collection of links and articles from the around the web to propel myself back into blogging. I hope you find something useful here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bootstrapping an etcd Cluster with TLS using Kubeadm</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/21/bootstrapping-etcd-cluster-with-tls-using-kubeadm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/08/21/bootstrapping-etcd-cluster-with-tls-using-kubeadm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/coreos/etcd/&#34;&gt;etcd distributed key-value store&lt;/a&gt; is an integral part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;. I first wrote about etcd back in 2014 in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2014/08/18/coreos-continued-etcd/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really discussed it in any great detail since then. However, as part of my recent efforts to dive &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; deeper into Kubernetes, I needed to revisit etcd. In this post, I wanted to share how to boostrap a new etcd cluster with TLS certificates using &lt;code&gt;kubeadm&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 101</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/technology-short-take-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/06/08/technology-short-take-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #101! I have (hopefully) crafted an interesting and varied collection of links for you today, spanning all the major areas of modern data center technology. Now you have some reading material for this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
