<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vExpert on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vexpert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vExpert on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 17:55:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vexpert/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMware vExpert 2010: Thank You!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/05/vmware-vexpert-2010-thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 17:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/05/vmware-vexpert-2010-thank-you/</guid>
      <description>While I was waiting in the airport last night to catch a flight back from Nashua, NH, where I&amp;rsquo;d been working with VPLEX at the EMC lab facility there, I received confirmation that I had been awarded a VMware vExpert 2010 award. I am humbled and honored by the award. Wow&amp;mdash;thank you!
It is a tremendous honor to be included among those that VMware feels have (quoting from the vExpert landing page) &amp;ldquo;significantly contributed to the community of VMware users over the past year&amp;rdquo; and who &amp;ldquo;have gone above and beyond their day jobs to share their technical expertise&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vExpert Awards</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/25/vmware-vexpert-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 09:48:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/25/vmware-vexpert-awards/</guid>
      <description>Today, VMware awarded their vExpert Awards, an award intended to highlight those IT professionals who have supported the VMware community through user groups, blogs, forums, tools, and other means. Quoting from John Troyer&amp;rsquo;s official announcement on the VMTN Blog:
 Email went out tonight informing around 300 hard-working bloggers, user group leaders, and virtualization evangelists of all types that they had received a VMware vExpert Award. VMware vExperts were chosen on the basis of the contributions they had made to the community of VMware and virtualization users in 2008.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vExpert Program Officially Launched</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/14/vmware-vexpert-program-officially-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2009 22:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/14/vmware-vexpert-program-officially-launched/</guid>
      <description>While a number of other blogs broke the news about the name for this program earlier today&amp;mdash;VMware vExpert&amp;mdash;the official announcement is now available on the VMTN Blog. You can also get to the official nomination form, where you can nominate yourself or someone else (cough, cough, me) for a VMware vExpert award.
In case you&amp;rsquo;ve been hiding under a rock and aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with this program, here&amp;rsquo;s more information:
 VMware is very proud to introduce the VMware vExpert Awards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
