<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ONTAP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ontap/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ONTAP on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ontap/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp VIF Member Limitations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/02/netapp-vif-member-limitations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 21:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/02/02/netapp-vif-member-limitations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a couple of times about NetApp virtual interfaces (VIFs), which are Data ONTAP&amp;rsquo;s name for a link aggregate using either EtherChannel or dynamic LACP. The earlier articles I wrote are:
Cisco Link Aggregation and NetApp VIFs
LACP with Cisco Switches and NetApp VIFs
I came across an issue today of which I was not aware. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a new NetApp deployment with a fellow engineer that called for a number of different VIFs to be created: one for CIFS traffic, one for NFS traffic, and one for SnapMirror traffic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031: Enhancements to NetApp Cloning Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on enhancements to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s cloning functionality. These enhancements are due to be released along with Data ONTAP 7.3.1, which is expected out in December. Of course, that date may shift, but that&amp;rsquo;s the expected release timeframe.
The key focus of the session was new functionality that allows for Data ONTAP to clone individual files without a backing Snapshot. This new functionality is an extension of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s deduplication functionality, and is enabled by changes within Data ONTAP that enable block sharing, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Couple More Articles Published</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/02/a-couple-more-articles-published-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2008 18:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/02/a-couple-more-articles-published-2/</guid>
      <description>So a couple more articles I wrote have been published by SearchVMware.com:
Deduplication enhancements improve NetApp on VMware ESX
 NetApp storage area network (SAN) deduplication is useful for reducing storage requirements and saving space out of the box. When combined with a VMware Infrastructure 3 (VI3) or a virtual desktop environment, however, a few simple configurations can offer additional space savings and minimize the overhead of running deduplication on a storage array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/05/storage-short-take-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 20:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/05/storage-short-take-2/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another installation of Storage Short Takes, with news and views of the storage world. Readers, if you have any more sources of information about storage happenings, please let me know in the comments. I&amp;rsquo;d love to expand the coverage of storage in these posts.
  I came across this EMC CLARiiON-focused blog the other day. Although it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since March of this year and the volume of posts is quite low, the quality of the posts seems pretty good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FlexClones Versus Deduplication with VMware Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/05/flexclones-versus-deduplication-with-vmware-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 11:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/05/flexclones-versus-deduplication-with-vmware-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>A number of times over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve run into situations where NetApp&amp;rsquo;s FlexClone technology was being heavily pitched to customers interested in deploying, or expanding their deployment of, VMware Infrastructure.
In case you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the use of NetApp FlexClones in conjunction with VMware Infrastructure, have a look at these earlier articles of mine:
How to Provision VMs Using NetApp FlexClones
NetApp FlexClones with VMware, Part 1</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning LUNs for Use with Deduplication</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/20/provisioning-luns-for-use-with-deduplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 22:10:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/20/provisioning-luns-for-use-with-deduplication/</guid>
      <description>The recent couple of articles I wrote about using NetApp deduplication&amp;mdash;in particular, the article on using NetApp deduplication with block storage&amp;mdash;have raised some questions that are probably worth addressing. Although NetApp deduplication works just fine with block-based storage, there are some considerations with regards to how the LUNs should be provisioned when deduplication will come into play.
Fortunately for me, someone at NetApp decided that it would be a good idea to document the five basic configurations of using NetApp deduplication with block storage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using NetApp Deduplication with Block Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/24/using-netapp-deduplication-with-block-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2008 10:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/24/using-netapp-deduplication-with-block-storage/</guid>
      <description>Building on my earlier article on setting up NetApp deduplication, I wanted to follow up with some information on using NetApp deduplication with block storage (LUNs presented via Fibre Channel or iSCSI).
For the most part, using NetApp deduplication with block storage is a lot like I described earlier:
  You (obviously) still need the NearStore and deduplication (A-SIS) licenses installed on the controller(s).
  You will still turn deduplication on using the sis on command for the FlexVol containing the LUNs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Blog Aggregator?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/20/netapp-blog-aggregator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 18:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/20/netapp-blog-aggregator/</guid>
      <description>VMware&amp;rsquo;s done a great job of rolling together the VMware news and views with their VMware blog aggregator, Planet V12n. Does anyone know of something equivalent for NetApp? Where is &amp;ldquo;Planet NetApp&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Guide to Setting up NetApp Deduplication</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/quick-guide-to-setting-up-netapp-deduplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 16:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/quick-guide-to-setting-up-netapp-deduplication/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m relatively new to NetApp deduplication (formerly A-SIS), so this article won&amp;rsquo;t be an advanced treatise on NetApp deduplication or its deep inner workings. Instead, this is intended to be a quick guide to setting up NetApp deduplication for others, like myself, who may be familiar with Data ONTAP but not necessarily deduplication.
Obviously, the first step will be to ensure that your NetApp storage system is licensed for deduplication. As of March 10, NetApp made the NearStore option, which was a prerequisite for deduplication, free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XenServer Taking Advantage of NetApp Functionality</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/11/xenserver-taking-advantage-of-netapp-functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2008 16:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/11/xenserver-taking-advantage-of-netapp-functionality/</guid>
      <description>Via Nick, it looks like the next version of Citrix XenServer (version 4.1, currently in beta) will have a new feature called Storage Delivery Services that is designed to take full advantage of some of the features of NetApp storage systems. Quoting from the Citrix datasheet:
 The adapter uses native NetApp APIs to implement XenAPI storage operations that provide access to hardware provisioning and snapshotting directly, without the proprietary layer that complicates management in other products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LACP with Cisco Switches and NetApp VIFs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/08/lacp-with-cisco-switches-and-netapp-vifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 23:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/08/lacp-with-cisco-switches-and-netapp-vifs/</guid>
      <description>In my previous article about using NetApp multi-mode VIFs with Cisco switches, I mentioned that you could&amp;mdash;at that time&amp;mdash;only use 802.3ad static link aggregation:
 Be aware that Data ONTAP&amp;rsquo;s multi-mode VIFs are only compatible with static 802.3ad link aggregation; you can&amp;rsquo;t use PAgP (Cisco proprietary protocol). I would assume dynamic LACP is also incompatible. For this reason we used the channel-group 1 mode on statement instead of something like channel-group 1 mode desirable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing LUN Space Requirements with NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 23:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Network Appliance storage before, you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with the idea of snap reserve (storage space set aside to accommodate for Snapshots) and fractional reserve (used with LUNs). I&amp;rsquo;m going to hold the in-depth discussion of why you need snap reserve and fractional reserve for a different day, but I did want to pass on these commands that were shared with me by a colleague of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco Link Aggregation and NetApp VIFs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/13/cisco-link-aggregation-and-netapp-vifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2007 14:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/06/13/cisco-link-aggregation-and-netapp-vifs/</guid>
      <description>Network Appliance storage systems support the use of virtual interfaces (VIFs) to provide link redundancy and improved network throughput. Two types of VIFs are available:
  Single-mode VIFs act like a fault tolerant team and will fail traffic over to a standby link when the active link goes down.
  Multi-mode VIFs act like a group of links providing aggregate bandwidth as well as link redundancy.
  Single-mode VIFs are great for fault tolerance, but the storage system isn&amp;rsquo;t leveraging all the links.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
