<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NAS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NAS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nas/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #74</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #74! The end of 2016 is nearly upon us, and it looks as if there will be only one more Technology Short Take before the end of the year. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with the content&amp;mdash;time is short!
Networking  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apstra, David Varnum has a great introduction to Apstra available on his site. Will Robinson talks about how to structure your Ansible playbooks in the context of using Ansible to control your network gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere on NFS Design Considerations Presentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/07/03/vsphere-on-nfs-design-considerations-presentation/</guid>
      <description>This presentation is one that I gave at the New Mexico, New York City, and Seattle VMUG conferences (this specific deck came from the Seattle conference, as you can tell by the Twitter handle on the first slide). The topic is design considerations for running vSphere on NFS. This isn&amp;rsquo;t an attempt to bash NFS, but rather to educate users on the things to avoid if you&amp;rsquo;re going to build a rock-solid NFS infrastructure for your VMware vSphere environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Alignment Document</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2009 19:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/03/31/storage-alignment-document/</guid>
      <description>NetApp has recently released TR-3747, Best Practices for File System Alignment in Virtual Environments. This document addresses the situations in which file system alignment is necessary in environments running VMware ESX/ESXi, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Citrix XenServer. The authors are Abhinav Joshi (he delivered the Hyper-V deep dive at Insight last year), Eric Forgette (wrote the Rapid Cloning Utility, I believe), and Peter Learmonth (a well-recognized name from the Toasters mailing list), so you know there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit of knowledge and experience baked into this document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031: Enhancements to NetApp Cloning Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on enhancements to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s cloning functionality. These enhancements are due to be released along with Data ONTAP 7.3.1, which is expected out in December. Of course, that date may shift, but that&amp;rsquo;s the expected release timeframe.
The key focus of the session was new functionality that allows for Data ONTAP to clone individual files without a backing Snapshot. This new functionality is an extension of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s deduplication functionality, and is enabled by changes within Data ONTAP that enable block sharing, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FalconStor Introduces a NAS Interface</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/falconstor-introduces-a-nas-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 11:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/falconstor-introduces-a-nas-interface/</guid>
      <description>FalconStor today announced a new file-interface deduplication system and enhancements to its Virtual Tape Library (VTL) software. FalconStor&amp;rsquo;s VTL product is resold by a number of other vendors, including EMC, Pillar, and SUN.
The new functionality being announced by FalconStor today is actually two-fold:
  First, FalconStor will now offer NFS and CIFS access to the deduplication repository through its file interface deduplication system (FIDS), enabling NAS-based disk-to-disk (D2D) backup solutions to integrate seamlessly with the FalconStor data repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Note Regarding VMware over NFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/18/important-note-regarding-vmware-over-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 12:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/18/important-note-regarding-vmware-over-nfs/</guid>
      <description>We ran into an interesting set of problems at work this week, all of them related to running virtual machines on VMware ESX over NetApp NFS. While we haven&amp;rsquo;t yet determined the root cause for all of the problem, we did uncover the root cause for one of the issues, and additional testing seems to indicate that one of the other problems may also be suffering from the same condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Protocol Performance Whitepaper from NetApp</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/14/storage-protocol-performance-whitepaper-from-netapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2008 09:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/14/storage-protocol-performance-whitepaper-from-netapp/</guid>
      <description>NetApp recently published a white paper summarizing some tests they ran to compare storage protocol performance in a VMware Infrastructure environment. The white paper, TR-3697, compares the storage performance of Fibre Channel, software iSCSI, and NFS against a couple of different NetApp storage systems.
I won&amp;rsquo;t go into all the sordid details here&amp;mdash;you can read the white paper yourself&amp;mdash;but the end results look something like this:
  Fibre Channel provided the highest throughput and the lowest processor utilization of all the storage protocols.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Blog Aggregator?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/20/netapp-blog-aggregator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 18:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/20/netapp-blog-aggregator/</guid>
      <description>VMware&amp;rsquo;s done a great job of rolling together the VMware news and views with their VMware blog aggregator, Planet V12n. Does anyone know of something equivalent for NetApp? Where is &amp;ldquo;Planet NetApp&amp;rdquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Guide to Setting up NetApp Deduplication</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/quick-guide-to-setting-up-netapp-deduplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 16:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/quick-guide-to-setting-up-netapp-deduplication/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m relatively new to NetApp deduplication (formerly A-SIS), so this article won&amp;rsquo;t be an advanced treatise on NetApp deduplication or its deep inner workings. Instead, this is intended to be a quick guide to setting up NetApp deduplication for others, like myself, who may be familiar with Data ONTAP but not necessarily deduplication.
Obviously, the first step will be to ensure that your NetApp storage system is licensed for deduplication. As of March 10, NetApp made the NearStore option, which was a prerequisite for deduplication, free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only Thin Provisioned in the Beginning</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/only-thin-provisioned-in-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 15:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/31/only-thin-provisioned-in-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>A niggling doubt about thin provisioned disks was placed in my head when I read Duncan&amp;rsquo;s article on a Storage VMotion problem; in that article, a statement is made that ESX Server 3.5 no longer supports thin provisioned disks. Intrigued by that comment, I started doing some digging to see if that was actually the case. I was unable to find any concrete statement one way or the other.
Some testing in my lab showed that with ESX Server 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Love It, But It&#39;s Not Available</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/28/i-love-it-but-its-not-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2008 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/02/28/i-love-it-but-its-not-available/</guid>
      <description>A friend of mine at Network Appliance was one of the presenters last year at VMworld 2007 for the now-famous presentation that showed a solution from Network Appliance where 100 VMs are created in just a couple of minutes. It&amp;rsquo;s great technology that is extremely useful in exactly those kinds of situations. I love it.
The video is so popular that it&amp;rsquo;s even been posted to YouTube. (By the way, did you know I&amp;rsquo;m on YouTube?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proving VMware Over NFS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/14/proving-vmware-over-nfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2008 09:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/14/proving-vmware-over-nfs/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of using NFS for VMware; I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned it before. I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one, either; there have been a number of recent blog entries from various people regarding the use of NFS for VMware:
Virtual Optics: Why VMware over NetApp NFS
Storage Nuts &amp;amp; Bolts: VMware over NetApp NFS: A Customer&amp;rsquo;s Testimonial
It&amp;rsquo;s great that this is receiving more attention in the spotlight, but I still have one question: where are the statistics proving NFS&amp;rsquo; value in VMware deployments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full VM Recovery with NetApp Snapshots</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/full-vm-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 16:17:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/full-vm-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>I guess I&amp;rsquo;m on a bit of a NetApp kick this week. After discussing (or perhaps revisiting) the idea of recovering files inside VMs using NetApp Snapshots (first here late last year, then again here), I wanted to take a closer look at full VM recovery using NetApp Snapshots.
First of all, it should go without saying that you should never use any of the procedures I&amp;rsquo;m describing here without first testing them yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nifty NFS-VMware Trick</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/27/nifty-nfs-vmware-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 23:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/27/nifty-nfs-vmware-trick/</guid>
      <description>I can take absolutely zero credit for this idea; it came completely from this aticle by Nick Triantos. But the trick is so absolutely cool, so incredibly useful, and yet so obvious (once you read it, you&amp;rsquo;ll smack yourself in the head and say, &amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t I think of that?&amp;rdquo;) that I just had to say something about it.
The use of NFS is getting more and more attention (I blogged about it briefly a few days ago) as a primary storage technology for VMware deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFS for VMware Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/21/nfs-for-vmware-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2007 20:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/21/nfs-for-vmware-storage/</guid>
      <description>I thought that I had blogged here before about using NFS for VMware storage, but it appears that I have not. (I guess that&amp;rsquo;s one of the downfalls of a fairly long-running weblog&amp;mdash;you blog about some things too often and not at all about other topics.) In any case, following some of the VMworld breakout sessions last week, NFS is getting a lot more attention these days as the storage protocol for VMware.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
