<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMotion on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmotion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMotion on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmotion/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #72</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/10/10/technology-short-take-72/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #72. Normally, I try to publish these on Fridays, but some personal travel prevented that this time around so I&amp;rsquo;m publishing on a Monday instead. Enough of that, though&amp;hellip;bring on the content! As usual, here&amp;rsquo;s my random collection of links, articles, and thoughts about various data center technologies.
Networking  Charles Min-Cheng Chan has a write-up on using IPv6 in Mininet. How&amp;rsquo;s this for Technology Short Take inception&amp;mdash;in TST #70, I mentioned the Cumulus topology converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #41</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/05/09/technology-short-take-41/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #41, the latest in my series of random thoughts, articles, and links from around the Internet. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Network Functions Virtualization (NFV) is a networking topic that is starting to get more and more attention (some may equate &amp;ldquo;attention&amp;rdquo; with &amp;ldquo;hype&amp;rdquo;; I&amp;rsquo;ll allow you to draw your own conclusion there). In any case, I liked how this article really hit upon what I personally feel is something many people are overlooking in NFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #28</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #28, the first Technology Short Take for 2013. As always, I hope that you find something useful or informative here. Enjoy!
Networking   Ivan Pepelnjak recently wrote a piece titled &amp;ldquo;Edge and Core OpenFlow (and why MPLS is not NAT)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s an informative piece&amp;mdash;Ivan&amp;rsquo;s stuff is always informative&amp;mdash;but what really drew my attention was his mention of a paper by Martin Casado, Teemu Koponen, and others that calls for a combination of MPLS and OpenFlow (and an evolution of OpenFlow into &amp;ldquo;edge&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; versions) to build next-generation networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #15</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #15, the latest in my irregular series of posts on various articles and links on networking, servers, storage, and virtualization&amp;mdash;everything a growing data center engineer needs!
Networking My thoughts this time around are pretty heavily focused on VXLAN, which continues to get lots of attention. I talked about posting a dissection of VXLAN, but I have failed miserably; fortunately, other people smarter than me have stepped up to the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stretched Clusters, Distance vMotion and L2 Adjacency</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/12/stretched-clusters-distance-vmotion-and-l2-adjacency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 12:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/05/12/stretched-clusters-distance-vmotion-and-l2-adjacency/</guid>
      <description>Beth Pariseau recently published an article discussing the practical value of long-distance vMotion, partially in response to EMC&amp;rsquo;s announcement of VPLEX Geo at EMC World 2011. In that article, Beth quotes some text from a tweet I posted as well as some text from Chad Sakac&amp;rsquo;s recent post on VPLEX Geo. However, there are a couple inaccuracies from Beth&amp;rsquo;s article that I really feel need to be cleared up:
  Long-distance vMotion and stretched clusters are not the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vMotion Layer 2 Adjacency Requirement</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/19/vmotion-layer-2-adjacency-requirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2010 10:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/19/vmotion-layer-2-adjacency-requirement/</guid>
      <description>The topic of vMotion, it&amp;rsquo;s practicality, and Layer 2 adjacency for vMotion has been a topic I&amp;rsquo;ve visited a few times over the last several months. The trend got kicked off with a post on vMotion reality, in which I attempted to debunk an article claiming vMotion was only a myth. The series continued with a discussion of the practicality of vMotion, where I again discussed the various Layer 2 requirements for vMotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vMotion Practicality</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/vmotion-practicality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/vmotion-practicality/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago I posted an article titled The vMotion Reality. In that article, I challenged the assertion that vMotion was a myth, not widely implemented in data centers today due to networking complexity and networking limitations.
In a recent comment to that article, a reader again mentions networking limitations&amp;mdash;in this instance, the realistic limits of a large Layer 2 broadcast domain&amp;mdash;as a gating factor for vMotion and limiting its &amp;ldquo;practical use&amp;rdquo; in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vMotion Reality</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/13/the-vmotion-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 19:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/06/13/the-vmotion-reality/</guid>
      <description>The quite popular GigaOm site recently published an article titled &amp;ldquo;The VMotion Myth&amp;rdquo;, in which the author, Alex Benik, debunks the myth of vMotion and the live migration of virtual machines (VMs).
In his article, Benik states that the ability to dynamically move workloads around inside a single data center or between two data centers is, in his words, &amp;ldquo;far from an operational reality today&amp;rdquo;. While I&amp;rsquo;ll grant you that inter-data center vMotion isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm, vMotion within a data center is very much an operational reality of today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xeon 5500 CPUs and EVC in vSphere</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/xeon-5500-cpus-and-evc-in-vsphere/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 10:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/xeon-5500-cpus-and-evc-in-vsphere/</guid>
      <description>In early April when I traveled to Houston to meet with HP about the ProLiant G6 servers&amp;mdash;a trip which resulted in this blog post&amp;mdash;I got into a discussion with representatives from HP and Intel regarding the Xeon 5500 CPUs and Enhanced VMotion Compatibility (EVC).
As you probably already know, EVC builds upon hardware extensions provided by AMD and Intel (AMD in the AMD-V extensions, Intel in FlexMigration) that allows a CPU to &amp;ldquo;alter&amp;rdquo; its personality or identification so as to allow live migration (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles on CPU Masking in VMware Environments</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/articles-on-cpu-masking-in-vmware-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 09:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/10/articles-on-cpu-masking-in-vmware-environments/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few years I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few articles on CPU masking within VMware environments. To make them easier to locate I wanted to bring them all together here. So, here are the links to these articles:
Sneaking Around VMotion Limitations
VMotion Compatibility
More on CPU Masking
Keep in mind that almost all forms of CPU masking are unsupported by VMware, so use this information at your own risk. However, in non-production environments that don&amp;rsquo;t support Enhanced VMotion Compatibility (EVC), this may be your only option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of Virtualization Short Takes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</guid>
      <description>My irregular &amp;ldquo;Virtualization Short Takes&amp;rdquo; series was put on hold some time ago after I started work on Mastering VMware vSphere 4. Now that work on the book is starting to wind down just a bit, I thought it would be a good time to try to resurrect the series. So, without further delay, welcome to the return of Virtualization Short Takes!
  Trigged by a series of blog posts by Arnim van Lieshout on VMware ESX memory management (Part 1, Part 2, and Part 3), Scott Herold decided to join the fray with this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Reboots with VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/23/random-reboots-with-vmware-esx-35-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 23:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/23/random-reboots-with-vmware-esx-35-update-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been communicating with a reader who is experiencing random reboots of virtual machines on his HA/DRS-enabled cluster running VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. At first, I thought his problem was related to the bug with VM failure monitoring that I discussed here, but upon further discussion the random reboots are continuing to occur even when VM failure monitoring is disabled. The only relief the reader has been able to find thus far has been to completely disable VMware HA on his cluster, which&amp;mdash;to be honest&amp;mdash;is a less than acceptable solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Got to be Kidding Me</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 14:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</guid>
      <description>Via jtroyer on Twitter, I learned of this post comparing Hyper-V and VMware ESX.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit that I&amp;rsquo;m a VMware fan, but as others in the virtualization industry know I also recognize that VMware is not a &amp;ldquo;one size fits all&amp;rdquo; solution. There are many places where other virtualization solutions, Hyper-V included, may be a better solution for the customer. It really all depends upon the customer&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s lots of good information flowing around the Internet, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming increasingly difficult to sort through all the useless stuff to find the valuable gems. Hopefully, some of the links that I have collected here will prove to be more useful than useless!
  I came across this VMware KB article titled &amp;ldquo;Dedicating specific NICs to portgroups while maintaining NIC teaming and failover for the vSwitch&amp;rdquo;. I was hoping it would shed new light on some NIC teaming functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
