<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMworld2010 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2010/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMworld2010 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 16:54:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmworld2010/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EMEA Spousetivities Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/01/vmworld-emea-spousetivities-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 16:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/10/01/vmworld-emea-spousetivities-update/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll make this one short and sweet. As many of you probably already know, my wife (Crystal) has been organizing spouse activities&amp;mdash;now affectionately called &amp;ldquo;Spousetivities&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;for VMware-related conferences for a few years now. This year, she&amp;rsquo;s extending Spousetivities to VMworld EMEA in Copenhagen, Denmark.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t visited Crystal&amp;rsquo;s web site to get the latest information on Spousetivities and the schedule of activities for Copenhagen, you really should. Her latest update is available here and has full information on the activities that are scheduled, the costs, and the locations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2010 General Session, Day 4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/02/vmworld-2010-general-session-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 11:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/02/vmworld-2010-general-session-day-4/</guid>
      <description>The VMworld 2010 general session on Thursday, September 2, gets kicked off by pictures of the party last night and opening remarks by Rick Jackson around innovation and the definition of innovation. It was nice to see VMware &amp;ldquo;tip their hat&amp;rdquo; to IBM for the creation of virtualization.
The first guest speaker to come up and discuss innovation is Pranav Mistry, who spends some time discussing some of the various next-generation interfaces that he&amp;rsquo;s created and worked with&amp;mdash;things like a virtual mouse, a pen that allows designers to draw on the screen, or a paper interface to computing devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DV7706: View Composer Technical Deep Dive and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/dv7706-view-composer-technical-deep-dive-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 18:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/dv7706-view-composer-technical-deep-dive-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of VMworld 2010 session DV7706, titled &amp;ldquo;View Composer Technical Deep Dive and Best Practices,&amp;rdquo; in Moscone West 2004. The presenter(s) are Jeff Whitman and Jim Yanik, both with VMware.
We start out the session with a quick review of some limitations. View Composer has a limit of eight ESX/ESXi hosts in a cluster. This is a VMFS limit involving the number of hosts that are accessing a read-only file at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2010 Keynote, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/vmworld-2010-keynote-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 10:53:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/31/vmworld-2010-keynote-day-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to liveblog the VMworld 2010 keynote this morning. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to keep up with the pace, and hopefully the site won&amp;rsquo;t melt down from additional traffic. Check back regularly and I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post as the keynote progresses.
As usual, the general session is opening with a video. This time, it&amp;rsquo;s a mock documentary discussing &amp;ldquo;What is the cloud?&amp;rdquo; The video compares &amp;ldquo;cloud computing&amp;rdquo; to pizza.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld Announcements, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/vmworld-announcements-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 20:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/vmworld-announcements-day-1/</guid>
      <description>A flurry of virtualization-related product announcements flew into my Inbox today, thoroughly disrupting the empty Inbox I&amp;rsquo;d cultivated before the show. Anyway, I thought readers might be interested in some of the announcements, so here they are:
  Akorri announced they&amp;rsquo;ve achieved VMware Ready status with their BalancePoint product. If you&amp;rsquo;re at VMworld and want to talk to Akorri, stop by booth 1331.
  Similarly, Avere Systems has also been awarded VMware Ready status for its FXT 2700 appliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TA8037: vApps, OVF, and Advanced VM Templates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/ta8037-vapps-ovf-and-advanced-vm-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 16:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/30/ta8037-vapps-ovf-and-advanced-vm-templates/</guid>
      <description>I managed to score a seat in the vApps/OVF/Advanced VM Templates session. Unfortunately, I arrived late, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know the presenter&amp;rsquo;s names (apparently the location of the session was changed from the time I put it on my calendar to today).
The OVF XML descriptor file contains package meta-data and has 10 core sections for describing virtual hardware, EULA, product information, upgrade instructions, etc. The actual software in an OVF is installed in one more more virtual disks, and any public specified virtual disk format is supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Pre-VMworld Product Announcements</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/24/some-pre-vmworld-product-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2010 10:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/24/some-pre-vmworld-product-announcements/</guid>
      <description>There were several new product announcements that hit the wire today. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to go in-depth on any of these, but I did want to point them out very briefly. If time permits, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to provide a bit more detail in the near future.
  VKernel today announced their new Capacity Management Suite 2.0, which is a bundling of existing VKernel products along with new integration points between the products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld 2010 Spouse Activities Calendar</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/22/vmworld-2010-spouse-activities-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 11:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/22/vmworld-2010-spouse-activities-calendar/</guid>
      <description>As many of you already know, this year is the third year that my wife, Crystal, is planning activities for spouses (i.e., &amp;ldquo;spousetivites&amp;rdquo;) who are in San Francisco with their VMworld-attending significant others. Crystal has even launched her own site, Spousetivities.com, where you can find more information as well.
While this information is already available on Crystal&amp;rsquo;s site, in an effort to help promote awareness of some of the stuff that Crystal has put together I&amp;rsquo;m posting a calendar (of sorts) here that lists all the activities that are available for non-attending spouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My VMworld 2010 Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/13/my-vmworld-2010-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2010 11:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/13/my-vmworld-2010-schedule/</guid>
      <description>This morning I finalized my VMworld 2010 schedule and I wanted to share it here. Here are the sessions for which I&amp;rsquo;m currently registered:
Monday, August 30, 2010 9:00AM: TA8631 - Future Direction of Networking Virtualization
10:30AM: TA6720 - Troubleshooting Using ESXTOP for Advanced Users
12:00PM: SE7813 - vShield Edge and Application Protection: Architecture and Use Cases
1:30PM: TA8037 - vApps, OVF, and Advanced VM Templates in vSphere
3:00PM: TA8245 - ESXi Internals: Better Understanding for Better Management and Troubleshooting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spouse Activities Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/05/spouse-activities-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 10:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/08/05/spouse-activities-update/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a guest post by my wife, Crystal, who is organizing spouse activities for VMworld. This is the third consecutive year for VMworld spouse activities and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to help support her efforts.)
VMworld 2010 in San Francisco, CA, is right around the corner! I&amp;rsquo;m excited about the activities planned for VMworld this year and I wanted to give you a quick update on activities planning and deadlines. Make a note of these deadlines&amp;mdash;you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spouse Activities: Back for Another Year!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/spouse-activities-back-for-another-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/07/12/spouse-activities-back-for-another-year/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever attended a technology conference and had your spouse go with you? More than likely, your spouse just sat around the hotel room, bored, waiting for you to get back after a long day of sessions and lectures and labs. Then, when you&amp;rsquo;re tired and just want to relax, your spouse wants to go out on the town, explore, and see some cool stuff. Does that sound familiar?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
