<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IE on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 23:25:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ie/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Office and IE Under Fire (Again)</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/28/office-and-ie-under-fire-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 23:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/28/office-and-ie-under-fire-again/</guid>
      <description>News of the unpatched PowerPoint vulnerability (via eWeek) comes after a summer-long struggle to contain vulnerabilities in Microsoft Office, the office suite that maintains a venerable monopoly in the market. As with previous PowerPoint exploits, this one uses a rigged PowerPoint file to install a backdoor application. I found some additional information available from Symantec; read that here.
Similarly, another exploit has surfaced for Internet Explorer. This exploit takes advantage of a flaw that was supposedly brought to Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s attention back in July and apparently still remains unpatched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More on the IE VML Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/21/more-on-the-ie-vml-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2006 12:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/21/more-on-the-ie-vml-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Taken from this Dark Reading article, here are a few ways to protect yourself from the VML vulnerability:
  Unregister the VML DLL (VGX.DLL, found in Program Files\Common Files\Microsoft Shared) using regsvr32.exe.
  Apply a restrictive access control list (ACL) to the VGX.DLL file. This weblog entry shows how to help automate this using Group Policy for larger organizations (very handy!).
  Disable &amp;ldquo;Binary and Script Behaviors&amp;rdquo; in Internet Explorer 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Zero-Day IE Exploits</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/19/new-zero-day-ie-exploits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2006 10:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/09/19/new-zero-day-ie-exploits/</guid>
      <description>First up was this alert from eWeek that exploit code had been posted for a previously unknown code execution hole in Internet Explorer. This article came on September 14, about 5 days ago.
On that same day Microsoft published this security bulletin, which describes an issue with the DirectAnimation Path ActiveX control. Although it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately apparent whether this security bulletin is related to the exploit code described in the eWeek article, a review of the CVE listing provides enough information to believe that the exploit described by eWeek does, in fact, use the vulnerability described by Microsoft in their security bulletin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IE Flaws</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/02/new-ie-flaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 23:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/07/02/new-ie-flaws/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the announcement of a new &amp;ldquo;trojan horse&amp;rdquo; for Mac OS X, a couple new flaws were uncovered and disclosed for Internet Explorer in the last few days as well.
According to eWeek, a security researcher has uncovered two new flaws for Internet Explorer. I have not been able to locate any additional details on the more critical of the two flaws, but the lesser flaw has a Secunia advisory posted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even Microsoft Knows It</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/04/even-microsoft-knows-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 16:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/04/04/even-microsoft-knows-it/</guid>
      <description>I hope Microsoft Vista is going to address the malware problem that is plaguing Windows users worldwide right now. Even Microsoft knows it&amp;rsquo;s bad. How bad? Read on.
In this article from eWeek, Mike Danseglio, a program manager in the Security Solutions group at Microsoft, is quoted as saying:
 &amp;ldquo;When you are dealing with rootkits and some advanced spyware programs, the only solution is to rebuild from scratch. In some cases, there really is no way to recover without nuking the systems from orbit&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch Out, IE Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 17:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</guid>
      <description>A couple of articles are highlighting a recently uncovered security flaw in Microsoft Internet Explorer&amp;mdash;this article from eWeek and this article from ComputerWorld, both of which reference this security advisory from Microsoft.
The fix is to set the Security Level for the Internet Zone to High, which disables the functionality required for the exploit to work. Unfortunately, it also disables a lot of other things that non-malicious sites use, so this workaround will affect your ordinary browsing experience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
