<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaboration on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaboration on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/collaboration/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: July 2017 Progress Report</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/10/linux-migration-july-2017-progress-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/10/linux-migration-july-2017-progress-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now roughly six months into using Linux as my primary laptop OS, and it&amp;rsquo;s been a few months since &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/12/linux-migration-april-2017-progress-report/&#34;&gt;my last progress report&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re just now picking up this thread, I encourage you to go back and read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/16/linux-migration-initial-progress-report/&#34;&gt;my initial progress report&lt;/a&gt;, see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/01/linux-migration-final-distro-selection/&#34;&gt;which Linux distribution&lt;/a&gt; I selected, or check how I chose to handle corporate collaboration (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share where things currently stand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</guid>
      <description>In discussing support for corporate communication and collaboration systems as part of my Linux migration, I&amp;rsquo;ve so far covered e-mail in part 1 and calendaring in part 2. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the last few remaining aspects of corporate collaboration: instant messaging/chat, meetings and teleconferences, and document sharing.
Teleconferences and meetings The topic of teleconferences and meetings is closely related to calendaring&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to access your calendar or others&amp;rsquo; calendars when coordinating meetings or teleconferences&amp;mdash;so I encourage you to read part 2 to get a better feel for the challenges around calendaring/scheduling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 in a series of posts describing how I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated my Fedora Linux laptop into my employer&amp;rsquo;s corporate communication and collaboration systems. Part 1 tackled e-mail; this post tackles the topic of calendaring and scheduling. Unlike e-mail, which was solved relatively easily, this issue is one that I don&amp;rsquo;t consider fully solved.
As I mentioned in part 1, my employer uses Office 365 (O365). While O365 supports standard protocols like IMAP and STMP for mail, it does not support standard protocols like CalDAV for calendaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Other Users&#39; Stories, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts sharing other users&amp;rsquo; stories about their migration to Linux as their primary desktop OS. As I mentioned in part 1 of the series, there seemed to be quite a bit of pent-up interest in using Linux as your primary desktop OS. I thought it might be helpful to readers to hear not just about my migration, but also about others&amp;rsquo; migrations. You may also find it interesting/helpful to read part 2 and part 3 of this series for more migration stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</guid>
      <description>One major aspect of my migration to Linux as my primary desktop OS is how well it integrates with corporate communication and collaboration systems. Based on the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten from others on Twitter, this is a major concern for a lot of folks out there. In fact, a number of folks have indicated that this is the only thing keeping them from migrating to Linux. There are a number of different aspects to &amp;ldquo;corporate communication and collaboration,&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m breaking this down into multiple posts (each post will discuss one particular aspect).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring the Rockstar: A Counterpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re a rockstar!&amp;rdquo; Chances are, you&amp;rsquo;ve either a) been told this as a compliment for some work you&amp;rsquo;d done; b) heard this told to someone else for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done; or c) told someone this for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done. If you said this to someone else&amp;mdash;I just told someone this quite recently&amp;mdash;chances are also very likely that you had nothing but positive intentions behind this statement and your goal was to compliment them on what you saw as outstanding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Comments Aren&#39;t Available Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 09:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</guid>
      <description>A number of readers have asked&amp;mdash;via e-mail, of course, given the subject of this post&amp;mdash;why comments aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet on the new site. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a quick moment to explain the current situation.
First and foremost, it&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t want feedback from readers. I would love to continue to have the outstanding feedback from readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the last 9 years of this site. It&amp;rsquo;s also not because it&amp;rsquo;s too much trouble (too much comment spam, too much time to moderate, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Fork-and-Branch Git Workflow</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/27/using-fork-branch-git-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/27/using-fork-branch-git-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve provided you with an introduction to Git and a brief overview of using Git with GitHub, it&amp;rsquo;s time to build on that knowledge by taking a closer look at one workflow often used when collaborating with Git. The &amp;ldquo;fork and branch&amp;rdquo; workflow is a common way of collaborating on open source projects using Git and GitHub. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to walk through this workflow (as I understand it&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m constantly learning), with a focus toward helping those that are new to this sort of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Git with GitHub</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/26/using-git-with-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/26/using-git-with-github/</guid>
      <description>Building on my earlier non-programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to Git, I wanted to talk a little bit about using Git with GitHub, a very popular service for hosting Git repositories. This post, in conjunction with the earlier introductory post on Git, will serve as the basis for a future post that talks about how to use Git and GitHub to collaborate with others on an open source project hosted on GitHub.
If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Git and haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the earlier introductory post, I strongly recommend reading that post first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Non-Programmer&#39;s Introduction to Git</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/14/non-programmer-git-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/14/non-programmer-git-intro/</guid>
      <description>Git is a distributed version control system that is widely used by a number of open source projects. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide a quick non-programmer&amp;rsquo;s introduction to Git, and encourage readers to spend some time getting familiar with Git. I think it is a time investment that will pay off down the road.
First, I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide some definitions/brief explanations in order to establish a foundation upon which you can build your Git knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up the Tools for Contributing to OpenStack Documentation</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/11/06/setting-up-the-tools-for-contributing-to-openstack-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 09:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/11/06/setting-up-the-tools-for-contributing-to-openstack-documentation/</guid>
      <description>For non-programmers, making a meaningful contribution to an open source project can be difficult; this is as true for OpenStack as for other open source projects. Documentation is a way to contribute, but in the case of OpenStack there is a non-trivial setup required in order to be able to contribute to the OpenStack documentation. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share how to set up the tools to contribute to OpenStack documentation in the hopes that it will help others get past the &amp;ldquo;barrier to entry&amp;rdquo; that currently exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Closing Comments on Old Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/23/closing-comments-on-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 17:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/23/closing-comments-on-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about this site is the interaction I enjoy with readers. It&amp;rsquo;s always great to get comments from readers about how an article was informative, answered a question, or helped solve a problem. Knowing that what I&amp;rsquo;ve written here is helpful to others is a very large part of why I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing here for over 9 years.
Until today, I&amp;rsquo;ve left comments (and sometimes trackbacks) open on very old blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStack Architecture and Design Book Sprint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/13/openstack-architecture-and-design-book-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 11:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/06/13/openstack-architecture-and-design-book-sprint/</guid>
      <description>In just a few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll be participating in a book sprint to create a book that provides architecture and design guidance for building OpenStack-based clouds. For those of you who aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with the idea of a book sprint, it&amp;rsquo;s been described to me like this:
  Take a group of people&amp;mdash;a mix of technical experts and experienced writers&amp;mdash;and lock them in a room.
  Don&amp;rsquo;t let them out until they&amp;rsquo;ve written a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with Jesse Proudman</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to conduct an e-mail interview with Jesse Proudman, founder and CEO of Blue Box. The interview is posted below. While it gets a bit biased toward Blue Box at times (he started the company, after all), there are some interesting points raised.
[Scott Lowe] Tell the readers here a little bit about yourself and Blue Box.
[Jesse Proudman] My name is Jesse Proudman. I love the Internet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;plumbing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Man is an Island</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/12/no-man-is-an-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 09:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/12/no-man-is-an-island/</guid>
      <description>The phrase &amp;ldquo;No man is an island&amp;rdquo; is attributed to John Donne, an English poet who lived in the late 1500s and early 1600s. The phrase comes from his Meditation XVII, and was borrowed later by Thomas Merton to become the title of a book he published in 1955. In both cases, the phrase is used to discuss the interconnected nature of humanity and mankind. (Side note: the phrase &amp;ldquo;for whom the bell tolls&amp;rdquo; comes from the same origin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
