<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/interview/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with Jesse Proudman</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to conduct an e-mail interview with Jesse Proudman, founder and CEO of Blue Box. The interview is posted below. While it gets a bit biased toward Blue Box at times (he started the company, after all), there are some interesting points raised.
[Scott Lowe] Tell the readers here a little bit about yourself and Blue Box.
[Jesse Proudman] My name is Jesse Proudman. I love the Internet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;plumbing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Virtualization Interview with Eric Hanselman of Leostream</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/27/desktop-virtualization-interview-with-eric-hanselman-of-leostream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2009 19:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/27/desktop-virtualization-interview-with-eric-hanselman-of-leostream/</guid>
      <description>Continuing on in our series of executive interviews, next up we have Eric Hanselman, Director of Professional and Technical Services for Leostream. Eric and I discussed the current state of desktop virtualization and what may be keeping organizations from fully adopting desktop virtualization.
The Interview Scott Lowe (SL): Experts and analysts have been predicting for the last couple of years &amp;ldquo;this year is the year of desktop virtualization.&amp;rdquo; Do you think is true for 2009?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Interview with Dave Malcolm, CTO of Surgient</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/09/cloud-computing-interview-with-dave-malcom-cto-of-surgient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 18:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/09/cloud-computing-interview-with-dave-malcom-cto-of-surgient/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the pleasure of conducting an e-mail interview with Surgient&amp;rsquo;s Chief Technology Officer, Dave Malcolm. I&amp;rsquo;ve reprinted the question and answer session here. Enjoy!
The Interview Scott Lowe (SL): The term &amp;ldquo;cloud computing&amp;rdquo; is used in a variety of different ways to describe a variety of different things. How would you define cloud computing?
Dave Malcolm (DM): I believe cloud computing is defined as a pool of abstracted, highly scalable, and managed computing infrastructure capable of running end customer applications and is billed or charged by consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Interview Posted</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/06/virtualization-interview-posted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 09:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/08/06/virtualization-interview-posted/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the honor of participating in an e-mail interview with OdinJobs regarding virtualization and how to &amp;ldquo;break into&amp;rdquo; the virtualization industry. My fellow cohorts in this e-mail interview were Bob Plankers and Martin MacLeod. The interview questions focused on things like the best way for a sysadmin to get started with virtualization, what skills may be vendor-specific or not, and where virtualization may be headed. It was pretty interesting to participate, and it&amp;rsquo;s even more interesting to see how Bob and Martin responded to the questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
