<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fedora on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fedora/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fedora on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/fedora/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 138</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 09:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/03/12/technology-short-take-138/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #138. I have what I hope is an interesting and useful set of links to share with everyone this time around. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do so well on storage links; apologies to my storage-focused friends! However, there should be something for most everyone else. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 133</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/06/technology-short-take-133/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/11/06/technology-short-take-133/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #133! This time around, I have a collection of links featuring the new Raspberry Pi 400, some macOS security-related articles, information on AWS Nitro Enclaves and gVisor, and a few other topics. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 130</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/08/21/technology-short-take-130/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #130! I&amp;rsquo;ve had this blog post sitting in my Drafts folder waiting to be published for almost a month, and I kept forgetting to actually make it live. Sorry! So, here it is&amp;mdash;better late than never, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixes for Some Vagrant Issues on Fedora</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/23/fixes-for-some-vagrant-issues-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 01:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/23/fixes-for-some-vagrant-issues-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I needed to perform some testing of an updated version of some software that I use. (I was conducting the testing because this upgrade contained some breaking changes, and needed to understand how to mitigate the breaking changes.) So, I broke out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vagrantup.com/&#34;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt; (with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vagrant-libvirt/vagrant-libvirt&#34;&gt;the Libvirt provider&lt;/a&gt;) on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; laptop&amp;mdash;and promptly ran into a couple issues. Fortunately, these issues were relatively easy to work around, but since the workarounds were non-intuitive I wanted to share them here for the benefit of others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Magic Mouse 2 and Magic Trackpad 2 on Fedora</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/08/review-magic-mouse-2-and-magic-trackpad-2-on-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 15:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/08/review-magic-mouse-2-and-magic-trackpad-2-on-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently purchased a new Apple Magic Mouse 2 and an Apple Magic Trackpad 2&amp;mdash;not to use with my MacBook Pro, but to use with my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;-powered laptop (a Lenovo 5th generation ThinkPad X1 Carbon; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/04/13/review-lenovo-thinkpad-x1-carbon/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;). I know it seems odd to buy Apple accessories for a non-Apple laptop, and in this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about why I bought these items as well as provide some (relatively early) feedback on how well they work with Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Jsonnet from Source</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/07/building-jsonnet-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/07/building-jsonnet-from-source/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided to start working with &lt;code&gt;jsonnet&lt;/code&gt;, a data templating language and associated command-line interface (CLI) tool for manipulating and/or generating various data formats (like JSON, YAML, or other formats; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://jsonnet.org/&#34;&gt;the Jsonnet web site&lt;/a&gt; for more information). However, I found that there are no prebuilt binaries for &lt;code&gt;jsonnet&lt;/code&gt; (at least, not that I could find), and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share here the process for building &lt;code&gt;jsonnet&lt;/code&gt; from source. It&amp;rsquo;s not hard or complicated, but hopefully sharing this information will streamline the process for others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Preparing for the Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/11/linux-migration-preparing-for-the-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/11/linux-migration-preparing-for-the-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As far back as 2012, I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/why-i-might-leave-os-x/&#34;&gt;already thinking&lt;/a&gt; about migrating away from Mac OS X (now known as macOS). While the migration didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/16/linux-migration-initial-progress-report/&#34;&gt;start in earnest until late 2016&lt;/a&gt;, a fair amount of work happened in advance of the migration. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of folks ask me about migrating to Linux, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d supplement &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/&#34;&gt;my Linux migration series&lt;/a&gt; with a &amp;ldquo;prequel&amp;rdquo; about some of the work that happened to prepare for the migration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 109</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/01/11/technology-short-take-109/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #109! This is the first Technology Short Take of 2019. It may be confirmation bias, but I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed of number of sites adding &amp;ldquo;Short Take&amp;rdquo;-type posts to their content lineup. I&amp;rsquo;ll take that as flattery, even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily intended that way. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: December 2018 Progress Report</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2016, I kicked off a migration from macOS to Linux as my primary laptop OS. Throughout 2017, I chronicled my progress and challenges along the way; links to all those posts are found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although I stopped the migration in August 2017, I restarted it in April 2018 when I left VMware to join Heptio. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to recap where things stand as of December 2018, after 8 months of full-time use of Linux as my primary laptop OS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration Series</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early 2017 I kicked off an effort to start using Linux as my primary desktop OS, and I blogged about the journey. That particular effort ended in late October 2017. I restarted the migration in April 2018 (when I left VMware to join Heptio), and since that time I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, specifically) full-time. However, I thought it might be helpful to collect the articles I wrote about the experience together for easy reference. Without further ado, here they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Fedora on my Mac Pro</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/19/running-fedora-on-my-mac-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/19/running-fedora-on-my-mac-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on migrating off macOS for a couple of years (10+ years on a single OS isn&amp;rsquo;t undone quickly or easily). I won&amp;rsquo;t go into all the gory details here; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/why-i-might-leave-os-x/&#34;&gt;this post for some background&lt;/a&gt; and then see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/25/linux-migration-wrap-up/&#34;&gt;this update from last October&lt;/a&gt; that summarized my previous efforts to migrate to Linux (&lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;, specifically) as my primary desktop operating system. (What I &lt;em&gt;haven&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; blogged about is the success I had switching to Fedora full-time when I joined Heptio.) I took another big step forward in my efforts this past week, when I rebuilt my 2011-era Mac Pro workstation to run Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercharging my CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/29/supercharging-my-cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/29/supercharging-my-cli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time in the terminal. I can&amp;rsquo;t really explain why; for many things it just feels faster and more comfortable to do them via the command line interface (CLI) instead of via a graphical point-and-click interface. (I&amp;rsquo;m not totally against GUIs, for some tasks they&amp;rsquo;re far easier.) As a result, when I find tools that make my CLI experience faster/easier/more powerful, that&amp;rsquo;s a big boon. Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve added some tools to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; laptop that have really added some power and flexibility to my CLI environment. In this post, I want to share some details on these tools and how I&amp;rsquo;m using them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 106</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #106! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while (over a month) since the last Tech Short Take, as this one kept getting pushed back. Sorry about that, folks! Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to find useful and helpful links to include below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 105</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/05/technology-short-take-105/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/05/technology-short-take-105/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #105! Here&amp;rsquo;s another collection of articles and blog posts about some of the common technologies that modern IT professionals will typically encounter. I hope that something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here proves to be useful for you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Markdown-to-PDF Workflow on Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/27/a-markdown-to-pdf-workflow-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/27/a-markdown-to-pdf-workflow-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In May of last year I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/08/using-makefile-with-markdown-documents/&#34;&gt;using a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; with Markdown documents&lt;/a&gt;, in which I described how I use &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; along with CLI tools like &lt;code&gt;multimarkdown&lt;/code&gt; (the binary, not the format) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandoc.org/&#34;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I&amp;rsquo;d figured out how to use combinations of the various CLI tools to create various formats from the source &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; document. The one format I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten right at that time was PDF. Pandoc &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; create PDFs, but only if &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.latex-project.org/&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; is installed. This article describes a method I found that allows me to create PDFs from my Markdown documents &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; using LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
