<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Snapshots on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/snapshots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Snapshots on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 22:19:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/snapshots/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanbolic Brings Snapshots to Melio FS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/sanbolic-brings-snapshots-to-melio-fs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 22:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/05/05/sanbolic-brings-snapshots-to-melio-fs/</guid>
      <description>Sanbolic is continuing to differentiate its clustered file system, Melio FS, in advance of the rudimentary clustered file system Microsoft plans on introducing in Windows Server 2008 R2. In an announcement last week, Sanbolic announced support for fully journaled snapshots. This functionality allows any server accessing the clustered file system to invoke a snapshot. The new snapshot functionality provides support for VSS and &amp;ldquo;full industry standard APIs,&amp;rdquo; although I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what those &amp;ldquo;full industry standard APIs&amp;rdquo; are exactly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2031: Enhancements to NetApp Cloning Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2008 15:43:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/03/2031-enhancements-to-netapp-cloning-technology/</guid>
      <description>This session provided information on enhancements to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s cloning functionality. These enhancements are due to be released along with Data ONTAP 7.3.1, which is expected out in December. Of course, that date may shift, but that&amp;rsquo;s the expected release timeframe.
The key focus of the session was new functionality that allows for Data ONTAP to clone individual files without a backing Snapshot. This new functionality is an extension of NetApp&amp;rsquo;s deduplication functionality, and is enabled by changes within Data ONTAP that enable block sharing, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/02/storage-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Last week I provided a list of virtualization-related items that had made their way into my Inbox in some form or another; today I&amp;rsquo;ll share storage-related items with you in Storage Short Take #4! This post will also be cross-published to the Storage Monkeys Blogs.
  Stephen Foskett has a nice round-up of some of the storage-related changes available to users in VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. Of particular note to many users is the VMDK Recovery Tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Releases Update 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/vmware-releases-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/vmware-releases-update-2/</guid>
      <description>VMware has released Update 2 for VMware Infrastructure 3 version 3.5, which includes updates to VMware ESX, VMware ESXi, VirtualCenter, and VMware Consolidated Backup (VCB). Check the Release Notes for the full details; I won&amp;rsquo;t reproduce them here, but instead I&amp;rsquo;ll just point out the particularly interesting details.
Also reporting this information (at the time of this writing) are David from VMblog.com, Rich from VM /ETC, and Duncan at Yellow Bricks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Array Snapshots with VMware</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/04/storage-array-snapshots-with-vmware/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 21:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/04/storage-array-snapshots-with-vmware/</guid>
      <description>A new article of mine has been published on SearchVMware.com! This article discusses the use of storage array snapshots with VMware, specifically focusing on ensuring that storage array snapshots are consistent and usable:
 When used in conjunction with a VMware infrastructure, storage array-based snapshots are touted for their ability to create point-in-time pictures of virtual machines (VMs) for business continuity, disaster recovery and backups. While this can be true, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand how virtualization affects storage array snapshot use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp OSSV with VMware ESX Server</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/29/netapp-ossv-with-vmware-esx-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2008 16:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/29/netapp-ossv-with-vmware-esx-server/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago my good friend Nick Triantos&amp;mdash;formerly of Storage Foo fame, now writing at the Storage Nuts &amp;amp; Bolts Blog&amp;ndash;published a short piece of a new version of Open Systems SnapVault (OSSV) that offers new functionality when used with VMware Infrastructure 3 (VI3).
For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with OSSV, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a way to bring NetApp-style snapshots to non-NetApp storage. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty common to use OSSV to take snapshots of a server that is not attached to a NetApp SAN and store those snapshots on a NetApp SAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #8</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/26/virtualization-short-take-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2008 15:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/05/26/virtualization-short-take-8/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time again, friends, time for another Virtualization Short Take!
  OpenSolaris on Fusion: As expected, Solaris/OpenSolaris fans are experimenting with OpenSolaris on Fusion. Apparently, it runs rather well.
  Brian Madden had an interesting thought about Thinstall (now ThinApp) plus WINE to eliminate Windows. In the end, Brian feels like many companies will just want to deal with the larger vendors, and won&amp;rsquo;t be willing to support this kind of &amp;ldquo;cobbled together&amp;rdquo; solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Thin VMDKs Using NetApp SnapRestore</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/09/keeping-thin-vmdks-using-netapp-snaprestore/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 15:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/09/keeping-thin-vmdks-using-netapp-snaprestore/</guid>
      <description>A short while ago, I discussed that VMDKs on NFS may start out thin provisioned, but will lose that thin provisioned status over time. Operations like cloning and Storage VMotion will cause these thin provisioned disks to become thick (fully provisioned) disks, and you lose one of the benefits of running VMware on NFS.
Fortunately, if you&amp;rsquo;re running a NetApp storage system as your NFS server, you can preserve the thin provisioned status of these VMDKs by leveraging NetApp&amp;rsquo;s single file SnapRestore functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetApp Snapshot Support</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/01/netapp-snapshot-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 21:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/01/netapp-snapshot-support/</guid>
      <description>For readers that didn&amp;rsquo;t already know this, Snapshots on NetApp-hosted CIFS shares are automatically and transparently recognized by Windows versions that support the &amp;ldquo;Previous Versions&amp;rdquo; tab. I believe this functionality is native on Windows Server 2003 and an add-on for Windows XP, but I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% certain. Either way, this means that users can easily recover files from NetApp Snapshots from within the Windows GUI.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a screenshot of the Previous Versions support on an out-of-the-box server running Windows Server 2003 R2:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/14/virtualization-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 09:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/03/14/virtualization-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Once again, here&amp;rsquo;s my take a few virtualization-related stories that have passed through my computer in the last few days:
  OK, this first one isn&amp;rsquo;t technically related to virtualization, but it was too good to pass up. Is there anyone besides me and The Register who thinks NetApp&amp;rsquo;s new logo is&amp;hellip;um&amp;hellip;well, not as good as the previous one?
  A new blog war is brewing between VMware and Citrix, and this time I had nothing to do with it: VMware apparently launched the first volley in discussing the value of ESX Server&amp;rsquo;s memory overcommitment and page sharing functionality; Citrix&amp;rsquo;s Roger Klorese then responded and Simon Crosby chimed in as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Virtualization Links</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/20/recent-virtualization-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2008 21:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/01/20/recent-virtualization-links/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting various virtualization-related links in NetNewsWire&amp;rsquo;s Flagged Items collection, with the intention of blogging about them, bookmarking them, or both. With time a bit short recently&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s just say that life is really, really busy right now&amp;mdash;I decided to just condense a bunch of them here with a brief commentary, where applicable, for each. Hopefully some of this information will prove useful to some readers here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing LUN Space Requirements with NetApp Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2007 23:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/12/05/managing-lun-space-requirements-with-netapp-storage/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked with Network Appliance storage before, you&amp;rsquo;re probably already familiar with the idea of snap reserve (storage space set aside to accommodate for Snapshots) and fractional reserve (used with LUNs). I&amp;rsquo;m going to hold the in-depth discussion of why you need snap reserve and fractional reserve for a different day, but I did want to pass on these commands that were shared with me by a colleague of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VM File-Level Recovery with NetApp Snapshots</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/vm-file-level-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 16:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/10/08/vm-file-level-recovery-with-netapp-snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Last year, I wrote an article about using NetApp Snapshots and LUN clones to enable the recovery on individual files within a VM. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;d like to have a quick at that same process, but this time using NFS instead of block-level storage.
As I mentioned a couple of weeks ago, NFS is getting more and more attention as a key storage enabler for Virtual Infrastructure implementations. I do still plan to conduct some tests of my own between iSCSI and NFS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nifty NFS-VMware Trick</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/27/nifty-nfs-vmware-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 23:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/27/nifty-nfs-vmware-trick/</guid>
      <description>I can take absolutely zero credit for this idea; it came completely from this aticle by Nick Triantos. But the trick is so absolutely cool, so incredibly useful, and yet so obvious (once you read it, you&amp;rsquo;ll smack yourself in the head and say, &amp;ldquo;Why didn&amp;rsquo;t I think of that?&amp;rdquo;) that I just had to say something about it.
The use of NFS is getting more and more attention (I blogged about it briefly a few days ago) as a primary storage technology for VMware deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LUN Clones vs. FlexClones</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/05/21/lun-clones-vs-flexclones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 12:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/05/21/lun-clones-vs-flexclones/</guid>
      <description>My recent article on how to provision VMs using FlexClones prompted a reader to ask the question, &amp;ldquo;What about using LUN clones?&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s an excellent question, and one that I myself asked when I first started using some of the advanced functionality of Network Appliance storage systems. I had expected that this question would come up, and so I&amp;rsquo;d already begun preparing an article discussing LUN clones vs. FlexClones. My thanks go to Aaron for prompting the discussion!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
