<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OVN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ovn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OVN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/ovn/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 91</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/08/technology-short-take-91/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/08/technology-short-take-91/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 91! It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit longer than usual since the last Tech Short Take (partly due to the US Thanksgiving holiday, partly due to vacation time, and partly due to business travel), so apologies for that. Still, there&amp;rsquo;s a great collection of links and articles here for you, so dig in and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 89</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/27/technology-short-take-89/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 89! I have a collection of newer materials and some older materials this time around, but hopefully all of them are still useful. (I needed to do some housekeeping on my Instapaper account, which is where I bookmark stuff that frequently lands here.) Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 84</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #84! This episode is a bit late (sorry about that!), but I figured better late than never, right? OK, bring on the links!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open vSwitch Day at OpenStack Summit 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/10/ovs-day-openstack-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/05/10/ovs-day-openstack-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a &amp;ldquo;liveblog&amp;rdquo; (not quite live, but you get the idea) of the Open vSwitch Open Source Day happening at the OpenStack Summit in Boston. Summaries of each of the presentations are included below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #77</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/03/technology-short-take-77/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #77. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new collection of links and articles from around the Web on various data center-focused technologies.
Networking  Mark Brookfield takes a moment to remind everyone that you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use the (deprecated) C# vSphere Client to manage NSX environments. Good advice. Michael Kashin has a great article on how Open Virtual Network (OVN, part of the Open vSwitch project) implements virtual networks in OpenStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #75</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/30/technology-short-take-75/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #75, the final Technology Short Take for 2016. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not the final Technology Short Take ever, as I&amp;rsquo;ll be back in 2017 with more content. Until then, here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related articles and links for your enjoyment.
Networking  Ajay Chenampara has some observations about running Ansible at scale against network devices. Andrey Khomyakov shares some information on automating the setup of whitebox switches running Cumulus Linux in part 2 of this series on learning network automation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #74</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #74! The end of 2016 is nearly upon us, and it looks as if there will be only one more Technology Short Take before the end of the year. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with the content&amp;mdash;time is short!
Networking  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apstra, David Varnum has a great introduction to Apstra available on his site. Will Robinson talks about how to structure your Ansible playbooks in the context of using Ansible to control your network gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OVN with KVM and Libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/using-ovn-with-kvm-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how to use OVN (Open Virtual Network; part of the Open vSwitch project) with KVM and Libvirt to provide virtual networking for KVM-based virtual machines. This post will build on some concepts around OVS and Libvirt that I&amp;rsquo;ve discussed previously; be sure to review the OVS posts and Libvirt posts on this site for more details and prerequisite knowledge.
I&amp;rsquo;ll structure this discussion around 2 key steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Environments for OVN</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/07/learning-environments-ovn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/07/learning-environments-ovn/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve added two new Vagrant-based learning environments to my GitHub &amp;ldquo;learning-tools&amp;rdquo; repository, both of them focused on Open Virtual Network (OVN). OVN, if you aren&amp;rsquo;t aware, is part of the Open vSwitch (OVS) project aimed at adding open source network virtualization functionality to OVS. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about OVN, you may want to check out these new learning environments.
Here&amp;rsquo;s more details on the two new learning environments:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #73</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/18/technology-short-take-73/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #73. Sorry for the long delay since the last Technology Short Take; personal matters have been taking quite the toll (if you follow me on Twitter, you&amp;rsquo;ll know to what personal matters I&amp;rsquo;m referring). In any case, enough of that&amp;mdash;here&amp;rsquo;s some data center-related content that I hope you find useful!
Networking  Ansible has made some good progress in supporting network automation in the latest release (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #56</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/17/technology-short-take-56/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #56! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a few links on various data center technologies, news, events, and trends. I hope you find something useful here.
Networking  Open Virtual Network (OVN) is really ramping up and getting lots of attention, which I personally think is absolutely well-deserved. Russell Bryant has a couple great articles on OVN&amp;mdash;how to test OVN&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;EZ Bake&amp;rdquo; release with DevStack as well as an article on implementing OpenStack security groups using OVN ACLs (which in turn leverage the integration between Open vSwitch and the Linux kernel&amp;rsquo;s conntrack module).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #51</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/22/technology-short-take-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/22/technology-short-take-51/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #51, another collection of posts and links about key data center technologies like networking, virtualization, cloud management, and applications/operating systems. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful in this collection!
Networking  I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this falls here or into the &amp;ldquo;Cloud Computing/Cloud Computing&amp;rdquo; category, but Shannon McFarland&amp;mdash;fellow co-conspirator with the Denver OpenStack Meetup group&amp;mdash;has a nice article describing some design and deployment considerations for IPv6 in the OpenStack Kilo release.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
