<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DockerCon2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dockercon2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DockerCon2016 on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/dockercon2016/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon 2016 Day 2 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/21/dockercon-2016-day-2-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/21/dockercon-2016-day-2-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the day 2 keynote of DockerCon 2016, which wraps up today in Seattle, WA. While today&amp;rsquo;s pre-keynote warm-up doesn&amp;rsquo;t include laser-equipped kittens, the music is much more upbeat and energetic (as opposed to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s more somber, dramatic music). If the number of laptops on the podium is any indicator (yesterday it was a cue to the number of demos planned), then today&amp;rsquo;s keynote will include a few demos as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon 2016 Vendor Meetings</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/21/dockercon-2016-vendor-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/21/dockercon-2016-vendor-meetings/</guid>
      <description>While at DockerCon 2016 in Seattle today, I took some time on the expo floor to talk to a number of different vendors, mostly focused on networking solutions. Here are some notes from these discussions. I may follow up with additional posts on some of these technologies; it will largely depend on time and the ease by which the technologies/products may be consumed.
Plumgrid My first stop was the Plumgrid booth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon 2016 Day 1 Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/20/dockercon-2016-day-1-keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/06/20/dockercon-2016-day-1-keynote/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog for the day 1 keynote of DockerCon 2016, taking place over the next couple of days in Seattle, WA. Before the keynote starts in earnest, Gordon the Turtle entertains attendees with some &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; Docker containers that affect the display on the main stage: showing butterflies, playing sounds, launching a Docker-customized version of Pac-Man, or initiating a full-out battle of laser-shooting kittens.
The keynote starts with Ben Golub taking the stage to kick things off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at DockerCon 2016</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/31/spousetivities-dockercon2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/05/31/spousetivities-dockercon2016/</guid>
      <description>Long-time readers of my site know that my wife, Crystal, launched what is now known as Spousetivities at VMworld 2008. Since that time, she&amp;rsquo;s been able to organize activities for hundreds of companions at dozens of events around the world. This year she&amp;rsquo;s adding another event to the roster: DockerCon 2016 in Seattle!
That&amp;rsquo;s right, Crystal and Spousetivities will be available at DockerCon in Seattle. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick look at some of the things she&amp;rsquo;s got planned:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
