<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 10:45:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/news/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities in Barcelona at VMworld EMEA 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/10/20/spousetivities-in-barcelona-vmworld-emea-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 10:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/10/20/spousetivities-in-barcelona-vmworld-emea-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Barcelona is probably my favorite city in Europe&amp;mdash;which works out well, since VMware seems to have settled on Barcelona at the destination for VMworld EMEA. VMworld is back in Barcelona again this year, and I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to be able to attend. VMworld in Barcelona wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the same without Spousetivities, though, and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to report that Spousetivities &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be in Barcelona. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;https://spousetivities.ticketleap.com/spousetivities-barcelona-2019/&#34;&gt;registration is already open&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousevitivities at VMworld 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/17/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/17/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vmworld.com/&#34;&gt;VMworld&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;VMware&amp;rsquo;s annual user conference&amp;mdash;moves back to San Francisco from Las Vegas. Returning to the Bay Area with VMworld is &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt;, which is happening again this year for the &lt;strong&gt;11th year at VMworld&lt;/strong&gt;. Better get your tickets sooner rather than later, there&amp;rsquo;s quite a good chance these activities will sell out!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at Oktane 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/spousetivities-at-oktane-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/03/15/spousetivities-at-oktane-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It should come as no surprise to anyone that I&amp;rsquo;m a huge supporter of &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt;, and not just because it was my wife, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/crystal_lowe&#34;&gt;Crystal Lowe&lt;/a&gt;, who launched this movement. What started as the gathering of a few folks at VMworld 2008 has grown over the last 11 years, and this year marks the appearance of Spousetivities at an entirely new conference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.okta.com/oktane19/&#34;&gt;Oktane 2019&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at DockerCon EU 18</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/29/spousetivities-at-dockercon-eu-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/29/spousetivities-at-dockercon-eu-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://europe-2018.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;DockerCon EU 18&lt;/a&gt; is set to kick off in early December (December 3-5, to be precise!) in Barcelona, Spain. Thanks to Docker&amp;rsquo;s commitment to attendee families&amp;mdash;something for which I have and will continue to commend them&amp;mdash;DockerCon will offer both childcare (as they have in years past) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; spouse/partner activities via Spousetivities. Let me just say: Spousetivities in Barcelona rocks. Crystal lines up a great set of activities that really cannot be beat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMworld EMEA 2018 and Spousetivities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/01/vmworld-emea-2018-and-spousetivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/10/01/vmworld-emea-2018-and-spousetivities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spousetivities.ticketleap.com/spousetivities-barcelona-2018/&#34;&gt;Registration is now open&lt;/a&gt; for Spousetivities at VMworld EMEA 2108 in Barcelona! Crystal just opened registration in the last day or so, and I wanted to help get the message out about these activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousevitivities at VMworld 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/18/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/07/18/spousetivities-at-vmworld-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In case there was any question whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt; would be present at VMworld 2018, let this settle it for you: Spousetivities &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; be there! In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;https://spousetivities.ticketleap.com/spousetivities-lv2018/&#34;&gt;registration for Spousetivities at VMworld 2018 is already open&lt;/a&gt;. If previous years are any indication, there&amp;rsquo;s a really good possibility these activities will sell out. Better get your tickets sooner rather than later!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DockerCon SF 18 and Spousetivities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/16/dockercon-sf-18-and-spousetivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/16/dockercon-sf-18-and-spousetivities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://2018.dockercon.com/&#34;&gt;DockerCon SF 18&lt;/a&gt; is set to kick off in San Francisco at the Moscone Center from June 12 to June 15. This marks the return of DockerCon to San Francisco after being held in other venues for the last couple of years. Also returning to San Francisco is &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt;, which has organized activities for spouses, significant others/domestic partners, friends, and family members traveling with conference attendees!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Week Until Spousetivities in Vancouver</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/14/one-week-until-spousetivities-in-vancouver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/14/one-week-until-spousetivities-in-vancouver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only one week remains until &lt;a href=&#34;https://spousetivities.ticketleap.com/openstack-summit-vancouver/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt; kicks off in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openstack.org/summit/vancouver-2018/&#34;&gt;Vancouver at the OpenStack Summit&lt;/a&gt;! If you are traveling to the Summit with a spouse, significant other, family member, or friend, I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to take a look at the great activities Crystal has arranged during the Summit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop ITX, Dell Technologies World, and Spousetivities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/20/interop-dell-tech-world-and-spousetivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/20/interop-dell-tech-world-and-spousetivities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spousetivities will be present at two additional events this year&amp;mdash;in fact, these events are only about 6 weeks away! Both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.delltechnologiesworld.com/index.htm&#34;&gt;Dell Technologies World&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interop.com/&#34;&gt;Interop ITX&lt;/a&gt; are in Las Vegas the last week of April (both starting April 30), and Spousetivities is running events for both conferences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making AWS re:Invent More Family-Friendly</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/13/making-aws-reinvent-more-family-friendly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/13/making-aws-reinvent-more-family-friendly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reinvent.awsevents.com/&#34;&gt;AWS re:Invent&lt;/a&gt; is just around the corner, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt; will be there to help bring a new level of family friendliness to the event. If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking of bringing a spouse, partner, or significant other with you to Las Vegas, I&amp;rsquo;d encourage you to strongly consider getting him or her involved in Spousetivities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Spousetivities Events</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/28/upcoming-spousetivities-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/28/upcoming-spousetivities-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long-time readers/followers know that my wife, Crystal, runs a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt;. This program organizes events for spouses/partners/significant others at IT industry conferences. This fall is a particularly busy season for Crystal and Spousetivities, as she&amp;rsquo;ll be organizing events at DockerCon EU, the fall OpenStack Summit, and AWS re:Invent! Here are some details on these upcoming events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Years of Spousetivities</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/15/ten-years-of-spousetivities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/07/15/ten-years-of-spousetivities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away (OK, so it was 2008 and it was here in this galaxy&amp;mdash;on this very planet, in fact), I posted an article about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/06/spouses-at-vmworld/&#34;&gt;bringing your spouse to VMworld&lt;/a&gt;. That one post sparked a fire that, kindled by my wife&amp;rsquo;s passion and creativity, culminates this year in &lt;strong&gt;ten years of Spousetivities!&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spousetivities.com/&#34;&gt;Spousetivities&lt;/a&gt; is back at VMworld (both US and Europe) this year, and Crystal has some pretty nice events planned for this year&amp;rsquo;s participants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big News About the Full Stack Journey Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/26/big-news-full-stack-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/26/big-news-full-stack-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following the Full Stack Journey podcast, you know that the podcast has been silent for a few months. Some of that was due to some adverse situations in life (it happens to all of us from time to time), but some of it was due to the coordination of a major transition in the podcast. And that&amp;rsquo;s the big news I&amp;rsquo;m here to share&amp;mdash;read on for the full details!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at DockerCon 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/06/spousetivities-at-dockercon-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/02/06/spousetivities-at-dockercon-2017/</guid>
      <description>DockerCon 2017 is coming up in mid-April in Austin, TX, and Spousetivities will once again be offering activities for folks traveling to Austin with conference attendees. This is Spousetivities&amp;rsquo; second time at DockerCon, and Crystal has a great lineup of activities planned.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick preview of the activities organized for DockerCon:
 Trip to Magnolia Market (from HGTV&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Fixer Upper&amp;rdquo;) Tour of LBJ State Park Visit to Fredricksburg Sightseeing through the Hill Country around Austin Lunch at the Salt Lick BBQ  Austin in the spring should be a great place to visit, and Crystal has some really enjoyable activities planned&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a great reason to bring your spouse, girlfriend/boyfriend, significant other, or family member with you to Austin when you come for DockerCon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spousetivities at AWS re:Invent</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/20/spousetivities-at-reinvent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/11/20/spousetivities-at-reinvent/</guid>
      <description>For the first time ever, Spousetivities will be at AWS re:Invent in Las Vegas! This means that IT pros traveling to Vegas can plan on bringing along their spouse, partner, significant other, or family member(s) and know that there are fun, safe, organized activities for them.
So what&amp;rsquo;s planned? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick look:
 More cooking fun with Chef Phillip Dell, a previous season winner on Food Network&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Chopped&amp;rdquo; show Hoover Dam and Grand Canyon tour (a must-see if you haven&amp;rsquo;t been before) Vegas food tour (hosted by Chef Dell, of course!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
