<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vblock on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vblock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vblock on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vblock/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/01/03/technology-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #19, the first Technology Short Take for 2012. Here&amp;rsquo;s this year&amp;rsquo;s first collection of links, articles, and thoughts regarding virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center technology-related topics. I hope you find something useful!
Networking   While configuration limits aren&amp;rsquo;t the most exciting reading, they are important from time to time. Here&amp;rsquo;s some configuration limits for the UCS 6100 and 6200 series.
  Understanding the differences&amp;mdash;both positive and negative&amp;mdash;between the various approaches to solving a particular challenge is a key skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UIM/Operations 3.0 Now GA</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/15/uimoperations-3-0-now-ga/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 23:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/15/uimoperations-3-0-now-ga/</guid>
      <description>Within the last couple of days, I received an e-mail notification that UIM/Operations 3.0 had been finalized and was now generally available (i.e., it was now considered GA).
For those that aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar, UIM has two flavors:
  UIM/Provisioning (also referred to as UIM/P), which is tasked with handling provisioning/de-provisioning tasks in a Vblock. This would include tasks like deploying UCS B-series blades, zoning FC fabrics, and setting up storage pools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Version of UIM/P</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/09/new-version-of-uimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 13:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/11/09/new-version-of-uimp/</guid>
      <description>An e-mail popped into my Inbox on Monday notifying me that Unified Infrastructure Manager/Provisioning (UIM/P) version 3.0 has been released and is now generally available. You might already be familiar with UIM/P as it is the primary provisioning tool for Vblocks.
Some features that are new to this version of UIM/P include:
  UIM/P now has the ability to not only add new blades, VLANs, and datastores to a cluster, but also the ability to remove VLANs and individual blades (called &amp;ldquo;elastic operations&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #15</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/10/03/technology-short-take-15/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #15, the latest in my irregular series of posts on various articles and links on networking, servers, storage, and virtualization&amp;mdash;everything a growing data center engineer needs!
Networking My thoughts this time around are pretty heavily focused on VXLAN, which continues to get lots of attention. I talked about posting a dissection of VXLAN, but I have failed miserably; fortunately, other people smarter than me have stepped up to the plate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #14</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/09/12/technology-short-take-14/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #14, another collection of links and tidbits of information I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered over the last few weeks. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive right in!
Networking Much of my focus in the networking space recently has been around virtualization-centric initiatives, so the items on this list might seem a bit skewed in that direction. Sorry!
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some reading on 802.1Qbg (Edge Virtual Bridging). I still have a long way to go, but I think that I&amp;rsquo;m starting to better understand this draft and the problem(s) it&amp;rsquo;s attempting to address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Vblock Posts</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/26/some-vblock-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/26/some-vblock-posts/</guid>
      <description>The Vblock is starting to get a bit more attention, which is a good thing. Part of it is driven by an increased awareness of the Vblock as a solution; I&amp;rsquo;d like to think of that as something Ed Saipetch and I had a little to do with after our Gestalt IT Tech Field Day presentation in Boston, but I&amp;rsquo;m not so naive as to actually believe that. However, I am confident that part of the increased visibility and discussion around Vblock is due to the continued investment and continued persistence by all three members of the VCE Coalition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using IP-Based Storage with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 09:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/02/04/using-ip-based-storage-with-vmware-vsphere-on-cisco-ucs/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me with a couple of questions, one of which I felt warranted a blog post. Paraphrased, the question was this: How do I make IP-based storage work with VMware vSphere on Cisco UCS?
At first glance, you might look at this question and scoff. Remember though, that Cisco UCS does&amp;mdash;at this time&amp;mdash;have a few limitations that make this a bit more complicated than at first glance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
