<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogging on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:55:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/blogging/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Site Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/01/some-site-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 15:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/12/01/some-site-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last three years, the site has been largely unchanged with regard to the structure and overall function even while I continue to work to provide quality technical content. However, time was beginning to take its toll, and some &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo; work was needed. Over the Thanksgiving holiday, I spent some time updating the site, and there are a few changes I wanted to mention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modifying Visual Studio Code&#39;s Bracketing Behavior</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/08/modifying-visual-studio-code-bracketing-behavior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/08/modifying-visual-studio-code-bracketing-behavior/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two things I&amp;rsquo;ve missed since I switched from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt; (I switched in 2018). First, the &lt;em&gt;speed.&lt;/em&gt; Sublime Text is &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much faster than Visual Studio Code; it&amp;rsquo;s insane. But, the team behind Visual Studio Code is working hard to improve performance, so I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly resigned myself to it. The second thing, though, was the behavior of wrapping selected text in brackets (or parentheses, curly braces, quotes, etc.). That part has annoyed me for two years, until this past weekend I&amp;rsquo;d finally had enough. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I modified Visual Studio Code&amp;rsquo;s bracketing behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 124</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/03/02/technology-short-take-124/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #124! It seems like the natural progression of the Tech Short Takes is moving toward monthly articles, since it&amp;rsquo;s been about a month since my last one. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s hoping that I&amp;rsquo;ve found something useful for you. Enjoy! (And yes, normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but I messed up and forgot. So, I decided to publish on Monday instead of waiting for Friday.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging Break</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/21/blogging-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/21/blogging-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to let readers know that there will be a break in my blogging over the next few weeks. Crystal and I are celebrating our 20th wedding anniversary and have decided to take a very long trip to someplace very far away from civilization so that we can relax, unplug, and simply enjoy each other&amp;rsquo;s company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Team&#39;s Blogs</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/04/08/my-teams-blogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/04/08/my-teams-blogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thankful to have the opportunity to work with an amazing team. Many of my teammates also produce some very useful content via their own sites, and so I thought it might be useful to my readers to share a list of links to my teammates&amp;rsquo; blogs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Creating Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October of this year, I published a blog post talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/&#34;&gt;a sample &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for publishing blog articles&lt;/a&gt;. That post focused on the use of &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the process of a publishing a blog post. This post is a companion to that post, and focuses on the use of a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the creation of blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Publishing Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some readers may already know, this site has been running on a static site generator since late 2014/early 2015, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;I migrated from WordPress to Jekyll on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve since migrated again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;this time to Hugo on S3/CloudFront&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken an interest in using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help automate certain tasks at the CLI. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I&amp;rsquo;m using a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help with publishing blog articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Static Site Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/21/some-static-site-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/21/some-static-site-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days&amp;mdash;prompted perhaps by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/18/some-qa-about-migration-hugo/&#34;&gt;my article with some additional information&lt;/a&gt; on my site migration&amp;mdash;a few folks in the community have reached out to me to share some resources they thought I might find useful. In turn, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share them with you, my readers, in the event you might find them useful as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website Features</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/new-website-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/19/new-website-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/&#34;&gt;migrated this site to Hugo&lt;/a&gt; a little over a month ago was that &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; offered the ability to do things with the site that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t (easily) do with Jekyll (via GitHub Pages). Over the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken advantage of Hugo&amp;rsquo;s flexibility to add a couple new features to the site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Q&amp;A About the Migration to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/18/some-qa-about-migration-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/09/18/some-qa-about-migration-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may already know, I recently completed the migration of this site from &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; (generated using &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;) to S3/CloudFront and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; for static site generation. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve talked with a few readers who had additional questions about the site migration. I thought others might have the same questions, so I decided to gather the most common questions here and share the answers with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information on the Recent Site Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2017 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/10/information-recent-site-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, I completed the migration of this site to an entirely new platform, marking the third or fourth platform migration for this site in its 12-year history. Prior to the migration, the site was generated using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; following &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;a previous migration in late 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to that, I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; for about 9 years. So what is it running now?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brief Site Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/07/brief-site-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/02/07/brief-site-update/</guid>
      <description>As many of you may already know, GitHub recently upgraded GitHub Pages to use Jekyll 3.0, and along with that upgrade comes a few (relatively) minor changes to the site as a result. Here are the details of what&amp;rsquo;s changed here.
The most notable difference is a change in the site&amp;rsquo;s feed URL. Whereas the feed used to be available at http://blog.scottlowe.org/feed/, changes in how Jekyll 3.0 handles permalinks mean that URL is no longer sustainable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Comments Aren&#39;t Available Yet</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 09:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/28/why-no-comments-yet/</guid>
      <description>A number of readers have asked&amp;mdash;via e-mail, of course, given the subject of this post&amp;mdash;why comments aren&amp;rsquo;t available yet on the new site. I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a quick moment to explain the current situation.
First and foremost, it&amp;rsquo;s not because I don&amp;rsquo;t want feedback from readers. I would love to continue to have the outstanding feedback from readers that I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the last 9 years of this site. It&amp;rsquo;s also not because it&amp;rsquo;s too much trouble (too much comment spam, too much time to moderate, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting URLs to Jekyll References</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/08/converting-urls-jekyll-refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 03:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/08/converting-urls-jekyll-refs/</guid>
      <description>In my post about the story behind the migration, I mentioned that I made extensive use of regular expressions (&amp;ldquo;regexes&amp;rdquo;) to help reformat portions of the Markdown documents that are used by Jekyll to build this site. In this post, I wanted to briefly share one of the regexes I used (and am still using) to convert URLs to Jekyll references.
First, let me clarify what I mean by Jekyll references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Story Behind the Migration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/06/the-story-behind-the-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/06/the-story-behind-the-migration/</guid>
      <description>A number of people have asked me why I migrated from WordPress&amp;mdash;which powered my blog for 9 years&amp;mdash;to Jekyll and GitHub Pages. Now that the migration is finally complete, I can share with you the story behind the migration: why I migrated, the process I followed, and some of the tools I used.
Why I Migrated &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo; is a question I heard quite a bit as I was sharing updates on the progress of the blog migration over the Christmas/New Year holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
