<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NAT on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NAT on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 13:10:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/nat/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD as a Simple NAT Router</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/10/06/openbsd-as-a-simple-nat-router/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 13:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/10/06/openbsd-as-a-simple-nat-router/</guid>
      <description>To setup a simple NAT router/firewall using OpenBSD, use these steps as a general guideline. I&amp;rsquo;m assuming that you have general knowledge of OpenBSD. This article applies to OpenBSD 3.9.
First, configure the network interfaces appropriately. Typically, this will involve editing the hostname.&amp;lt;NIC type&amp;gt; file. In a VMware ESX Server environment, OpenBSD uses pcn0 for the first virtual NIC, pcn1 for the second virtual NIC, etc., so the appropriate configuration files would be hostname.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco NAT Issue Resolved</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/22/cisco-nat-issue-resolved/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 21:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/22/cisco-nat-issue-resolved/</guid>
      <description>A short while back I mentioned that I was having a bit of a problem with network address translation (NAT) on a Cisco router. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get the issue resolved, so here&amp;rsquo;s the solution in case someone runs across this problem in the future.
In this instance, the original configuration of the router provided a means for both dynamic NAT and static NAT. Specifically, all the workstations on the LAN would be dynamically translated using port address translation (PAT) behind the external interface of the router, while the web server itself would be statically translated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco NAT Issue</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/14/cisco-nat-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 11:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/01/14/cisco-nat-issue/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been helping a customer try to resolve a network address translation (NAT) problem on a Cisco router for the last week or so, and the solution to the problem is escaping me. What&amp;rsquo;s worse, all the documentation I can find from Cisco says the current configuration is correct.
It&amp;rsquo;s a really simple situation. Customer has a web server at their office that needs to be accessible from the outside. OK, fine, no problem, I use&amp;mdash;in accordance with the Cisco documentation&amp;mdash;the ip nat inside source static command to create a static NAT entry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
