<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/cloud/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running the gcloud CLI in a Docker Container</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/13/running-gcloud-cli-in-a-docker-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/13/running-gcloud-cli-in-a-docker-container/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few times over the last week or two I&amp;rsquo;ve had a need to use the &lt;code&gt;gcloud&lt;/code&gt; command-line tool to access or interact with &lt;a href=&#34;https://cloud.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Cloud Platform (GCP)&lt;/a&gt;. Because working with GCP is something I don&amp;rsquo;t do very often, I prefer to not install the Google Cloud SDK; instead, I run it in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; container. However, there is a trick to doing this, and so to make it easier for others I&amp;rsquo;m documenting it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/31/book-review-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/31/book-review-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/03/05/looking-ahead-2018-projects/&#34;&gt;my 2018 projects&lt;/a&gt;, I committed to reading and reviewing more technical books this year. As part of that effort, I recently finished reading &lt;em&gt;Infrastructure as Code&lt;/em&gt;, authored by Kief Morris and published in September 2015 by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly (more details &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920039297.do&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Infrastructure as code is very relevant to my current job function and is an area of great personal interest, and I&amp;rsquo;d been half-heartedly working my way through the book for some time. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve completed it, here are my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Look at VMware&#39;s Three Cloud Approaches</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/30/brief-look-vmwares-three-cloud-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/30/brief-look-vmwares-three-cloud-approaches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m at VMworld 2017 this week (obviously, based on my tweets and blog posts), and in the general sessions &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/28/vmworld-2017-day-1-keynote/&#34;&gt;Monday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/29/vmworld-2017-day-2-keynote/&#34;&gt;yesterday&lt;/a&gt; VMware made a big deal about how VMware is approaching cloud computing and cloud services. However, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking to other attendees, it&amp;rsquo;s become clear to me that many people don&amp;rsquo;t understand the three-pronged approach VMware is taking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Stack Journey Episode #1: Bart Smith</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/08/full-stack-journey-ep001/</guid>
      <description>In this first-ever episode of the Full Stack Journey podcast, I talk with Bart Smith (old GitHub account migrating to new GitHub account, YouTube channel). Bart shares some details about his journey from being a Microsoft-centric infrastructure engineer to what he calls a cloud-native full-stack engineer. Here are some notes from our conversation, along with some additional resources Bart wanted to share with readers/listeners. Enjoy!
The podcast audio recording is available on Soundcloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rubrik and Converged Data Management</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/26/rubrik-converged-data-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 11:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/05/26/rubrik-converged-data-management/</guid>
      <description>Rubrik today announced a new Series B investment (of $41 million) and introduced their r300 Series Hybrid Cloud Appliance, powered by what they&amp;rsquo;re touting as a &amp;ldquo;Converged Data Management&amp;rdquo; platform. Wow&amp;mdash;that&amp;rsquo;s a mouthful, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? It sounds a bit like buzzword bingo, but after having spent a bit of time talking to Rubrik last week, there are some interesting (in my opinion) things going on here.
So what exactly is Rubrik doing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: The Post-Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/the-post-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 12:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/the-post-cloud/</guid>
      <description>This session is titled &amp;ldquo;The Post-Cloud,&amp;rdquo; and the speaker is Nick Weaver, Director of SDI-X at Intel.
Nick starts his presentation with a summary of our society: some people produce goods through an effort, and others consume what is produced. Things have changed over the years that have affected this production-consumption model, but Nick quickly turns his focus to the use of machines in the production portion of this cycle. As production efficiency increased, the level of consumption also increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interop Liveblog: Thursday Cloud Connect Keynote</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/cloud-connect-keynote-liveblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 11:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/30/cloud-connect-keynote-liveblog/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the Thursday morning Cloud Connect keynote at Interop 2015 in Las Vegas. The title of the presentation is &amp;ldquo;Doing it Live,&amp;rdquo; and the speaker is Jared Wray (@jaredwray on Twitter; he&amp;rsquo;s Cloud CTO and SVP of Platform at CenturyLink).
As the session kicks off, Wray shares that his presentation was drastically altered, a nod to the drastic changes that he is seeing at CenturyLink. He then shares a bit of background on him, his history in IT, and the events that brought him to CenturyLink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running vSphere on AWS or GCE</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/24/vsphere-on-aws-gce-ravello/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/24/vsphere-on-aws-gce-ravello/</guid>
      <description>By now you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen or heard the news about Ravello Systems launching Inception&amp;mdash;the ability to run nested VMware ESXi on AWS or GCE, including the ability to run VMs on these nested ESXi instances. (Here&amp;rsquo;s Ravello&amp;rsquo;s press release.)
In my opinion, this is pretty cool, and it opens the door to a lot of different possibilities: upgrade testing, automation testing, new feature testing, hosted home labs (aka &amp;ldquo;Lab as a Service&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu, cloud-init, and OpenStack Heat</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/23/ubuntu-openstack-heat-cloud-init/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/04/23/ubuntu-openstack-heat-cloud-init/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a couple of things I recently learned about the interaction between cloud-init and OpenStack Orchestration (aka &amp;ldquo;Heat&amp;rdquo;). This may be stuff that you already know, but in the interest of helping others who may not know I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here.
One issue that I&amp;rsquo;d been repeatedly running into was an apparent &amp;ldquo;failure&amp;rdquo; on the part of Heat to properly apply cloud-init configurations to deployed Ubuntu instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Update on OpenStack Congress</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/12/quick-update-congress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/12/quick-update-congress/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Congress, a project aimed at providing &amp;ldquo;policy as a service&amp;rdquo; for OpenStack clouds, is a project I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of being involved in from very early days. I first mentioned Congress almost a year ago, and since then the developers have been hard at work on the project. Recently, one of the lead developers posted a summary of some pretty impressive performance improvements that have been made with Congress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #47</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/07/technology-short-take-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/07/technology-short-take-47/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #47! This is the first Technology Short Take for 2015 and the first to be published on the new blog platform. I have quite a bit of information to share this time around, so buckle up and let&amp;rsquo;s get started!
Networking  Michael Webster isn&amp;rsquo;t a name that normally pops up here in the Networking section of my Technology Short Takes, but he recently wrote an article on installing Cumulus Linux from a MacBook Pro that I thought might be handy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining the Needs of a Policy Solution</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/07/14/examining-the-needs-of-a-policy-solution/</guid>
      <description>In April of this year, we started a series of articles at Network Heresy on the topic of policy in the data center. The first of these articles, which I mentioned in this post, focused on the problem of policy in the data center. This was a great introduction to the need for policy and the challenges with the current ways of addressing policy in the data center.
A short while ago, we published the second of our series on policy, titled &amp;ldquo;On Policy in the Data Center: The solution space&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Policy Discussion Into High Gear</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 12:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/04/22/kicking-the-policy-discussion-into-high-gear/</guid>
      <description>Most IT vendors agree that more extensive use of automation and orchestration in today&amp;rsquo;s data centers are beneficial to customers. The vendors may vary in their approach to providing this automation and orchestration&amp;mdash;some may prefer to do it in software (VMware would be one of these, along with other software companies like Microsoft and Red Hat), while others want to do it in hardware. There are advantages and disadvantages to each approach, naturally, and customers need to evaluate the various solutions against their own requirements to find the best fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Interview with Jesse Proudman</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/16/an-interview-with-jesse-proudman/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the opportunity to conduct an e-mail interview with Jesse Proudman, founder and CEO of Blue Box. The interview is posted below. While it gets a bit biased toward Blue Box at times (he started the company, after all), there are some interesting points raised.
[Scott Lowe] Tell the readers here a little bit about yourself and Blue Box.
[Jesse Proudman] My name is Jesse Proudman. I love the Internet&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;plumbing&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Interview with Dave Malcolm, CTO of Surgient</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/09/cloud-computing-interview-with-dave-malcom-cto-of-surgient/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 18:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/09/cloud-computing-interview-with-dave-malcom-cto-of-surgient/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the pleasure of conducting an e-mail interview with Surgient&amp;rsquo;s Chief Technology Officer, Dave Malcolm. I&amp;rsquo;ve reprinted the question and answer session here. Enjoy!
The Interview Scott Lowe (SL): The term &amp;ldquo;cloud computing&amp;rdquo; is used in a variety of different ways to describe a variety of different things. How would you define cloud computing?
Dave Malcolm (DM): I believe cloud computing is defined as a pool of abstracted, highly scalable, and managed computing infrastructure capable of running end customer applications and is billed or charged by consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
