<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VXLAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vxlan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VXLAN on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vxlan/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IPv6 Primer for Deployments</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/06/ipv6-primer-for-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/06/ipv6-primer-for-deployments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a liveblog of the OpenStack Summit Sydney session titled &amp;ldquo;IPv6 Primer for Deployments&amp;rdquo;, led by Trent Lloyd from Canonical. IPv6 is a topic with which I know I need to get more familiar, so attending this session seemed like a reasonable approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 84</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/06/19/technology-short-take-84/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #84! This episode is a bit late (sorry about that!), but I figured better late than never, right? OK, bring on the links!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #76</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/01/19/technology-short-take-76/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #76, the first Technology Short Take of 2017. Normally, I&amp;rsquo;d publish this on a Friday, but due to extenuating circumstances (my mother-in-law&amp;rsquo;s funeral is tomorrow) I&amp;rsquo;m posting it today. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking  As of Vagrant 1.9.1, the Cumulus plugin for Vagrant is no longer needed. See this post for more details. Ivan Pepelnjak (one of my absolutely favorite folks in the IT industry) has a great post on using regex filters in Ansible to parse text printouts from network devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #71</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #71! As always, I have a list of links related to various data center technologies found below; hopefully something here proves useful.
Networking  Dmitri Kalintsev is back with another article in a series of articles on using hardware VXLAN tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) with VMware NSX. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s on validating HW VTEP deployment for integration with NSX. In particular, Dmitri points out that you need connectivity both on the management plane as well as on the data plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #60</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/01/29/technology-short-take-60/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #60. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered what I hope to be a useful but varied collection of articles and links on key data center technologies. I hope something I&amp;rsquo;ve included here will be helpful&amp;mdash;enjoy!
Networking  The rise of Linux in importance in the networking industry continues, with Arista announcing enhancements to Arista EOS to support&amp;mdash;among other things&amp;mdash;Docker containers. (See this SDx Central article or this Network World article for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #49</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/10/technology-short-take-49/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #49 (also known as Distraction-as-a-Service)! I have here for your reading pleasure an eclectic collection of links and articles from around the web, focusing on data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful. Bring on the content!
Networking  I love this post from Matt Oswalt on five next-gen skills for networking pros. I highly recommend you read the entire post, but in short the five skills Matt recommends are software skills (which includes configuration management and software development tools like Git), Linux, deep protocol knowledge, hypervisor and container networking, and IPv6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #45</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #45. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a collection of links to various articles pertaining to data center-related technologies for your enjoyment. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Cormac Hogan has a list of a few useful NSX troubleshooting tips.
  If you&amp;rsquo;re not really a networking pro and need a &amp;ldquo;gentle&amp;rdquo; introduction to VXLAN, this post might be a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #44</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/03/technology-short-take-44/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #44, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles, links, ideas, and thoughts about various data center-related technologies. Enjoy!
Networking   One of the original problems with the VXLAN IETF specification was that it (deliberately) didn&amp;rsquo;t include any control plane information; as a result, the process of mapping MAC addresses to VTEPs (VXLAN Tunnel Endpoints) wasn&amp;rsquo;t defined, and the early implementations relied on multicast to handle this issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #33</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2013 11:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/06/04/technology-short-take-33/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #33, the latest in my irregularly-published series of articles discussing various data center technology-related links, articles, rants, thoughts, and questions. I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!
Networking   Tom Nolle asks the question, &amp;ldquo;Is virtualization reality even more elusive than virtual reality?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a good read; the key thing that I took away from it was that SDN, NFV, and related efforts are great, but what we really need is something that can pull all these together in a way that customers (and providers) reap the benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #32</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 09:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/03/technology-short-take-32/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #32, the latest installment in my irregularly-published series of link collections, thoughts, rants, raves, and miscellaneous information. I try to keep the information linked to data center technologies like networking, storage, virtualization, and the like, but occasionally other items slip through. I hope you find something useful.
Networking   Ranga Maddipudi (@vCloudNetSec on Twitter) has put together two blog posts on vCloud Networking and Security&amp;rsquo;s App Firewall (part 1 and part 2).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Overlays vs. Network Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/16/network-overlays-vs-network-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/16/network-overlays-vs-network-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Dan Wendlandt said something today in the NVP deep dive session (liveblog of the session here) that really crystallized something for me. I thought perhaps I might be the only one that was seeing a trend, but Dan&amp;rsquo;s comment leads me to believe there are others seeing this trend as well. Here&amp;rsquo;s the quote, taken from my liveblog of the session:
 It is important to note, as Dan does, that a tunneling protocol alone is not network virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #28</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 12:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/01/10/technology-short-take-28/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #28, the first Technology Short Take for 2013. As always, I hope that you find something useful or informative here. Enjoy!
Networking   Ivan Pepelnjak recently wrote a piece titled &amp;ldquo;Edge and Core OpenFlow (and why MPLS is not NAT)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s an informative piece&amp;mdash;Ivan&amp;rsquo;s stuff is always informative&amp;mdash;but what really drew my attention was his mention of a paper by Martin Casado, Teemu Koponen, and others that calls for a combination of MPLS and OpenFlow (and an evolution of OpenFlow into &amp;ldquo;edge&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; versions) to build next-generation networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining Some Networking-Virtualization Chimeras</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/11/examining-some-networking-virtualization-chimeras/</guid>
      <description>I like to spend time examining the areas where different groups of technologies intersect. Personally, I find this activity fascinating, and perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the reason that I find myself pursing knowledge and experience in virtualization, networking, storage, and other areas simultaneously&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s an effort to spend more time &amp;ldquo;on the border&amp;rdquo; between various technologies.
One border, in particular, is very interesting to me: the border between virtualization and networking. Time spent thinking about the border between networking and virtualization is what has generated posts like this one, this one, or this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/06/technology-short-take-27/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #27! This is my usual collection of links, thoughts, rants, and ideas about data center-related technologies. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more about OpenFlow and software-defined networking but need to do this on a shoestring budget in your home lab, a number of guides have been written to help out. I haven&amp;rsquo;t personally used any of these guides yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m working my way in that direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #26</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/10/29/technology-short-take-26/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #26! As you might already know, the Technology Short Takes are my irregularly-published collections of links, articles, thoughts, and (sometimes) rants. I hope you find something useful here!
Networking   Chris Colotti, as part of a changed focus in his role at VMware, has been working extensively with Nicira NVP. He&amp;rsquo;s had a couple of good posts; this one is a primer on how NVP works, and this one discusses the use of the Open vSwitch (OVS) vApp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
