<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 11:15:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/productivity/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Details on the New Desk Layout</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/04/details-on-new-desk-layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 11:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/01/04/details-on-new-desk-layout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the holiday break I made some time to work on my desk layout, something I&amp;rsquo;d been wanting to do for quite a while. I&amp;rsquo;d been wanting to &amp;ldquo;up my game,&amp;rdquo; so to speak, with regard to producing more content, including some video content. Inspired by&amp;mdash;and heavily borrowing from&amp;mdash;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WedG8LKO6ks&#34;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;, I decided I wanted to create a similar arrangement for my desk. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share more details on my setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 122</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/27/technology-short-take-122/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 16:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/12/27/technology-short-take-122/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #122! Luckily I &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; manage to get another Tech Short Take squeezed in for 2019, just so all my readers could have some reading materials for the holidays. I&amp;rsquo;m kidding! No, I mean I really am kidding&amp;mdash;don&amp;rsquo;t read stuff over the holidays. Spend time with your family instead. The investment in your family will pay off in later years, trust me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 114</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/17/technology-short-take-114/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/17/technology-short-take-114/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #114! There will be a longer gap than usual before the next Tech Short Take (more details to come on Monday), but in the meantime here&amp;rsquo;s some articles and links to feed your technical appetite. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: December 2018 Progress Report</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/31/linux-migration-december-2018-progress-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December 2016, I kicked off a migration from macOS to Linux as my primary laptop OS. Throughout 2017, I chronicled my progress and challenges along the way; links to all those posts are found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2018/12/23/the-linux-migration-series/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although I stopped the migration in August 2017, I restarted it in April 2018 when I left VMware to join Heptio. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to recap where things stand as of December 2018, after 8 months of full-time use of Linux as my primary laptop OS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better XMind-GNOME Integration</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/01/better-xmind-gnome-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/09/01/better-xmind-gnome-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In December of 2017 I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/15/installing-xmind-8-on-fedora-27/&#34;&gt;how to install XMind 8 on Fedora 27&lt;/a&gt;, and at the time of that writing I hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite figured out how to define a MIME type for XMind files that would allow users to double-click on an XMind file in Nautilus and open that file in XMind. After doing a bit of additional research and testing, I&amp;rsquo;ve found a solution and would like to share it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 93</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/19/technology-short-take-93/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/19/technology-short-take-93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 93! Today I have another collection of data center technology links, articles, thoughts, and rants. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing XMind 8 on Fedora 27</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/15/installing-xmind-8-on-fedora-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/12/15/installing-xmind-8-on-fedora-27/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xmind.net/&#34;&gt;XMind&lt;/a&gt; is a well-known cross-platform mind mapping application. Installing the latest version of XMind (version 8) on Linux is, unfortunately, more complicated than it should be. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to get XMind 8 running on &lt;a href=&#34;https://getfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; 27.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Creating Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/27/sample-makefile-creating-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In October of this year, I published a blog post talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/&#34;&gt;a sample &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for publishing blog articles&lt;/a&gt;. That post focused on the use of &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the process of a publishing a blog post. This post is a companion to that post, and focuses on the use of a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; for automating the creation of blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sublime Text Keymap for Bracketeer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/02/sublime-text-keymap-bracketeer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/11/02/sublime-text-keymap-bracketeer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made no secret of the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sublimetext.com/&#34;&gt;Sublime Text&lt;/a&gt; (ST). I&amp;rsquo;ve evaluated other editors, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://atom.io/&#34;&gt;Atom&lt;/a&gt;, but still find that ST offers the right blend of performance, functionality, customizability, and cross-platform support. One nice thing about ST (other editors have this too) is the ability to extend it via packages. &lt;a href=&#34;https://packagecontrol.io/packages/Bracketeer&#34;&gt;Bracketeer&lt;/a&gt; is one of many packages that can be used to customize ST&amp;rsquo;s behavior; in this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a keymap I&amp;rsquo;m using with Bracketeer that I&amp;rsquo;ve found very helpful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Wrap-Up</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/25/linux-migration-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/25/linux-migration-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As many readers are probably already aware, I embarked on a journey earlier this year to make Linux my primary laptop OS (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/12/linux-migration-april-2017-progress-report/&#34;&gt;this update&lt;/a&gt; from April of this year). That journey ended (for now) when I ordered a new 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro just before VMworld US. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to reflect a bit on my journey, and what it means for others who may be interested in similar journeys of their own.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sample Makefile for Publishing Blog Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/23/sample-makefile-publishing-blog-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some readers may already know, this site has been running on a static site generator since late 2014/early 2015, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;I migrated from WordPress to Jekyll on GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve since migrated again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2015/01/05/blog-migration-complete/&#34;&gt;this time to Hugo on S3/CloudFront&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken an interest in using &lt;code&gt;make&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help automate certain tasks at the CLI. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I&amp;rsquo;m using a &lt;code&gt;Makefile&lt;/code&gt; to help with publishing blog articles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/04/03/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt3/</guid>
      <description>In discussing support for corporate communication and collaboration systems as part of my Linux migration, I&amp;rsquo;ve so far covered e-mail in part 1 and calendaring in part 2. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss the last few remaining aspects of corporate collaboration: instant messaging/chat, meetings and teleconferences, and document sharing.
Teleconferences and meetings The topic of teleconferences and meetings is closely related to calendaring&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s often necessary to access your calendar or others&amp;rsquo; calendars when coordinating meetings or teleconferences&amp;mdash;so I encourage you to read part 2 to get a better feel for the challenges around calendaring/scheduling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/27/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt2/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 in a series of posts describing how I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated my Fedora Linux laptop into my employer&amp;rsquo;s corporate communication and collaboration systems. Part 1 tackled e-mail; this post tackles the topic of calendaring and scheduling. Unlike e-mail, which was solved relatively easily, this issue is one that I don&amp;rsquo;t consider fully solved.
As I mentioned in part 1, my employer uses Office 365 (O365). While O365 supports standard protocols like IMAP and STMP for mail, it does not support standard protocols like CalDAV for calendaring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Other Users&#39; Stories, Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/22/linux-migration-other-users-stories-pt4/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a series of posts sharing other users&amp;rsquo; stories about their migration to Linux as their primary desktop OS. As I mentioned in part 1 of the series, there seemed to be quite a bit of pent-up interest in using Linux as your primary desktop OS. I thought it might be helpful to readers to hear not just about my migration, but also about others&amp;rsquo; migrations. You may also find it interesting/helpful to read part 2 and part 3 of this series for more migration stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Migration: Corporate Collaboration, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/03/21/linux-migration-corp-collab-pt1/</guid>
      <description>One major aspect of my migration to Linux as my primary desktop OS is how well it integrates with corporate communication and collaboration systems. Based on the feedback I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten from others on Twitter, this is a major concern for a lot of folks out there. In fact, a number of folks have indicated that this is the only thing keeping them from migrating to Linux. There are a number of different aspects to &amp;ldquo;corporate communication and collaboration,&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m breaking this down into multiple posts (each post will discuss one particular aspect).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
