<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MPLS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/mpls/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MPLS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/mpls/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 116</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/07/05/technology-short-take-116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #116! This one is a bit shorter than usual, due to holidays in the US and my life being busy. Nevertheless, I hope that I managed to capture something you find useful or helpful. As always, your feedback is welcome, so if you have suggestions, corrections, or comments, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/scott_lowe&#34;&gt;contact me via Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #69</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/07/22/technology-short-take-69/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #69! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of links related to major data center technology areas. This episode is a bit long; sorry about that!
Networking  Lindsay Hill recently noted that he&amp;rsquo;s been working to add support to netmiko for the Brocade ICX and MLXe, and is looking into support for VDX. Netmiko, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, is a fantastic Python library that&amp;rsquo;s really useful when writing Python-based network automation scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Out Loud: Why Not MPLS-in-IP?</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thinking-out-loud-why-not-mpls-in-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 09:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/06/26/thinking-out-loud-why-not-mpls-in-ip/</guid>
      <description>As I was reviewing my list of actions in OmniFocus this morning, I saw an action I&amp;rsquo;d added a while back to review RFC 4023. RFC 4023 is the RFC that defines MPLS-in-IP and MPLS-in-GRE encapsulations, and was written in 2005. I thought, &amp;ldquo;Let me just read this real quick.&amp;rdquo; So I did.
It&amp;rsquo;s not a terribly long RFC (only about 13 pages or so), but I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to summarize it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #22</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 13:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/05/03/technology-short-take-22/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #22! Once again, I find myself without too many articles to share with you this time around. I guess that will make things a bit easier for you, the reader, but it does make me question whether or not I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;listening&amp;rdquo; to the right communities. If any readers have suggestions on sources of information to which I should be subscribing or I should be following, I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear your suggestions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Initial MPLS Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/01/some-initial-mpls-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 09:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2011/12/01/some-initial-mpls-reading/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned on Twitter yesterday that I was doing some basic/introductory reading on MPLS, and someone asked what materials I was using. While I&amp;rsquo;m still very early in the process of trying to understand MPLS, I thought I might share the resources I&amp;rsquo;ve used so far in trying to wrap my head around MPLS, what it is, and the basics of how it works.
Here are some of the sites I&amp;rsquo;ve used so far:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
