<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WordPress on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wordpress/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WordPress on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 15:14:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/wordpress/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Theme!</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/07/new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/09/07/new-theme/</guid>
      <description>I finally got around to installing a new theme here on the site. I was both eager to install a new theme&amp;mdash;after all, how many thousands of other sites looked just like this one&amp;mdash;and yet also apprehensive, because I&amp;rsquo;d gotten the previous theme tweaked just the way I wanted it.
So, I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in hearing from the readers as to the new layout. Do you like it? What can be improved?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/05/wordpress-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2007 12:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2007/03/05/wordpress-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>I had been stubbornly clinging to WordPress 1.5.2, which worked just fine and, in all reality, provided all the functionality I really needed. I figured it would probably be best to keep up with the newer versions of the software, however, so I decided to upgrade.
To give all credit to the WordPress developers, the upgrade process for WordPress itself was very straightforward and rather quick. The trouble came in having to update or replace certain plugins that weren&amp;rsquo;t compatible with the newer versions of WordPress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Search Tags</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/12/site-search-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2006 09:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/06/12/site-search-tags/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the site to use a tagging plugin called Ultimate Tag Warrior. It&amp;rsquo;s taken some time to get things working the way I&amp;rsquo;d like, but it&amp;rsquo;s working now and I&amp;rsquo;m really pleased with how things have turned out. Read on for more details.
I had been using ecto (my Mac OS X-based blogging client) to add Technorati-specific tags to my posts. This was all well and good, but these tags were not getting added to my RSS feeds and therefore weren&amp;rsquo;t getting picked up fully by Technorati, even though I was pinging Technorati every time I published an entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comment Spam</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/22/comment-spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 21:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2006/05/22/comment-spam/</guid>
      <description>The level of comment spam I&amp;rsquo;ve been receiving over the last few days has suddenly skyrocketed (as in approximately 200 spam comments in just a couple of days). It was time to do something.
That something was Akismet, a highly-regarded spam mechanism for blocking comment and trackback spam. I&amp;rsquo;ve now installed Akismet to protect this weblog, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how well it works. Blog spammers beware!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Weblog Updates</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/04/some-weblog-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 22:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/12/04/some-weblog-updates/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been a few updates to this weblog over the last few days. Nothing major, just a few minor changes here and there.
First, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to showing excerpts only on the index page. Of course, the archives pages (both category archives as well as monthly archives) were already showing excerpts only. Note that RSS feeds are still showing the full content.
The full entry page (the &amp;ldquo;single page,&amp;rdquo; in WordPress parlance) now shows the sidebar as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unrelated Items</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/09/22/unrelated-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 22:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2005/09/22/unrelated-items/</guid>
      <description>I have a few things I wanted to mention here, but none of them were really long enough to warrant their own entry. So, I&amp;rsquo;m lumping them all together here.
First, I&amp;rsquo;ve started going back and adding excerpts (or summaries) to most of the entries posted on this weblog. This makes the WordPress archive views cleaner (no more Technorati tags showing up for short entries). I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are probably other reasons why this is a good idea as well, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are (yet).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
