<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ActiveDirectory on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/activedirectory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ActiveDirectory on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:15:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/activedirectory/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 140</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/07/technology-short-take-140/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 09:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/05/07/technology-short-take-140/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #140! It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe it&amp;rsquo;s already the start of May 2021&amp;mdash;my how time flies! In this Technology Short Take, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered some links for you covering topics like Azure and AWS networking, moving from macOS to Linux (and back again), and more. Let&amp;rsquo;s jump right into the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, May 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/18/posts-from-the-past-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/05/18/posts-from-the-past-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month&amp;mdash;May 2018&amp;mdash;marks &lt;strong&gt;thirteen years&lt;/strong&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve been generating content here on this site. It&amp;rsquo;s been a phenomenal 13 years, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the opportunity to share information with readers around the world. To celebrate, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick &amp;ldquo;Posts from the Past&amp;rdquo; and highlight some content from previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts from the Past, October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/10/26/posts-from-the-past-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After over 12 years of writing here, I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a pretty fair amount of content. To help folks discover older content, I thought it might be fun to revisit what I&amp;rsquo;ve published in October in years past. Here are some &amp;ldquo;posts from the past,&amp;rdquo; all from October of previous years. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potential Fix for Kerberos, SSH, LDAP, and Active Directory Issue</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/02/potential-fix-for-kerberos-ssh-ldap-and-active-directory-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 17:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/05/02/potential-fix-for-kerberos-ssh-ldap-and-active-directory-issue/</guid>
      <description>I had a reader contact me with a question on using Kerberos and LDAP for authentication into Active Directory, based on Active Directory integration work I did many years ago. I was unable to help him, but he did find the solution to the problem, and I wanted to share it here in case it might help others.
The issue was that he was experiencing a problem using native Kerberos authentication against Active Directory with SSH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3010: A MultiStore Primer</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/08/3010-a-multistore-primer/</guid>
      <description>This session describes NetApp&amp;rsquo;s MultiStore functionality. MultiStore is the name given to NetApp&amp;rsquo;s functionality for secure logical partitioning of network and storage resources. The presenters for the session are Roger Weeks, TME with NetApp, and Scott Gelb with Insight Investments.
When using MultiStore, the basic building block is the vFiler. A vFiler is a logical construct within Data ONTAP that contains a lightweight instance of the Data ONTAP multi-protocol server. vFilers provide the ability to securely partition both storage resources and network resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyTrust Launches Security Appliance</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/06/hytrust-launches-security-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 16:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/06/hytrust-launches-security-appliance/</guid>
      <description>Today HyTrust launched its flagship product, the HyTrust Appliance, a security solution that is designed to centralize the control, management, and visibility for virtualized environments, in particular VMware Infrastructure environments. The HyTrust appliance achieves this through a number of key features:
  The HyTrust Appliance provides integration with Active Directory or other LDAP-based directory services to enable centralized authentication. This allows organizations to leverage existing directory services for authentication, both for access via the VI Client or via SSH to the Service Console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux-AD Integration Issue: Persistent Connections</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/02/linux-ad-integration-issue-persistent-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 14:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/04/02/linux-ad-integration-issue-persistent-connections/</guid>
      <description>A reader contacted me a short while ago to inquire about a problem he was having with his Linux-AD integration efforts. It seems he had recently added a new domain controller (DC) that was intended to be a DC for a disaster recovery (DR) site. When he took this new DR DC offline in order to physically move it to the DR site, some of his AD-integrated Linux systems started failing to authenticate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blasts from the Past</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/01/blasts-from-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 19:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/01/blasts-from-the-past/</guid>
      <description>I was visiting Unclutterer and saw them sharing older content from the site in a similar fashion. So, I thought I might try it here. Enjoy some of these &amp;ldquo;blasts from the past&amp;rdquo;!
One Year Ago LACP with Cisco Switches and NetApp VIFs
Hyper-V Architectural Issue
Latest VDI Article Published
Two Years Ago Bookmark Spam?
Personal Computing as a Collection of VMs?
Application Agnosticism
Three Years Ago Mac OS X and .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #24</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 11:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/virtualization-short-take-24/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s lots of good information flowing around the Internet, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming increasingly difficult to sort through all the useless stuff to find the valuable gems. Hopefully, some of the links that I have collected here will prove to be more useful than useless!
  I came across this VMware KB article titled &amp;ldquo;Dedicating specific NICs to portgroups while maintaining NIC teaming and failover for the vSwitch&amp;rdquo;. I was hoping it would shed new light on some NIC teaming functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Solaris-AD Integration Update</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/19/no-solaris-ad-integration-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2008 13:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/19/no-solaris-ad-integration-update/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, folks, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to have the time or the resources to publish an update to my existing instructions for integrating Solaris 10 into Active Directory. Quite some time ago I had posted that I planned on creating an update to the original instructions so as to incorporate some lessons learned, but it keeps get pushed aside for other tasks that are more important and more relevant to my day-to-day work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSH with Kerberos and Active Directory</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/openssh-with-kerberos-and-active-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2008 23:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/26/openssh-with-kerberos-and-active-directory/</guid>
      <description>I ran across this handy white paper about OpenSSH on Linux using Kerberos authentication with Windows and Active Directory. There&amp;rsquo;s not a whole lot in there that isn&amp;rsquo;t also covered in my Active Directory integration notes, but it is useful information nevertheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Works</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/15/in-the-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 23:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/07/15/in-the-works/</guid>
      <description>I just wanted to provide a quick update on some articles I have in the works to be (hopefully) published soon.
  I&amp;rsquo;m working on an article discussing when to use various NIC teaming configurations with VMware ESX. There are some significant repercussions here for a variety of network configurations, but especially so for configurations involving IP-based storage (iSCSI or NFS).
  I&amp;rsquo;m finally wrapping up an article on the Xsigo I/O Director.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding UNIX-Enabled Accounts in Active Directory MMC</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/18/finding-unix-enabled-accounts-in-active-directory-mmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2008 11:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/06/18/finding-unix-enabled-accounts-in-active-directory-mmc/</guid>
      <description>In UNIX/Linux integration scenarios, it&amp;rsquo;s useful to know which accounts have been UNIX-enabled, i.e., have had the UID number, NIS domain, login shell, and home directory attributes configured.
It&amp;rsquo;s certainly very possible to do this with command-line tools such as AdFind or DsQuery, but users may also find it useful to have a saved query available within the Active Directory Users &amp;amp; Computers console for easy reference.
The way to do this is define a custom query using this string:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AD Integration Tip: Dealing With More Than 1,000 Users</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/11/ad-integration-tip-dealing-with-more-than-1000-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 12:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/11/ad-integration-tip-dealing-with-more-than-1000-users/</guid>
      <description>Reader Scott Merrill pointed out something to me in an e-mail regarding a Registry change that might be necessary in some Active Directory integration scenarios:
 Finally, I would like to share one registry change that we&amp;rsquo;ve found to be necessary in our AD integration. By default, the MS LDAP server only returns 1,000 results. As a university department with more than 1000 active students, this limitation has caused us some frustration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles in Progress</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/03/articles-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2008 20:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/04/03/articles-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list of a few of the articles that I currently have in progress:
  I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at the recently-announced products from Altor Networks and have their VNSA (Virtual Network Security Analyzer) running in the lab right now. Look for a short post on the product and my initial thoughts. (One piece of advice I can offer to Altor right now: use the virtual appliance OVF format and save your customers a lot of trouble.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
