<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VMwareHA on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwareha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VMwareHA on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 16:03:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/vmwareha/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuing the Consolidation Discussion</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/26/continuing-the-consolidation-discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 16:03:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/04/26/continuing-the-consolidation-discussion/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick post inspired by Mike Laverick&amp;rsquo;s recent &amp;ldquo;Stupid IT&amp;rdquo; post, in which he weighed in on the blog discussion between Steve Chambers and I regarding &amp;ldquo;putting all your eggs in one basket,&amp;rdquo; the most common argument against high consolidation ratios and, in some cases, against consolidation in general.
Mike&amp;rsquo;s articles&amp;ndash;part 1 and part 2&amp;ndash;are excellent articles. The interesting thing here is that, when you really boil it down, my viewpoint is not that far off from both Steve and Mike (spoiler warning: Mike agrees with Steve).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware HA, VMware FT, and OS Clustering</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/30/vmware-ha-vmware-ft-and-os-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2009 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/10/30/vmware-ha-vmware-ft-and-os-clustering/</guid>
      <description>With the release of VMware vSphere 4 earlier this year, VMware officially introduced VMware Fault Tolerance (VMware FT), a new mechanism for providing extremely high levels of availability to virtual machine workloads. As I&amp;rsquo;ve talked with customers, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a growing number of customers who are unaware of the differences between the types of high availability that VMware provides (in the form of VMware HA and VMware FT) and operating system-level clustering (such as Microsoft Windows Failover Clustering).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Return of Virtualization Short Takes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2009 13:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/06/05/the-return-of-virtualization-short-takes/</guid>
      <description>My irregular &amp;ldquo;Virtualization Short Takes&amp;rdquo; series was put on hold some time ago after I started work on Mastering VMware vSphere 4. Now that work on the book is starting to wind down just a bit, I thought it would be a good time to try to resurrect the series. So, without further delay, welcome to the return of Virtualization Short Takes!
  Trigged by a series of blog posts by Arnim van Lieshout on VMware ESX memory management (Part 1, Part 2, and Part 3), Scott Herold decided to join the fray with this blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #25</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2009 14:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2009/01/07/virtualization-short-take-25/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Virtualization Short Take #25, the first edition of this series for 2009! Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collected a variety of articles and posts that I found interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off today&amp;rsquo;s list with some Hyper-V links. First up is this article on how to manually add a VM configuration to Hyper-V. It would be interesting to me to know some of the technical details&amp;mdash;i.e., the design decisions that led Microsoft to architect things in this way&amp;mdash;that might explain why this process is, in my opinion, so complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Reboots with VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/23/random-reboots-with-vmware-esx-35-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2008 23:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/23/random-reboots-with-vmware-esx-35-update-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been communicating with a reader who is experiencing random reboots of virtual machines on his HA/DRS-enabled cluster running VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3. At first, I thought his problem was related to the bug with VM failure monitoring that I discussed here, but upon further discussion the random reboots are continuing to occur even when VM failure monitoring is disabled. The only relief the reader has been able to find thus far has been to completely disable VMware HA on his cluster, which&amp;mdash;to be honest&amp;mdash;is a less than acceptable solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;ve Got to be Kidding Me</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 14:35:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/15/youve-got-to-be-kidding-me/</guid>
      <description>Via jtroyer on Twitter, I learned of this post comparing Hyper-V and VMware ESX.
Now, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit that I&amp;rsquo;m a VMware fan, but as others in the virtualization industry know I also recognize that VMware is not a &amp;ldquo;one size fits all&amp;rdquo; solution. There are many places where other virtualization solutions, Hyper-V included, may be a better solution for the customer. It really all depends upon the customer&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware HA Problem with Update 3</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/12/vmware-ha-problem-with-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 17:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/12/12/vmware-ha-problem-with-update-3/</guid>
      <description>A problem has been identified with VMware ESX 3.5 Update 3 when using VMware HA and VM failure monitoring. This problem results from a delay in the transmission of a heartbeat from a VM to VMware HA; VMware HA then detects this as a VM failure and restarts the VM. It appears that this problem affects both VMware ESX and VMware ESXi.
More information on the problem is available in this KB article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #22</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/11/virtualization-short-take-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2008 11:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/11/11/virtualization-short-take-22/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m out of town this week at NetApp Insight, I wanted to go ahead and get out the latest installation of Virtualization Short Takes&amp;mdash;my sometimes-weekly collection of interesting or useful links and tidbits.
  Much ado has been made about VMware&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of Trango and the announcement of VMware MVP (Mobile Virtualization Platform). Rich Brambley has a great write-up, and I completely agree with Rich and Alex Barrett about what this really means: don&amp;rsquo;t expect to see Windows XP on your smartphone any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #20</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 22:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/23/virtualization-short-take-20/</guid>
      <description>This week&amp;rsquo;s Short Take is a collection of links and articles that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last few weeks (or longer ago, in some cases!) that I thought others might find interesting or useful. Enjoy!
  Alessandro broke the news to the general public about some anticipated new virtualization features that are expected to make their debut in Windows Server 2008 R2, expected sometime in 2010. Microsoft announced live migration for Hyper-V back at the beginning of September, so that part was already known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization Short Take #19</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/14/virtualization-short-take-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 21:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/10/14/virtualization-short-take-19/</guid>
      <description>Virtualization Short Take #19 is here, with news, headlines, and commentary on a few things that have passed my way over the last few weeks. Feel free to share your own interesting tidbits in the comments!
  Rick Blythe, aka VMwarewolf, regales us with a tale of a new &amp;ldquo;feature&amp;rdquo; in VirtualCenter 2.5 Update 2. This new feature prevents VM migrations when putting a VMware ESX server into maintenance mode if it will violate the VMware HA failover level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>everRun VM, VMware HA, and VMware FT</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/everrun-vm-vmware-ha-and-vmware-ft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 11:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/26/everrun-vm-vmware-ha-and-vmware-ft/</guid>
      <description>Having previously discussed Marathon Technologies&amp;rsquo; everRun VM product in conjunction with XenServer HA as part of XenServer 5, I think that I have some useful information to bring to the recent discussion that has come to light about everRun VM vs. VMware HA vs. VMware FT.
Apparently, this discussion started with a blog entry by Marathon titled VMware FT - The Top Four Reasons it&amp;rsquo;s Kinda Sorta Fault Tolerance. Mike DiPetrillo of VMware responded from his personal blog, first tackling Marathon&amp;rsquo;s blog post and then again tackling comparisons posted on Marathon&amp;rsquo;s web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware Keynote - Automating DR with VMware SRM</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 12:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/18/vmware-keynote-automating-dr-with-vmware-srm/</guid>
      <description>There is no general session this morning at VMworld 2008; instead, a &amp;ldquo;keynote&amp;rdquo; will be delivered about automating disaster recovery (DR) using VMware Site Recovery Manager (SRM). This is similar to the way in which other vendors have delivered various &amp;ldquo;keynotes&amp;rdquo; throughout the conference instead of all the announcements being crammed into the morning general sessions.
The speaker this morning is Jay Judkowitz, the product manager for VMware SRM. I&amp;rsquo;ve met Jay before; he&amp;rsquo;s a good guy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BC2621: Fault-Tolerant VMs in VI: Operations and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc2621-fault-tolerant-vms-in-vi-operations-and-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2008 16:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/16/bc2621-fault-tolerant-vms-in-vi-operations-and-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Well, it looks like wireless coverage pretty much stinks, so this will have to be published post-session as well.
This session is BC2621, titled &amp;ldquo;Fault Tolerant VMs in VMware Infrastructure: Operations and Best Practices&amp;rdquo;, presented by Dan Scales, Principal Engineer with VMware. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty full session, but I&amp;rsquo;m lucky (unlucky?) enough to get a seat toward the front of the session.
This is a technical preview of VMware FT, a new feature that is slated to be included in VDC-OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware&#39;s Virtual Datacenter OS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/vmwares-virtual-datacenter-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 11:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/vmwares-virtual-datacenter-os/</guid>
      <description>So, the news is out on VMware&amp;rsquo;s new announcement regarding the Virtual Datacenter OS (VDC-OS). You can find more coverage of this on a few other sites:
Virtual Datacenter OS from VMware
VMware moving to cloud-computing with Virtual Datacenter Operating System (VDC-OS)
VMware testing data center OS for managing, literally, everything
VMware Tries to Expand Throughout the Data Center
I&amp;rsquo;m kind of excited to be able to talk about this, because it was a topic of the Partner Technical Advisory Board today and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d be able to talk about it until later in the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marathon and XenServer HA</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/marathon-and-xenserver-ha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 09:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2008/09/15/marathon-and-xenserver-ha/</guid>
      <description>Marathon Technologies played a pivotal role in the development of the XenServer HA functionality unveiled today in XenServer 5. In addition to leading the development of the basic XenServer HA functionality that is included in XenServer, Marathon also offers enhanced levels of HA through the use of everRun VM.
In order to understand the enhanced levels of HA that everRun VM offers, it&amp;rsquo;s important to first understand what XenServer HA does and does not address.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
