<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/intel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Intel on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/intel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 151</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #151, the first Technology Short Take of 2022. I hope everyone had a great holiday season and that 2022 is off to a wonderful start! I have a few more links than normal this time around, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t find articles in a couple categories. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my eyes peeled and my RSS reader ready to pull in new articles in those categories for next time. And now for the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 148</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 21:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/11/19/technology-short-take-148/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #148, aka the Thanksgiving Edition (at least, for US readers). I&amp;rsquo;ve been scouring RSS feeds and various social media sites, collecting as many useful links and articles as I can find: from networking hardware and networking CI/CD pipelines to Kernel TLS and tricks for improving your working memory. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the range! I hope that you find something useful here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 144</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/27/technology-short-take-144/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #144! I have a fairly diverse set of links for readers this time around, covering topics from microchips to improving your writing, with stops along the way in topics like Kubernetes, virtualization, Linux, and the popular JSON-parsing tool &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;. I hope you find something useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 128</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2020/06/19/technology-short-take-128/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #128! It looks like I&amp;rsquo;m settling into a roughly monthly cadence with the Technology Short Takes. This time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a (hopefully) interesting collection of links. The collection seems a tad heavier than normal in the hardware and security sections, probably due to new exploits discovered in Intel&amp;rsquo;s speculative execution functionality. In any case, here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered for you. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 113</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/03/technology-short-take-113/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2019/05/03/technology-short-take-113/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #113! I hope the collection of links and articles I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered for you contains something useful for you. I think I have a pretty balanced collection this time around; there&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of something for almost everyone. Who says you can&amp;rsquo;t please everyone all the time?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 106</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/11/09/technology-short-take-106/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #106! It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a while (over a month) since the last Tech Short Take, as this one kept getting pushed back. Sorry about that, folks! Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve still managed to find useful and helpful links to include below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 92</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/05/technology-short-take-92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2018/01/05/technology-short-take-92/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take 92, the first Technology Short Take of 2018. This one was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be the last Tech Short Take of 2017, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it published in time (I decided to spend time with my family instead&amp;mdash;some things are just more important). In any case, hopefully the delay of one additional week hasn&amp;rsquo;t caused any undue stress&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s jump right in!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 85</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2017/08/11/technology-short-take-85/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #85! This is my irregularly-published collection of links and articles from around the Internet related to the major data center technologies: networking, hardware, security, cloud computing, applications/OSes, storage, and virtualization. Plus, just for fun, I usually try to include a couple career-related links as well. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #74</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/12/09/technology-short-take-74/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #74! The end of 2016 is nearly upon us, and it looks as if there will be only one more Technology Short Take before the end of the year. So, let&amp;rsquo;s get on with the content&amp;mdash;time is short!
Networking  If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Apstra, David Varnum has a great introduction to Apstra available on his site. Will Robinson talks about how to structure your Ansible playbooks in the context of using Ansible to control your network gear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #71</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/09/technology-short-take-71/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #71! As always, I have a list of links related to various data center technologies found below; hopefully something here proves useful.
Networking  Dmitri Kalintsev is back with another article in a series of articles on using hardware VXLAN tunnel endpoints (VTEPs) with VMware NSX. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s on validating HW VTEP deployment for integration with NSX. In particular, Dmitri points out that you need connectivity both on the management plane as well as on the data plane.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #64</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/04/04/technology-short-take-64/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #64. Normally, I try to publish Short Takes on Friday, but this past Friday was April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day. Given the propensity for &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; information to get lost among all the pranks, I decided to push this article back to today. Unlike most of what is published around April Fools&amp;rsquo; Day, hopefully everything here is helpful, informative, and useful!
Networking  Phil Gervasi has an article on fate sharing in the network core, where he discusses some of the advantages&amp;mdash;and disadvantages&amp;mdash;of centralizing the control plane in network designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #62</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/09/technology-short-take-62/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #62. Sorry for the long delay since the last TST; some global travel has really thrown my schedule off. In any case, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait until Friday (the day I normally publish these) so I&amp;rsquo;m putting this out there sooner. Enjoy!
Networking  PowerNSX is pretty cool&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a set of PowerShell cmdlets for administrators of VMware NSX running in vSphere environments. Check out Anthony Burke&amp;rsquo;s introductory post on PowerNSX for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #45</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/10/08/technology-short-take-45/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #45. As usual, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a collection of links to various articles pertaining to data center-related technologies for your enjoyment. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping you find something useful!
Networking   Cormac Hogan has a list of a few useful NSX troubleshooting tips.
  If you&amp;rsquo;re not really a networking pro and need a &amp;ldquo;gentle&amp;rdquo; introduction to VXLAN, this post might be a good place to start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking About Intel Rack-Scale Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2014/09/22/thinking-about-intel-rack-scale-architecture/</guid>
      <description>You may have heard of Intel Rack-Scale Architecture (RSA), a new approach to designing data center hardware. This is an idea that was discussed extensively a couple of weeks ago at Intel Developer Forum (IDF) 2014 in San Francisco, which I had the opportunity to attend. (Disclaimer: Intel paid my travel and hotel expenses to attend IDF.)
Of course, IDF 2014 wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first time I&amp;rsquo;d heard of Intel RSA; it was also discussed last year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
