<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Symmetrix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/symmetrix/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Symmetrix on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 21:05:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/symmetrix/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take #4</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/28/technology-short-take-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 21:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/28/technology-short-take-4/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Technology Short Take #4, the latest collection of virtualization, storage, networking, and other data center-related links, news, thoughts, and views. As always, I hope you find something interesting here!
  First up, we&amp;rsquo;ll revisit the idea of multi-hop FCoE. You might recall a couple of articles I wrote a while ago about Network Interface Virtualization (NIV) and the role of NIV in FCoE. One of my new favorite networking bloggers, Ivan Pepelnjak, picked up this same topic recently in this post on multi-hop FCoE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New User&#39;s Guide to Symmetrix VMAX Auto Provisioning Groups via CLI, Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/22/new-users-guide-to-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups-via-cli-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 13:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/09/22/new-users-guide-to-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups-via-cli-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Readers who also follow me on Twitter have probably noticed that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in an EMC Symmetrix VMAX training class this week. As part of that class, we&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Auto-Provisioning Groups. For other users who might be new to SYMCLI (the Symmetrix CLI) and Auto-Provisioning Groups (APGs), I thought this &amp;ldquo;new user&amp;rsquo;s guide&amp;rdquo; to APGs via the CLI might be handy. Comments from experienced users are welcome! In future posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll provide some additional commands for modifying and viewing APGs via CLI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC World 2010: Symmetrix VMAX Auto-Provisioning Groups</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/11/emc-world-2010-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 09:33:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/11/emc-world-2010-symmetrix-vmax-auto-provisioning-groups/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few notes from another Symmetrix session I attended Monday afternoon. It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete session blog (the presenter was presenting so much information I couldn&amp;rsquo;t capture it all).
Auto-provisioning groups include storage groups, port groups, and initiator groups. A storage group is just a collection of storage resources that are presented to a cluster of hosts. Similarly, a port group is a collection of front-end ports, and initiator groups are just groups of hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMC World 2010: Enginuity 5874 Enhancements for VMAX</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-enginuity-5874-enhancements-for-vmax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 10:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2010/05/10/emc-world-2010-enginuity-5874-enhancements-for-vmax/</guid>
      <description>This is a liveblog of the session titled &amp;ldquo;Performance Improvements and Enhancements of Enginuity 5874 for Symmetrix VMAX: What&amp;rsquo;s New Since Last Year&amp;rdquo;. The presenter&amp;rsquo;s name is John Aurin. (Note: the product branding is changing from &amp;ldquo;V-Max&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;VMAX&amp;rdquo;.)
The session starts with a recap of the Symmetrix VMAX architecture: the directors, front-end ports, the Virtual Matrix connectivity for sharing data between directors, and the various expansion cabinets and drives that are supported.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
