<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/categories/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/categories/rant/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Now Using VirtualBox with Vagrant</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/09/28/why-now-using-virtualbox-with-vagrant/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I often tell people is, &amp;ldquo;Use the right tool for the job.&amp;rdquo; As technologists, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t get so locked onto any one technology or product that we can&amp;rsquo;t see when other technologies or products might solve a particular problem more effectively. It&amp;rsquo;s for this reason that I recently made VirtualBox&amp;mdash;not VMware Fusion&amp;mdash;my primary virtualization provider for Vagrant environments.
I know it seems odd for a VMware employee to use/prefer a non-VMware product over a competing VMware product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Topic of Lock-In</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/17/on-topic-of-lock-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2016/03/17/on-topic-of-lock-in/</guid>
      <description>While talking with customers over the past couple of weeks during a multi-country/multi-continent trip, one phrase that kept coming up is &amp;ldquo;lock-in&amp;rdquo;, as in &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re trying to avoid lock-in&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;this approach doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any lock-in&amp;rdquo;. While I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of memes, this phrase always brings to mind The Princess Bride, Vizzini&amp;rsquo;s use of the word &amp;ldquo;inconceivable,&amp;rdquo; and Inigo Montoya&amp;rsquo;s famous response. C&amp;rsquo;mon, you know you want to say it: &amp;ldquo;You keep using that word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BusyCal and Textual</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/13/busycal-and-textual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/11/13/busycal-and-textual/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to call out a couple of software packages whose vendors I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with recently that I felt had really good customer service. The software packages are BusyCal (from BusyCal, LLC) and Textual (from Codeux Software, LLC).
As many of you know, the Mac App Store (MAS) recently suffered an issue due to an expired security certificate, and this caused many MAS apps to have to be re-downloaded or, in limited cases, to stop working (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, Tweetbot 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retiring the Rockstar: A Counterpoint</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 07:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/03/23/retire-the-rockstar-a-counterpoint/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re a rockstar!&amp;rdquo; Chances are, you&amp;rsquo;ve either a) been told this as a compliment for some work you&amp;rsquo;d done; b) heard this told to someone else for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done; or c) told someone this for some work they&amp;rsquo;d done. If you said this to someone else&amp;mdash;I just told someone this quite recently&amp;mdash;chances are also very likely that you had nothing but positive intentions behind this statement and your goal was to compliment them on what you saw as outstanding work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Thought About Mesos-DNS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/17/quick-thought-mesos-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2015 10:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2015/02/17/quick-thought-mesos-dns/</guid>
      <description>A colleague recently pointed me to the recent Mesosphere announcement of Mesos-DNS, a DNS-based service discovery mechanism for Apache Mesos clusters. A comment made in the announcement got me thinking, and I wanted to briefly share my thoughts.
The comment that got me thinking was this:
 Mesos-DNS is simple and stateless. Unlike Consul and SkyDNS, it does not require consensus mechanisms, persistent storage, or a replicated log.
 If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along here on my site, you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Consul before (see here), and I have more Consul content planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Man is an Island</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/12/no-man-is-an-island/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 09:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/12/no-man-is-an-island/</guid>
      <description>The phrase &amp;ldquo;No man is an island&amp;rdquo; is attributed to John Donne, an English poet who lived in the late 1500s and early 1600s. The phrase comes from his Meditation XVII, and was borrowed later by Thomas Merton to become the title of a book he published in 1955. In both cases, the phrase is used to discuss the interconnected nature of humanity and mankind. (Side note: the phrase &amp;ldquo;for whom the bell tolls&amp;rdquo; comes from the same origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weirdness with Virtual Ethernet Interfaces on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/weirdness-with-virtual-ethernet-interfaces-on-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2013 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/12/02/weirdness-with-virtual-ethernet-interfaces-on-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some experimenting with virtual Ethernet (veth) interfaces in Ubuntu as part of the ongoing work with network namespaces, LXC, and related technologies. A few times I&amp;rsquo;ve run into a very weird situation, and I have yet to figure out exactly what&amp;rsquo;s happening. I thought I might share it here in the hopes that someone else has seen this behavior and knows a) what causes it, and b) how to fix it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Network Virtualization and SDN</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/30/on-network-virtualization-and-sdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 18:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/30/on-network-virtualization-and-sdn/</guid>
      <description>Is there a difference between network virtualization and Software-Defined Networking (SDN)? If so, what is the relationship between them? Is one a subset of the other? This is a topic that is increasingly being discussed and debated. So, in a similar fashion to my post on network overlays vs. network virtualization, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d weigh in with some thoughts. This post, like all of my posts, is intended to help spark a conversation, so I encourage you to share your thoughts in the comments after you&amp;rsquo;ve finished reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Overlays vs. Network Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/16/network-overlays-vs-network-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 09:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2013/04/16/network-overlays-vs-network-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Dan Wendlandt said something today in the NVP deep dive session (liveblog of the session here) that really crystallized something for me. I thought perhaps I might be the only one that was seeing a trend, but Dan&amp;rsquo;s comment leads me to believe there are others seeing this trend as well. Here&amp;rsquo;s the quote, taken from my liveblog of the session:
 It is important to note, as Dan does, that a tunneling protocol alone is not network virtualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a CLI for Dropbox on Mac OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/08/why-a-cli-for-dropbox-on-mac-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 22:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/12/08/why-a-cli-for-dropbox-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking about a command-line interface (CLI) for Dropbox, and how I personally would take advantage of such a feature. So, after failing to find any indication that the Mac OS X Dropbox client contained a CLI, tonight on Twitter I made this comment:
 Too bad the #Mac version of @Dropbox doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a CLI.
 Shortly thereafter, I received this response:
 @scott_lowe @Dropbox What would you do with it if you did?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Might Leave OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/why-i-might-leave-os-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 13:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/30/why-i-might-leave-os-x/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Mac OS X user for a long time; I switched from Windows to OS X in 2003 when the OS X flavor of the day was 10.2 &amp;ldquo;Jaguar.&amp;rdquo; Since that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded hardware (moving from a Titanium PowerBook G4 to a Core 2 Duo MacBook Pro circa 2006, then to a 2009-era 15&amp;quot; Core 2 Duo-based MacBookPro, and finally to a 13&amp;quot; MacBook Pro with a Core i7) and I&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded OS X releases (from Jaguar to Panther to Tiger to Leopard and finally to Snow Leopard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Warning About Compiling libvirt</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/06/a-quick-warning-about-compiling-libvirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/11/06/a-quick-warning-about-compiling-libvirt/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve been reading my site for any length of time, you know that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with libvirt, the open source virtualization API, for a while. As part of my testing with libvirt, I&amp;rsquo;ve needed to stay on the &amp;ldquo;cutting edge&amp;rdquo; of libvirt&amp;rsquo;s development (so to speak), so I&amp;rsquo;ve been compiling my own version of libvirt from the source packages available from the libvirt HTTP server.
You can see some of the posts I&amp;rsquo;ve written about compiling libvirt:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling for the Best Storage Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/18/calling-for-the-best-storage-recommendations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 20:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/18/calling-for-the-best-storage-recommendations/</guid>
      <description>The funny thing about technology is that there is rarely one answer that fits all situations. This is the root of the reason behind the all-too-familiar IT answer, &amp;ldquo;It depends.&amp;rdquo; Rarely is this challenge more evident than when trying to write a book that is applicable to as broad an audience as possible. The challenge is compounded when the topic of your book is a large, complex suite of software like VMware vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subduing OpenStack Is a Bit Strong</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/10/subduing-openstack-is-a-bit-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 13:13:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/09/10/subduing-openstack-is-a-bit-strong/</guid>
      <description>Mirantis, a company that &amp;ldquo;delivers OpenStack cloud and open source application infrastructure&amp;rdquo; (taken from their About page), recently posted a blog entry about how accepting VMware as an OpenStack Foundation gold member was a mistake. In the post, the author states:
 Subduing OpenStack is exactly what VMWare [sic] did by joining the foundation.
 My readers know that I have, historically, been a big VMware fan, so naturally you might assume that I&amp;rsquo;m writing this post to defend VMware and their intentions, and talk about how the Mirantis author is wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hypervisor is Only Part of the Picture</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2012/03/29/the-hypervisor-is-only-part-of-the-picture/</guid>
      <description>The question of VMware&amp;rsquo;s future in the face of increasing competition is not a new one; it&amp;rsquo;s been batted around by quite a few folks. So Steven J. Vaughan-Nichols&amp;rsquo; article &amp;ldquo;Does VMware Have a Real Future?&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t really open any new doors or expose any new secrets that haven&amp;rsquo;t already been discussed elsewhere. What it does do, in my opinion, is show that the broader market hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet fully digested VMware&amp;rsquo;s long-term strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
