<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AWS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</title>
    <link>https://www.howellyang.com/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AWS on Scott&#39;s Weblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.howellyang.com/tags/aws/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 155</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/27/technology-short-take-155/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #155, just in time for the 2022 Memorial Day holiday weekend! (Here in the US, at least.) I mean, don&amp;rsquo;t you want to spend this weekend catching up on some technology-related articles instead of cooking on the grill and gathering with friends and family? I certainly hope not! Still, for those who need a little technology fix over the weekend, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve included something useful in the list of articles below. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-Tuning Control Plane Access with Cluster API</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/12/fine-tuning-control-plane-access-with-cluster-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/05/12/fine-tuning-control-plane-access-with-cluster-api/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api.sigs.k8s.io&#34;&gt;Cluster API&lt;/a&gt; creates a workload cluster, it also creates a load balancing solution to handle traffic to the workload cluster&amp;rsquo;s control plane. This is necessary so that the control plane endpoint is decoupled from the underlying control plane nodes (which facilitates scaling the control plane, among other things). On AWS, this mean creating an ELB and a set of security groups. For flexibility, Cluster API provides a limited ability to customize this control plane load balancer. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to use this functionality to fine-tune access to a workload cluster&amp;rsquo;s control plane when using Cluster API with AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 152</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/02/28/technology-short-take-152/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #152! Normally I&amp;rsquo;d publish a Technology Short Take in the morning on a Friday, but I really wanted to get this one out so I&amp;rsquo;m making it live late in the day on a Monday. Here&amp;rsquo;s hoping I&amp;rsquo;ve included some content below that you find useful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 151</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2022/01/21/technology-short-take-151/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #151, the first Technology Short Take of 2022. I hope everyone had a great holiday season and that 2022 is off to a wonderful start! I have a few more links than normal this time around, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t find articles in a couple categories. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll keep my eyes peeled and my RSS reader ready to pull in new articles in those categories for next time. And now for the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 149</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/12/10/technology-short-take-149/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #149! I&amp;rsquo;ll have one more Technology Short Take in 2021, scheduled for three weeks from now (on the last day of the year!). For now, though, I have a small collection of articles and links for your reading pleasure&amp;mdash;not as many as I usually include in a Technology Short Take, but better than nothing at all (I hope!). Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 147</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/29/technology-short-take-147/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #147! The list of articles is a bit shorter than usual this time around, but I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a good collection of articles and posts covering topics in networking, hardware (mostly focused on Apple&amp;rsquo;s processors), cloud computing, and virtualization. There&amp;rsquo;s bound to be something in here for most everyone! (At least, I hope so.) Enjoy your weekend reading!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing Cluster API AMI Selection</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/25/influencing-cluster-api-ami-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 09:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/25/influencing-cluster-api-ami-selection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api.sigs.k8s.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes Cluster API (CAPI) project&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;which recently released v1.0&amp;mdash;can, if you wish, help manage the underlying infrastructure associated with a cluster. (You&amp;rsquo;re also fully able to have CAPI &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api-aws.sigs.k8s.io/topics/consuming-existing-aws-infrastructure.html&#34;&gt;use existing infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; as well.) Speaking specifically of &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;, this means that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api-aws.sigs.k8s.io/&#34;&gt;Cluster API Provider for AWS&lt;/a&gt; is able to manage VPCs, subnets, routes and route tables, gateways, and&amp;mdash;of course&amp;mdash;EC2 instances. These EC2 instances are booted from a set of AMIs (Amazon Machine Images, definitely pronounced &amp;ldquo;ay-em-eye&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.technodrone.cloud/2019/03/ami-has-3-syllables-ami-aws.html&#34;&gt;three syllables&lt;/a&gt;) that are prepared and maintained by the CAPI project. In this short and simple post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to influence the AMI selection process that CAPI&amp;rsquo;s AWS provider uses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the External AWS Cloud Provider for Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/12/using-the-external-aws-cloud-provider-for-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/12/using-the-external-aws-cloud-provider-for-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018, after finding a dearth of information on setting up &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; with AWS integration/support, I set out to try to establish some level of documentation on this topic. That effort resulted in a few different blog posts, but ultimately culminated in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howellyang.com/2019/08/14/setting-up-aws-integrated-kubernetes-115-cluster-kubeadm/&#34;&gt;this post on setting up an AWS-integrated Kubernetes cluster using &lt;code&gt;kubeadm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Although originally written for Kubernetes 1.15, the process described in that post is still accurate for newer versions of Kubernetes. With the release of Kubernetes 1.22, though, the in-tree AWS cloud provider&amp;mdash;which is what is used/described in the post linked above&amp;mdash;has been deprecated in favor of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes/cloud-provider-aws&#34;&gt;the external cloud provider&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to set up an AWS-integrated Kubernetes cluster using the external AWS cloud provider.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 146</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/10/08/technology-short-take-146/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #146! Over the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve gathered a few technology-related links for you all. There&amp;rsquo;s some networking stuff, a few security links, and even a hardware-related article. But enough with the introduction&amp;mdash;let&amp;rsquo;s get into the content!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 145</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/09/24/technology-short-take-145/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #145! What will you find in this Tech Short Take? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s see&amp;hellip;stuff on Envoy, network automation, network designs, M1 chips (and potential open source variants!), a bevy of security articles (including a couple on very severe vulnerabilities), Kubernetes, AWS IAM, and so much more! I hope that you find something useful here. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing VPC Peering with Pulumi and Go</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/26/establishing-vpc-peering-with-pulumi-and-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 09:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/26/establishing-vpc-peering-with-pulumi-and-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pulumi.com/&#34;&gt;Pulumi&lt;/a&gt; to manage my lab infrastructure on &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/&#34;&gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt; (I shared some of the details in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pulumi.com/blog/supporting-kubernetes-with-pulumi/&#34;&gt;this April 2020 blog post&lt;/a&gt; published on the Pulumi site). Originally I started with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typescriptlang.org/&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt;, but later switched to &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;. Recently I had a need to add some VPC peering relationships to my lab configuration. I was concerned that this may pose some problems&amp;mdash;due entirely to the way I structure my Pulumi projects and stacks&amp;mdash;but as it turned out it was more straightforward than I expected. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share some example code and explain what I learned in the process of writing it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the AWS CLI to Tag Groups of AWS Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/23/using-aws-cli-tag-groups-of-aws-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 12:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/23/using-aws-cli-tag-groups-of-aws-resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To conduct some testing, I recently needed to spin up a group of &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; clusters on AWS. Generally speaking, my &amp;ldquo;weapon of choice&amp;rdquo; for something like this is &lt;a href=&#34;https://cluster-api.sigs.k8s.io/&#34;&gt;Cluster API (CAPI)&lt;/a&gt; with the AWS provider. Normally this would be enormously simple. In this particular case&amp;mdash;for reasons that I won&amp;rsquo;t bother going into here&amp;mdash;I needed to spin up all these clusters in a single VPC. This presents a problem for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/cluster-api-provider-aws/&#34;&gt;Cluster API Provider for AWS (CAPA)&lt;/a&gt;, as it currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t add some required tags to existing AWS infrastructure (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/cluster-api-provider-aws/issues/2584&#34;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt;). The fix is to add the tags manually, so in this post I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I used the AWS CLI to add the necessary tags.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 143</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 08:45:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/08/06/technology-short-take-143/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #143! I have what I think is an interesting list of links to share with you this time around. Since taking my new job at Kong, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending more time with Envoy, so you&amp;rsquo;ll see some Envoy-related content showing up in this Technology Short Take. I hope this collection of links has something useful for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology Short Take 142</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:25:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/07/16/technology-short-take-142/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Technology Short Take #142! This time around, the Networking section is a bit light, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got plenty of cloud computing links and articles for you to enjoy, along with some stuff on OSes and applications, programming, and soft skills. Hopefully there&amp;rsquo;s something useful here for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Port Names and Terminating HTTPS Traffic on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/21/kubernetes-port-names-and-terminating-https-traffic-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.howellyang.com/2021/06/21/kubernetes-port-names-and-terminating-https-traffic-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t immediately intuitive with regard to terminating HTTPS traffic on an AWS Elastic Load Balancer (ELB) when using &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; on AWS. At least, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t intuitive to &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that it may not be intuitive to some other readers as well. Kudos to my teammates &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hhoover&#34;&gt;Hart Hoover&lt;/a&gt; and Brent Yarger for identifying the resolution, which I&amp;rsquo;m going to call out in this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
